<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66154" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, SEPT 23-SUNDAY, 29.</title>
<headline>EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, SEPT 23-SUNDAY, 29.</headline>
<text>
<p>****</p>
<p>HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU social affairs ministers meet (Tuesday); agenda includes first reading on the changes to &quot;carcinogens&quot; directive and continued discussion on equal rights between men and women in decision-making.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (Wednesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission President Santer and Austrian Chancellor Franz Vranitzki hold joint news conference (Wednesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Economic and Social Committee holds plenary session (Wednesday-Thursday).</p>
<p>GALWAY, Ireland - EU culture and audiovisual ministers hold informal meeting (Wednesday-Thursday); main discussions focus on strategy for enhancing role of culture in the EU.</p>
<p>BERGEN, Norway - NATO defence ministers hold informal meeting (Wednesday-Thursday); main discussions focus on post-IFOR security arrangements and NATO external relations especially with Russia.</p>
<p>DUBLIN - EU justice and home affairs ministers hold informal meeting (Thursday-Friday); first broad discussion on trafficking in women and the problem of child abuse.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU telecoms ministers meet (Friday); discussions cover telecoms licences and liberalisation of postal services.</p>
<p>MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 23</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - IGC Working Party of EU foreign ministers' representatives meets to continue review of EU treaties (and Tuesday). Statement to be delivered on the state of the EU. European Commissioner Oreja attends.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Pinheiro attends EU/ACP joint assembly (1500/1300 GMT) (and Thursday).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- The future of EU/ACP relations.</p>
<p>- Urban development in ACP countries.</p>
<p>- Regional cooperation in ACP countries.</p>
<p>- Fisheries in ACP countries.</p>
<p>- The situation in Burundi, Great Lakes Region, Liberia, Nigeria, Angola, Mozambique, Sudan, Somalia and the Western Sahara.</p>
<p>- ACP-South Africa relations.</p>
<p>- Results of the conference on the information society.</p>
<p>- The draft EU directive on cocoa and its consequences for the ACP countries.</p>
<p>- The EU regulation on bananas.</p>
<p>NEW YORK (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioners Marin and van den Broek attend U.N. general assembly (to Friday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(1500/1300 GMT) Foreign Affairs subcommitee on Human Rights;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Regional Policy;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Fisheries;</p>
<p>Petitions.</p>
<p>PARIS - Group of the Party of European Socialists presents report on &quot;Public service television - the future of European television and cinema industry&quot; (1130/0930 GMT). Venue: Information office, 288, Blvd. St. Germain. Contact: Ambroise Perrin (322) 284 3062.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - Council of Europe parliamentary assembly meets (to Thursday). Portuguese President Jorge Sampaio gives address.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds seminar on &quot;World competition rules&quot; (1315/1115 GMT). Speaker is Karel Van Miert, member of the European Commission responsible for competition policy. Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, SEPTEMBER 24</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (EXPANDED ITEM) - Social Affairs Council (1000/0800 GMT).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Draft recommendation on equal participation of men and women in decision-making COM(95)593.</p>
<p>- Draft resolution on equal opportunities between men and women and the European structural funds.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on the establishment of an employment and labour market policy committee.</p>
<p>- First reading on the modification of the &quot;carcinogens&quot; directive 90/394/EEC; principally to fix professional exposition limits to benzene.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Flynn information to the Council on information and consultation of workers COM(95)547.</p>
<p>- Joint report on employment.</p>
<p>- Commission presents on new proposal for directive on the burden of proof in the event of discrimination due to sex.</p>
<p>- Green paper on living and working in the information society: priotiry to human dimension.</p>
<p>- Other:</p>
<p>- Commissioner Flynn communication on the amendment of directive 86/378/EEC on equal treatment in occupational social security schemes.</p>
<p>- &quot;A&quot; point:</p>
<p>- Adoption of the directive on posting of workers COM(91)230.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IGC Working Party of EU foreign ministers' representatives meets to continue review of EU treaties (second of two days).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner de Silguy meets Russian Central Bank Chairman Serguei Doubinine.</p>
<p>LONDON - European Commission hosts conference on &quot;Private security industry in society: a European perspective&quot; (and Wednesday). Topics include: vocational training, regulation, standards of service and employment. Venue: Forte Crest Hotel. Contact: Nigel Greaves Associates, Andrew Mackay (44) 1886 833 034.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(0900/0700 GMT) Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Regional Policy;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Fisheries;</p>
<p>Petitions;</p>
<p>Inquiry into Fraud in Transit;</p>
<p>(1500/1300 GMT) Agriculture;</p>
<p>Budget - European Commissioner Oreja gives address;</p>
<p>External Economic Relation;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Social Affairs;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>(1630/1430 GMT) Economic and monetary; European Commissioner Monti gives address.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - The International Planned Parenthood Federation holds news conference to launch &quot;Charter of sexual and reproductive rights&quot; (1500/1300 GMT). Venue: International Press Centre (IPC). Contact: Vicky Claeys (322) 230 9271.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - The European Aviation Club holds symposium on &quot;The impact of the third package&quot; (0915/0715 GMT). Speakers include: European Commissioner Kinnock Head of Cabinet Philip Lowe and Air Transport Policy Head of Unit Frederik Sorensen. Venue: Amigo Hotel. Contact: the European Aviation Club (322) 647 0760.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds seminar on &quot;The inter-governmental conference&quot; (1315/1115 GMT). Speaker is Michael Patijn, State Secretary for Foreign Affairs, The Netherlands. Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - Council of Europe parliamentary assembly (second of four days). Lativian President Guntis Ulmanis and Estonian Foreign Minister Slim Kallas give addresses.</p>
<p>ROTTERDAM, The Netherlands - Royal Dutch Jaarbeurs holds conference on &quot;The European market for infrastructural projects - EMIP '96&quot; (1400/1200 GMT) (to Thursday). Venue: Erasmus Expo and Congress Centre. Contact: Pieter Kannegieter (31) 30 2955 453.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, SEPTEMBER 25</p>
<p>GALWAY, Ireland - Informal Culture and Audiovisual Council (and Thursday). Main discussions focus on developing a strategy for enhancing the position and role of culture in the EU and debate the importance of the cultural element in the EU's audiovisual policy, particularly in the context of the vital position of public service broadcasting services in EU member states. Venue: Galway University.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (0930/0730 GMT). No agenda available yet.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission President Santer meets Austrian Chancellor Franz Vranitzki; hold joint news conference at 1300/1100 GMT.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission President meets Palestinan Parlement President Ahmed Qurie.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(0900/0700 GMT) Agriculture;</p>
<p>Budget - European Commissioner Pinheiro gives address;</p>
<p>External Economic Relations;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Social Affairs;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>(1500/1300 GMT) Social Affairs;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>Budgetary Control;</p>
<p>Institutional Affairs.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (EXPANDED ITEM) - Economic and Social Committee (ECOSOC) holds plenary session (1430/1230 GMT) (and Thursday).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Impact of EMU - Economic and social aspects of the convergence and sensibilisation of the single currency.</p>
<p>- Surveillance and control network for transmissible diseases COM(96)78.</p>
<p>- Community water policy COM(96)59.</p>
<p>- Legal, regulatory and administrative requirements in consumer credits COM(96)79.</p>
<p>- Community law in the protection of consumer interests COM(95)712.</p>
<p>- Green paper on the legal protection of encrypted services in the internal market COM(96)76.</p>
<p>- Accessibility to the establishment of credit and solvency ratio COM(96)183.</p>
<p>- Solvency ratio of credit establishment COM(95)709.</p>
<p>- Aid to shipbuilding COM(96)309.</p>
<p>- Multi-annual programme for European tourism (1997-2000) &quot;Philoxenia&quot; COM(96)168.</p>
<p>- Cohesion and environment policy COM(95)509.</p>
<p>- EU's role in urbanism.</p>
<p>- Towards an equal and efficient pricing in transport COM(95)691.</p>
<p>- Admission conditions for non resident drivers transporting passengers by road COM(95)729.</p>
<p>- Implementation of a Community policy in telecoms and postal services COM(96)45.</p>
<p>- Requirements for summer time COM(96)106.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Evolution of the telecoms universal service COM(96)73.</p>
<p>- Harmonisation of technical regulations and administrative procedures in civil aviation COM(96)186.</p>
<p>- Future of social protection: framework for a European debate.</p>
<p>- Equal treatment for men and women in employment, training and working conditions COM(96)93.</p>
<p>- Conservation of fisheries ressources in the Mediterranean COM(96)128.</p>
<p>- Technical conservation measures in fisheries COM(96)296.</p>
<p>- Agricultural problems in EU peripherical and insular zones.</p>
<p>- Marketing of sugar beet grain, durum wheat, cereals COM(96)127.</p>
<p>- Intervention conditions in the fisheries, aquaculture and product processing sectors COM(96)189.</p>
<p>- Marketing of lemon based processed foods COM(96)240.</p>
<p>- Protection of geographical indications and denominations of farm products and foodstuff COM(96)266.</p>
<p>- Technical conservation measures in fisheries COM(96)317.</p>
<p>- White paper &quot;Internal market - central and eastern European countries&quot; COM(95)163.</p>
<p>BERGEN, Norway (EXPANDED ITEM) - NATO defence ministers hold informal meeting (and Thursday).</p>
<p>Main discussions focus on post-IFOR security arrangements; NATO internal reorganisation and NATO external relations with Russia in the partnership for peace process.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - Council of Europe parliamentary assembly (third of four days). OECD Secretary General Donald Johnston gives address.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>THURSDAY, SEPTEMBER 26</p>
<p>DUBLIN (EXPANDED ITEM) - Informal Justice and Home Affairs Council (and Friday). Discussions include widening the remit of the Europol Drugs Unit; first broad discussion on the Commission's forthcoming communication on trafficking in women and discussion on child sex abuse.</p>
<p>NEW YORK (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner van den Broek addresses U.N. general assembly on &quot;Is the EU's foreign policy taking shape?&quot;</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(0900/0700 GMT) Environment;</p>
<p>Budgetary Control;</p>
<p>Institutional Affairs;</p>
<p>Economic and Monetary - European Commissioner Van Miert gives address;</p>
<p>(1500/1300 GMT) Institutional Affairs.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - The Greens in the European Parliament and EuroCommerce hold joint news briefing for the launch of a world-wide initiative for the protection of the consumer &quot;Unlabelled gene-soya soon in every supermarket?&quot;. EuroCommerce Secretary General Henrik Kroener and MEP Hiltrud Breyer jointly comment on: how can consumer-protection be guaranteed; how can the right of information be safeguarded and what action will the European retailers take? Venue: International Press Centre (IPC). Contact: EuroCommerce by fax (322) 230 0078.</p>
<p>BERLIN - The Kangaroo Group in collaboration with the Fondation Europe et Societe host European Parliament and Commission conference on &quot;On the way to the European home market: the single currency&quot; (to Saturday). Agenda includes: role of the single currency in the development of the EU; priorities of the Irish Presidency regarding the single currency; preparation for the move to the single currency; impact on the French banking system; impact on financial services and policy; impact on business; single currency and social aspects; relations between the single currency and the currencies which will join the EMU later; single currency and political union. Speakers include: MEPs Karl von Wogau, Giorgos Katiforis and Elmar Brok; Irish Finance Minister Ruairi Quinn; European Economy Commissioner Yves-Thibault de Silguy. Venue: Steigenberger Hotel. Contact: Kangaroo Group conference office (322) 284 4438.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Forum Europe holds conference on behalf of DG XIII on &quot;Wide-screen television 16:9&quot; (0900/0700 GMT). Main topics discussed: Issues past, present and future; broadcasting beyond; the political challenges for 16:9. Speakers include: European Commissioner Bangemann. News conference at 1100/0900 GMT). Venue: Albert hall, 651 chaussee de Wavre. Contact: Forum Europe (322) 736 1430.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (EXPANDED ITEM) - Club de Bruxelles holds conference on &quot;The future of Biotechnologies in Europe&quot; (and Friday). Topics include: development and role of biotechnology R&amp;D in the EU; innovation in health care: novel pharmaceutical products; new crops from plant biotechnology; the &quot;greening&quot; of industry: clean products and processes; biotechnology in Europe society: public perceptions; industrial competitiveness and biotechnological innovation. Speakers include: European Commissioner Cresson. Contact: Club de Bruxelles (322) 743 1520.</p>
<p>BERGEN, Norway (NEW ITEM) - NATO defence ministers hold informal meeting (second of two days). NATO defence ministers meet Russia Defence Minister Igo Rodionov (&quot;16 + 1&quot;).</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - Council of Europe parliamentary assembly (last of four days). Andorran government head Marc Forne gives address.</p>
<p>DUESSELDORF, Germany - Euromanagement holds conference on &quot;The future of European thermal waste treatment - waste to energy&quot; (and Friday). Main topics include: how can you most benefit from the growing waste-energy market; how can you lower the costs of thermal waste treatment; strategic issues for waste to energy: opportunities v/ obstacles; the future of price policies for renewable energy across Europe; improving efficiency of waste power plants. Venue: Radisson SAS Hotel. Contact: Euromanagement, Michele Nichols (31) 40 2 974 944.</p>
<p>WARSAW - Euromoney Seminars holds third annual conference on &quot;The 1996 Polish investment forum&quot; (and Friday). Venue: Bristol Hotel. Contact: Euromoney Seminars (44) 171 7798793.</p>
<p>ROME - European Association of Advertising Agencies (EAAA) holds annual conference on &quot;The future of brand-building across borders&quot;. Contact: Paola di Discordia, EAAA (322) 280 1603.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, SEPTEMBER 27</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Telecoms Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a European Parliament and Council directive on a common framework for general authorisations and individual licences in the field of telecommunications services COM(95)545.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a European Parliament and Council directive on common rules for the development of Community postal services and the improvement of services quality COM(95)227.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a European Parliament and Council decision on action at Union level in the field of satellite personal communications services in the European Union COM(95)529.</p>
<p>- Proposal for EP and Council directive on the application of Open Network Provision (ONP) to voice telephony COM(95)575.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds workshop on &quot;Completing the internal market for electricity: the meaning of the June 20th decision&quot; (1300/1100 GMT). Speakers include MEP Claude Desama. Venue: Place du Congres 1. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>STRESA, Italy (NEW ITEM) - Assembly of European Regions (AER) holds news conference on &quot;AER-OECD: a new dynamic for east-west cooperation&quot; (1200/1000 GMT). Venue: Regina Palace Hotel. Contact: Sylvie Gaschet by fax (33) 88 32 84 97.</p>
<p>SATURDAY, SEPTEMBER 28</p>
<p>WASHINGTON (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner de Silguy attends G7 Finance and IMF interim committee and World Bank development committee meetings (and Sunday).</p>
<p>SUNDAY, SEPTEMBER 29</p>
<p>No events scheduled.</p>
<p>If you have items for inclusion in the Reuter European</p>
<p>Community diary, please contact:</p>
<p>Telephone: Cynthia Simpson (322) 287 6851</p>
<p>Fax: (322) 230 5573</p>
<p>For technical queries regarding</p>
<p>the service, please call (322) 287 6666</p>
<p>Reuters 61, rue de Treves 1040 BRUSSELS</p>
<p>- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -</p>
<p>EC Report (C)opyright Reuters Limited</p>
<p>Unauthorised copying prohibited.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
