<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661516" id="root" date="1997-06-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Jospin team prepares key French policy statement.</title>
<headline>Jospin team prepares key French policy statement.</headline>
<byline>Francois Raitberger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's new Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin met his cabinet on Thursday to prepare a first statement to parliament on how to turn election promises into jobs.</p>
<p>Before the two-hour working session, Jospin met European Commission President Jacques Santer and said afterwards that France's concern to redirect European economic policy towards promoting growth and jobs had been &quot;understood&quot;.</p>
<p>Less than two weeks after winning power in elections, Jospin faces intense pressure from Paris's partners to ratify the European Union's budget stability pact, a condition for European monetary union, at a summit in Amsterdam next week.</p>
<p>He is also under conflicting pressures at home from unions calling for wage hikes and pushing him to keep campaign promises to create 700,000 jobs for young people and cut the working week to 35 hours from 39 with no reduction in pay.</p>
<p>Louis Viannet, leader of the Communist-led CGT union, told reporters after talks with Jospin that he had asked for the monthly minimum wage to be raised to 8,500 francs ($1,465) from 6,400 ($1,100).</p>
<p>Nicole Notat of the Socialist-dominated CFDT union also urged Jospin to hike the minimum wage and quickly boost other subsidies for low-paid workers.</p>
<p>But Jaen Gandois, head of the powerful CNPF employers' organisation, said the business community opposed raising the minimum wage unless the cost was offset by lower payroll taxes.</p>
<p>Jospin will outline his policies in his first statement to the National Assembly on June 19 and announce key dates for implementing his programme -- a revised budget and a national conference on jobs, wages and working hours, bringing together government, employers and trade unions.</p>
<p>In a departure from recent practice, the policy statement will not be followed by a confidence vote, newly elected National Assembly speaker Laurent Fabius announced, reading a note from Parliamentary Relations Minister Daniel Vaillant.</p>
<p>The 577-member assembly met for the first time since the June 1 election which swept a leftist alliance including Socialists, Communists and Greens into power and ended four years of centre-right rule.</p>
<p>Unlike the weekly cabinet meetings chaired by President Jacques Chirac at his Elysee palace, the ministers met on Thursday at Jospin's Matignon office across the Seine river.</p>
<p>Aides said Jospin would hold similar full-cabinet sessions without Chirac once a month, with meetings of senior ministers every two weeks to stimulate exchanges of ideas.</p>
<p>They said Jospin asked his ministers to impose a new, more easy-going style. They cited as an example a friendly visit paid by Jospin on his office's switchboard operators.</p>
<p>Thursday's working session ended with an official picture of the cabinet, taken without Chirac, who has refused to pose with the ministers at the Elysee, a symptom of the uneasy &quot;cohabitation&quot; between the conservative president and a left-wing government.</p>
<p>Jospin and Chirac have been warily circling each other since the left took power, anxious to mark out their respective turf without causing sparks.</p>
<p>In an apparent sign of deference to Chirac, Jospin announced he would not accompany the president to a summit of the Group of Seven industrialsied nations next week in Denver.</p>
<p>He had initially said he wanted to attend major international meetings but later clarified the remark by saying he had not made up his mind on Denver.</p>
<p>The first wave of opinion polls since the election showed voters had a good initial impression of Jospin.</p>
<p>But the polls were mixed on Chirac. Most showed his popularity falling after he was forced to begin sharing power with Jospin, but one showed voter confidence in the president rising somewhat since the election.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jean-Pierre Chevenement said he planned changes in France's immigration laws, toughened earlier this year when the centre-right controlled parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;My goal is to draft a bill for the autumn session,&quot; he said. The Socialists pledged during the election campaign to repeal the earlier legislation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
