<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66164" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks end at fifth straight record close.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks end at fifth straight record close.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CHANGE				   CHANGE</p>
<p>TSE	  5287.47    +11.44  HI   5289.26	 LO 5274.47</p>
<p>DJI	  5893.26    +25.52  GOLD (LONDON)   US$382.50 -0.25</p>
<p>FTSE100    3964.10    -10.20  GOLD (NY-COMEX) US$</p>
<p>NIKKEI    21112.24   -210.61  LME CASH NICKEL US$7265   -0.40</p>
<p>CANDLR	1.3669		LME CASH ALUM   US$1377.0 -0.13</p>
<p>CAN 30-YR   101.65     -0.05  BRENT OCT CRUDE US$21.86  -0.05</p>
<p>--------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>* Toronto stocks end the week with fifth straight record close * TSE volumes heavy due to triple witching expiry * 14 sectors evenly split * 94 million shares traded worth C$1.36 billion  </p>
<p>Toronto stocks ended at record highs for a fifth straight session on Friday, while triple witching expiry spurred a day of heavy trading on Canada's biggest stock market.</p>
<p>The TSE 300 Composite Index climbed 11.44 points to 5287.47, surpassing the previous record close set on Thursday.</p>
<p>The index also recorded a new intra-day high of 5289.26.</p>
<p>Just over 94 million shares were traded worth C$1.36 billion. Triple witching is the quarterly period when options, futures and options on futures all expire. Advancing stocks outnumbered declines 462 to 443 with 268 issues flat.  </p>
<p>Toronto's 14 sub-groups were evenly split. The strong side was led by consumer products, conglomerates, technology and financial services.</p>
<p>&quot;Bank stocks have been doing well. There is some expectation that the Bank of Canada may lower rates again and that will help interest sensitive stocks,&quot; said Rolie Bradley, an institutional salesman with Maison Placements Canada Inc.</p>
<p>The TSE weakest groups included gold and precious metals, transportation and communications. Analysts said investors will be watching the bond market next week and its reaction to the U.S. Federal Reserve's policy meeting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Loewen Group Inc fell 0.60 to 57.40 on 564,000 shares. Loewen, the target of a US$2.8 billion takeover bid from rival Service Corp International, announced a US$240 million acquisition of a California funeral home operator today.</p>
<p>* Among heavy traders, Toronto-Dominion Bank rose 0.60 to 28.60, a 52-week high, on 1.7 million shares. National Bank of Canada closed up 0.10 to 12 on 2.2 million shares after hitting a 52-week peak of 12.10.</p>
<p>* Stampeder Exploration Ltd topped the most-active list, ending up 0.15 to 5.65 on 2.7 million shares.</p>
<p>	  -- Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
