<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661636" id="root" date="1997-06-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-JENKINS SCORES 24 POINTS IN LIONS WIN.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-JENKINS SCORES 24 POINTS IN LIONS WIN.</headline>
<byline>Mark Stokes</byline>
<dateline>DURBAN 1997-06-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Welsh full-back Neil Jenkins contributed 24 points as the British Lions turned in the best display of their South African tour to outclass the Natal Sharks 42-12 at Kings Park on Saturday.</p>
<p>Just a week away from their first test against the Springboks, the Lions produced impressive pace and control to run in three unanswered tries through Gregor Townsend, Mike Catt and Lawrence Dallaglio.</p>
<p>Natal, South Africa's reigning Currie Cup champions, may have been missing six Springboks in this match but they appeared shell-shocked and erratic as the Lions upped the tempo throughout.</p>
<p>All Natal's points came from their fullback Gavin Lawless with four successful penalty kicks out of four, while Jenkins announced his goal-kicking intentions for the forthcoming test series with six penalties and three conversions from 11 attempts.</p>
<p>After a storming start by the Lions, Jenkins opened the scoring in the eighth minute with a penalty in front of the posts after Natal were guilty of lowering a scrum inside their own 22.</p>
<p>However Lawless put the home side ahead 6-3 going into the second quarter with two penalty kicks in the space of seven minutes.</p>
<p>But the Lions, dominating both territory and possession, then took charge through their inspirational flyhalf Townsend.</p>
<p>The Scottish stand-off levelled the scores with a snap drop goal from 30 metres out and then scored a try just one minute later.</p>
<p>Irish hooker Keith Wood chipped the ball ahead from open play and, with Natal flyhalf Hans Scriba failing to gather cleanly, Townsend won the race to the touchdown. Jenkins converted to give the Lions a 13-6 lead.</p>
<p>Lawless and Jenkins then exchanged penalties for a halftime score of 16-9 and the Lions maintained their impressive pace of play right to the end, scoring two tries in the last seven minutes.</p>
<p>Replacement centre Catt scored under the posts after charging down a Townsend kick-ahead and England flanker Dallaglio then crossed the line on the stroke of full-time. A sweeping passage of play down the right wing, with the ball speedily recycled, provided the loose forward with an inviting gap to score under the posts.</p>
<p>Jenkins coolly slotted his third conversion of the match for a haul of 24 points.</p>
<p>Welsh scrum-half Rob Howley left the field in the 13th minute of the match with a serious shoulder injury and has been ruled out of the rest of the tour.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Natal: Gavin Lawless; Shaun Payne, Jeremy Thomson, Pieter Muller, Joos Joubert; Hans Scriba, Robert du Preez; Dieter Kriese, Wayne Fyvie (captain), Wickus van Heerden (Ryan Strudwick 32 min), Nico Wegner, John Slade, Rob Kempson, John Allan, Ollie le oux (John Smit 75 min).</p>
<p>British Lions: Neil Jenkins; Ieuan Evans, Allan Bateman (Mike Catt 65 min), Scott Gibbs, Alan Tait; Gregor Townsend, Rob Howley (Matt Dawson 13 min); Eric Miller, Richard Hill, Lawrence Dallaglio, Simon Shaw, Martin Johnson (captain), David Young, Keith Wood, Tom Smith (Jason Leonard 67 min).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
