<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661726" id="root" date="1997-06-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatia's &quot;father&quot; expected to remain at helm.</title>
<headline>Croatia's &quot;father&quot; expected to remain at helm.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Smith</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-06-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Franjo Tudjman, who built independent Croatia from the ruins of the Yugoslav war and has held power since with an iron grip, is expected to sweep to victory in Sunday's presidential election.</p>
<p>He will then have, on paper, five more years to try to realise Croatia's dream of becoming a paid-up member of Western Europe.</p>
<p>But Tudjman is reported to be suffering from cancer and observers say he is unlikely to survive a full term of office.</p>
<p>He has won sympathy during the last year as his trademark shock of silver hair has gradually thinned and he has vanished from public view sporadically while undergoing medical treatment.</p>
<p>Who will succeed him remains a big question in Croatia -- neither of the two opposition candidates in Sunday's election are considered presidential material, and the field remains open.</p>
<p>A charismatic politician with a penchant for wearing white military uniforms bedecked with medals when inspecting troops on national days, Tudjman has emulated his mentor Josip Broz Tito, partisan and later communist Yugoslav leader.</p>
<p>Tudjman led his country in a successful war against Serbian-led Yugoslavia in 1991.</p>
<p>After proclaiming independence for the first time since Croatia came under Hungarian rule in 1102, he was hailed as the &quot;Father of the Nation&quot;. His popularity has remained strong despite criticism at home and abroad in later years.</p>
<p>He was accused of plotting with Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic to divide Bosnia during the war to form a greater Serbia and a greater Croatia.</p>
<p>However he later won praise from the West for signing the Dayton peace treaty which ended the Bosnian war in 1995.</p>
<p>His critics recently returned to berate him for failing to meet commitments he made in that treaty, especially his control of the media and failure to stop attacks on minority Serbs.</p>
<p>In 1989 he formed the Croatian Democratic Union (HDZ) which set its sights on Croatian independence as the federation unravelled and communist governments across eastern Europe collapsed.</p>
<p>He first gained international attention spearheading a national revival movement which culminated in the 1991 secession from Yugoslavia, a year after the HDZ defeated the communists in the first free democratic elections.</p>
<p>But following his election as president of independent Croatia with 56 percent of the vote in August 1992, Tudjman had to face accusations of corruption in his party and criticism of his autocratic style.</p>
<p>Since the end of the Bosnian war, Croatia has been viewed by the United States as a possible stabilising force in the region and diplomats say its role is vital to shore up Bosnia's Moslem-Croat Federation, a cornerstone of the treaty formed with the help of U.S. diplomacy in 1994.</p>
<p>The United States has led attacks on Tudjman and a recent visit by U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright highlighted impatience with Croatia's slow progress on compliance with the Dayton treaty.</p>
<p>His reluctance to hand over indicted war criminals to The Hague war crimes tribunal has also irritated the West.</p>
<p>The United States has told Croatia that international loans and integration into Western institutions could be blocked if their demands are not met.</p>
<p>In his second term Tudjman will have to manage the reintegration of the last Serb enclave to come under Zagreb's rule, now administered by a United Nations mission.</p>
<p>The current U.N. mandate, covering 5,000 troops, ends on July 15 but the United States has hinted it might call for an extension.</p>
<p>The U.N. Security Council will vote soon on whether to reduce the mandate to a smaller monitoring mission.</p>
<p>With around 100,000 Serbs living in Eastern Slavonia, Croatia has to orchestrate a huge population swap to free the homes of Croats expelled from the region early in the war. The Serbs will have to leave -- around half are expected to go back to their pre-war homes, and the rest to leave for Serbia.</p>
<p>Some will stay, and their integration with thousands of Croat refugees will be closely watched.</p>
<p>Tudjman's rhetoric led Jews, Serbs and human rights groups to accuse him and the HDZ of reviving symbols of the World War Two fascist regime and trying to whitewash their crimes.</p>
<p>But his nationalist government denied accusations of having fostered a revival of fascist ideology, saying the symbols dated from mediaeval times. He also apologised to world Jewry for perceived insensitivity.</p>
<p>Tudjman's relations with Bosnian Croats are bound to come under the microscope as Croatia tries to restart negotiations on a cooperation agreement with the European Union.</p>
<p>Zagreb armed and paid hardline Herzegovina Croats during their 1993-94 war against Bosnia's central government, with the aim of carving out a Croat state in western Bosnia and merging it with Croatia.</p>
<p>The Herzegovina Croats have not honoured Dayton treaty commitments to dismantle their fiefdom and merge it with the Moslem-Croat federation -- they spend the Croatian kuna and drive cars with almost identical plates to those in Croatia.</p>
<p>In 1995 voters angered by corruption and keen for a more genuine democracy slashed the HDZ majority in parliament and voted in an opposition mayor in Zagreb. But Tudjman refused to hand over power, citing a presidential &quot;national security&quot; veto.</p>
<p>He appointed an acting mayor until elections were held in April this year, when an HDZ candidate was elected.</p>
<p>A rise in popular discontent reinvigorated opposition parties and stirred rare street protests in Zagreb in 1996, particularly over an independent radio station which Tudjman had tried to close down. The licence was later renewed.</p>
<p>However he has risen above his critics and sympathy for his illness, as well as solidarity among Croats in the face of foreign criticism, seem likely to see him romp home on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
