<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661722" id="root" date="1997-06-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian official criticises Kulikov over Chechnya.</title>
<headline>Russian official criticises Kulikov over Chechnya.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior Russian official on Saturday accused Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov of hampering progress towards lasting peace in breakaway Chechnya by blocking a prisoner exchange.</p>
<p>Boris Berezovsky, deputy secretary of Russia's policy-making Security Council, told a news conference that he was perplexed by Kulikov's behaviour over the exchange, which involved 11 special policemen who fall within his ministry's remit.</p>
<p>&quot;I am at a loss to understand the interior minister's position on this issue,&quot; Berezovsky said. &quot;Kulikov, who should be concerned above all about helping to free people, especially because they are his people who are being held.&quot;</p>
<p>Kulikov, who was not immediately available for comment on the charge, has been accused before of taking a hawkish line over Chechnya, torn by 21 months of fighting between local separatists and Russian troops.</p>
<p>He commanded Moscow's military campaign in Chechnya before being appointed minister in July 1995 and is the only senior official involved in the conflict to have survived a subsequent sweep-out of hardliners by President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>The biggest clash came when former Security Council Secretary Alexander Lebed, who organised a truce in Chechnya in August, asked Yeltsin to choose between himself and Kulikov.</p>
<p>Yeltsin told Kulikov to stay on and later sacked Lebed, accusing him of overstepping his position and having overt presidential ambitions.</p>
<p>Berezovsky, a business magnate whose appointment to the Security Council last year sparked a row over his suitability for the job, played a key role in securing last month's peace deal which built on the August ceasefire.</p>
<p>He said that Kulikov's move was particularly unhelpful now that Moscow had decided to tell the truth and keep its promises to the Chechens.</p>
<p>&quot;What happened before was that the federal centre played a cheating game with the Chechen side. I don't want to say whether the Chechen side cheated the federal centre or not. What's very important is that we have fundamentally changed our position.&quot;</p>
<p>Berezovsky said that, as agreed, the Chechens had handed over a list of three Chechen prisoners they wanted released in return for freeing the 11 policemen, along with the places they were being held.</p>
<p>&quot;Kulikov said they weren't in the places mentioned, but a bit later, about a month, I found out they were there,&quot; he said. &quot;Here we suddenly come across an obstacle. I think it's completely wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>Berezovsky, who took part in the latest round of talks with the separatists, which brought a memorandum on transporting oil across Chechnya, declined to give details of the deal, saying only that Russia had to pay for peace in Chechnya.</p>
<p>The security of the pipeline, which runs from Azerbaijan to the Russian Black Sea port of Novorossiisk, is important for an international consortium involved in an $8 billion deal to extract oil from the Caspian Sea.</p>
<p>The consortium plans to send the first oil through the pipeline by October.</p>
<p>Berezovsky said he could not rule out a return to the conflict if hawks came to the helm in Russia, but that Yeltsin had done much &quot;to correct the situation at the end of 1994&quot;, when he launched his military campaign.</p>
<p>Hundreds of prisoners, both Chechens and Russian soldiers remain in capitivity and a recent spate of kidnappings of journalists in Chechnya have complicated the peace process.</p>
<p>But Berezovsky said that both he and Chechen President Aslan Maskhadov were determined to make sure that everyone was freed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
