<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661769" id="root" date="1997-06-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Burma says seeks to end isolation through ASEAN.</title>
<headline>Burma says seeks to end isolation through ASEAN.</headline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1997-06-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burma hopes to end nearly 30 years of isolation with its imminent membership in the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), official media reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>Lieutenant General Khin Nyunt, Secretary One of the ruling military State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC), was quoted as saying Burma hoped to exploit its vast natural resources with help from members of the regional bloc.</p>
<p>&quot;Although Myanmar (Burma) is not economically strong, it is the richest in natural resources in the region and it is poised for economic development. Although it lacks know-how it has technicians,&quot; Khin Nyunt said on Friday in his first public comments on Burma's entry into ASEAN.</p>
<p>&quot;With support and assistance from other ASEAN members, Myanmar will achieve development within a short time and contribute to the progress and stability of the region,&quot; he said in an address to a Burmese committee he chairs that is preparing for ASEAN entry.</p>
<p>ASEAN groups Thailand, Malaysia, Philippines, Indonesia, Singapore, Brunei and Vietnam.</p>
<p>It agreed last month to allow Burma, Laos and Cambodia to become new members at the end of July despite pleas from the United States and other opponents of the Burmese military not to let Rangoon in.</p>
<p>Burma has been criticised for human rights abuses and suppressing the democratic opposition led by Nobel Peace laureate Aung San Suu Kyi.</p>
<p>&quot;Myanmar has stood in complete isolation for nearly 30 years. Today's world situation suggests that powerful nations are bullying small nations increasingly,&quot; Khin Nyunt said.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore it is impossible for a nation to stand alone with the doors closed and it is necessary to join hands with the nations which have mutual understanding and respect.&quot;</p>
<p>Burma was annexed to British-ruled India in the 19th century and became independent in January 1948.</p>
<p>In 1962, armed forces chief of staff General Ne Win staged a coup and ruled the country with an iron hand. Soon afterwards, he established the &quot;Burmese Way to Socialism&quot;, nationalising key sectors of the economy and almost sealing the country off from the rest of the world.</p>
<p>He resigned in 1988 after the rise of Suu Kyi's democracy movement which was suppressed two months later.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
