<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661754" id="root" date="1997-06-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai army advises caution over Pol Pot reports.</title>
<headline>Thai army advises caution over Pol Pot reports.</headline>
<byline>Sutin Wannabovorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-06-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's powerful army chief said on Saturday journalists should be wary of reports that Khmer Rouge supremo Pol Pot is on the run because they might be politically motivated.</p>
<p>&quot;You (media) have to be cautious about every bit of information about Cambodia before reporting, because I get the sense that many reports might have been politically motivated,&quot; General Chetta Thanajaro said.</p>
<p>Cambodia's deputy chief of general staff Nhiek Bun Chhay told reporters on Saturday that Pol Pot had slaughtered his defence chief Son Sen and 11 members of his family and was holding fellow leader Khieu Samphan and two other senior Khmer Rouge officials as hostages.</p>
<p>He said Pol Pot was holed up about 20 km (12 miles) east of the northern guerrilla stronghold of Anlong Veng with some 300 fighters and their families, but about 1,000 Khmer Rouge rebels who had defected to the Cambodian government were closing in on him.</p>
<p>&quot;This is also one of the reports that you have to be cautious about, because the report may have been leaked out to benefit one party and discredit another,&quot; Chetta said.</p>
<p>Some scepticism has greeted the reports on Pol Pot, first disclosed by Cambodia's First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh on Friday.</p>
<p>Ranariddh's political rival and co-premier Hun Sen confirmed that Son Sen had been killed but said he was not convinced that Pol Pot was the murderer. He also did not believe that Pol Pot had taken his fellow senior comrades-in-arms as hostages.</p>
<p>Cambodia's two rival premiers are seeking to make political capital out of the Khmer Rouge issue ahead of planned general elections next year, analysts said.</p>
<p>With his latest reports on disarray within the Khmer Rouge, Ranariddh may be aiming to remove reviled Khmer Rouge leaders from the political scene and marshall the support of as many guerrilla defectors as possible to his side during the polls, they said.</p>
<p>Chetta also denied that the Maoist hardliner had fled into Thailand with the group.</p>
<p>&quot;That Pol Pot might be in Thailand is a groundless report spread by some out to damage the reputation of the country,&quot; Chetta said in response to reporters' questions.</p>
<p>&quot;No, Pol Pot is not in Thailand, and he is not welcome here. If I myself do not know about this news then who else will know about him?&quot;</p>
<p>Thailand and Cambodia have sealed the border areas near Anlong Veng in efforts to trap Pol Pot.</p>
<p>Thailand used to be the closest ally of the reviled Khmer Rouge and its leader in the early 1980s.</p>
<p>Bangkok led the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) in establishing a Cambodian coalition of resistance forces including the Khmer Rouge to topple the then Vietnamese-installed Phnom Penh government.</p>
<p>With supplies from China, the resistance forces used Thai territory to fight Phnom Penh until the warring factions signed a peace accord in Paris in 1991 that paved the way for a 1993 U.N.-sponsored general election.</p>
<p>&quot;The Thai connection with Khmer Rouge has been totally cut right after they reached the peace agreement,&quot; Chetta said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
