<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661810" id="root" date="1997-06-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli troops wound 20 Palestinians in Hebron.</title>
<headline>Israeli troops wound 20 Palestinians in Hebron.</headline>
<dateline>HEBRON, West Bank 1997-06-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli troops firing rubber bullets shot and slightly wounded 20 Palestinian protesters in the West Bank town of Hebron on Saturday, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The Hebron clashes erupted when dozens of Palestinian youths began hurling stones and petrol bombs at Israeli troops guarding Jewish enclaves in the city of 100,000 Palestinians. Some 400 Jewish settlers live in the heavily fortified enclaves.</p>
<p>The Israeli army confirmed there were clashes but said so far it had no reports of casualties.</p>
<p>Several Palestinian demonstrators told Reuters they had come to confront the Israelis to protest against a non-binding U.S. House of Representatives resolution on Tuesday calling on President Bill Clinton to affirm that Jerusalem must remain Israel's undivided capital.</p>
<p>Witnesses said they saw demonstrators drag away at least 20 Palestinians who had been hit by rubber bullets -- some to nearby ambulances which took them to hospital and others to Palestinian medical personnel who treated them on the spot.</p>
<p>They said there were no Palestinian police at the scene.</p>
<p>Israel handed 80 percent of Hebron to Palestinian rule in January under an interim peace deal but kept troops to protect the settler enclaves in the town.</p>
<p>Earlier on Saturday, Palestinian gunmen shot and wounded an Israeli woman motorist on the outskirts of Har Adar Jewish settlement in the West Bank north of Jerusalem, Israeli security sources said.</p>
<p>The army said that at least one gunman hit a woman driving a car at Har Adar near the Jerusalem-Tel Aviv highway. The victim, who was not named, was in moderate condition, it added.</p>
<p>The army set up roadblocks and searched surrounding Palestinian villages for the attackers. It later said troops arrested six residents of Biddu village and that a curfew had been imposed on the village of Qatannah.</p>
<p>Tensions between Israel and the Palestinians have been high since Israel began building a new Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem in March, plunging peacemaking into deep crisis.</p>
<p>Palestinians say settlement building in Jerusalem pre-empts final peace talks that are to be held covering issues including the status of Jerusalem. They want Arab East Jerusalem as capital of a future state.</p>
<p>Israel vows never to cede any part of the city. It captured East Jerusalem in the 1967 Middle East war and in move unrecognised by the international community annexed it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HEBRON, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
