<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661851" id="root" date="1997-06-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Even if you're not looking, keep networking.</title>
<headline>Even if you're not looking, keep networking.</headline>
<byline>Sherwood Ross</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Even if you're not looking for another job, it's vital to keep networking, executive search experts say.</p>
<p>Why? Because while headhunters may sift through files and databases in their search for talent, they'll get their best information from &quot;people in and around the industry,&quot; said John Rau, president of Chicago Title &amp; Trust Co. and a former dean of the Indiana University business school.</p>
<p>&quot;Search firms rely on these people to provide opinion, perspective, judgments on quality and reputation,&quot; Rau said.</p>
<p>&quot;Only people can provide the history and background that allows a search firm to assess if someone is the right kind of candidate or just happens to be occupying a 'qualifying' place, but has none of the other desired traits,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>So if you want to be considered, even if you're not looking, &quot;You must become a name with a reputation (in your company),&quot; Rau said. &quot;Whatever else, make sure you are not an invisible member of the organisation or of any groups in which you are active.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If you're the best-kept secret in your industry, that better job is not going to be offered to you,&quot; added Alfred Judge, president of The Cambridge Group, a national executive recruitment firm based in Westport, Conn.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of an aggressive career strategy is making sure your accomplishments and skills are known within your company and within your industry,&quot; Judge said.</p>
<p>When networking in organisations outside your firm, Rau writes in his new book, &quot;Secrets From The Search Firm Files,&quot; (McGraw-Hill), &quot;be just as professional, enthusiatic, helpful, creative and dynamic as you are on the job. Take leadership roles ... (and) build your reputation within the groups as a doer or leader. That will be the reputation when people ask about you from the outside.&quot;</p>
<p>This way, you're much more apt to be one of those called, either as a prospective candidate or as a reference for others.</p>
<p>When taking that all-important first call, Rau said, the first rule is &quot;don't answer too quickly.&quot;</p>
<p>Instead, &quot;listen quietly and listen carefully,&quot; even if the job is something in which you have no interest, understanding that &quot;you are being evaluated not only as a candidate but as a person who might be a future candidate.</p>
<p>&quot;If you turn off someone at this stage, you are going to cut yourself off for future opportunities to build a reputation within the search firm community, Rau said.</p>
<p>&quot;If a consultant phones, say, 'Great, how can I help you(?)' You don't have to declare yourself interested or not interested. Just take the call, don't be aloof and offer help if you can,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Besides, at this early stage, no negotiating is going on. Only afterwards, if you are someone the talent scouts might be interested in, will they ask you to describe your achievements.</p>
<p>When responding, Rau said, &quot;never exaggerate, never obfuscate, never eliminate important times, places or events.&quot; This means, &quot;Don't weasel around situations where you were either fired, quit or had gaps in your resume.</p>
<p>&quot;No matter how good you are or even how good the reasons might be, if there is an inconsistency between what you say in the first interview and what comes out later, you are certainly out of the running for this job,&quot; Rau stressed.</p>
<p>Better learn how to describe the results you have achieved in your work &quot;succinctly, clearly and candidly,&quot; as you will be judged on how you give your response as well as on your record itself.</p>
<p>For example: &quot;I was the general manager of the dry cereal group for two years. My two biggest accomplishments were the introduction of the new brand Captain Smackey's that built $5 million in volume and achieved profitability in less than two years,&quot; etc. Short and sweet.</p>
<p>And, who knows? Even though you may not be looking, it's not so bad to find yourself sought after, is it?</p>
<p>(EDITORS: Sherwood Ross is a free-lance writer who covers workplace issues for Reuters. Any opinions in the column are solely those of Mr. Ross.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
