<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661951" id="root" date="1997-06-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - June 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - June 14.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for REUTERS by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi Tel:3324842, 3351006, 3761233 Fax:+91-11-3351006 Internet: biznis@giasbm01.vsnl.net.in</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			 TOP STORIES</p>
<p>The Times Of India</p>
<p>59 KILLED IN CINEMA HALL FIRE, STAMPEDE</p>
<p>Fifty-nine people were killed and more than 100 injured in a fire that broke out in a cinema in south Delhi on Friday evening. Most of the victims, among them children and women, died of suffocation. The rest were trampled in a stampede as people tried to escape a thick black smoke that engulfed the four-storey cinema. Witnesses said the fire broke out at around 4:30 p.m. when an electric transformer in the basement burst during a house-full premier show. Following the explosion, fuel tanks of a few vehicles parked in the ground-floor parking lot also exploded, stoking the fire, they said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>PLAN TO REGULATE PUBLIC DEPOSIT-RAISING</p>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram said steps were underway to bring greater stringency in norms regulating companies raising deposits from the public. He said the existing law would be amended to relax the debt-equity ratio requirement to be met by companies after a buy-back operation. Certain relaxations in the procedure of postal ballots were also being examined. The minister stated that the retirement age fixed at 65 for directors of companies as stipulated in the working draft would not be reconsidered. The clauses relating to managerial remuneration and loans to directors were adequate, the minister said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>BOMBAY BOURSE INDEX CROSSES 4,000 POINTS</p>
<p>All-round buying by foreign institutional investors and speculators pushed pivotals up on the Bombay bourse and drove its sensitive index to 4,065 points. But the rally lost its pace following profit-taking at higher levels in late trade and forced the index to retreat and close at 4,029.99, up 193 points or 5.03 percent over the week.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>PLAN TO CONVERT EXPORT, IMPORT LICENCES INTO SECURITIES</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry is examining a proposal by the Commerce Ministry to declare replenishment export promotion licences, transferable advance licences and transferable special import licences as securities. If this is done, the licences can be traded on stock exchanges and will be governed by the bourse regulator and stock exchange regulations. They will also be subject to all rules applicable to securities. It will also lead to organised trading of such import licences which are already bought and sold by exporters and interested parties.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>BOURSE REGULATOR GIVES NOTICES TO 134 FIRMS</p>
<p>The Securities and Exchhange Board of India (SEBI) has given notices of cancellation or suspension of licences to 134 firms for not honouring underwriting commitments in public issues. Of these firms, 95 are first category merchant bankers. SEBI also issued notices for cancellation of merchant banking licences to these firms since it felt they posed a threat to the integrity of the market.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>SMITHKLINE PROPOSAL TURNED DOWN AGAIN</p>
<p>The government has for the second time rejected Smithkline Beecham Asia's proposal to manufacture and market pharmaceuticals products in India. The firm is a wholly owned subsidiary of Smithkline Beecham in India. The Foreign Investment Promotion Board in March rejected for the first time Smithkline Beecham's proposal to manufacture, market and distribute pharmaceutical and other products. This included products emerging from research in human gene-mapping technology. The proposal was rejected following opposition from the department of chemicals and the Petrochemicals Ministry.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>VSNL TO SET UP NEW GLOBAL GATEWAYS</p>
<p>Videsh Sanchar Nigam Ltd (VSNL) will be setting up international gateways in Ernakulam, Jallandhar and Ahmedabad by the end of the year, and two more next year, in Hyderabad and Kanpur. Bangalore will also be upgraded, but it will not be a full-fledged gateway since there is no switch there yet, said VSNL chairman and managing director. He said functioning as a gateway would be the new focus of the company, after it ceases to be monopoly provider of Internet services in 2004.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>SIEMENS LOGS 845 MLN RUPEE LOSS</p>
<p>Siemens India has posted a loss of 845 million rupees due to a fall in orders, high interest and operating costs and one-off charges due to restructuring of its telecommunications division. The company's losses would have been higher, at 1,049 million rupees, if it had not changed its depreciation method last year, from the written-down value to the straight-line method. As a result, the company was able to write back excess depreciation of 205 million rupees.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>STATE BANK OF INDIA OFFICERS CONTINUE STRIKE</p>
<p>Officers of the State Bank of India (SBI) in Bombay struck work for the third day on Friday as conciliation talks between their union leaders and the bank's chairman and managing director on the suspension of three bank officials remained inconclusive. They decided to meet again on Saturday morning. Two senior leaders of the All India SBI officers Association arrived in Bombay on Friday for the talks. According to an official of the Association, since the officers were suspended at the insistence of the Finance Ministry, the leaders doubted whether the SBI management could revoke the suspension without the permission of the ministry.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>EXTERNAL BORROWING NOT TO COVER 10-YEAR LOANS</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry further relaxed guidelines for external commercial borrowings (ECBs) by keeping long-term loans outside the annual ceiling of $8.5 billion and permitting flexibility in spreads and entitlements for the infrastructure sector, particularly for telecommunications projects. Loans with a minimum maturity of 10 years and above will not be bound by the parameters governing borrowings which fall within the annual ECB cap. By implication, a larger fund will be given to non-infrastructure projects within the annual ceiling.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>RAILWAYS PLAN SIZE TO BE RAISED TO 84.7 BLN RUPEES</p>
<p>The government has agreed to enhance the railways' plan size for 1997/98 from the budgeted 83 billion rupees to 84.7 billion rupees. It has also agreed to increase the budgetary support to the railways for the current year from 18.31 billion rupees to 20.01 billion rupees to make up for the 1.7 billion rupee increase. The Railway Board chairman said this was indicated to him at the highest level, implying that the increase in the plan size and budgetary support could be considered final, with only the official communication yet to come.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer</p>
<p>COTTON PRODUCTION IN NORTH LIKELY TO DECLINE</p>
<p>Production of cotton in northern India is likely to decline by 15 to 20 percent this year due to adverse weather during the sowing season, the Central Institute of Cotton Research said. Its director said a large quantity of seeds could not be sown and were still lying with farmers. This resulted in reduction of total sown area in northern India. Production in the region, which comprises the states of Punjab, Haryana and Rajasthan, will also decline due to a plant disease called leaf curl spread in the region, which originated in Pakistan and gripped almost the entire north, he said. The disease caused wide-spread damage to crop in Pakistan too.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>CLOSURE THREAT BY NEWSPAPER INDUSTRY</p>
<p>The Indian newspaper industry threatened indefinite closure if the Finance Ministry accepted recommendations to levy anti-dumping duty on newsprint imports. The Indian Newspaper Society President said the society took a unanimous decision. Representatives of the newspaper industry will meet the prime minister and the finance minister in this regard next week. A delegation led by the president of the Society called on the revenue secretary on Friday and told him they were against slapping anti-dumping duty on newsprint imports from the United States, Canada and Russia.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
