<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="661934" id="root" date="1997-06-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Two Italian generals resign over Somalia scandal.</title>
<headline>Two Italian generals resign over Somalia scandal.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-06-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two generals who led Italian forces on a peacekeeping mission to Somalia resigned on Saturday over allegations that their troops tortured, sexually abused and killed unarmed Somalis.</p>
<p>The office of the Army Chief of Staff said General Bruno Loi and General Carmine Fiore had asked to be replaced &quot;to ease and speed up the investigations underway&quot; into the allegations.  </p>
<p>The Army Chief of Staff &quot;accepted the request in order to contribute with the maximum determination to the rapid clarification of this affair,&quot; a statement said.</p>
<p>Graphic reports of alleged abuses in news magazine Panorama spurred the government on Friday to announce a joint civilian and military commission to investigate the claims that Italian troops tortured and abused Somalis during a U.S.-led humanitarian mission in 1992.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Prodi promised swift action to identify culprits in the alleged brutality, which included purported sexual violence against a Somali woman and allegations that Italian soldiers killed unarmed civilians.</p>
<p>President Oscar Luigi Scalfaro has also called a meeting next Wednesday of Italy's Supreme Defence Council, a body rarely meets, to hear a report from defence chief Admiral Guido Venturoni on international missions by Italy's armed forces.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SOMAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
