<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662095" id="root" date="1997-06-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HORSE RACING-HONG KONG BETTING FRENZY FOR RECORD HORSE RACE POT.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-HONG KONG BETTING FRENZY FOR RECORD HORSE RACE POT.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A gambling frenzy is sweeping Hong Kong with punters chasing the biggest pay-out in the territory's horse racing history.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong Jockey Club will pay more than HK$400 million (US$51.6 million) on Sunday to holders of a HK$10 (US$1.30) winning ticket for a Triple Trio wager.</p>
<p>The South China Morning Post Sunday edition said the pot could reach a world record HK$700 million (US$90.5 million) by the start of the races in the afternoon.</p>
<p>The races at Sha Tin are also the last before Hong Kong reverts to Chinese rule at midnight on June 30, ending more than 150 years of colonial rule.</p>
<p>The Jockey Club, which has a monopoly on gambling in the British colony, already had a staggering Triple Trio pool of HK$435.8 million by Saturday night, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>To win the Triple Trio, punters must choose the first three horses across the line in any order in three selected races, a wager that has more than 48 million possibilities.</p>
<p>Dreams of winning the huge purse has gripped the territory, leading to long queues at Jockey Club off-track betting outlets on Saturday.</p>
<p>The races are the only legal outlet for a flutter in gambling-mad Hong Kong. The track is one of the biggest businesses in the territory of 6.4 million people, outperforming some weighty blue-chip stocks in turnover.</p>
<p>Betting turnover in the 1995/96 season was HK$80 billion (US11 billion), believed the highest per capita in the world.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
