<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66209" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Han-Padron starts bid package for Oman port.</title>
<headline>Han-Padron starts bid package for Oman port.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Han-Padron Associates LLP said it it has started engineering and bid package preparation for a nearly $270 million container transshipment terminal under a contract with the Sultanate of Oman.</p>
<p>Han-Padron said the new port is intended to establish Oman as a gateway for container traffic in the Mid-East.</p>
<p>The Sultanate is funding the project's $128.7 million in dredging and infrastructure costs at Port Raysut and CSX Corp's Sea-Land will provide $140 million of investment for container handling equipment and other facilities over the first five years, Han-Padron said.  </p>
<p>The terminal is planned to have an industrial and free trade zone, Han-Padron said. Construction is expected to start February 1997, the firm said.</p>
<p>Oman's natural gas resources are expected to provide low cost fuel and electricity, Han-Padron said. The first two berths, designed to handle the largest container ships, are set to be in operation by the second quarter.</p>
<p>Four berths will be built in the first phase of development and the facilities will include 12 high-speed, 50 ton capacity container cranes, Han-Padron said.</p>
<p>Support facilities include systems to supply ships with fuel and water, container repair facilities, storage facilities for 500 refrigerated containers on 50 hectares of land. The terminal may be enlarged to accommodate as many as 12 ships at a time, Han-Padron said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
