<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662200" id="root" date="1997-06-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatia awaits outcome of presidential election.</title>
<headline>Croatia awaits outcome of presidential election.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Smith</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-06-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatians voted on Sunday for a president to lead them into the 21st century in an election which the opposition branded as undemocratic and biased.</p>
<p>Incumbent President Franjo Tudjman, 75, was expected to win a second five-year term and ran a vigorous campaign despite American medical reports that he has stomach cancer.</p>
<p>Voting ended at 7 p.m. (1700 GMT) and first results were expected soon after midnight, though final results will not be known until Monday or Tuesday.</p>
<p>The former army general who led Croatia to independence from Yugoslavia in 1991 looked stern and was reluctant to talk when he voted, but told reporters the country would be &quot;rich and democratic&quot; if he won.</p>
<p>Both opposition candidates, Vlado Gotovac of the Social Liberal party and Zdravko Tomac of the Social Democrats, criticised Tudjman for using his state institutions and funds to promote his campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;This election was not democratic,&quot; said Tomac, after casting his vote. &quot;Gotovac and I were in such a disadvantageous position that any result we achieve will be a good result.&quot;</p>
<p>Tudjman maintains a tight grip over the media, particularly state television which he runs as a fief of his ruling Croatian Democratic Union (HDZ) party.</p>
<p>He was last elected with 56 percent of the vote in August 1992 but had already assumed the title when Croatia won independence from former Yugoslavia in 1991.</p>
<p>Election officials said overall turnout at 4 p.m. (1400 GMT) was 42.5 percent and just over 50 percent in the capital.</p>
<p>Tudjman, who steered Croatia through the 1991-1995 war against the Serbs, has won high praise from Croats for being a strong leader and is idolised for bringing the country to independence.</p>
<p>His share of the vote was expected to be increased by recent criticism from the United States over Croatia's treatment of Serbs, which many Croats view as unjustified.</p>
<p>Democracy was a big issue in the campaign which was marred by attacks on both opposition candidates. They were offered state protection only half way through the campaign.</p>
<p>In the most serious incident Gotovac, who is supported by nine centrist parties, was hit on the head by a Croatian army captain during a rally.</p>
<p>He was treated for concussion and was then forced to cut his campaign activities. The government rejected his request for the poll to be postponed.</p>
<p>Opposition leaders blamed the attack on the HDZ and state television, who they accuse of portraying opposition candidates as enemies of the state.</p>
<p>Tomac's campaign van was stoned at least twice and he was prevented from holding a rally in Zagreb. Independent polls showed he and Gotovac were expected to get around 15 percent.</p>
<p>The opposition also complained about an electoral law which allows Croats living abroad to take part in the poll. Out of just over four million voters, nearly one-tenth of them live abroad. Most of them are Bosnian Croats.</p>
<p>Tomac said if they all vote for Tudjman it would be &quot;yet more proof that something is wrong with democracy in Croatia as the president will be elected by those who do not pay Croatian tax nor are eligible to serve in the Croatian army.&quot;</p>
<p>The election included eastern Slavonia, the last Serb-controlled area of Croatia, which is due to revert to Zagreb's rule in a month.</p>
<p>Ivan Mrkonjic, head of the state electoral commission, told reporters turnout in Vukovar, the enclave's main town, was only 10.4 percent by 4 p.m.</p>
<p>Some 150 delegates of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) monitored the poll.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
