<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662355" id="root" date="1997-06-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinian, Israeli violence in absence of talks.</title>
<headline>Palestinian, Israeli violence in absence of talks.</headline>
<byline>Colleen Siegel</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israelis and Palestinians have descended once more into violence now that the latest bid -- this time by Egypt -- to return them to substantive peace talks seems to be foundering.</p>
<p>Fifteen Palestinians and two Israeli soldiers were wounded on Sunday in the second day of clashes between troops and stone-throwing Arab demonstrators in the West Bank town of Hebron, witnesses and hospital officials said.</p>
<p>The two days of Hebron clashes followed unrest in Gaza on Thursday in which Israeli soldiers and a Jewish settler shot and wounded four Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that there is an organising hand and there is a political intent behind it...and it will not work,&quot; Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said of the violence.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat told reporters after meeting co-Nobel peace laureate and former Israeli Prime Minister Shimon Peres in Ramallah: &quot;There's a deep crisis in the peace process caused by the Israeli government's refusal to implement the (peace) agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>Peace negotiations between the sides ground to a halt in March when Netanyahu gave the go-ahead for construction of a new Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Palestinians demand settlement building stop before they will resume substantive negotiations. They say it pre-empts final peace talks on Jerusalem and the West Bank. Netanyahu vows the building will go on.</p>
<p>Palestinians have been further angered by a non-binding U.S. House of Representatives vote last week saying Jerusalem, the Arab eastern half of which Israel captured and annexed in 1967 in a move not recognised by the international community, must remain Israel's undivided capital.</p>
<p>Egypt in late May stepped into a mediating breach left after the United States, the official peace process sponsor, failed to resolve the crisis.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Egyptian envoy Osama el-Baz shuttled between Netanyahu and Arafat in his latest bid to solve the impasse. He returned to Egypt saying more work was needed to end the crisis.</p>
<p>Palestinian peace negotiators headed for Cairo on Sunday evening ahead of Monday talks with el-Baz and Foreign Minister Amr Moussa on salvaging peacemaking.</p>
<p>The Palestinian Authority has made clear it feels time is running out. In a statement issued after the weekly cabinet meeting chaired by Arafat at week's end, it said:</p>
<p>&quot;The Palestinian public was patient for a long time over the accelerating Israeli trespasses and violations and Netanyahu's affirmations on continuing the settlement attacks. They cannot be patient anymore.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu's office said on Saturday he would not make a planned trip to New York on June 21 because of sensitive impending legislation. Local media said he did not want to risk meeting President Bill Clinton with the crisis raging.</p>
<p>Diplomats at the European Union summit in Amsterdam said leaders would consider an appeal to the peoples of the Middle East to press their governments to resume stalled peace talks.</p>
<p>They said France had offered a draft statement, voicing deep concern at the impasse in the Arab-Israeli peace process and at the potential threat to peace, which EU foreign ministers would study on Monday night and leaders could issue on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Late on Sunday, the Palestinian news agency WAFA said Arafat had given EU peace envoy Miguel Angel Moratinos a letter for the Amsterdam summit calling on the EU to save the peace process.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
