<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66241" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: South Jersey sets shareholder rights plan.</title>
<headline>South Jersey sets shareholder rights plan.</headline>
<dateline>FOLSOM, N.J. 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Jersey Industries Inc said on Friday its board of directors adopted a shareholder rights plan and declared a dividend distribution of one right per common share payable to holders of record on October 11.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement rights would initially be represented by stock certificates and would trade with the common shares.  </p>
<p>Each right would entitle shareholders to by one one-thousandth of share of the company's newly created preference stock at an exercise price of $90. Rights, which expire on September 20, 2006, would only be exercisable if a person or group acquired 10 percent or more of South Jersey Industries or announced a tender offer, the company said.</p>
<p>If South Jersey Industries was acquired or a person or group bought a stake of 10 percent or more, the right would let holders buy a number of the acquiring company's shares or of South Jersey Industries' common stock, the company said.</p>
<p>This would mean a market value of twice the exercise price, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rights are not being distributed in response to any specific effort to acquire control of the company and the board is not aware of any such effort,&quot; Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer William Ryan said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FOLSOM, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
