<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662454" id="root" date="1997-06-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: &quot;Speed&quot; sequel takes top spot at U.S. box office.</title>
<headline>&quot;Speed&quot; sequel takes top spot at U.S. box office.</headline>
<byline>Dean Goodman</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-06-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Speed 2: Cruise Control&quot; got off to a slow start over the weekend as it narrowly took the top spot at the box office after generally poor reviews, according to studio estimates Sunday.</p>
<p>The sequel to the 1994 blockbuster &quot;Speed&quot; earned an estimated $16.2 million for the Friday to Sunday weekend, while &quot;Con Air&quot; slipped to second with $15.2 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Speed 2,&quot; which cost a reported $125 million to make, again stars Sandra Bullock, who is joined by Jason Patric. He replaces Keanu Reeves, who opted not to return so that he could spend more time with his rock band, Dogstar.</p>
<p>Whereas the first version revolved around a bomb on a Los Angeles bus, the sequel takes place aboard a cruise ship. The action film is from News Corp. unit 20th Century Fox.</p>
<p>Most critics yawned. According to Variety, only three major national reviewers liked the movie, while 33 did not and nine were mixed.</p>
<p>&quot;Con Air,&quot; an airborne thriller starring Nicolas Cage and John Malkovich, slipped 37 percent from its opening weekend, as its 10-day total rose to $49.5 million. It earned $5,373 from 2,829 screens, the second-highest average in the top 10. The movie is released by Walt Disney Co..</p>
<p>&quot;Steven Spielberg's &quot;The Lost World: Jurassic Park&quot; slipped to third in its fourth weekend with $12 million, a drop of 35 percent from last weekend. It averaged $3,368 from 3,563 screens.</p>
<p>Its gross to date is $190.3 million, placing it 24th on the list of all-time top hits. The dinosaur sequel is released by Universal Pictures, a unit of Seagram Co. Ltd..</p>
<p>Far behind in fourth, with $2.3 million, was the Meg Ryan romantic comedy &quot;Addicted To Love.&quot; The movie has earned $30.2 million after four weeks. Ticket sales fell 37 percent from last weekend, as it averaged $1,181 from 1,948 screens. The movie is released Time Warner Inc.'s Warner Bros.</p>
<p>&quot;Speed 2&quot; averaged $6,200 from 2,613 screens. The original opened with sales of $14.5 million and went on to make $121.2 million at the domestic box office.</p>
<p>Next weekend's new offerings include &quot;Batman and Robin,&quot; starring George Clooney as the Caped Crusader, and &quot;My Best Friend's Wedding,&quot; starring Julia Roberts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
