<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66247" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Midcontinent spot unleaded gasoline firms.</title>
<headline>U.S. Midcontinent spot unleaded gasoline firms.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Midcontinent spot unleaded gasoline basis firmed on steady differentials and a late-day rebound in front-month NYMEX unleaded prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Low sulphur diesel differentials in Chicago and Group Three were unchanged as trade wound down for the week, sending cash prices surging higher on gains in NYMEX front-month heating oil prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders remained bearish on the outlook for spot products prices in the Midwest due to a perceived glut of petroleum products -- particularly low sulhur diesel -- in the market.  </p>
<p>High sulphur diesel remained 0.50/0.25 cent a gallon under October heating oil in both Chicago and Group Three, traders said. Low sulphur differentials also were steady in both markets.</p>
<p>Chicago late-September unleaded gasoline was unchanged at 1.50/1.25 cents under the print, with premium talked 2.75 cents higher.</p>
<p>Group Three prompt unleaded gasoline was steady at 1.0/0.75 cent a gallon under the print, with premium steady at 2.50 cents higher.</p>
<p>Jet/kero was unchanged in discussion late Friday at 3.0/3.25 cents over the print in Chicago and 2.75/3.0 cents over the print in Group Three.</p>
<p>-- Houston Bureau 713 210-8508</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
