<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662444" id="root" date="1997-06-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oklahoma bombing jurors wept after guilty verdict.</title>
<headline>Oklahoma bombing jurors wept after guilty verdict.</headline>
<byline>Judith Crosson</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-06-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The jurors in the Oklahoma City bombing trial said on Saturday they needed only one vote to agree that Timothy McVeigh was guilty but they wept for 90 minutes before announcing it.</p>
<p>Eleven of the 12 jurors who sentenced McVeigh to die on Friday gathered for a news conference to speak out for the first time about their experiences during one of the most high-profile trials in American history.</p>
<p>The jurors said they found it difficult to sentence McVeigh to death; but not as difficult as the decision they made 11 days earlier to find the 29-year-old Gulf War veteran guilty of blowing up the Alfred P. Murrah federal building, killing 168 people.</p>
<p>The April 19, 1995 attack was the worst against civilians on U.S. soil.</p>
<p>&quot;Twelve people cried when we pronounced him guilty. It took us a good hour, hour and a half to calm ourselves down so we could go into the courtroom again,&quot; juror Ruth Meier said.</p>
<p>&quot;I cried every day, every night and I prayed the entire time. It was only with God's help that I got through it,&quot; Meier said.</p>
<p>The jurors said that they carefully examined the evidence and testimony and reached a unanimous verdict after just one vote in both the trial and the sentencing phase.</p>
<p>The jurors, whose identities had been kept secret during the trial, said the sheer volume of the prosecution's evidence convinced them of McVeigh's guilt</p>
<p>Jury foreman Jim Osgood said the jury did not look at one piece of evidence or one witness in isolation. &quot;We looked at it in total ... I was compelled by the absolute plethora of the evidence,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>McVeigh's lawyers will file appeals that could take several years to wind their way through the courts. Unless the conviction or sentence are overturned, McVeigh could be executed as early as the year 2000, legal experts said, a relatively short time for Death Row appeals.</p>
<p>McVeigh, who prosecutors said was a right-wing fanatic bent on avenging the deaths of about 80 Branch Davidian cult members in a confrontation with federal agents at Waco, Texas in 1993, showed little emotion during the seven-week trial.</p>
<p>Several of the jurors said they looked McVeigh in the eyes before announcing their sentence of death on Friday. &quot;We felt that this is an ultimate challenge ... the ability to look a person right in the face and tell them this is what we've decided, without a doubt,&quot; said juror Michael Leeper.</p>
<p>Several of the jurors said their decisions would not weigh on their consciences. &quot;I can live with myself ... I can sleep at night,&quot; said Doug Carr.</p>
<p>Fred Clarke said the jurors did not rely totally on the testimony of Michael and Lori Fortier, former friends of McVeigh's who gave devastating testimony against him. The defence attacked the Fortiers' credibility because Lori Fortier testified under a grant of immunity and her husband reached a pleabargain with authorities.</p>
<p>&quot;We only used Michael Fortier and Lori Fortier's testimony when there was other things to back it up,&quot; said Meier.</p>
<p>The jurors also said they were not bothered by the question of whether unidentified people were involved in the bombing and still at large.</p>
<p>Nor were they swayed by defence attempts to explain the bombing as the result of McVeigh's anger over Waco.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw Waco as a political statement. We're talking about actions that a man needs to be held accountable for,&quot; Osgood said.</p>
<p>When asked what question they would most like to ask McVeigh about the bombing, the 11 jurors said in unison &quot;Why?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
