<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662490" id="root" date="1997-06-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Franco-German rift set to dominate EU summit.</title>
<headline>Franco-German rift set to dominate EU summit.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-06-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A rift between France and Germany over the direction of monetary union was set on Sunday to dominate one of the European Union's most contentious summits in years.</p>
<p>Leaders of the 15-nation bloc were due to arrive in the Dutch capital later in the afternoon ahead of a two-day meeting that was supposed to culminate in agreement of a new treaty setting Europe's course for the new century.</p>
<p>But the election of a Socialist government in France committed to creating jobs and hostile to the economic austerity required to qualify for economic and monetary union (EMU) has turned the leaders' plans on their head.</p>
<p>France stunned its partners last week by saying it wanted more time to study EMU's so-called stability pact, a framework for keeping EU budgets from ballooning into deficit after the introduction of the single currency in January, 1999.</p>
<p>New French Prime Minister Lionel Jospin says he wants EMU to start on time, but that he believes not enough attention is being paid to the bloc's double-digit employment rate.</p>
<p>A classic EU compromise is in the works in which resolutions underlining the importance of creating jobs and of coordinating economic policy would be attached to the stability pact, agreed in principle in Dublin in December.</p>
<p>But French and German leaders meeting in Poitiers in western France on Friday failed to agree the compromise.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the Germans had let it be known that they had not expected an agreement in Poitiers and that they wanted a solution to be brokered by the Dutch EU presidency.</p>
<p>Germany is vehemently opposed to any weakening of the criteria for the single currency and to any job creation pumping by grand finance projects.</p>
<p>&quot;I will not go along (with state job creation) under which Germany pays one third to Europe and gets only 15 percent back,&quot; German Finance Minister Theo Waigel said in the Frankfurter Allgemeine Sonntagzeitung newspaper on Sunday.</p>
<p>EU finance ministers were to meet to discuss the crisis over dinner on Sunday evening (1900 GMT) ahead of the full summit on Monday and Tuesday.</p>
<p>French Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn said before arriving in Amsterdam that he believed a compromise could be found.</p>
<p>&quot;Mutual concessions are the very definition of co-operation between two countries. It's difficult, but things are moving and I hope we will reach agreement in Amsterdam,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The rift overshadowed the bloc's real purpose for meeting in Amsterdam which was to reach agreement on a new EU treaty to prepare for enlargement into eastern Europe.</p>
<p>A draft treaty to be considered by the leaders on Monday and Tuesday promises to create an area of freedom and justice for the EU's citizens, to put job creation at the top of the agenda and streamline EU decision-making.</p>
<p>Security at the summit was particularly tight. Around 150 demonstrators clashed with police on Saturday when a protest march by up to 50,000 Europeans against hardship wrought by the bloc's quest for monetary union turned violent.</p>
<p>A large group of mainly German radicals, anarchists and punks broke away from the march and tried in vain to storm the Central Bank building where the summit will be held.</p>
<p>They smashed office and shop windows, overturned a police vehicle and pelted riot police with stones in the city centre.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
