<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662577" id="root" date="1997-06-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Gujral seen safe despite stronger Congress.</title>
<headline>India's Gujral seen safe despite stronger Congress.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Verma</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-06-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Congress party may have emerged stronger from a leadership election but its resurgence is unlikely to threaten Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral's coalition government, political analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>They said Congress president Sitaram Kesri, who  swept the party's internal poll on Thursday, was emboldened by his easy victory but unlikely to flex his political muscle too quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in a turbulent transitional period, but I see nothing that is going to rock the boat to the point where it capsizes,&quot; B.G. Verghese, analyst at the Centre for Policy Research, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Kesri won a three-way contest for the presidency with more than 6,000 votes of the 7,557 votes polled.</p>
<p>Immediately after his re-election, Kesri said the victory vindicated his decision in March to withdraw support to then prime minister H.D. Deve Gowda's government and topple him in a parliamentary confidence vote.</p>
<p>&quot;The ruling United Front government, which survives on Congress support, will have to contend with the fact that this (victory) indicates a solid endorsement of Mr Kesri's decision to bring down the Deve Gowda government,&quot; the Business Standard said in an editorial.</p>
<p>&quot;It could only be a matter of time before he decides to make a play for the top job,&quot; the daily said.</p>
<p>Congress and the eight-week-old United Front coalition government are locked in an uneasy alliance. Congress's 140 deputies provide vital support in the 543-member lower house of parliament to the United Front's 179 lawmakers.</p>
<p>When Kesri abruptly withdrew Congress backing to the government in March, he plunged the country into political turmoil, drawing sharp criticism from his opponents.</p>
<p>Congress, India's oldest political party and for decades its most powerful, swiftly staked a claim to form a new government but was later forced to back down and offer support to the coalition under its new leader, Gujral.</p>
<p>&quot;Kesri was rapped on the knuckles last time for staking a claim and later having to climb down,&quot; Verghese said. &quot;This statement should be seen as a retrospective justification of his decision rather than a fresh threat.&quot;</p>
<p>Once the driving force behind the movement against colonial rule, Congress has ruled India for all but five years since independence in 1947, with former prime ministers Jawaharlal Nehru, Indira Gandhi and Rajiv Gandhi in power for 37 years.</p>
<p>This week's polls were only the third elections in the 112-year history of the party, traditionally run by charismatic leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;Kesri still has a dream of grandeur,&quot; said Mahesh Rangarajan, analyst at the Centre for Contemporary Studies.</p>
<p>&quot;But if there is a fresh general election, the party that will suffer the most serious reverses is Congress.&quot;</p>
<p>On Friday Kesri said he wanted a stable government, and was committed to supporting the United Front -- until the next polls. General elections are not due until 2001.</p>
<p>Gujral faces a more serious threat to his authority from squabbling within his deeply divided Janata Dal party if the group splinters in the course of its own internal polls set for Wednesday, Verghese said.</p>
<p>The Janata Dal, the largest party in the coalition, is split between supporters and critics of its president, Laloo Prasad Yadav, who has been linked to a $280 million corruption case.</p>
<p>Yadav says he is innocent, and on Saturday said he would not resign, preferring &quot;like Saddam Hussain, (to) take on the whole world alone&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
