<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662582" id="root" date="1997-06-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian firms overtaken by catalytic convertor boom.</title>
<headline>Indian firms overtaken by catalytic convertor boom.</headline>
<byline>Sanjit Singh</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-06-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's demand for catalytic converters is set to leap nearly seven-fold by 2000, but local manufacturers are not excited.</p>
<p>Current annual demand averages 200,000 converters, a study by Britain's Royal Society of Chemistry said last December.</p>
<p>The Indian goverment made catalytic converters the norm in April 1995 for all cars sold in the four largest cities -- Delhi, Bombay, Madras and Calcutta.</p>
<p>Nearly half of the 440,000 cars sold in India in 1996/97 are in the four cities.</p>
<p>The need for catalytic converters is urgent. The Associated Chambers of Commerce and Industry (Assocham) said in a recent study that vehicles are responsible for 1,050 tonnes of pollution a day in Delhi, 650 tonnes a day in Bombay, and 250 to 300 tonnes a day in Calcutta, Madras and Bangalore.</p>
<p>The government's Economic Survey for 1996/97 ended March 31 said the catalytic converter directive would extend to the capitals of all India's 26 states by 1998 and the entire country by 2000, coinciding with the availability of unleaded fuel.</p>
<p>But while the government moves to enforce converters, production has slowed down, industry sources said.</p>
<p>The Association of Indian Automobile Manufacturers (AIAM) estimates that the car market in India will grow between 15 percent and 20 percent over the next five years.</p>
<p>A total of 411,305 cars were sold in 1996/97 compared with 345,340 in 1995/96. AIAM predicts that this will climb to 850,000 in four years.</p>
<p>The government erased the advantage domestic makers of converters had over imports by trimming tariffs on imported converters to 5.0 percent from 15 percent in its fiscal budget for 1997/98.</p>
<p>Two Indian companies, Sona Steering Ltd and Subros Ltd have killed plans to manufacture catalytic converters since the federal budget was unveiled at the end of February.</p>
<p>&quot;The volumes in India are small, and the lowered duties have reduced margins making the project unviable. The minimum economic size for a plant is a million pieces annually,&quot; Surinder Kapoor, managing director of Sona Steering, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He added that Sona would not have seen returns on its investment for the next three or four years. Sona had announced a joint venture with Germany's Obermann Manngold GmbH in November 1993.</p>
<p>Two other firms, Delphi Automotive Controls, a division of General Motors and AlliedSignal Inc of the United States are going ahead with plans to manufacture catalytic converters but are keeping their options open.</p>
<p>Delphi said it planned to make catalytic converters in India, but did not specify a date. &quot;We will manufacture in India, but I will not say when and in what quantity,&quot; A. Raghavan, vice-president, marketing, said.</p>
<p>AlliedSignal had initially been a partner with Subros but now planned to go it alone. &quot;We will manufacture here to be close to our clients. It is true that with the duty cuts, the real benefits of local manufacture are not there,&quot; a senior official of the company's Indian subsidiary said.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are sure of is the demand. The government will make it compulsory for two-wheeler manufacturers to fit catalytic converters by 2000, giving us a ready market of a million pieces. Cars, too, will account for 500,000 by then,&quot; the official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
