<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662633" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX natgas ends mixed, fronts off but hold range.</title>
<headline>NYMEX natgas ends mixed, fronts off but hold range.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures were mixed Monday in a sluggish session, with fronts closing down slightly but still holding recent ranges in the face of uncertainty about market direction, sources said.</p>
<p>July eased 0.2 cent to close at $2.147 per million British thermal units. August settled one cent lower at $2.157. Other months ended mixed, with some 1999s scoring modest gains.</p>
<p>&quot;Cash was up today and I think the heat in Texas helped, but without more heat or hurricanes soon, I think these (price) levels could be difficult to sustain,&quot; said one Midwest trader.  </p>
<p>With Midwest and Northeast temperatures this week expected to stay around normal and extended forecasts showing no consensus, few expected a significant rally near-term, adding heat in Texas was not enough to firm the market.</p>
<p>Chart traders said recent ranges were intact, with July support still at last week's low of $2.055 and then at $2. After $2.21 and $2.25, technicians pegged July resistance at $2.37 and then at the $2.44 contract high.</p>
<p>In the cash Monday, Louisiana Gulf Coast gas firmed by about five cents to the mid-teens or higher. Midcon pipes gained a similar amount to the low-$2s. New York city gate gas also was about a nickel higher in the low-to-mid $2.40s.</p>
<p>The NYMEX 12-month Henry Hub strip slipped 0.6 cent to $2.231. NYMEX said 25,577 contracts traded, down from Friday's revised tally of 42,848.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, July finished 0.3 cent lower at $2.01, while deferreds ended down by one-half cent. The East/West spread widened by 0.1 cent to 13.7 cents (NYMEX premium). KCBT said 387 lots traded, up from Friday's total of 187.</p>
<p>((--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
