<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662731" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rubin says U.S. economy best in decades.</title>
<headline>Rubin says U.S. economy best in decades.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States is hosting next weekend's Denver summit of industrialized nations with its economy in its strongest condition in years, Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin said on Monday.</p>
<p>While countries like Japan are just starting to emerge from five years of sluggish performance, the U.S. economy is thriving partly because the federal deficit has fallen to about one percent of GDP from nearly five percent in 1993.</p>
<p>Unemployment is down, inflation is low and 12 million jobs have been created, Rubin said.  </p>
<p>&quot;These are the best sustained economic conditions in this country in many decades, and the best in the industrialized world,&quot; Rubin said in a speech prepared for delivery to the Bretton Woods/Overseas Delopment Council.</p>
<p>With the Group of Seven countries -- the United States, Japan, Britain, Germany, Italy, Canada and France -- meeting next weekend, Rubin said one U.S. objective will be to promote growth in order to keep the global economy thriving.</p>
<p>Rubin repeated that the world has a strong interest in seeing Japan achieve a strong domestic demand-led recovery without running up huge trade surpluses.  </p>
<p>&quot;And we have a major stake in seeing Japan achieve a successful deregulation program that will open Japan's markets further and promote financial liberalization,&quot; Rubin added.</p>
<p>The G7 industrialized countries will be joined by Russia for many of the weekend discussions in Denver, making it a Group of Eight for part of the annual summit.</p>
<p>The Treasury Secretary repeated that the G7 countries want to bring desperately poor sub-Saharan Africa into the global economy and said President Clinton will unveil proposals on Tuesday for promoting growth there.  </p>
<p>Rubin repeated his praise for the work done by international institutions like the International Monetary Fund, World Bank and multilateral development banks, and said it was important for the United States to pay the $1 billion in arrears it owes for supporting them.</p>
<p>&quot;We are the world's largest and richest economy yet we account for the lion's share of arrears to the multilateral development banks,&quot; Rubin said.</p>
<p>He urged Congress to help find the necessary funds, noting that &quot;by not paying what we owe, we risk losing our leverage&quot; over the directions the institutions take in future in fostering development.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
