<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662844" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: ATHLETICS-FINAL SPRINT EARNS MATTHEUS '97 COMRAD.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-FINAL SPRINT EARNS MATTHEUS '97 COMRAD.</headline>
<byline>Mark Stokes</byline>
<dateline>DURBAN 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's Charl Mattheus put in a powerful sprint over the closing five kilometres to win the 1997 Comrades ultra marathon title by more than two minutes from compatriot Nick Bester on Monday.</p>
<p>The 32-year-old Mattheus, who was disqualifed for taking a banned substance before winning the 1992 race, managed to hold off strong early challenges from Bester and South African standard marathon record-holder Zithulele Sinqe.</p>
<p>The three opened up a significant lead over the chasing pack with 26 kilometres to go but Sinqe slipped off the pace over the last few uphill stretches to finish fourth.</p>
<p>Mattheus, who finished second in 1995 the last time the Comrades was raced &quot;down&quot; from Pietermaritzburg to Durban, then surged ahead of the strong-running Bester to win his first legitimate title.</p>
<p>Mattheus was disqualified in 1992 - despite crossing the finishing line first - after taking an illegal substance for a cold before the race began.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I got over the disappointment of 1992 when I came second in 1995 but all of this will hit me in a day or two. At last I'm back and I'm pleased with the time that I ran today,&quot; Mattheus said.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally the pace was aggressively fast but I felt comfortable all the way. I kept up the pressure and I certainly didn't want to lose this title.</p>
<p>&quot;I worked very hard for this race in the United States at high elevation in Colorado and, on the downhill stretch, I gave everything I had to get rid of Nick Bester...he's such a strong runner.&quot;</p>
<p>Mattheus completed the gruelling 89.9km course from Pietermaritzburg to Durban in five hours 28 minutes 37 seconds while Bester, the 1991 champion, posted a time of 5:30:41.</p>
<p>Leading times in the men's marathon (South African unless stated):</p>
<p>1. Charl Mattheus five hours 28 minutes 37 seconds</p>
<p>2. Nick Bester 5:30:41</p>
<p>3. Jaroslaw Janicki (Poland) 5:32:50</p>
<p>4. Zithulele Sinqe 5:33:18</p>
<p>5. Andrew Kelehe 5:33:24</p>
<p>6. Sarel Ackermann 5:33:27</p>
<p>7. Shaun Meiklejohn 5:34:04</p>
<p>8. Mahlala Mohloli 5:34:34</p>
<p>9. Peter Camenzind (Switzerland) 5:34:47</p>
<p>10. Konstantin Santalov (Russia) 5:37:36</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
