<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="662985" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE straight-run offer up after trade at $108 cif.</title>
<headline>NWE straight-run offer up after trade at $108 cif.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>European low sulphur straight-run got a shot in the arm on Monday after a cargo was said to have fetched $108 cif a tonne, leaving the last seller increasing his asking price.</p>
<p>A Scandinavian refiner, one of only two sellers with prompt 0.5 to 0.7 pct material, said it sold its cargo to a British refiner at $108 cif -- which he said was the equivalent of $98/$99 fob given the high freight rate.</p>
<p>Other traders cited this number although one believed the price seemed a &quot;bit rich&quot;.</p>
<p>The deal allowed the second seller to bid up his asking price to $102 a tonne, compared with Friday's $100/$101, which was also an increase of $1 from a day earlier.</p>
<p>Bids were heard to be in the high nineties.</p>
<p>&quot;He's the only seller now with a cargo, so he can charge that price,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Sellers have recently increased their asking price in line with gains by crude.</p>
<p>For better quality material, bids rose a little, traders said.</p>
<p>One seller of 0.4 percent straigh run said his asking  price was steady at $103/$104 a tonne, adding he reeived two bids at $102.</p>
<p>Traders said that some buying interest was coming in from the United States, but that the high freight cost which has to be factored into bids was delaying deals.</p>
<p>--Haitham Haddadin, London newsroom, +44 171 542 8145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
