<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663086" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Tudjman wins Croatian presidential vote-radio.</title>
<headline>Tudjman wins Croatian presidential vote-radio.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Smith</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian President Franjo Tudjman won a convincing reelection victory on Monday that endorsed his post-communist drive to align the former Yugoslav republic with the West.</p>
<p>He pledged his immediate priority would be to attack low living standards hit by war and recession.</p>
<p>With just over 90 percent of Sunday's votes counted, Tudjman had won over 61 per cent of the vote with Social Democrat Zdravko Tomac on 21 per cent and Vlado Gotovac of the Social Liberal Party on just under 18 percent.</p>
<p>His position is now stronger than ever, with his ruling HDZ party also entrenched in parliament and local government.</p>
<p>The opposition challenge suffered because of infighting and public doubts about the leadership strengths of the candidates.</p>
<p>&quot;People still feel uncertain about Croatia and I have a feeling the support for Tudjman has been growing in the context of pressure from outside,&quot; said one diplomat.</p>
<p>Officials said the turnout on Sunday was 57 percent -- one of the lowest since Croatia held its first democratic vote in 1990 while still part of the former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>Celebrating at a banquet as the results came in, Tudjman said: &quot;I promise the continuity of the policy with which we established freedom and independence in Croatia, a stable economy and currency...now we shall dedicate ourselves with all our forces to raising the standards of living for the entire population.&quot;</p>
<p>Tudjman presided over a post-communist economic reform programme launched in 1993 which slashed inflation and stabilised the currency, boosting foreign investor interest and domestic growth.</p>
<p>The majority of Croatians are struggling to make ends meet after a war which destroyed infrastructure and shut factories.</p>
<p>The strong exchange rate hurts exports and tourism, a big earner before the war, is only just beginning to pick up again.</p>
<p>Zarko Miljenovic, chief economist at Zagrebacka Banka, said he didn't expect Tudjman to be able to do much after already using a large part of the budget to compensate war victims.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever was possible has already been done, and more,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;Unless there is a radical change in fiscal policy and more money is switched from military spending to social needs I can't see a big improvement.&quot;</p>
<p>The Croatia kuna was unmoved on Monday and traded at rates set on Friday of 3.57 against the German mark and 6.17 against the dollar.</p>
<p>Tudjman's popularity among ordinary citizens seems to have stayed intact despite poverty and doubts about his health after reports from U.S. administration officials that he has stomach cancer.</p>
<p>After leading Croatia to independence from former Yugoslavia in 1991 and steering it through the 1991-1995 war against the Serbs, he is praised as a strong leader and idolised by many as &quot;the father of the nation&quot;.</p>
<p>Tudjman's first priority will be to manage the reintegration of the last Serb-held enclave in Croatia, Eastern Slavonia, which is currently run by the United Nations. It is due to revert to Zagreb's rule in July and the process will involve the resettlement of thousands of people.</p>
<p>&quot;Tudjman's highest priority now will definitely be the reintegration of Eastern Slavonia,&quot; a diplomat said after the results became clear. He expected Tudjman to be stricter about reintegrating the area now he has won a new mandate.</p>
<p>The reintegration will mean the last Serb-held area on Croatian soil has been returned to Zagreb, something Tudjman holds very dear.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
