<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663127" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian presidential vote free but not fair-OSCE.</title>
<headline>Croatian presidential vote free but not fair-OSCE.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>International election observers said on Monday the Croatian presidential election which President Franjo Tudjman won with 61 percent of the vote was free but not fair.</p>
<p>&quot;Croatia has experienced a free but not fair election. While candidates were able to speak freely, the process leading up to the election was fundamentally flawed,&quot; Paul Simon, co-ordinating a monitoring mission organised by the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), said in a statement given to reporters.</p>
<p>The pre-election process &quot;did not meet the minimum standards for democracies. By contrast the election itself was, with some exceptions, conducted efficiently,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Before the poll, opposition candidates had already branded the campaign biased and undemocratic because of Tudjman's virtual control of the state media especially television, and accused him of using his position to promote his candidacy.</p>
<p>Simon, a U.S. senator, was appointed special co-ordinator for the election observation mission in Croatia. The OSCE established its mission a month before the vote to observe the campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot separate the democratic process from economic growth. If the leadership of this country wants to move ahead it has to make proper adjustments,&quot; Simon told reporters.</p>
<p>U.S. ambassador to Croatia Peter Galbraith told Reuters the American position on the election &quot;corresponded&quot; with that of the OSCE.</p>
<p>Kare Vollan of the OSCE mission said he regretted that some of the observers' complaints about Croatia's 1995 parliamentary elections and the muncipal elections in April &quot;were not properly addressed.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the main problems were with media coverage of the campaign and voting by Croats living abroad, particularly in Bosnia.</p>
<p>Simon said it would take time for democracy to develop in Croatia. &quot;We don't move from communist states to full democracy overnight. These are recommendations we make. It's up to them to consider and, we hope, act upon.&quot;</p>
<p>Both opposition candidates were subjected to violence during the campaign. Vlado Gotovac of the Social Liberal party was hit on the head by a Croatian army captain at a rally and Zdravko Tomac of the Social Democrat party had stones thrown at his campaign van while touring the country.</p>
<p>&quot;This election was not democratic. Gotovac and I were in such a disadvantageous position that any result we achieved would be a good result,&quot; Tomac said after casting his ballot on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
