<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663108" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GEORGIA: Georgia to sell 300 medium and large enterprises.</title>
<headline>Georgia to sell 300 medium and large enterprises.</headline>
<dateline>TBILISI 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Georgia will begin selling off remaining shares in about 300 medium and large state enterprises later this month, the deputy property minister said on Monday.</p>
<p>Merab Gabunia told Reuters the government would begin selling reduced-price shares in large enterprises already partially privatised. In some cases, the enterprises' 20 to 30 percent of the shares were already in private hands, he said.</p>
<p>Some properties to be sold include a small hydroelectric station, a canning plant and other industrial enterprises, said Gabunia.</p>
<p>The government says it has significantly cut share prices from a first round of sales at the beginning of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The high prices of the shares was the main obstacle,&quot;  he said, referring to the first round of sales.</p>
<p>Foreign investors will have equal rights with Georgian institutions and individuals in the share sales. There is also no limit as to how many shares in one enterpris investors may purchase.</p>
<p>Properties that fail to attract enough buying might have to be closed, Gabunia said.</p>
<p>The deputy property minister said purchasers would be obliged to assume the enterprises' outstanding debts, which in some case are substantial, in proportion to the percentage of shares purchased. &quot;In some cases, the volume of their debts is more than the price of enterprises,&quot; said Gabunia.</p>
<p>Gabunia said Georgia had rejected a World Bank recommendation that the government use a so-called &quot;zero&quot; initial price, which would allow purchasers to make open bids.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot agree with that because we would have to sell off our state property for nothing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some analysts were skeptical of the privatisation process, saying it was proceeding too slowly.</p>
<p>&quot;The privatisation process in Georgia has slowed down dramatically,&quot; said a report issued by the European Union's Technical Assistance to the Commonwealth of Independent States program (TACIS).</p>
<p>The Ministry of State Property Management said 524 medium and large enterprises had been privatised by the beginning of 1997. It also said privatisation of small enterprises is nearly complete, with 9,570 small enterprises in the private sector as of January 15.</p>
<p>So-called &quot;strategic&quot; properties, such as hydroelectric, oil, gas and coal production and metal mining will not be privatised. --Tbilisi bureau, +995-32 999-370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GRGIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TBILISI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GEORGIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
