<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663332" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian tourism to lure young Japanese women.</title>
<headline>Australian tourism to lure young Japanese women.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia on Monday announced plans to tempt more young Japanese &quot;office ladies&quot; to its shores and halt a slide in Australia's share of the huge Japanese tourism market.</p>
<p>The official Australian Tourist Commission (ATC) said it and four Australian and Japanese airlines would spend a total of A$10 million in an advertising and marketing campaign aimed at Japan's young, experienced female travellers.</p>
<p>&quot;This is one of Australia's core segments, accounting for more than 20 percent of travel from Japan,&quot; the ATC said.  </p>
<p>The ATC, funded by the government, said it was supported in the campaign by Australia's Qantas Airways Ltd and Ansett as well as Japan Airlines and All Nippon Airways.</p>
<p>Australia's share of the Japanese market has been slipping in recent years, with Japanese travellers preferring instead to make one last trip to colonial Hong Kong, shop in Italy or place a bet in the casinos of Las Vegas, the ATC said.</p>
<p>Australia A$16 billion tourism industry, the nation's most lucrative export industry, is keen to arrest the decline.  </p>
<p>&quot;Without winning back this experienced female segment, which is the only underperforming one, we are not going to achieve this,&quot; said Tony Virili, the ATC's regional director for Japan.</p>
<p>The ad campaign begins in earnest next January in Japanese media and will be aimed at women aged between 20 and 34 years who have &quot;bought their Gucchi and Prada bags&quot; and now want a place to relax and &quot;be themselves&quot;, Virili told Reuters.</p>
<p>Japanese tourists account for one fifth of all visitors to Australia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
