<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663347" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK cargo chief seeks &quot;soft&quot; opening for airport.</title>
<headline>HK cargo chief seeks &quot;soft&quot; opening for airport.</headline>
<byline>Jim Gilchrist</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The managing director of Hong Kong Air Cargo Terminals Limited (HACTL), Anthony Charter, told Reuters he is still seeking an overlapped opening of Hong Kong's new airport to prevent potential chaos due to teething troubles.</p>
<p>Charter wants a &quot;soft&quot; opening with freighters landing at Chek Lap Kok when Kai Tak is closed during the night to fully test the new airport's handling facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not the only one in this industry who feels it would be best to have an overlapping period with freight operators using the new airport during the night so the highly complicated handling equipment can be fully tested to make sure there are no snarl-ups,&quot; Charter added.</p>
<p>In a mammoth overnight removal operation sometime next April, the Hong Kong Airport Authority currently plans to close Kai Tak and reopen at Chek Lap Kok the following morning.</p>
<p>The Authority has said it has no plans for a staggered opening as Hong Kong' Civil Aviation Department would not be able to operate two airports at once partly because the airport approaches are in conflict.</p>
<p>Aviation sources said Charter's warning, which he has voiced before, has so far fallen on deaf ears. The new cargo terminal is a vital part of the new airport and very complex: &quot;and if there are snarl-ups the authority can't say they were not warned,&quot; an industry told Reuters.</p>
<p>HACTL'S said its new US$1 billion cargo terminal called Superterminal One now under construction at Chek Lap Kok will be the world's largest and most advanced capable of handling 2.6 million tonnes of cargo per year.</p>
<p>But Charter said it will only be 50 percent operational by next April and is not expected to be fully complete until June.</p>
<p>Charter said he expects the terminal will be able to cope with initial demand until complete.</p>
<p>Testing of some of the hardware is already under way with first integrated testing of the highly complex computer system software due to start in October.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
