<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663426" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila's Food Terminal privatisation opposed.</title>
<headline>Manila's Food Terminal privatisation opposed.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Philippine business groups are asking President Fidel Ramos to stop the sale of the government's 51 percent stake in Food Terminal Inc (FTI) on June 25, the groups said on Monday.</p>
<p>In a statement, the FTI-Taguig Chamber of Commerce and Industry and the FTI Lesees Association said they were not consulted by the government on the sale even though it would affect 500 tenants of the complex.</p>
<p>The two groups said the Cabinet-level Committee on Privatisation failed to consider the dislocation of 50,000 employees of the affected firms and the high cost of relocating businessess to new sites.</p>
<p>The groups added that the sale may violate existing bilateral agreement between Japan and the Philippines on the pre-export inspection and processing at FTI of mango exports to Japan. They did not elaborate.</p>
<p>The two associations requested that they be allowed to join discussions on the privatisation plan for FTI.</p>
<p>FTI operates a 121-hectare agro-industrial complex located at the outskirts of Makati, Manila's financial district.</p>
<p>The Government is planning to sell a total of 44.9 million shares at a minimum price of 155 pesos per share.</p>
<p>The terminal was incorporated in 1968 to stabilise prices of commodities in Manila through an efficient agricultural marketing system. Deterioration of stocks and high interest costs, however, had hit the complex and resulted in huge losses.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (63 2) 8418939 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
