<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663417" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta stocks end up on Wall Street, forecasts.</title>
<headline>Jakarta stocks end up on Wall Street, forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta stocks ended higher on Monday in active trading on foreign-led buying following sharp gains on Wall Street on Friday and recent announcements of upward revisions in 1997 net profit forecasts, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta composite index ended up 6.67 points, or 0.95 percent, at 705.29 points. Advancers led decliners by 84 to 53 with 65 issues unchanged.</p>
<p>Total turn-over was estimated at 628 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;Wall Sreet's strong performance last week coupled with upward revisions of 1997 net profit forecasts from blue-chips like Astra have boosted sentiment,&quot; one broker said.  </p>
<p>Brokers and analysts said reports of strong car sales last month also helped boost sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;Car sales rose sharply last month despite earlier worries that the general election may weaken demand,&quot; Willianto Iie, an automotive analyst with Standard Chartered Indonesia said.</p>
<p>Indonesia held general elections on May 29.</p>
<p>Total vehicle sales in May were 38,242 units, compared with 35,411 units in April, according to a report made available to securities companies by PT Astra International.</p>
<p>A total of 26,964 vehicles were sold in May last year.  </p>
<p>In the monthly statistical report obtained by Reuters on Monday, Astra said passenger car sales rose to 5,649 units in May from 5,468 units in April, compared with 2,817 units in May last year.</p>
<p>Astra said last week it had revised its 1997 net profit forecast to 627 billion rupiah from the previous forecast of 614 billion rupiah. Astra posted a net profit of 470 billion rupiah in 1996.</p>
<p>Large retailer Ramayana also said last week it had revised up its 1997 net profit forecast to 105 billion rupiah from the previous forecast of 90.2 billion rupiah.  </p>
<p>Ramayana posted a net profit of 82.4 billion rupiah in 1996.</p>
<p>Astra rose 100 rupiah to 7,050 rupiah, while Ramayana rose 50 rupiah to close at 6,600 rupiah.</p>
<p>Blue-chip Bank Internasional Indonesia closed at a year-high of 2,175 rupiah from 2,000 rupiah.</p>
<p>Second-liners Bakrieland, Roda Vivatex and Lippo Securities made modest gains in active trading due mostly to speculative reasons, brokers said.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
