<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663524" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rite Aid reports sharply higher earnings.</title>
<headline>Rite Aid reports sharply higher earnings.</headline>
<dateline>CAMP HILL, Pa.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rite Aid Corp., the nation's largest drugstore chain, Monday reported sharply higher earnings for its fiscal first quarter and a strong increase in sales at stores open at least a year.</p>
<p>The Camp Hill, Pa.-based company, which owns the Rite Aid and Thrifty PayLess drugstore chains, said its earnings rose to $68.2 million, or 56 cents per share, in the quarter ended May 31 from $32.7 million, or 39 cents a share, a year earlier.</p>
<p>The company said net income from the prior year included a pre-tax charge of $16 million for costs associated with the attempted acquisition of rival drugstore chain Revco D.S. Inc. Before the charge, net income for last year's first quarter was $42.6 million.</p>
<p>Rite Aid last year gave up the attempted $1.8 billion acquisition of Revco due to opposition from state and federal regulators, who were concerned the merger would reduce competition and drive up prices.</p>
<p>Revenues rose 89.6 percent to $2.66 billion from $1.41 billion. Prescription revenue accounted for half of drugstore sales.</p>
<p>Rite Aid's same-store sales, or sales from stores open at least a year, for the quarter increased 9.5 percent, and Thrifty PayLess same-store sales increased by 5.3 percent for the period.</p>
<p>During the quarter, the company opened 28 drugstores, closed 29 smaller outlets, enlarged 6 locations and relocated 29 units. Rite Aid is the largest U.S. drugstore chain, by number of stores, and had 3,622 stores in operation at the end of the quarter.</p>
<p>Rite Aid's stock was off 37.5 cents at $48.875 in morning trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAMP HILL, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
