<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663547" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs close higher, pork bellies up sharply.</title>
<headline>CME hogs close higher, pork bellies up sharply.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog futures finished stronger on expectations of firmer cash hog markets as the week progresses while a firmer tone to cash bellies added to technical buying and pushed pork bellies to sharply higher closes, traders said.</p>
<p>Hog futures closed 0.850 to 0.100 cent per lb higher with July up most at 80.875 cents. Pork bellies finished 2.300 to 1.250 cent per lb higher with July up most at 79.200 cents.</p>
<p>Expectations for higher cash hog prices and firmer wholesale pork prices supported hog futures, floor sources said. Hog runs have eased and packers cut back on slaughter Monday to strengthen the cash pork complex values, traders said.</p>
<p>USDA estimated hog slaughter at 285,000 head on Monday, below 305,000 a week ago and 307,000 a year ago.</p>
<p>Cash hog prices were called steady to firm Tuesday and most pork product values showed a steadier tone at noon Monday with pork belly prices posting a steady to higher trend compared with Friday's close. Seasonally, hog numbers should decline over the next few weeks and some traders also cited renewed talk of stepped up Japanese pork export business.</p>
<p>IBP Inc said it was adding 80 workers to its Columbus Junction, Iowa, pork plant to process pork for Japan and Taiwan. But traders said this expansion was likely planned some time ago an may not be directly tied to the Taiwan hoof and mouth outbreak and expected larger Japanese pork exports.  </p>
<p>R.J. O'Brien, Rand Financials and Refco notably bought July hogs late while locals bought August. In hog options, trade was very thin with volitility flat, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Pork belly futures ran up early on technical buying prompted by an oversold condition and remained strong late when cash bellies appeared to be turning steady to firmer. The outlook for a bullish USDA Cold Storage report Friday also prompted buying which took futures up sharply, traders said.</p>
<p>Packers cut back on slaughter Monday and 14-16 lb cash bellies were quoted at $75 to $76 per cwt, steady to up $2, the first real upturn in two weeks, sources noted.</p>
<p>Technically, futures looked oversold after falling much of last week and reaching lowest levels since March 31. Adding to support were expectations of a bullish storage report Friday which could show storings at the second lowest level on record for the end of May, they said.</p>
<p>Early analysts' estimates for U.S. frozen bellies ranged from 55.1 million to 57 million lbs stored in U.S. warehouses as of May 31 versus 63.5 million on hand last year. This compares with the record low of 54.98 million lbs for the same period in 1973.</p>
<p>STR, a division of Spike Trading, and E.D.&amp;F. Man notably bought early while Refco bought late, traders said. ADM Investor Services and FIMAT Futures USA sold, pit sources said.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
