<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663606" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot natgas prices lifted by southern heat.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot natgas prices lifted by southern heat.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot natural gas prices edged higher Monday, lifted by warmer weather in parts of the Southwest, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Louisiana Gulf Coast prices at the Henry Hub moved a few cents higher to about $2.17-2.21 per mmBtu, with most of the Gulf pipes at $2.15-2.17.</p>
<p>Similarly in south Texas prices rose four cents to $2.08-2.13 as temperature highs in Houston through Thursday were expected to reach the mid-90s F amid a high humidity level.  </p>
<p>Stronger Gulf values also boosted prices at the New York city gate to about $2.40-2.45, up about five cents from Friday's levels.</p>
<p>Temperatures in the Northeast were expected to average near normal through week's end, Weather Services Corp (WSC) reported.</p>
<p>In the Midwest, prices were equally higher in the low-$2 area, with Chicago city-gate quoted at $2.20-2.22.</p>
<p>Mostly normal temperatures are forecast to continue in the Midcontinent throughout most of this week, according to WSC.</p>
<p>In west Texas, the rising cooling demand coupled with the outage in the San Juan basin pushed prices about 10 cents higher to about $2.</p>
<p>Southern California prices also gained at least 10 cents to about $2.15-2.17.</p>
<p>El Paso Natural Gas Co's Blanco natural gas plant in the San Juan basin will remain shut through Saturday for its annual maintenance outage.</p>
<p>As a result, the pipeline will cut capacity by 240 million cubic feet per day (mmcfd) on Monday and by 815 mmcfd on Tuesday and Wednesday. Flows will be cut by 415 mmcfd on Thursday and by 240 mmcfd on Friday and Saturday.</p>
<p>Because of the absent San Juan supply next week, capacity on the North Mainline for deliveries to Topock and South markets will be cut by 195 mmcfd Monday through Thursday for pipeline replacement.</p>
<p>((--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
