<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663763" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU set for fresh bid to improve food safety.</title>
<headline>EU set for fresh bid to improve food safety.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission, pressed by Britain, is expected on Wednesday to make a fresh bid to tighten controls on mad cow disease and ensure common standards throughout the 15 member states.</p>
<p>Commission officials said Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler was due to resubmit a proposal to ban specified risk material from cattle and sheep -- brains, eyes, spinal cord and spleen -- from human and animal food.</p>
<p>The EU's executive is under pressure to act following a warning from Britain that it may ban imports of beef unless the EU agrees by July 22 to enforce tough British food safety standards in all member states.</p>
<p>In December, 10 EU farm ministers threw out the proposal, arguing that it was an unnecessary expense given that their countries were free of bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE) and scrapie, a similar brain-wasting disease in sheep.</p>
<p>Only Britain, Ireland, France, Sweden and Luxembourg supported the move.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation has changed,&quot; said one official, noting that BSE was more widespread than previously recognised and public pressure for tougher action after EU inspectors criticised member states for not enforcing rules to eradicate the disease.</p>
<p>The EU's Standing Veterinary Committee of senior veterinary officials is expected to give the Commission's proposal a preliminary airing on June 20.</p>
<p>If the committee gives no clear opinion, the proposal would be referred to EU farm ministers. But this time they may not reach the necessary simple majority of eight member states needed to throw it out, officials said, adding that the Commission could then adopt it.</p>
<p>&quot;A final decision may not be taken until the autumn,&quot; a Commission official said.</p>
<p>Although this would not meet the British deadline, London may be prepared to wait if it felt that tougher EU measures were in the pipeline.</p>
<p>The proposal also includes a formal ban on British exports of gelatine extracted from British cattle. However this would only be a cosmetic change as Britain has not been exporting locally sourced gelatine.</p>
<p>It would also clarify that beef imported into Britain for processing could be re-exported. Last November the French government closed the Paris branch of the Hard Rock Cafe, a U.S.-style chain organised by the Rank Organisation, alleging that it had imported frozen hamburger from Britain.</p>
<p>The Netherlands may switch position after two cases of BSE were reported there, probably caused by imports of contaminated animal feed.</p>
<p>Germany, France, Spain and Sweden face legal action after criticism in the EU inspectors' reports for failing to implement rules from April 1 requiring meat and bone meal to be processed at higher temperatures and for longer periods.</p>
<p>Infected meat and bone meal mixed into cattle and sheep feed is believed to be the main cause of BSE, which has killed more than 165,000 cattle, mostly in Britain, in the past 10 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100124">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
