<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663748" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: DHL Intl to lease converted Airbus freighter.</title>
<headline>DHL Intl to lease converted Airbus freighter.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>DHL International, part of the DHL Worldwide Express group, said it had signed a letter of intent with U.S. based, Pinnacle Aircraft Leasing, for the long-term lease of three Airbus 300B4-200 converted freighter aircraft.</p>
<p>&quot;The aircraft will be deployed on DHL's high volume intra-European routes, starting in the fourth quarter of 1997,&quot; DHL said in a statement.</p>
<p>These will be the first widebody aircraft to be used by DHL in Europe and are the first Airbus aircraft to enter the DHL International fleet, the statement added.</p>
<p>&quot;This lease arrangement is the first step in a long-term fleet investment programme which will probably extend to a further five A300Fs over the next 12 to 15 months,&quot; DHL International's Brussels-based Operations director, Neil Ferguson, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Ferguson added: &quot;The A300 comfortably meets the most rigorous standards of noise regulations and with its 43-tonne capacity is a welcome addition to our European air network allowing us to meet ever-increasing demand from our customers.&quot;</p>
<p>DHL's intra-European volumes had been growing at 30 percent per year, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a number of our intra-European routes -- Scandinavia, Iberia, Italy, Iberia, Ireland and the UK, Turkey and Greece, were loads exceed the 20 to 21 tonne-capacity of our Boeing 727Fs making it necessary to double frequencies in some cases. The A300Fs will help us to address this kind of capacity squeeze.&quot;</p>
<p>DHL International currently deploys around 25 727Fs on intra-European routes and earlier this year said it planned to operate a further two Boeing 727Fs from autumn 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true that the number of 727Fs we operate on intra-European routes will increase before they decrease, but our longer term policy for them is as replacements for the Lockheed Electras we operate in the same sector and also their redeployment in Asia and Latin America,&quot; Ferguson added.</p>
<p>Main shareholders in DHL Worldwide Express are Deutsche Lufthansa AG and Japan Airlines Co Ltd. -- Reuters Air Cargo Service Tel+ 44 171 542 7706 Fax +5017 - www.racs.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I84804">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8480401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
