<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663710" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Investors pour billions into Swiss mutual funds.</title>
<headline>Investors pour billions into Swiss mutual funds.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA</dateline>
<text>
<p>The growth in Switzerland's mutual fund business continues unabated, with mostly foreign investors pouring in about $11.4 billion in the 12 months to end of May, a new market survey said.</p>
<p>The figures released by Swiss fund statistician Bopp ISB showed combined assets of public mutual funds set up by Swiss banks at home and abroad grew 16.4 billion Swiss francs ($11.4 billion) to 251.4 billion francs ($175 billion) at end-May over a year ago. Bopp ISB said net flows to Swiss-run mutual funds totalled 1.5 billion Swiss francs ($1.04 billion) in May.</p>
<p>Thanks partly to dizzying returns on world markets this year, there seems to be no end to the growth in Switzerland's ever-rising mountain of cash.</p>
<p>The Latest foreign newcomer to the market is Templeton Emerging Market Funds, whose President Mark Mobius, asked why he was setting up in Switzerland, said this month, &quot;Money, money, money.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bopp ISB figures are just about the only ones released on the fund industry in Switzerland, whose notoriously secretive private banks do not disclose data on mutual funds and assets they manage and there are no signs they might open up soon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
