<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663998" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - June 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - June 16.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories were reported in Monday's electronic version of The Wall Street Journal:</p>
<p>* Northwest Airlines Corp is close to an agreement to order 50 Airbus Industrie jetliners, worth about $2 billion at list prices, sources said.</p>
<p>* Tobacco-settlement talks hinge on whether cigarette makers will receive immunity from punitive damages. Sources close to the settlement talks say negotiators are likely to leave that issue unresolved.</p>
<p>* Smith Barney fund executive Jessica Bibliowicz, the daughter of Travelers Chairman Sanford Weill, is leaving to become president of money manager John Levin.</p>
<p>* Wholesale prices dropped 0.3 percent in May.</p>
<p>* The California Public Employees' Retirement System, the largest public pension fund in the United States, will soon demand that big firms bolster their boards' power and independence through stronger corporate-governance practices.</p>
<p>* European Union leaders are meeting in Amsterdman for a summit as efforts to create a single currency remains in limbo.</p>
<p>* PacifiCorp's plan to acquire Energy Group Plc hinges on its strategy of linking coal, gas and electricity so it can swap any of them in one market to meet needs in another.</p>
<p>* Century Telephone Enterprises Inc's agreement to acquire PacifiCorp's telephone segment for $1.52 billion, plus assumed debt, would create one of the largest independent phone companies in the United States.</p>
<p>* Japan's gross domestic product rose at an annual rate of 6.6 percent in the latest quarter.</p>
<p>* Andrew Lloyd-Webber plans to take over as chairman of his Really Useful Group, hoping to stem an estimated loss of about $16.3 million for the year.</p>
<p>* Entrepreneur Clark McLeod has agreed to acquire Consolidated Communications, an Illinois telephone carrier, for about $360 million in cash and stock.</p>
<p>* Some of the world's largest personal computer makers plan to unveil new machines called NetPCs that are meant to lower the cost of corporate computer networks.</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones Industrials average rose 70.57 points on Friday, closing at 7782.04, posting a sixth consecutive record.</p>
<p>* America Online is expected to release a series of new online games that would cost subscribers about $2 an hour above their monthly fee.</p>
<p>* &quot;Speed 2: Cruise Control,&quot; released by News Corp Ltd's Twentieth Century Fox, posted $16.2 million for its debut weekend.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
