<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="663943" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Opposition forces launch new attack on Taleban.</title>
<headline>Opposition forces launch new attack on Taleban.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opposition forces launched a new attack against the purist Islamic Taleban militia north of Kabul on Monday, a Pakistan-based news agency reported.</p>
<p>The Afghan Islamic Press (AIP) said guerrillas loyal to former government commander Ahmad Shah Masood had used artillery to pound Taleban positions at Pul-i-Matak, between the towns of Charikar and Jabal-os-Siraj on the main highway to the north.</p>
<p>At least four fighters from both sides were killed in the fighting, which was still going on, AIP said.</p>
<p>Masood has been battling the Taleban in the Jabal-os-Siraj area since he broke out of his Panjsher Valley fiefdom more than two weeks ago to trap a Taleban force that had crossed the Hindu Kush range into the north via the Salang Pass.</p>
<p>Opposition forces drove that force out of Pul-i-Khumri, the Taleban's last stronghold in the north, last Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Taleban have suffered a series of military setbacks at the hands of opposition forces in the past few weeks.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the militia had been using night flights to send the bodies of killed fighters from Kabul to the eastern town of Jalalabad to be returned to their families.</p>
<p>They said at least 20 bodies had been flown to Jalalabad on Saturday and Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
