<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="664487" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: EU finance ministers reach budget, jobs deal.</title>
<headline>EU finance ministers reach budget, jobs deal.</headline>
<byline>Myra MacDonald</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union finance ministers on Monday agreed a budget stability pact for countries joining a single currency and a resolution on jobs and growth, defusing a row that threatened economic and monetary union.</p>
<p>Dutch Finance Minister Gerrit Zalm told reporters after a morning of talks with his colleagues that a deal had been reached that could be presented later on Monday to EU leaders at their mid-year summit.</p>
<p>&quot;We have reached complete agreement on the stability pact and the resolution for growth and employment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>France and Germany, sharply divided over the issue, both said they were happy with the agreement.</p>
<p>Zalm declined to give the contents of the agreement, but EU Monetary Affairs Commissioner Yves-Thibault de Silguy told reporters a link would be extablished between a pact limiting budget deficits of countries which join a single European currency and one one growth and employment.</p>
<p>De Silguy also said the ministers agreed to authorise the European Investment Bank, the EU's main lending arm, to help small businesses and high-technology companies as a way of boostoing employment.</p>
<p>A special European Union summit on jobs was also likely later this year in the autumn to keep the issue of unemployment high on the EU's agenda.</p>
<p>The latest crisis in the EU's plans for a single currency erupted last week when France's new Socialist government held up routine agreement of the stability pact, a framework for keeping EU budgets tight after EMU is launched.</p>
<p>Paris wants more political control over economic issues and is keen to see jobs creation given a higher role. Germany is vehemently committed to budgetary discipline and wary of government intrusion.</p>
<p>The mark dipped against the French franc and Italian lira on on news of the deal. Brian Venables, a senior bond analysts at ABN AMBRO said the agreement underlined that EMU would go ahead, probably with a broad group of countries.</p>
<p>&quot;What can derail it now?&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
