<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="664457" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: PRESS DIGEST - MALTA - JUNE 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - MALTA - JUNE 16.</headline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the  leading stories in the Maltese press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE TIMES - FOI withdraws from tax talks because of selective exemptions. Prime Minister Alfred Sant said the Malta Federation of Industry had backed out of talks with the government on exemptions from the new system of indirect taxation because it did not want to discriminate among its members. The new system, replacing VAT comes into force on July 1. It includes certain exemptions on import duties on raw materials and tax refunds for exporting firms</p>
<p>L-ORIZZONT - Prime Minister says government policies are helping economy to grow. He says deficit in the balance of payments in the first three months fell by 25 million Malta pounds ($65m) to 39 million pounds ($83.6m) compared to the same period last year.</p>
<p>IN-NAZZJON - Maltese involved in plan to kill senior Sicilian police officer. Magistrates in the Sicilian city of Palermo are planning to ask the Maltese government to extradite a Maltese businessman allegedly for association with the Mafia and involvement in a plot to kill a senior police officer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
