<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="664490" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Air cargo industry needs common communications systems.</title>
<headline>Air cargo industry needs common communications systems.</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The air cargo industry must develop single airline and freight forwarder communication systems or face losing further market share to integrators, a senior Lufthansa Cargo manager warned.</p>
<p>Joachim Haas, the al1-freight airline's vice-president Europe, said there were clearly fundamental problems with the existing air cargo industry structure given that shipments still took six days to arrive just like 25 years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The integrators show us how to do it. We (airlines and forwarders) make small improvements and then it emerges that it achieves nothing,&quot; he told an air cargo forum at the Transport 97 trade fair in Munich.</p>
<p>The main problem for the air cargo industry was the large number of processes and lack of standards in transporting shipments compared to the single in-house Systems of the integrators, Haas said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not win the war with aircraft but with systems. Airlines and forwarders must co-ordinate their systems as soon as possible,&quot; he urged.</p>
<p>'What is missing is the link to the client. We are looking at how to change from a data-rich to an information-rich system for shippers and forwarders,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo itself wanted to develop customer-orientated partnerships with freight forwarders to meet the needs of global clients and to become &quot;an integrator for heavy freight&quot;, Haas said.</p>
<p>Siegfried Koehier, chairman of the Air Cargo Club Deutschland industry association, which organised the forum, added: &quot;We are faced with the problem that all the forwarders and each airline has its own system. We need to develop one system.&quot;</p>
<p>Shippers also expected the industry to adapt to changing client needs, Hans Helge Westernholt, head of shipping and transportation for Siemens AG Power Generation told the forum.</p>
<p>Firms needed door-to-door services and reliable services in order to be able to deliver goods and Services to their customers, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Last-minute fuel surcharges and rapid rates increases are not acceptable in view of the global competition (affecting industry),&quot; he added in reference to last autumn's cargo fuel surcharge and this spring's rates rises.</p>
<p>Heavy-lift cargo operators such as users of Antonov freighters were also gaining custom from shippers while the planned Cargolifter cargo airship would be of interest to the machine building industry, he added. - Reuters Air Cargo Service Tel+ 44 171 542 7706 Fax +5017 - www.racs.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
