<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="664649" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: EU leaders, EMU weight lifted, plod away at treaty.</title>
<headline>EU leaders, EMU weight lifted, plod away at treaty.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union leaders, a row over monetary union fast dissipating, worked their through a draft EU treaty on Monday seeking a careful balance that would meet all countries' concerns yet still have some meaning.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the leaders at their mid-year summit almost immediately agreed that an Employment Chapter should be added to the treaty, making job creation a prime focus of EU policy.</p>
<p>But they said German Chancellor Helmut Kohl had held off complete support for now because he wanted countries to have a veto on any plans for job creation initiatives.</p>
<p>Originally a Nordic proposal, the Employment Chapter was opposed for a long time during treaty negotiations by Germany and Britain, which feared interference in the market place.</p>
<p>London changed its mind when the Labour government was election. Bonn has indicated it could live with jobs language in the treaty as long as there were no funding or target proposals.</p>
<p>&quot;(It) strikes a fair balance between efficient cooperation and the realisation that principle responsibility for employment rests with member states,&quot; an aide quoted British Prime Minister Tony Blair as saying.</p>
<p>The leaders, meeting at their mid-year summit, spent most of Monday working through a draft treaty prepared by the Dutch EU presidency before ordering a new version to be written overnight for agreement on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The treaty, the result of more than 15 months' negotiation, is expected to offer the bloc's citizens a broad range of freedoms and to lift internal borders across the continent.</p>
<p>But it is likely to cover up sharp differences over integration among the EU's 15 countries with a series of opt outs and protocols.</p>
<p>Britain and Ireland, for example, are expected to be allowed to keep their border controls. Denmark will be seeking language to protect its constitution and avoid seeing its citizens reject the treaty in a referendum as they initially did with the Maastrict treaty.</p>
<p>Fervent integrationists will be give some succour in the form of language authorising them in principle to move ahead of others if they wish -- so-called flexibility.</p>
<p>But a sharp dispute was expected over whether countries wishing to integrate faster could do so by majority vote or whether the agreement of all was needed.</p>
<p>Sweden, Britain and other reluctant intergrationists were expected to insist that they have a veto over the moves of others.</p>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac, however, told his colleagues that flexibility &quot;only made sense if decisions are taken by majority.&quot;</p>
<p>A tough fight was also expected over plans to reform EU institutions ahead of planned enlargement into eastern Europe in the next decade.</p>
<p>Chirac said plans to give the larger countries more clout in decision making did not go far enough, a position likely to clash sharply with those of smaller countries trying to protect their turf.</p>
<p>Some countries were also worried that a compromise over how many members the European Commission should have would discourage the bloc from enlarging beyond four or five new countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
