<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="664773" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ shares end firm, FCL Paper, Forests well-sought.</title>
<headline>NZ shares end firm, FCL Paper, Forests well-sought.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's leading share prices ended modestly firmer on Monday thanks mostly to strength in the domestic bond market, brokers said.</p>
<p>But the slight gain of 4.53 points to 2,370.82 was again on healthy turnover, which was high for a Monday at NZ$51.7 million.</p>
<p>Fletcher Paper rose two to NZ$3.40 and Fletcher Forests closed up four at $1.99.</p>
<p>FCL Paper, Forests and Telecom were actively traded and Murray Rutherford at SBC Warburg said it was a leader's market.  </p>
<p>Chemicals group Fernz Corp took a step back, despite favourable publicity over the weekend about its latest initiative in France. By the close Fernz had lost nine cents to NZ$4.95, though on light turnover.</p>
<p>Energy stocks performed strongly, among them being TransAlta up 10 at NZ$2.00, Bay of Plenty Electricity, up five at $6.90 and Enerco, up five at $5.70.</p>
<p>Rutherford said the sector had run well in response to the expectation that further rationalisation, particularly in electricity, would take place.  </p>
<p>&quot;A lot of these companies will benefit from further rationalisation and I'm sure it will happen over time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- James Gray, Auckland newsroom +64 9 302 1253</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
