<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="664765" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>PM SAYS COMMUNITY FUNDS COULD BE BETTER USED</p>
<p>The Prime Minister says Australian religious and community groups could not justify the cost of taking out a full page advertisement in a British newspaper.</p>
<p>John Howard was commenting after the groups drafted a letter to British leader Tony Blair, urging him to raise native title and human rights issues when he meets John Howard later this week.</p>
<p>Mr Howard has told ABC Radio that while it was their democratic right to send such a letter, having it published in a paid advertisment would be a costly stunt.</p>
<p>Mr Howard says he believes many members of the organisations would prefer their contributions to be spent aiding disadvantaged Australians.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HOWARD STANDS BY HIS MAN</p>
<p>Prime Minister, John Howard, says Small Business Minister, Geoff Prosser, has not breached the Ministerial Code of Conduct, despite Labor's claims.</p>
<p>The Opposition says Mr Prosser's investments in shopping centres represent a conflict of interest, because issues such as the rights of franchisees are part of his portfolio.</p>
<p>But Mr Howard told ABC Radio, Mr Prosser has not contravened the code of conduct because he has not made any decisions relating to his particular investments.</p>
<p>He says there seems to be a desire within the A-L-P and Democrats to try to drive out of Parliament anyone who has any kind of business background.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister says Mr Prosser's small business background is a positive rather than a negative.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BEAZLEY NOT INFORMED ABOUT MPS UNDER INVESTIGATION</p>
<p>Opposition leader Kim Beazley says there may be some merit in revealing the names of two federal politicians who are under Federal Police investigation for alleged travel allowance fraud. Administrative Services Minister David Jull says no details about the pair can be released because it is a police matter.</p>
<p>Mr Beazley says the release of the names may help ensure all MPs are not tarred with the same brush, now it has been revealed that a police investigation is underway.</p>
<p>But he says there is always the possibility that the claims against the pair are vexatious.</p>
<p>Two Coalition parliamentarians and an Independent Senator are already being investigated over alleged travel claim irregularities.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>DEMOCRATS OPPOSE POSTAL VOTE FOR CONVENTION</p>
<p>The Democrats say it is a pity the Constitutional Convention looks like being hijacked by an obsession with voluntary voting. Democrats Leader, Cheryl Kernot, says the convention, planned for December, should not be treated as an occasion for a Liberal Party experiment in voluntary voting.</p>
<p>Senator Kernot believes the Senate will block the Government's plan to have a postal vote to elect delegates to the convention.</p>
<p>The Democrats and Opposition claim the non-compulsory postal ballot to elect half of the 152 delegates is undemocratic and could disenfranchise many people.</p>
<p>But the Parliamentary Secretary responsible for the Convention, Nick Minchin, says the Government will not accept changes.</p>
<p>Senator Minchin says the Government is not ruling out the option of scrapping the convention if the Senate amendments succeed.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
