<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66479" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-BERGER SET TO MAKE HOME DEBUT FOR LEADERS LIVERPOOL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BERGER SET TO MAKE HOME DEBUT FOR LEADERS LIVERPOOL.</headline>
<byline>Paul Radford</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Liverpool hope Czech forward Patrik Berger will hope to extend his remarkable scoring spree when he makes his home debut in the English premier league top-of-the-table clash with Chelsea on Saturday.</p>
<p>Berger, signed from Borussia Moenchengladbach in the summer, scored twice last week when he came on after the interval as Liverpool went top by beating Leicester City 3-0.</p>
<p>He scored two more in a midweek World Cup qualifier as the Czech Republic crushed Malta 6-0 and is likely to hold his place in the Liverpool line-up at the expense of the striker he replaced last week, England international Stan Collymore.</p>
<p>Liverpool manager Roy Evans said: &quot;Two goals in half a game isn't bad and it's given me an extra problem. It's nice to have people competing for places but it's difficult to keep everyone happy as they all want to play.&quot;</p>
<p>Chelsea, two points behind the league leaders in third place, recall two of their foreign signings, Italian striker Gianluca Vialli and French sweeper Franck Leboeuf, who both missed a midweek League Cup game with niggling injuries.</p>
<p>Second-placed Manchester United, also two points adrift of Liverpool, face a tough away game against Aston Villa but will have the tough-tackling Roy Keane back in midfield after missing six matches with injury.</p>
<p>Like Evans, Manchester United manager Alex Ferguson has an embarrassment of strikers to choose from with Andy Cole staking his claim for a recall by hitting a hat-trick in a midweek match in the reserves. Norwegian Ole Gunnar Solskjaer could make way for him.</p>
<p>Arsenal, managerless until Arsene Wenger joins them at the end of the month, travel to Middlesbrough where they face the highest-scoring team in the league.</p>
<p>Italian Fabrizio Ravanelli, top scorer with six league goals and with a further four in his first League Cup game, will be joined up front by Nicky Barmby who is back from injury.</p>
<p>Arsenal, fearful of a hangover, welcome back England centre-back Tony Adams who declared last week he was fighting alcoholism but the defender is likely to start on the substitutes' bench.</p>
<p>Former Arsenal manager George Graham, still waiting for his first victory with new club Leeds United, may have to continue to be patient as he has five first-teamers out with injury against Newcastle United.</p>
<p>&quot;The challenge of this job is probably bigger than I anticipated,&quot; said a rueful Graham.</p>
<p>Kevin Keegan's Newcastle, fourth in the league, are at full strength and will entertain hopes of continuing their push towards the top of the table.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
