<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="664778" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian PM draws heat for summer holiday.</title>
<headline>Australian PM draws heat for summer holiday.</headline>
<byline>Terry Friel</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard, Australia's chief monarchist and cricket fan, leaves on Tuesday for a 16-day visit to Britain and the United States that his opponents have dismissed as a mere summer jolly.</p>
<p>On his first visit to Canberra's main Western allies since winning power 16 months ago, Howard is aiming to build personal ties with newly-elected British Prime Minister Tony Blair and U.S. President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>But critics complain the main spin of Howard's tour, at least on the London leg, is not politics but cricket.</p>
<p>The right-arm off-spinner, who refuses to sing or dance on daytime television but is happy to pick up a bat for the cameras, has at least three cricket-related engagements in London, and may also take time out for the tennis at Wimbledon.</p>
<p>Newspapers and cartoonists have seized on the cricketing spin -- &quot;PM packs his sun hat, bat and ball for London visit&quot;, said the daily Australian Financial Review.</p>
<p>The visit has also prompted comparisons to Australia's most famous conservative prime minister, Sir Robert Menzies, who routinely sailed to London to spend months at a time in the capital of Australia's former colonial master.</p>
<p>&quot;Appearances at Lords and Wimbledon and the general jollies of what might have been acceptable in the 1950s is not what is acceptable now,&quot; Labor opposition leader Kim Beazley said.</p>
<p>Howard's first two official engagements centre on cricket -- a dinner on the eve of the second match of the traditional Ashes series between Britain and Australia and watching the match start next day at Lord's, the hallowed home of cricket. He wraps up the London leg with the opening of an Ashes exhibition.</p>
<p>Howard will meet Blair and new finance minister Gordon Brown. But he will spend more time with his conservative idol, former prime minister Margaret Thatcher, and Queen Elizabeth, Australia's head of state.</p>
<p>As he flies into the northern summer Howard leaves behind a national capital in the grip of winter, as well as a government beset by poor opinion polls, stubborn unemployment and damaging rows over Aboriginal land rights, immigration and race.</p>
<p>Church and aid groups said on Monday they had written an open letter due to be published in The Times of London on Tuesday appealing to Blair to raise the Aboriginal issues in his talks with Howard -- a move Howard dismissed as a stunt.</p>
<p>High on the official agendas in Britain and the United States will be security, European agricultural policy, China and Canberra's bid to encourage the European Union and Washington to ease their stand on compulsory cuts to greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the evident deep involvement of Australia with the nations of the Asia-Pacific region, the very important links between Australia and the United Kingdom, Australia and the United States should not only be maintained but should be enhanced,&quot; Howard told parliament on Monday.</p>
<p>Australia is lobbying hard against European and U.S. plans to impose fixed targets for cuts to carbon dioxide emissions, which Howard said would cut gross domestic product by 1.5 percent, damage industry and throw thousands out of work.</p>
<p>Howard flies from London to Washington on June 25, travels to New York on June 28 and returns home on July 3.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
