<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="664927" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul stocks end lower, finance reform ignored.</title>
<headline>Seoul stocks end lower, finance reform ignored.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Consolidation in reaction to recent sharp rises pushed Seoul stocks to close lower on Monday but brokers said representative companies in each industry came into the spotlight.</p>
<p>They said investors widely shrugged off the government's final proposals to reform the country's backward financial industry.</p>
<p>Taehwa Shopping filed for court receivership due to high finance costs but brokers said investors were unmoved.</p>
<p>The composite stock index closed on Monday 2.92 points lower at 789.05. But losers more than doubled gainers by 505 to 291.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market needs a rest as it is overheated,&quot; said Woo Sang-chul at Tongyang Securities. &quot;But the market liquidity remains fluid with about 3.5 trillion won.&quot;</p>
<p>Kim Wan-hee at Dongsuh Securities said: &quot;Recent rises were so fast. But the consolidation will not last long.&quot;</p>
<p>Brokers said buying interest remains strong among industrial representatives. Hyundai Engineering and Construction hit the largest trading volume of 2.43 million. It briefly hit a new yearly high of 26,700 and then closed at 26,700, up 1,900. LG Electronics briefly touched, 17,400, a new yearly high, but closed at 16,900, up 500 won.  </p>
<p>Finance Minister Kang Kyong-shik said in a news conference his ministry would accept most of the financial reform proposals presented by the Presidential Commission for Financial Reform. He said the central bank governor would be asked to set an annual inflation target and be held responsible for meeting it.</p>
<p>Investors had hoped the government draft would include expansion of individual ownership in banks, as local media speculated over the weekend, but Kang did not mention it.</p>
<p>Brokers said some disappointed investors had sold off banking shares. The banking sub-index lost 10.18 points, or 2.34 percent, to 424.84.  </p>
<p>The Korea Stock Exchange suspended trading in Taehwa Shopping as it filed for court receivership. It said trading of Taehwa shares would resume from Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was already discounted in the market as some investors were informed about the news on Saturday,&quot; Woo said. &quot;Taehwa has had limited impact today.&quot;</p>
<p>The bourse also halted trading in Korea Long Term Credit Bank during the afternoon session as the bank announced a one-for-10 bonus issue in August.</p>
<p>Insurance shares were in strong demand on rotational buying as they had long been suffered from a lack of buying interest.  </p>
<p>The insurance sub-index rose 216.18 points, or 5.80 percent, to 3,945.74.</p>
<p>Hyundai Marine and Fire Insurance went limit up, gaining 3,100 won to its new nearly high of 42,000.</p>
<p>Some brokers said a local securities house seemed to recently boost Hyundai Group shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Large-cap shares had posted handsome profits during the recent rally. Investors are wondering where the next buying interest will go to,&quot; Woo said.</p>
<p>-- Yeom Yoon-jeong (822) 727 5647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
