<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="665154" id="root" date="1997-06-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Financials, industrials push Taiwan stocks higher.</title>
<headline>Financials, industrials push Taiwan stocks higher.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices were sharply higher at mid-session on Monday as electronics emerged to take up a charge initiated at the open by the rejuvenated financial sector, brokers said.</p>
<p>With 70 minutes left, at 0250 GMT, the index was up 136.60 points or 1.61 percent at 8,638.78.</p>
<p>Turnover was strong at T$108 billion.</p>
<p>In an unusual twist, financials and major industrials were up at the same time, prompting analysts to venture that an April-May correction was easing and that bulls of early 1997 may be running anew.  </p>
<p>&quot;This time financials and industrials are rising together, indicating how bullish the sentiment is,&quot; said HSBC James Capel analyst Alex Chen.</p>
<p>Chen noted that a financials rise generally accompanied by a decline in industrial sectors and vice versa.</p>
<p>Financials opened with a bang after lagging in the market's recent rally, and were up 1.64 percent at mid-session, with China Development up T$3 to T$124.</p>
<p>Electronics had surged 3.52 percent, with leading chipmaker Taiwan Semiconductor up T$6 to T$101.5 and rival semiconductor maker Macronix up T$3 to T$64.5.  </p>
<p>Brokers attributed Monday's unexpected rise chiefly to local newspaper reports reiterating details of the finance ministry's April announcement that it would raise the limit on bank stock market holdings to 20 percent of a bank's net asset value from 15 percent.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Paul Chiu had said the reform would take effect by the end of June.</p>
<p>Brokers said they expected the index soon to test a seven-year closing high of 8,661.72 recorded on April 26.</p>
<p>-- James Peng (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
