<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66512" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: TENNIS-NOAH MISGIVINGS AS FRANCE FALTER AGAINST ITALY.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-NOAH MISGIVINGS AS FRANCE FALTER AGAINST ITALY.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>NANTES, France 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>French captain Yannick Noah, whose team are one defeat from elimination by underdogs Italy in the Davis Cup semifinals, said on Friday there had been shortcomings in the run-up to the tie.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't regret the defeats but I've got regrets about a lot of things before the tie, during the preparation,&quot; Noah said after France had lost both singles on the opening day.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll talk about those things after (the tie). We're still in the match and now the priority is to win tomorrow,&quot; said Noah, captain when France last won the Davis Cup in 1991.</p>
<p>The French were surprised when they arrived on Monday to find the brand-new synthetic surface laid in the Palais des Sports de Beaulieu was slower than they expected.</p>
<p>It became faster with each practice session but still suited the Italian slow-court specialists.</p>
<p>&quot;There were mistakes that were not the players' fault. They wanted to win. They were hyper-motivated,&quot; Noah said.</p>
<p>French number one Cedric Pioline lost to Andrea Gaudenzi in four sets in the opening singles, then Italian first string Renzo Furlan beat Arnaud Boetsch, also in four sets.</p>
<p>&quot;We became a bit relaxed before the first match, myself included,&quot; Noah said. &quot;Cedric did not play at his usual level.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Things happened the way we feared. The Italians are solid on the baseline and very hard to pass.&quot;</p>
<p>Noah is considering changing his line-up for Saturday's doubles from the pairing of Guy Forget and Guillaume Raoux, who have never played together, he named at Thursday's draw.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll hold a council of war tonight,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>When France went 2-0 up against Germany in their quarter-final in April, Noah opted to drop Raoux and send Forget, a veteran of France's 1991 triumph, out with Boetsch to clinch the tie 3-0.</p>
<p>Noah may decide on the same pairing again on Saturday in a bid to secure France's survival.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NANTES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
