<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="665405" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK--CPI, housing starts, production.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK--CPI, housing starts, production.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A big batch of May economic data will attract the market's attention on Tuesday but none of it threatens to sink a buoyant market, analysts said.</p>
<p>The market has climbed steadily since late May, fueled by reports of weak consumer demand and nearly absent inflation.</p>
<p>Monday's action proved no exception to the upward trend. Even without fresh data to drive it higher, the benchmark 30-year Treasury bond nonetheless rose 14/32 to 99-4/32, its yield ending at 6.69 percent, the lowest closing yield for the bond since February 25.  </p>
<p>The May Consumer Price Index (CPI) and new housing starts figures top Tuesday's calendar of economic reports.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters expect the CPI, due at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT, to be up 0.2 percent in May after a 0.1 percent April rise.</p>
<p>The core CPI, the price measure without its more volatile food and energy items, is also expected to be up 0.2 percent, the economists said, after a 0.3 percent April increase.</p>
<p>Housing starts remained flat, said economists, estimating new starts occurred at a seasonally adjusted, annualized rate of 1.47 million in May versus 1.473 million starts in April.  </p>
<p>After the housing and consumer price data releases at 0830 ECT/1230 GMT, the Federal Reserve will report May industrial production and capacity utilization figures at 0915 EDT/1315 GMT. Economists believe industrial production rose just 0.2 percent in May after remaining flat in April partly due to strikes in the automobile sector.</p>
<p>The portion of the nation's mines, factories and utilities employed in that production, known as capacity utilization, is forecast at 83.4 percent, unchanged from the previous month and well below a level that would augur production bottlenecks and attendant inflationary pressures, economists said.  </p>
<p>Data on U.S. real earnings in May are due at 1000 EDT/1400 GMT. Earnings fell 0.9 percent in April. A May forecast was not available. The data are not expected to impact the market.</p>
<p>In the midst of the more comprehensive data for May, the market also gets two up-to-date snapshots of consumer demand in June.</p>
<p>BTM/Schroders weekly chain store sales index for the week ended June 14 is due at 0900 EDT/1300 GMT officially, but the index reading is usually rumored in the market before then.</p>
<p>Lynch, Jones &amp; Ryan Inc will report the Redbook Index for the same week later on Tuesday at 1455 EDT/1855 GMT.  </p>
<p>The BTM Schroders index fell 0.9 percent in the week ended June 7 while the Redbook index rose 2.3 percent. Forecasts for the store sales indices due on Tuesday were not available.</p>
<p>Analysts said if the market is to move higher from here, the gains are more likely to be made at the long end of the maturity range.</p>
<p>&quot;The market can go higher but you really can't rally the front end of the market at this point until you start to make a case for a Fed easing and I don't think most people are ready to do that yet,&quot; said Dana Johnson, managing director and research head at First Chicago Capital Markets Inc.  </p>
<p>The long end of the maturity range, in contrast, has &quot;a little more value,&quot; said Johnson. &quot;You could see the long bond yield move down to 6-5/8 percent and circle around that area.&quot;</p>
<p>Johnson said he believes that the middle of the trading range for the bond yield this year is more like seven percent rather than 6-5/8 percent, but that for now, &quot;momentum and the correct belief that the Fed will not change policy in July allows the market to pursue lower yields in the near term.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1679))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
