<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="665813" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-BANGLADESH, KENYA GIVEN ONE-DAY STATUS.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-BANGLADESH, KENYA GIVEN ONE-DAY STATUS.</headline>
<byline>Barney Spender</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya, conquerors of West Indies in the 1996 World Cup, and Bangladesh have both been awarded one-day international status by world cricket's ruling body.</p>
<p>However, their bid to join the elite of test-playing nations has been put on hold for at least another 12 months.</p>
<p>The president of the International Cricket Council (ICC), Jagmohan Dalmiya, announced the news at Lord's on Tuesday after the ICC's annual conference.</p>
<p>It was also confirmed that moves were definitely being made to establish cricket at Disney World in Orlando, Florida.</p>
<p>Negotiations are starting which would commit all nine test teams to playing there at least once so that the ICC could stage a triangular one-day international tournament over the next three years.</p>
<p>&quot;The development committee has got a mission to turn the sport into a global one,&quot; said David Richards, whose term as chief executive of the ICC has also been extended for another five years.</p>
<p>&quot;North America is one of the main areas where we want to develop and it's important to remember that the first international cricket match was not, as most people think, the first test between England and Australia in 1877.</p>
<p>&quot;It was, in fact, Canada versus the USA in 1844. We want to go back to those roots and build on them. Whether a ground of international quality will be ready by September next year when we hope to begin, who knows? But there's goodwill on both sides.&quot;</p>
<p>Dalmiya said all one-day internationals played by Kenya and Bangladesh, who have both qualified for the 1999 World Cup in England, would now be considered offical.</p>
<p>Any three-day or four-day games they played against first-class opposition, including each other, would take on first-class status.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe this will assist both countries with their rapid progress towards higher performance standards,&quot; said Dalmiya.</p>
<p>Bangladesh, who won the ICC Trophy in Kuala Lumpur earlier this year to qualify for the World Cup, had made a concerted effort to win full test status but that was deferred.</p>
<p>Richards added that the decision to upgrade the status of the two countries was also intended to act as an incentive to nations such as Scotland, who also qualified for the World Cup, and Ireland, who just missed out.</p>
<p>&quot;This is meant to send out the signals that if the infrastructure and the resources are right then all those countries will be considered,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>They also announced the inaugural Youth World Cup which will be held in South Africa in 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
