<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="665844" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-REDS SHORTSTOP LARKIN TO MISS TWO TO SIX WEEKS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-REDS SHORTSTOP LARKIN TO MISS TWO TO SIX WEEKS.</headline>
<dateline>CINCINNATI, Ohio 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cincinnati Reds shortstop Barry Larkin, the 1995 National League MVP, was placed on the 15-day disabled list Tuesday with a strained left calf.</p>
<p>Larkin, who has battled a heel injury since spring training, was injured while running out a double in the Reds' 4-1 interleague win over the Cleveland Indians.</p>
<p>Team doctors said Larkin would be sidelined anywhere from two to six weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a devastating loss and it looks like he will be out a long time,&quot; Reds manager Ray Knight said after the game. &quot;Barry carries the load offensively and we are going to have to scrap without him.&quot;</p>
<p>Larkin, who has played in just 57 games this season, is hitting .317 with 14 doubles, three triples and four homers.</p>
<p>In 1996, Larkin became the first shortstop in major-league history to hit 30 homers and steal 30 bases in the same season. The previous year, he was named MVP after hitting .319 with 15 homers, 66 RBI and 51 stolen bases.</p>
<p>To replace Larkin on the roster, pitcher John Smiley was activated from the disabled list and will start Tuesday night against the Indians.</p>
<p>The Reds (28-39), also beset by injuries to outfielder Reggie Sanders and reliever Jeff Brantley, are just one-half game ahead of the last-place Cubs in the NL Central.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CINCINNATI, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
