<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="665961" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EMI to return cash to shareholders.</title>
<headline>EMI to return cash to shareholders.</headline>
<byline>Keith Weir</byline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>British music company EMI Tuesday announced details of plans to return almost 500 million pounds ($820 million) to shareholders.</p>
<p>EMI, whose artists range from 1960s idols The Beatles to current favourites The Spice Girls, said the planned capital return was equivalent to 114.5 pence ($1.87) per existing ordinary share.</p>
<p>The 499.1 million pound ($816.67 million) buyback, to be funded through borrowing, represents some 10 percent of the total five billion pound market capitalisation of the company.</p>
<p>The plan, to be put to shareholders at a meeting on July 18, involves the issue of special 'B' shares which EMI will offer to repurchase. EMI is also proposing to split its ordinary shares to make them easier to trade.</p>
<p>Investors will receive nine new ordinary shares and five B shares for every five EMI shares held.</p>
<p>The company said it had spent 1.38 million pounds ($2.25 million) repurchasing 120,000 of its own shares on the market at 1170 pence ($19.14) on Tuesday as part of the scheme.</p>
<p>Share analysts said the move was likely to underpin the stock, under pressure since the company was demerged from rentals company Thorn last August.</p>
<p>EMI shares soared to 1460p ($23.89) in the immediate aftermath of the demerger but have fallen as bid talk failed to lead to anything concrete and growth in the global music industry slowed.</p>
<p>&quot;It's great to return cash to shareholders but the real issue is whether this is still a growth stock,&quot; said analyst Anthony de Larrinaga of broker Panmure Gordon.</p>
<p>De Larrinaga said EMI's strong presence in music publishing and emerging markets left it in good shape to weather the current difficulties in the industry.</p>
<p>The global music market is worth some $40 billion annually but sales growth has slipped back well into single figures after a decade of double digit progress.</p>
<p>EMI last year took a 117 million pound ($191.4 million) charge on restructuring of its north American operations, where it is the weakest of the top five music companies. Outside North America it ranks second only to PolyGram.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
