<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666060" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Hard/soft euro debate remains hazy after Amsterdam.</title>
<headline>Hard/soft euro debate remains hazy after Amsterdam.</headline>
<byline>Astrid Zweynert</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The debate about whether the planned European single currency will be hard or soft is just as obscure after the Amsterdam agreement on the stability pact and jobs creation as it was before, analysts said.</p>
<p>Many key questions on the future value of the euro lie outside the political bickering that has spooked the markets so many times and apart from another proof of the strong political will to get the get the project off the ground in 1999 as planned, financial markets were given no new information in Amsterdam.</p>
<p>Details of the policy of the planned European Central Bank (ECB) is just one of several unresolved aspects determining the euro's future value.</p>
<p>The Euro would be hard if it maintained a robust and stable value against other major currencies, whch in turn hinges on the monetary and economic credibility of the EMU process.</p>
<p>EU leaders agreed at their summit in Amsterdam on Monday to adopt the stability pact and a resolution on jobs and growth to help ease the plight of Europe's 18 million unemployed, an economic problem that has undermined public support for EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;It's encouraging from an inflation perspective that the stability pact has been left unscathed, but the inclusion of a jobs pact has encouraged expectations that the euro will be soft,&quot; said Brian Martin, chief economist forex at BZW. &quot;But at this stage the markets can only speculate whether the euro will be soft or hard.&quot;</p>
<p>The stability pact - a brainchild of German finance minister Theo Waigel - is aimed at reinforcing the credibility of the single currency by ensuring budgetary discipline among member states after the start of monetary union.</p>
<p>But the resolution stopped short of any concrete spending commitments for job creation, appeasing concern in the markets that EU budget deficits would balloon even further.</p>
<p>&quot;This has been interpreted as a German victory in repelling an attempt to weaken the euro,&quot; said Stephen Lewis, chief economist at London Bond Broking.</p>
<p>&quot;Nevertheless, the markets appear reluctant to follow the logic of this scenario to its conclusion,&quot; said Lewis, adding the agreement had achieved to preserve the status quo on EMU plans and put off the tough decisions to a later date.</p>
<p>Concrete measures about how to solve Europe's jobless crisis are expected at a special summit this autumn.</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, the forex market's reaction to the Amsterdam agreement was rather subdued.</p>
<p>The mark dropped slightly against the dollar and its European crosses on Monday. But forex traders reported no great shakes, with the exception of the lira, which posted a four-month high against the mark on Tuesday amid higher expectations that Italy will be a first-wave EMU member.</p>
<p>The expected participation of a larger group of countries is adding weight to the soft euro scenario, analysts said.</p>
<p>A larger group of EMU participants may make it more difficult for the ECB to reach swift interest rate decisions - each country will have a representative on its policy-making board. But its mandate to achieve stable and low inflation gives it a high degree of autonomy, thus boosting the euro's credibility. The state of other large world economies - such as the United States - at the start of EMU will also be crucial, as will be the ability among EMU members to tighten fiscal policy if needed, analysts said. &quot;We will see more problems with the Germans keeping their own budget deficit on track. And will the French be prepared to introduce further austerity measures if they look necessary for 1998,&quot; said Brian Hilliard, chief economist at SocGen Strauss Turnbull. Another important aspect of the euro's future value - global portfolio shifts - is even more obscure since it is hard to predict where fund managers will put their money before the euro is traded in the forex market. -- London newsroom + 44 171 542 7792</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
