<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666174" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GABON: African leaders and U.N. envoy seek Congo peace.</title>
<headline>African leaders and U.N. envoy seek Congo peace.</headline>
<byline>Gregory Mintsa</byline>
<dateline>LIBREVILLE 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>African heads of state and U.N. special envoy Mohamed Sahnoun held peace talks on Monday with representatives of the warring parties from the embattled Congo Republic capital of Brazzaville.</p>
<p>The leaders of Chad, Central African Republic and Mali joined Gabon's veteran president Omar Bongo, the host for a mini peace summit, for a day of bilateral talks with representatives of Congolese mediators and the warring parties.</p>
<p>Gabonese officials said the mini-summit, likely to consider a call from Congo President Pascal Lissouba for deployment of an African peace force, would begin later. It was not clear whether that meeting would take place on Monday night or on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Chad President Idriss Deby arrived in Libreville on Monday to join Mali President Alpha Oumar Konare and President Ange-Felix Patasse of the Central African Republic.</p>
<p>Representatives of Lissouba, his arch rival and former Marxist military leader Denis Sassou Nguesso and from a mediation committee presided over by Brazzaville mayor Bernard Kolelas, arrived in Libreville on Sunday on the same plane. The envoys have the power to take decisions.</p>
<p>Bloody political and ethnic clashes pitting soldiers loyal to Lissouba and militiamen loyal to Sassou Nguesso, his predecessor, have rocked Brazzaville since June 5.</p>
<p>They broke out after soldiers surrounded Sassou Nguesso's home as part of a crackdown on private militias and illegal weapons in the runup to a July 27 presidential election.</p>
<p>A French military force has evacuated 5,719 foreign nationals from the city.</p>
<p>Lissouba has said he wants the election to go ahead as planned. Sassou Nguesso says it can do so only if conditions are in place to ensure fair and transparent polling. He has not ruled out deployment of an African force.</p>
<p>Kolelas, whose supporters were in the thick of bloody clashes that killed 2,000 people after a disputed 1993 parliamentary poll, has been a key mediator. His militia have stayed out of the fighting this time.</p>
<p>Sahnoun was special U.N. and Organisation of African Unity envoy on the crisis in the former Zaire, Congo's huge neighbour now called the Democratic Republic of Congo.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't rule out an African presence,&quot; he said at the weekend. &quot;We are going to discuss this issue. Then we have a meeting in Libreville with plenipotentiaries representing different movements so we can formalise this idea.&quot;</p>
<p>An African peace force operates in Patasse's Central African Republic capital Bangui where similar political and ethnic clashes broke out in November, December and January after a third army mutiny in under a year.</p>
<p>Lissouba has suggested that French troops stay to be part of a buffer force. Paris says its embassy will stay open with appropriate security but it began pulling out its 1,200 or so troops from Brazzaville on Monday.</p>
<p>Sassou Nguesso, named president in 1979, bowed to pressure for multi-party politics in 1990 but was among candidates knocked out in the first round of a 1992 presidential poll.</p>
<p>Lissouba defeated Kolelas in the second round.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHAD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIBREVILLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GABON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
