<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666187" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANGOLA: U.N. commanders says Angolan diamond area tense.</title>
<headline>U.N. commanders says Angolan diamond area tense.</headline>
<byline>Lesley Wroughton</byline>
<dateline>LUANDA 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations said on Tuesday a fact-finding mission to Angola's northeastern diamond area, where fighting has been reported between the government army and former rebel UNITA, had found the area tense.</p>
<p>The mission, led by the U.N. force commander in Angola Philip Sibanda of Zimbabwe, also found a large number of internally displaced people and heard sporadic artillery fire, a U.N. statement said.</p>
<p>It said the delegation visited the town of Luia and a crossing point on the Cassai River which marks the eastern border between Angola and the Democratic Republic of Congo, formerly Zaire.</p>
<p>Sibanda was accompanied by military observers from Portugal, Russia and the United States who are helping the U.N. oversee a two-year-old peace process signed by the government and UNITA in 1994 to end two decades of civil war.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation in Luia, Lunda Norte, remains tense. General Sibanda said he could hear sporadic artillery fire in the distance during his visit. He also observed a large number of internally displaced people,&quot; the statement from the U.N. spokesman's office in Angola said.</p>
<p>The statement also said the delegation had been &quot;manhandled on their arrival by UNITA militants&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;UNITA's personnel were angry that media reports are claiming that a UNAVEM statement issued on Saturday...said there is no conflict in the Lundas,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Sibanda visited three towns in the northeast last Friday, where clashes between the two Angolan factions were reported two weeks earlier.</p>
<p>In a statement after that visit, Sibanda said he had found the situation calm with no signs of heavy combat.</p>
<p>&quot;UNAVEM is well aware that the Lundas have long been an area of tensions between the government and UNITA,&quot; Tuesday's statement said.</p>
<p>It added that the U.N. was investigating reports of heavy fighting in the northeast and its findings would be presented to a joint peace commission later this week.</p>
<p>Expatriate mining officials on the ground in the area of the fighting told Reuters of gunbattles between both sides south of the town of Nzage two weeks ago.</p>
<p>The reports were independently confirmed with senior military sources who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>They said the government, while moving south, had come across strong resistance from armed groups in the area controlled by UNITA.</p>
<p>These sources had also witnessed the government reinforcing its artillery stocks last Monday, and said state forces appeared determined to continue their advance south deeper into UNITA's diamond areas.</p>
<p>Although the government and UNITA were joined in a unity government in April, the former rebels still hold onto some 80 percent of all diamond territory in the country, mostly in the northeast.</p>
<p>In terms of the 1994 peace treaty, the government can now extend state administration into UNITA areas after the movement last year declared its guerrilla army had been dismantled and disarmed.</p>
<p>But UNITA has accused the government of forcibly taking territory.</p>
<p>An Angolan government military build-up in the northeast began during a seven-month war in Angola's northern neighbour of Zaire aimed at protecting the country's borders after government ministers claimed thousands of refugees from the former Zaire had crossed the border.</p>
<p>But Western diplomats say this was a pretext to retake diamond territory from UNITA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANGOLA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
