<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666263" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GABON: African leaders fail to achieve Congo breakthrough.</title>
<headline>African leaders fail to achieve Congo breakthrough.</headline>
<dateline>LIBREVILLE 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>African heads of state and U.N. special envoy Mohamed Sahnoun said on Monday that they had failed to achieve a breakthrough in a bloody power struggle in the Congo Republic but would carry on trying for a solution.</p>
<p>A communique issued at the end of a day of bilateral meetings with the representatives of the warring parties and of Congolese mediators said that they had not yet identified sufficient common ground to promote dialogue and conciliation.  </p>
<p>Gabon's veteran president, Omar Bongo, hosted the talks with the help of the presidents of Chad, Mali and the Central African Republic.</p>
<p>&quot;The international mediating committee on the Congo crisis notes that for the moment it has not been able to bring the interested parties round to a certain number of proposals which it thinks would help promote an environment for dialogue and consultation,&quot; the communiqu said.</p>
<p>Senegalese Foreign Minister Moustapha Niasse read the communique, in which the committee called for an immediate and lasting ceasefire in Brazzaville, the embattled capital of the former French colony.</p>
<p>Supporters of President Pascal Lissouba and his predecessor former Marxist military leader Denis Sassou Nguesso have engaged in bloody political and ethnic fighting there since June 5 when troops surrounded Sassou Nguesso's home as part of a crackdown on private militia ahead of a July 27 presidential election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIBREVILLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GABON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
