<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66654" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ETHIOPIA: Mubarak's would-be killers get death penalty.</title>
<headline>Mubarak's would-be killers get death penalty.</headline>
<dateline>ADDIS ABABA 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Ethiopian court on Friday sentenced three Egyptians to death for attempting to kill Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak in Addis Ababa last year, the official Ethiopian News Agency (ENA) reported.</p>
<p>Mubarak escaped unhurt after Egyptian Moslem militants opened fire on his motorcade as he was on his way to an Organisation of African Unity (OAU) summit in the Ethiopian capital on June 26, 1995.</p>
<p>The agency said the three men sentenced to death were members of Egypt's al-Gama'a al-Islamiya (Islamic Group), which is fighting to set up an Islamic state in Egypt.</p>
<p>The prosecutor told the court that the three gunmen used false names and carried Yemeni, Sudanese and Ethiopian passports to enter Ethiopia in 1995 after receiving military training at a clandestine camp in Afghanistan, the agency reported.</p>
<p>Ethiopia has said that 11 members of al-Gama'a were involved in the plot to kill Mubarak, with two of the men directing the failed operation from neighbouring Sudan.</p>
<p>Egypt also accused Sudan of helping the gunmen and sheltering three of them after the attack, which Sudan denied. Three other gunmen were apprehended in Ethiopia and five more were killed.</p>
<p>The state-run news agency, quoting a spokesman for the Central High Court of Ethiopia, said the three were also found guilty of killing two policemen, wounding seven civilans and smuggling arms into the country.</p>
<p>The trial was held in camera.</p>
<p>Ethiopia's president must approve the sentences before they are carried out, the agency said.</p>
<p>The United Nations Security Council last May imposed diplomatic sanctions on Sudan to pressure Khartoum into handing over the three suspects said to be there.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADDIS ABABA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ETHIOPIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
