<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666638" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>Council threat to boycott TransAlta: TransAlta NZ faces court action from Wellington City Council over what councillors say is the power company's failure to help protect customer interests. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Child service falsified documents, says Shirley: Social Welfare Minister Roger Sowry will investigate allegations by ACT NZ MP Ken Shirley that the Children, Young Persons and their Families Service falsified legal documents, including children's death certificates. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Joint caucus hailed: The second joint caucus of National and NZ First MPs was a success, senior government whip John Carter said on Tuesday. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Bolger plays down Budget: Prime Minister Jim Bolger on Tuesday told business leaders, who have called for a confidence-boosting signal from the government, not to hold their breath waiting for the Budget. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Gibbs sells Telecom shares worth $190 million: The very private Auckland millionaire Alan Gibbs has sold 26.8 million Telecom shares in a five-month period to March for $190 million. Page 15.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>Blue Star tipped as rival in courier bid: The acquisitive Blue Star group is tipped as a rival for New Zealand Post in bidding for the courier and express freight businesses of Freightways Ltd.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Positive news for farmers: The Ministry of Agriculture has forecast that farm sector products will rise 1.5 percent in value in the current March year, but will recover only half of last year's decline.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Seller absence keeps Telecom shares up: Telecom's share price has again confounded expectations as sellers who swamped the stock in the first quarter of the $1 billion buy-back have been conspicuously absent in the second.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Ownership shuffle opens doors: Property consultancy Colliers Jardine's individual shareholders are expected to sell their holdings in the next week, but could later become owners in a larger international business.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Tranz Rail in hunt for Aust rail businesses: Tranz Rail expects to begin due diligence this week on three rail businesses earmarked for sale by the Australian Federal Government.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE PRESS</p>
<p>Sell Southpower -- Luxton: Sell Southpower. That was the suggestion acting Energy Minister John Luxton made in Parliament on Tuesday while debating the South Island power price differential. Page 3.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Prebble's green stand 'misguided': A campaign launched on Tuesday by ACT leader Richard Prebble to save parts of Wellington's green belt from Telecom and Capital Coast Health is misguided, the organisations said on Tuesday. Page 7.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
