<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666678" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAPUA NEW GUINEA: PNG politician released by Bougainville rebels.</title>
<headline>PNG politician released by Bougainville rebels.</headline>
<byline>Abby Yadi</byline>
<dateline>PORT MORESBY 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Papua New Guinea politician kidnapped by separatists on Bougainville Island on June 1 was finally released on Tuesday, officials said.</p>
<p>John Momis, the member of parliament for Bougainville Province, was taken captive on the strife-torn island while campaigning for national elections which began last Saturday.</p>
<p>He was released after three days only to be re-captured by a different rebel faction and taken to a village in the rebel heartland near the vast Panguna copper mine.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, a helicopter was sent to fetch Momis and he was flown to Buka Island -- Bougainville's administrative centre on the island's northern tip -- to a rousing welcome.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Momis shed a few tears at the kind of welcome he got,&quot; local official Taheau Pius told Reuters by telephone. &quot;He did not look as tired as we were expecting. All Bougainville is happy that Mr Momis has been released.&quot;</p>
<p>Momis, a former Roman Catholic priest who has represented Bougainville in the national parliament since 1975, met secessionist leader Francis Ona -- president of the self-styled Republic of Bougainville -- during his incarceration.</p>
<p>Local media this week carried a joint statement from Ona and Momis in which the two men said they were committed to working towards peace after nine years of secessionist conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;We now appeal to all Bougainvilleans to cooperate with us towards a resolution of the Bougainville conflict,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The Bougainville conflict began in 1988 when local landowners demanded extra compensation from the government for damage done by Bougainville Copper Ltd's mining operations and began attacking buses carrying workers to Panguna.</p>
<p>The mine, which generated a third of the South Pacific nation's foreign earnings, was closed by guerrilla attacks in May the following year as the conflict worsened. The war has since claimed hundreds of lives.</p>
<p>Earlier this year Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan enlisted the help of British military consultancy Sandline International to put down the rebellion and recapture Panguna, but 70 African mercenaries sent by Sandline were forced home by an army revolt which forced Chan to stand aside.</p>
<p>Chan resumed office earlier this month ahead of the elections. Electoral officials said on Tuesday that voting, which is spread over two weeks across PNG, was going smoothly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT MORESBY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAPUA NEW GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
