<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666613" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: German fugitive sighting said to be obvious ploy.</title>
<headline>German fugitive sighting said to be obvious ploy.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fugitive leader of a secretive German colony in southern Chile made a clumsy attempt over the weekend to throw authorities off his trail by arranging for someone to surface in Argentina under his name, officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Carlos Figueroa said the episode in the Argentine ski resort of Bariloche, in which a man calling himself Schaefer checked into a posh hotel but fled through a window when police knocked on his door, was an obvious diversionary ploy.</p>
<p>&quot;Here is a man who has an international arrest warrant out for him, and he would have us believe that he checked into a hotel with his real name and his real document number? They must think we're a bunch of incompetents to fall for that,&quot; said Interior Minister Carlos Figueroa.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me an absolutely obvious diversionary tactic,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>The man calling himself Schaefer, a former Nazi army corporal wanted on charges of molesting boys at the German enclave of Colonia Dignidad (Dignity Colony), checked into the hotel on Friday but fled through a second-floor window when police, alerted by an anonymous phone call, came knocking on his door.</p>
<p>All the police found inside the room was the man's pajamas.</p>
<p>The mysterious episode -- front-page news in Chile on Monday -- suggested Schaefer had fled over the Andes into Argentina but Chilean authorities said it was an obvious red herring.</p>
<p>Figueroa's deputy Belisario Velasco said on Sunday that the man who checked into the Bariloche hotel was taller and heavier than descriptions of the real Schaefer.</p>
<p>&quot;The characteristics of the person in question don't match those of Paul Schaefer,&quot; said Velasco on local television.</p>
<p>He said authorities were not sure if Schaefer was still in Chile but that Colonia Dignidad, nestled among the Andean foothills near the town of Parral, &quot;has thousands of hectares (acres) of forests and rivers, as well as tunnels and bunkers&quot; where Schaefer could hide.</p>
<p>Schaefer, who has not been seen in public in recent years, faces charges of sexually molesting at least five Chilean boys who attended a boarding school at Colonia Dignidad. He and other leaders of the colony, founded by Schaefer in 1961, face various other charges including illegal detention of children and obstruction of justice.</p>
<p>He came to Chile sometime in the late 1950s fleeing charges of molesting boys at an orphanage he founded in Germany.</p>
<p>Chilean police, acting on a judge's search warrant, have made a series of inspections at the German settlement since mid-May but say they found no obvious sign of Schaefer. Four other leaders, two of them German citizens, have been arrested recently and released on bail.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
