<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666686" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian titanium minerals output to rise-ABARE.</title>
<headline>Australian titanium minerals output to rise-ABARE.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian production of titanium minerals will grow strongly in 1997/98 (July-June) with increased demand from the expansion of commercial airline fleets and new applications such as golf club heads, the Australian Bureau fo Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE) said.</p>
<p>In its June quarter Australian Commodities report, the government's major economics forecaster said there would be substantial increases in the output of rutile, ilmenite and the beneficiated products -- synthetic rutile and titanium dioxide pigment (TiO2).  </p>
<p>Ilmenite production was expected to rise by up to 25 percent and synthetic rutile output by about 19 percent.</p>
<p>Australian TiO2 production was forecast to rise by about 13 percent and total zircon output was expected to rise only marginally next financial year.</p>
<p>Rising prices and higher export volumes were expected to increase Australian export earnings from titanium minerals and zircon by more than 19 percent in 1997/98 to A$1.15 billion.  </p>
<p>Higher ilmenite production would be mainly due to greater output from the Chandala project owned by Tiwest partners Ticor Ltd and Kerr-McGee Corp and the expected commissioning of the new kiln at the North Capel plant in late 1997. The plant is owned by Westralian Sands Ltd.</p>
<p>World prices for titanium minerals were likely to rise in 1997/98 after mixed results this financial year, ABARE said.</p>
<p>The Australian export price of TiO2 was expected to rise by almost 11 percent and the prices of feedstocks for pigment production (rutile, ilmenite and synthetic rutile) would rise by about three percent following strong rises in 1996/97.  </p>
<p>The average price of zircon was forecast to rise by almost six percent in 1997/98 after gaining about 23 percent this year.  </p>
<p>			    Unit  1995    1996    1997     1998</p>
<p>World</p>
<p>Production</p>
<p>    Rutile		 kt    370     342     340	430</p>
<p>    Ilmenite	     kt  7,791   7,865   8,150    8,500</p>
<p>    Zircon		 kt    976     992   1,021    1,060</p>
<p>    Australian exports	94/5    95/6    96/7     97/8</p>
<p>Rutile		 kt    231     189     165	196</p>
<p>    Ilmenite	     kt  1,808   2,071   2,161    2,701</p>
<p>    Zircon		 kt    527     496     460	464</p>
<p>    Sythetic rutile    kt    489     517     534	634</p>
<p>    Ti02 pigment	 kt    165     185     166	188</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WORLD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
