<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666791" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW-Broking is history says Aon executive.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Broking is history says Aon executive.</headline>
<byline>Nick Edwards</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Traditional insurance broking is dead, a senior executive at the world's second largest brokerage told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Insurance broking per se is history,&quot; said Christopher Lawrence, chief executive of Aon Singapore, a subsidiary of U.S.-based Aon Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;Risk services really captures the essence of what we're doing for clients now,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview after unveiling a new corporate structure in Singapore.  </p>
<p>The changes were necessary to digest a series of takeovers Aon began 1996 that briefly propelled it to the apex of the industry before being overtaken again by the previous undisputed giant, Marsh &amp; McLennan Inc.</p>
<p>The mergers swallowed up the famous broking names of Alexander &amp; Alexander, Minet, Inchcape, Rollins Hudig Hall and Heath Hudig Langeveldt.</p>
<p>Aon's 1996 move to buy Alexander &amp; Alexander Inc for US$1.2 billion was the first of its wave of takeovers, sparking retalliatory action by Marsh &amp; McLennan which earlier this year announced the US$1.6 billion takeover of Johnson &amp; Higgins.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the takeovers were a reaction to the pressure of falling revenues from traditional brokerage commissions as clients switched from buying old style insurance to modern risk financing packages.</p>
<p>The word broker does not appear in two of Aon's three new operational units in Singapore -- Aon Risk Services, Aon Benefits and Aon Reinsurance Brokers Asia.</p>
<p>Bernard Fung, chief executive of Aon Holdings Asia Ltd, the operation overseeing the corporation's businesses at the regional level, broking is dying a natural death.  </p>
<p>&quot;The key is to value your services properly. No one broking company has a handle on this yet -- not even us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Recognising this fundamental shift had been behind Aon's multi-billion dollar spending spree, which was &quot;driven by the needs of our customers&quot;, rather than simply aiming to squeeze out competition at the top end of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;I certainly think there is room for more than two global brokers, but the question now is who else wants to be in this arena,&quot; Fung said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Clients are more sophisticated in their approach to risk and risks are getting more complex. The potential for the sale of risk management solutions is unlimited,&quot; Fung told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;But the whole industry is bogged down in the technicalities of being Lloyd's brokers, liability brokers or reinsurance brokers. There are consultants and transaction completers, that's all,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Fung said the transition from broking to consulting was forcing brokers to assess their true value in the insurance industry, a task that was far from complete.  </p>
<p>&quot;People have said Willis (Corroon) has got to merge, that Sedgwick has got to merge, but they haven't got to do anything. They just have to decide where they want to be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brokers also had to be catalysts for change, Fung said.</p>
<p>&quot;Brokers have got to think about how to repackage risk, how to commoditise insurance, to bring in the financial markets and to use technology to do this,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But change in Asia must be driven by clients, traditionally more hesistant about change than Western counterparts.  </p>
<p>&quot;You should only be about one and a half steps ahead of your clients. If you're three steps ahead, you've lost them,&quot; Fung said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-870-3080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
