<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="666800" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL overnight steady as banks cover short positions.</title>
<headline>KL overnight steady as banks cover short positions.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The overnight interbank rate was steady on Tuesday as commercial banks continued to cover short positions, dealers said.</p>
<p>The overnight traded between 8.0 and 9.0 percent, unchanged from Monday, they said.</p>
<p>Dealers said they believed Bank Negara was lending at 9.0 percent through an agent bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Nine percent was taken, as a number of commercial banks were still short,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;Bank Negara has also been actively lending one-month money due to the market tightness.&quot;</p>
<p>No confirmation was available as Bank Negara does not comment on its money market operations.</p>
<p>Earlier, other interbank rates were also boosted by borrowing by commercial banks.</p>
<p>One-week money was at 7.8/8.0 percent against 7.50/80 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>One- and three-month money were at 8.0 percent against 7.80/90.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected rates to come off on Wednesday due to the maturity of Bank Negara bills worth one billion ringgit. Another maturity worth 500 million ringgit is due on Friday.</p>
<p>The central bank did not announce any new issue to roll-over the maturing bills.</p>
<p>&quot;Rates should ease due to the inflows but I don't think they will fall very much, as banks are still short,&quot; said another dealer at a Malaysian bank.</p>
<p>Interest rate futures on the Malaysia Monetary Exchange were generally lower.</p>
<p>At 0900 GMT, the three-month Kuala Lumpur Interbank Offered Rate (KLIBOR) June contract was down four points to 92.09, or an implied yield of 7.91 percent.</p>
<p>The September contract fell three to 92.48, or 7.52 percent, and December was down two to 92.60, or 7.40 percent.</p>
<p>-- Syed Azman (603-206 2323) .</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
