<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="667242" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Boeing sued by Peru crash victims' families.</title>
<headline>Boeing sued by Peru crash victims' families.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The families of 28 victims of AeroPeru Flight 603, which crashed off the coast of Peru in 1996, have filed a products liability lawsuit against Boeing Co., attorneys for the plaintiff said Tuesday.</p>
<p>The lawsuit filed in U.S. District Court in Miami alleges that multiple design defects in Boeing's 757-200 aircraft sensor and computer systems -- and Boeing's failure to adequately train and warn of those defects -- resulted in the crash. The Oct. 2, 1996, crash killed 61 passengers and nine crew members, .</p>
<p>The attorneys could not immediately say whether the amount of the damages being sought is being disclosed.</p>
<p>AeroPeru Flight 603, which left New York City bound for Santiago, Chile, via Miami and Lima, Peru, started experiencing trouble when it took off from Lima.</p>
<p>According to the lawsuit, the aircraft's flight instruments and flight management computer systems began giving conflicting and erroneous information, warnings and alarms to the flight crew, and the computer system also sent erroneous information back to the control tower in Lima.</p>
<p>The confusion continued for 29 minutes as the captain attempted to bring the aircraft back to Lima. The plane crashed after one of its engines failed.</p>
<p>According to a plaintiffs' lawyer, the crash of a Birgenair 757 off the coast of the Dominican Repuplic less than eight months earlier showed &quot;striking similarities&quot; to the Aeroperu crash.</p>
<p>The lawyer said he believes that if Boeing had taken &quot;reasonable steps&quot; to address the problems which caused the Birgenair crash, the AeroPeru disaster might have been avoided.</p>
<p>Officials at Seattle-based Boeing could not immediately be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Boeing's stock fell 62.5 cents to $57.125 on the New York Stock Exchange shortly before midday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
