<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="667363" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NATO training exercise opens in Louisiana.</title>
<headline>NATO training exercise opens in Louisiana.</headline>
<byline>Jua Nyla Hutcheson</byline>
<dateline>FORT POLK, La 1997-06-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A joint peacekeeping training exercise combining troops from four NATO countries and 18 eastern European nations opened on Monday amid optimism that NATO will vote next month to add three new members.</p>
<p>&quot;These exercises are very important to us in terms of gaining experience for our future officers and to help show our abilities to be a worthwhile member of NATO,&quot; said Col. Krzysztof Polkowski of Poland. &quot;Everything is in order and we could be a very good NATO member.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. officials have endorsed adding Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic to NATO when member nations meet in Madrid next month.</p>
<p>The training, which ends on June 29, is designed to foster international operations in peacekeeping and humanitarian aid among the NATO forces and former eastern bloc countries that have joined NATO's Partnership for Peace.</p>
<p>Platoons of soldiers arrived at the central Louisiana military base late last week from Albania, Bulgaria, Czech Republic, Estonia, Georgia, Hungary, Kazakstan, Kyrgyzstan, Latvia, Lithuania, former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia, Moldova, Poland, Romania, Slovak Republic, Slovenia, Ukraine and Uzbekistan.</p>
<p>In addition to U.S. troops, military units were sent by NATO members Canada, Belgium, and Turkey.</p>
<p>For the first few days, the PFP troops will be trained in basic skills, including setting up traffic control points, observation posts and checkpoints, securing personnel and facilities, escorting convoys and distributing humanitarian aid.</p>
<p>Then, aided more than 700 personnel protraying civilians and relief support personnel, the troops will participate in a reality-based field exercise by trying to establish a buffer zone between two feuding countries.</p>
<p>U.S. Army Special Forces units are providing support teams as advisers and translators for the multi-national forces.</p>
<p>During the programme officers from the 20 participating nations, plus officers from Armenia, Austria, Azerbaijan and Sweden, will join NATO officers from Denmark, France, Germany and Italy for a staff officers programme at the Peacekeeping Institute in Carlisle, Pennsylvania and the School of Americas at Fort Benning, Georgia.</p>
<p>Similar training exercises were held at Fort Polk in 1995 and Camp LeJeune, North Carolina, last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT POLK, La"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
