<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66754" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Bucharest mayor slams school start amid epidemic.</title>
<headline>Bucharest mayor slams school start amid epidemic.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The mayor of Bucharest threatened on Friday to sue Romania's education ministry over a decision to start the new school year next week despite a meningitis epidemic which has killed 39 people.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as the cause of the epidemic remains unkown and sanitary conditions in schools are bad the new (school) year must not start,&quot; Bucharest general mayor Victor Ciorbea told a news conference.</p>
<p>Education Minister Liviu Maior said earlier his ministry had decided that classes should resume next Monday. The epidemic, which began at the end of July, has stricken more than 450 people including 53 children across Romania.</p>
<p>Ciorbea said Bucharest city hall would sue the education ministry unless it withdrew its order. He said the decision was illegal and the city had issued a decree ordering schools to remain closed until October 1 to allow for thorough sanitation checks.</p>
<p>&quot;The municipal laws are very clear: in case of a disaster or an epidemic it is for the mayor to decide on matters concerning public institutions, schools included,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Starting classes is a big risk as neither the cause nor the way the disease is spreading is known.&quot;</p>
<p>Meningitis is usually spread through poor hygiene. Inquiries so far revealed that 55 schools in Bucharest had badly-damaged sewers and three had no sewers at all.</p>
<p>The health ministry sent test samples for identification to Britain's Collindale Institute after experts from Pasteur Institute of France failed to identify the virus which triggered the epidemic.</p>
<p>Ciorbea said Bucharest allocated 1.0 billion lei ($310,000) last week for an emergency programme to improve hygiene in schools.</p>
<p>The viral disease, which has spread to nearly half of Romania with most cases registered in Bucharest, affects the gastro-intestinal tract and causes high fever, headaches and vomiting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
