<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="667658" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German auto group sees 1997 registrations up 1 pct.</title>
<headline>German auto group sees 1997 registrations up 1 pct.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top official of the VDA German automobile manufacturers' association said on Tuesday in a radio interview that he expected about one percent growth in new vehicle registrations in Germany for 1997.</p>
<p>VDA manager Kunibert Schmidt told Germany's Saar radio that registrations for the first five months of the year were down about five percent but that sales should recover in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>He also said the VDA expected registrations next year to rise about three percent. But he said the predictions depended on what the German government did about tax reform, particulary in view of calls by some politicans for a higher oil tax.</p>
<p>&quot;Our positive expectations for the second half of the year and for the coming year are very dependent on what happens in Bonn in terms of taxes,&quot; Schmidt said.</p>
<p>He said a survey by the VDA showed 75 percent of those surveyed were against Bonn raising oil taxes as part of its bid to plug deficit holes and qualify for European monetary union, which is scheduled to begin in January 1999.</p>
<p>Schmidt said any increase in the energy tax would curb vehicle sales.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
