<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="667893" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FINNISH GOVERNMENT SEEN STUDYING NESTE-IVO MERGER.</title>
<headline>FINNISH GOVERNMENT SEEN STUDYING NESTE-IVO MERGER.</headline>
<byline>Peter Starck</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A cautiously worded statement by the Finnish ministry of trade and industry about studying the joint development of state-owned power groups Neste Oy and Imatran Voima Oy (IVO) led to merger speculation on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The ministry said in a statement it would undertake a review to &quot;evaluate the options for broadening the shareholder base and the structural alternatives for joint development of the two companies.&quot;</p>
<p>It referred to oil, chemicals and energy group Neste and power producer IVO.</p>
<p>The state owns 84 percent of Neste and all of IVO. A partial floatation of IVO has been expected. The government has an authorisation by parliament to cut its stakes in both companies to 50.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Neste and IVO together have core competencies across the whole energy chain,&quot; Neste said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The combined strengths of the companies will offer maximum access to growth opportunities in the Nordic region, Russia and the Baltic area and will allow a significant position to be built in the gas and electricity markets of North and central Europe,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Neste President Jukka Viinanen told Reuters by telephone that a merger was one option under investigation.</p>
<p>&quot;Our perception is that a merger is one option being investigated here,&quot; he said. &quot;We feel it would be good for shareholders,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Asked what other options than a merger would be studied, Viinanen gave no details but said: &quot;what point would there be in a context of this scale to create smaller units?&quot;</p>
<p>IVO CEO Heikki Marttinen said he saw some potential synergies from a merger.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that there could be synergies in some areas, but also there are clearly areas where there would not be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Underlining they had hardly any facts to rely on, share analysts took a cautiously positive approach.</p>
<p>&quot;A merger can certainly not be ruled out although the operations of the groups' operations differ so much,&quot; said Visa Manninen, analyst at Carnegie Securities, adding it was unusual to merge an oil and a nuclear power company.</p>
<p>Aktia Bank analyst Henry Kallio said the owners' intention was probably to create a stronger entity. &quot;One can safely discount a bigger cashflow for Neste in the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is positive for Neste ... future earnings expectations can be improved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Aktia's neutral recommendation on Neste would stand since &quot;we have nothing concrete yet,&quot; Kallio added.</p>
<p>Neste's Viinanen said combining IVO and Neste would create a bigger group than Swedish Vattenfall, but it would remain smaller than Norsk Hydro and some German rivals measured by assets.</p>
<p>At end-1996, Neste's balance sheet total was 31.6 billion markka and IVO's 28.2 billion. Neste's 1996 net sales were 43.4 billion markka asnd IVO's 12.1 billion.</p>
<p>The ministry's review is scheduled to be completed by the end of August.</p>
<p>Neste's share initially rose when trade started after a suspension pending the afternoon announcement. It hit a 15-week high 145.00 markka, up 7.00 markka or five percent, but later closed at 138.50 markka, up 0.50.</p>
<p>--Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 245, news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
