<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="667901" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FOCUS-DUTCH PTT PLANS 1998 SPLIT,SEPARATE LISTINGS.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-DUTCH PTT PLANS 1998 SPLIT,SEPARATE LISTINGS.</headline>
<byline>Keiron Henderson</byline>
<dateline>THE HAGUE 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Koninklijke PTT Nederland (KPN) said on Tuesday it planned to list its telecoms and postal units separately in the first half of 1998, freeing them up to pursue their own markets independently.</p>
<p>The company said the move was a logical step following the rapid development of both businesses after a phased privatisation in 1994 and 1995 which has left the Dutch government with a minority holding of around 45 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If ever there was a small synergy between Post and Telecom it's decreasing, and there is no overlap,&quot; KPN chairman Wim Dik said in a telephone interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>KPN said in a statement that existing and potential synergies were not considered crucial to the business strategies of PTT Post and PTT Telecom, adding the split would widen strategic opportunities and make the valuation of the shares more transparent.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the KPN umbrella, Post and Telecom were already very independent, so the step from that to full independence and minding your own business isn't such a big step,&quot; Dik said.</p>
<p>PTT Post, with 1996 sales of 13.5 billion guilders ($6.9 billion), grabbed the headlines last year with a 2.7 billion guilder takeover of the Australian express delivery service TNT Ltd, while PTT Telecom, with 1996 sales of 14.3 billion guilders, is gearing itself up for the complete liberalisation of its domestic telecommunications market next month.</p>
<p>In the international arena, PTT Telecom has recently announced plans to merge its international networks with those of its partners in the Unisource alliance -- Telia of Sweden and Swiss Telecom PTT.</p>
<p>Dik said the split reflected the very different growth potentials in the postal and telecoms markets.</p>
<p>&quot;You just cannot go and buy a whole telecoms operator, you have to do alliances...whereas we could buy a worldwide successful carrier like TNT in one go by putting down less than three billion guilders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dik said a proposal would be put to the 1997 annual meeting early in 1998, after which another shareholders' meeting would be called to approve the split.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a proposal submitted to break up the company on the basis of a certain balance division and cost division. We will show two separate companies with their own accounts.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dutch state would need to give its consent to the split as holder of a special share in KPN, although Dik said the group did not specifically need its go-ahead otherwise.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the Dutch Finance Ministry said it had no comment on what it planned to do with its remaining 45 percent holding in KPN.</p>
<p>&quot;It's our vision that we should have a separate listing for Post and Telecom in the coming spring. The shareholder with a KPN share gets the possibility to get a Post and a Telecom share if he wishes. I don't know whether it will be one to one, that's something that is to be seen in the future,&quot; Dik said.</p>
<p>He said creating the two listings would generate value for shareholders and noted analysts had speculated the two shares together could be worth more than a single KPN share, although he declined to give his view on analysts' conjecture.</p>
<p>&quot;They (shareholders) will benefit by having two dedicated companies, people focused on their own goals and their own shareholder value. It focuses people better when they really fight for their own companies in the open market, judged by the market and the stock exchange,&quot; said Dik.</p>
<p>KPN said late last year it would review its structure with a view to a split. It has said it felt no need to hurry a decision which it had given itself until the end of 1997 to make.</p>
<p>Asked whether KPN had brought the decision forward Dik replied: &quot;We think we went through the review quickly and carefully. We know that those two companies diverge more and more. Knowing that, and having the reputation as a management board which is proactive we'd rather do it now, although we could have waited another another year or two.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts welcomed the news as a positive step, while the shares gained 3.20 guilders or 4.20 percent, to 78.90 guilders on a mainly lower Amsterdam bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd expect the demerger to add modest value to the group, giving greater focus to the attractions of PTT post which is likely to achieve a greater multiple than KPN currently stands on. European investors tend to like restructuring stories and this is one of them,&quot; said Paul Norris of Lehman Brothers.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000, Fax +31 20 504 5040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE HAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
