<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="667982" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sterling firmer against generally softer mark.</title>
<headline>Sterling firmer against generally softer mark.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sterling was higher against the mark, buoyed by the German unit's weakness in the wake of the European Union's agreement on a stability pact aimed at ensuring the planned start of monetary union in 1999. &quot;The main story is the mark and its weakness on the European crosses after the stability pact agreement gave a helping hand to sterling,&quot; said Adam Cole, economist at HSBC James Capel.</p>
<p>The agreement on a stability pact, hammered out by EU leaders on Monday at their summit in Amsterdam - which concludes today - is aimed at budget discipline after EMU begins.</p>
<p>Analysts said the agreement, which included a resolution on jobs and growth creation in Europe, increased the risk of a soft single currency.</p>
<p>Sterling was little moved by public sector borrowing data showing the PSBR was above forecasts in May. The PSBR hit 3.96 billion pounds, compared with market forecasts for a 2.9 billion shortfall.</p>
<p>At 1045 GMT the pound was at 2.8390/00, up from 2.8295/05 in late European trading on Monday.</p>
<p>But the pound's tone was consolidative after it revisited 57-month peaks above 2.84 marks on Monday. Traders said no great shakes were expected ahead of the UK budget on July 2.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks a little tired, frankly, up here,&quot; said Simon Cook, head of trading at Co-operative Bank in London, adding that he expected an attack on trendline support around 2.8180/8200 marks.</p>
<p>The pound's upside against the dollar was limited by the generally firmer dollar. Cable was at $1.6355/65 against $1.6349/54 in late Europe on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Astrid Zweynert London newsroom + 44 171 542 7792</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
