<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="668052" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Carpetright confident of further progress.</title>
<headline>Carpetright confident of further progress.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Carpetright Plc, one of Britain's leading carpet retailers, on Tuesday reported a 28 percent increase in profits for last year and said trading had been satisfactory since May, the start of its current financial year.</p>
<p>The group said it expected to at least maintain an improvement in gross margins during the coming year. Chairman and chief executive Lord Harris said the group was confident of further progress over the next 12 months.  </p>
<p>Lord Harris said, &quot;With a prosperous economy and an improving housing market, we are confident of further market progress over the next 12 months.&quot;</p>
<p>The group boosted sales by 26 percent to 233.9 million pounds ($382.7 million), and increased its dividend by 31 percent to 19.0 pence a share.</p>
<p>Sales benefited from a slightly stronger market, but trading conditions weakened in the run up to Britain's general election on May 1.</p>
<p>The company aims to have a 30 percent share of the UK market in the next few years. It currently trades from 210 stores and plans to open 20 more in the next year. It's target is for 260 stores in mainland Britain, plus 10 in Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>During the year the company also expanded its Carpet Depot format, which had 57 stores by the end of the financial year. ($ = 0.611 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
