<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="668212" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK democrats suffer fresh setbacks before handover.</title>
<headline>HK democrats suffer fresh setbacks before handover.</headline>
<byline>Peter Humphrey</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's democracy movement suffered fresh setbacks on Tuesday when authorities blocked plans to stage the first pro-democracy rally under Chinese rule and the future government acted to dilute freedoms.</p>
<p>At the same time China put its army on alert, and Hong Kong people showed ebbing political confidence as they faced the reality of Chinese rule -- two weeks away.</p>
<p>At midnight on June 30 the British Union Jack will be furled away, Prince Charles will hand Hong Kong back to China's President Jiang Zemin, and the red flag of Communist China will be hoisted, marking an end to 156 years of colonial rule.</p>
<p>The Urban Council rejected a request by the Alliance in Support of the Patriotic Democratic Movement in China to stage a rally in Victoria Park, named after Britain's late empress.</p>
<p>&quot;You can imagine that's a purely, you know, a kind of political censorship, (to) try to block the Alliance to use Victoria Park (for) a rally,&quot; said Fred Li, a councillor and legislator of the popular Democratic Party.</p>
<p>Future leader Tung Chee-hwa, appointed by China, sparked fresh suspicions by announcing changes to the lower tiers of government in a further rollback for democracy.</p>
<p>Tung, who takes over on July 1, unveiled measures to dilute the presence of pro-democracy politicians in local government by appointing extra pro-China figures to local councils.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Tung has put the old story back. It is a very bad message to the whole world that Hong Kong is going backward in terms of democracy,&quot; said Yeung Sum, vice chairman of the Democratic Party, the biggest party in the old legislature.</p>
<p>The changes complement plans to replace the elected Legislative Council with an interim China-appointed body.</p>
<p>The interim legislature, which will govern Hong Kong until elections promised within the next year, has become a flashpoint of controversy between China and local democrats and Western nations objecting to the rollback of democracy.</p>
<p>China meanwhile has put its three-million-strong People's Liberation Army and police force on high alert against unrest in the run-up to the Hong Kong handover.</p>
<p>The People's Liberation Army, the paramilitary People's Armed Police, police and security agents have gone on high alert in Beijing and in other parts of China in case of ethnic unrest or internal instability, reports from Beijing said.</p>
<p>&quot;The authorities are worried the jobless and the democracy movement will create trouble,&quot; one source there said.</p>
<p>Beijing regards the handover as one of the events of the year -- if not of the century -- for China, and the official China Daily carried a banner headline on Tuesday promising the &quot;Best Welcome Home Party Ever&quot; for the night of the handover.</p>
<p>However, a survey of Hong Kong people's feelings on the changeover highlighted worries about corruption and restrictions on political freedom, tempering their economic optimism.</p>
<p>The confidence survey was carried out for the Baptist University of Hong Kong, which is tracking shifting attitudes on the handover.</p>
<p>&quot;Political pessimism this time seems to have risen over the survey in February,&quot; political analyst Michael DeGolyer said.</p>
<p>The survey also underlined the division between economic and political confidence, with two-thirds of people confident about their economic future but uncertain about their political fate.</p>
<p>The findings confirm a prevailing attitude of &quot;doom and boom&quot; in Hong Kong, DeGolyer said, with the stock market hitting dizzy new highs and China-related &quot;red chip&quot; stocks roaring ahead on handover optimism while political confidence slides.</p>
<p>China's Foreign Minister Qian Qichen showed Beijing was unruffled by a British-American boycott of a July 1 ceremony to swear in the appointed provisional legislature.</p>
<p>&quot;It is their own business as to whether they attend or not,&quot; he told the South China Morning Post, adding that he hoped to see a new start in Sino-British relations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
