<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="668556" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel foreign currency reform agreed -Netanyahu.</title>
<headline>Israel foreign currency reform agreed -Netanyahu.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime</p>
<p>Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Tuesday an agreement had been reached with Bank of Israel Governor Jacob Frenkel and Finance Minister Dan Meridor on a foreign currency reform.</p>
<p>In remarks broadcast on Israel Radio he said an additional budget cut had also been agreed during a marathon all-night meeting at Caesarea. But no decision had been reached yet on the thorny issue of widening the shekel's trading band and Netanyahu said talks would continue later on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;We agreed on a series of</p>
<p>steps...The first of which, and the important one, is the far-reaching reform on all foreign currency matters. This matter will touch every citizen in Israel, institutional elements, businesses and citizens,&quot; Netanyahu said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to make a great revolution that will really allow freedom in all foreign currency matters,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The second issue that we agreed was about another cut in the budget in order to achieve the deficit goal we set ourselves,&quot; Netanyahu said.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget already includes a reduction of seven billion shekels.</p>
<p>The prime minister did not specify the size of the new cut but Israel Radio reported it would be 600 million shekels.</p>
<p>&quot;One issue remains and we will continue to discuss it today in order to finalise it,&quot; Netanyahu said.</p>
<p>When asked whether the remaining issue was the policy of foreign exchange Netanyahu said: &quot;Those are issues connected to a number of things, I prefer not to get into them now. We will continue discussing them today in order to finalise them.&quot;</p>
<p>($1 = 3.42 shekels)</p>
<p>-Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
