<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="668613" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Tracor Aerospace and Saudi AEC in deals.</title>
<headline>Tracor Aerospace and Saudi AEC in deals.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tracor Aerospace, a unit of Tracor Inc, and the Saudi-based economic offset company Advanced Electronics Co have entered into licensing agreements for AEC to make and sell chaff and flare countermeasures, AEC said.</p>
<p>In a statement, AEC said the agreements cover RR-170 and RR-180 chaff and MJU-7, MJU-10 and M-206 flare expendables used on F-5, F-15, F-16, C-130 and other aircraft and helicopters.</p>
<p>&quot;The 10 year agreements provide AEC with exclusive manufacturing rights in Saudi Arabia and exclusive sales rights in the GCC. It is expected the regional sales will exceed $30 million over the next five years,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The GCC (Gulf Cooperation Council) is made up of Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Kuwait, Oman, Qatar and Bahrain.</p>
<p>Chaff countermeasures are strands of radar reflective material which create a diversionary target for attacking missiles and other radar-guided threats, AEC said.</p>
<p>Flare countermeasures are pieces of heat-emitting material which, when ejected from an aircraft, create a diversionary target for infra-red-guided threats.</p>
<p>Under the agreements, AEC will use equipment supplied by Tracor to make and customise products in Riyadh.</p>
<p>&quot;It is estimated that the Gulf region has a combined total of over 800 tactical fighters, cargo aircraft and helicopters that utilise countermeasures,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The AEC-Tracor agreements are subject to final review and approval by the companies' respective governments, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
