<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="668823" id="root" date="1997-06-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Nemtsov's snub mars EU trade chief's Moscow visit.</title>
<headline>Nemtsov's snub mars EU trade chief's Moscow visit.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian First Deputy Prime Minister Boris Nemtsov refused to meet the European Union's top trade official on Tuesday in protest at EU anti-dumping measures against Russian pipe and tube manufacturers, officials said.</p>
<p>Nemtsov's snub came as Trade Commissioner Leon Brittan ended a two-day visit aimed at promoting Russian membership of the World Trade Organisation, the body that supervises trade accords and provides a negotiating forum for new agreements.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a shame that Mr. Nemtsov has not had the opportunity of putting his concerns to me in an honest, manful way, face-to-face, rather than engage in this kind of boycott,&quot; Brittan told a news conference in the Russian capital.</p>
<p>An aide to Nemtsov, who is a leading economic liberal, said the meeting was scrapped in reaction to the EU slapping import duties on non-alloy steel and iron pipes to stop alleged dumping by Russia of such goods at below-market prices in Europe.</p>
<p>The EU applied provisional anti-dumping duties on May 29 of 32.9 percent against Russian producers of the pipes, which are used in oil and gas pipelines.</p>
<p>Russian officials are also irritated by Europe's designation of Russia as a &quot;non-market&quot; economy in its anti-dumping proceedures. Brittan said he proposed changing that status as soon as Russia became a WTO member.</p>
<p>In meetings with other Russian government officials and parliamentarians, the European Commission vice- president said he had emphasised that European policy sought to reach out to Russia, not act against it.</p>
<p>Brittan said: &quot;98.9 percent of Russian goods reach the European market without any kind of impediment of this sort. That, therefore, shows that trade is not substantially affected and I think it is very misleading to pretend to the contrary.&quot;</p>
<p>Brittan was also scheduled to hold talks with Nemtsov's fellow first deputy premier, Anatoly Chubais. Russian officials said late on Tuesday afternoon that the two had not yet met.</p>
<p>Chubais, in charge of economic reforms since March, has led Russia's intensified efforts to join a series of world economic bodies including the Paris Club of creditors, the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) and the WTO.</p>
<p>Russian membership in these organisations is expected to be a central focus of President Boris Yeltsin's talks at the G7 summit of the world's richest nations in Denver this week.</p>
<p>The WTO has 131 members. Neither Russia nor China are members. Chubais has said he expects Russia to join by the end of 1998.</p>
<p>Responding to charges that the EU has discriminated against Russia in trade matters, Brittan said: &quot;If you are talking about discrimination, it is interesting that the average European tariff is four percent and the Russian tariff vis-a-vis European products is 19 percent, so who is discriminating?&quot;</p>
<p>About 40 percent of Russia's imports and exports are to the European Union, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We make no complaints because, of course, the state of the Russian economy is very different and we are trying to help it to develop,&quot; added Brittan, a former British cabinet minister.</p>
<p>The International Federation of the Phonographic Industry, the recording industry lobby, has complained about widespread sales of illegal compact discs in Russia and said Moscow should not be let into the WTO without action against music piracy.</p>
<p>Brittan said he did not agree with &quot;making threats of that kind&quot;, but said he had proposed a plan for the Russian government to protect intellectual property.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
