<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="668935" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK -- Jobless claims, Philadelphia Fed.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK -- Jobless claims, Philadelphia Fed.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The weekly jobless claims report and the Philadelphia Federal Reserve's June survey headline the economic data that the U.S. government securities market must digest on Thursday, analysts said.</p>
<p>U.S. trade figures for April are scheduled for release near the start of the trading session. Their impact on the Treasury market will probably be limited, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The currency markets will watch the trade data more closely than we will,&quot; said Patrick Dimick, Treasury market strategist at UBS Securities.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our market has had a bit of a disconnect with the dollar recently,&quot; said Dimick, observing that the U.S. unit has undergone a &quot;massive depreciation&quot; since early May while the Treasury market has rallied.</p>
<p>&quot;The April trade data will let economists fine tune their GDP (Gross Domestic Product) estimates, but they won't tell you a lot about what happened to domestic demand, which is what matters,&quot; Dimick said.  </p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters estimated, on average, that the U.S. trade gap widened to $10.0 billion in April from $8.51 billion in March.</p>
<p>After seeing two weeks of higher jobless claims numbers, economists polled by Reuters estimated, on average, that new claims dropped to 333,000 in the week ended June 14 from 339,000 a week earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;We had two weeks of higher claims and we're looking for the number to come down this time,&quot; said James Glassman, senior economist at Chase Securities Inc.  </p>
<p>Glassman said he expected claims for the week ended June 14 to fall to 320,000.</p>
<p>&quot;I would take notice if they run higher,&quot; he said, adding that a strong industrial sector should keep claims low.</p>
<p>Glassman said even though domestic demand has slowed, the industrial sector remains strong because of strong demand for U.S. exports and because businesses are building inventories.</p>
<p>&quot;If spending remains as soft as it has been, the industrial sector will start to slow, but there's no reason to expect that to happen yet,&quot; said Glassman.  </p>
<p>Dimick said the Philadelphia Fed's survey of business conditions in its region will be important to the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy hit the skids in March through May,&quot; said Dimick. &quot;That's old news to th emarket now. What we need to concentrate and focus on right now is how strongly will the economy rebound in the summer after the spring downshift. We might get a hint to that answer in the Philly Fed report.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists forecast a 7.3 reading on the Philadelphia Fed survey, up from a reading of 1.6 in May.  </p>
<p>After the Philadelphia Fed survey, the only news the market will get on June are the privately collected weekly chain store sales indices and U.S. jobless claims figures for the week ended June 21.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a long pause after the Philadelphia Fed report before we get more June data,&quot; said Dimick.</p>
<p>&quot;Then you have to wait for the holiday-shortened first week of July, when we get unit car and chain store sales, to get a better picture of consumer demand in June,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond ended at 99-6/32, up 14/32 to yield 6.69 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers indicated that Fed funds would open at 5-1/2 percent on Thursday.</p>
<p>(( -- North American Treasury Desk 212-859-1679))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
