<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="668943" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Opponents appealing PECO securitization.</title>
<headline>Opponents appealing PECO securitization.</headline>
<dateline>HARRISBURG, Pa. 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>State consumer and environmental groups said Wednesday they are appealing a Pennsylvania Pubic Utiliy Commission decisison that allows PECO Energy Co to securitize $1.1 billion of stranded costs.</p>
<p>On May 22, the commission ruled that the electric utility could refinance $1.1 billion of costs over the next ten years by issuing transitional bonds.</p>
<p>PECO is seeking to securitize a total of $6.8 billion and had requested that this be done in two equal tranches.  </p>
<p>State Senator Vincent J. Fumo, a Philadelphia Democrat, IPALCO Enterprises Inc, Philadelphia area consumer organizations and state environmental groups each filed four separate appeals of the commission's decision in Commonwealth Court Wednesday, Fumo spokesman Gary Tuma said.</p>
<p>The appeal will most likely prevent PECO from sailing transition bonds to refinance its unprofitable investments until the case is disposed of, the filers' statement said.</p>
<p>It said they believe allowing PECO to add stranded costs onto customer's bills violates the standards of Pennsylvania's deregulations law.  </p>
<p>They said it also negates the financial advantage customers might find in switching generation companies, thereby delaying the benefits of competition for 10 years.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the decision was neither just and reasonable nor in the public interests,&quot; Fumo said. &quot;It would deny electricity consumers the primary benefits of the deregulation law that was enacted last year.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Giving PECO the right to continue charging customers even if they switch to another company inhibits competition,&quot; said John Hodowal, IPALCO chairman.  </p>
<p>&quot;It will adversely affect the ability of other electric companies to compete against PECO for customers in Southeastern Pennsylvania.&quot;</p>
<p>Although PECO customers would receive a 1 percent rate reduction under the commission's ruling, that savings pales in comparison to what they might save by choosing to their own supplier without having to pay PECO, the statement claimed.</p>
<p>It noted the utility had requested the right to securitize $3.7 billion and said it plans to seek commission approval of more than $3 billion in additional securitization later.</p>
<p>The commission acted under an expedited, 120-day process, reviewing the PECO request before the company submitted its overall rate restructuring filing required by the new law.</p>
<p>In making its decision, the commissioners ignored their own administrative law judge, Louis Cocheres, the statement pointed out.</p>
<p>He recommended PECO's request be denied and had stated that the process was &quot;fundamentally unfair to the customers, which violates the statute,&quot; and &quot;there is an insufficient record upon which to base a well-reasoned decision.&quot;</p>
<p>Cocheres further noted: &quot;PECO failed to demonstrate that it had reasonably mitigated its stranded costs in compliance with the Act.&quot;</p>
<p>Alan Barak, attorney representing the statewide environmental groups, said the &quot;groups were hoping the PUC would provide electric customers the price break they deserve and at the same time help improve air quality.  We have no choice but to ask the courts, in the public interest, to overturn the PUC decision.&quot;</p>
<p>Fumo pointed out that the PECO case is the first that the PUC has reviewed under the electric competition act.</p>
<p>&quot;In filing this appeal, we hope to have the courts establish that consumers are entitled to the financial benefits of marketplace competition in the electric industry. That was the way the law was presented to the public when it was before the General Assembly, and I'm not going to allow the PUC to turn it into a corporate welfare program for big utility companies, at least not without a fight.&quot;</p>
<p>The Philadelphia area consumer groups who have opposed PECO's securitization request are: Consumers Educational Protective Association, Tenants Action Group and Action Alliance of Senior Citizens.</p>
<p>The Pennsylvania environmental organizations are:  the Council for Clean Air, the Sierra Club, Citizen Action, the Pennsylvania Public Interest Research Group, the Grass Roots Alliance for a Solar Pennsylvania, Philadelphia Solar Energy Association, Trout Unlimited and the Nonprofit Energy Savings Investment Program.</p>
<p>Fumo and two of the Philadelphia groups also have a separate case before Commonwealth Court seeking to have the deregulation act declared unconstitutional due to the method by which it passed the Legislature.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARRISBURG, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
