<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="669065" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FRENCH SOCCER STAR IN COURT FOR INDECENT EXPOSURE.</title>
<headline>FRENCH SOCCER STAR IN COURT FOR INDECENT EXPOSURE.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A state prosecutor on Wednesday asked a court to give French soccer international Patrice Loko a suspended eight-month sentence on charges of indecent exposure and damaging property.</p>
<p>The 27-year-old Paris-Saint-Germain forward ran amok two years ago, kicking cars outside a Paris nightclub, insulting and spitting at police who arrested him and repeatedly exposing his genitals to a policewoman.</p>
<p>An embarrassed Loko told the Paris court he did not remember anything from what French media called his &quot;crazy night&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I still cannot understand how this happened. I want to apologise,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Loko's lawyer said a prison term, even suspended, could lead to the revocation of his player's licence.</p>
<p>Policemen testified that Loko had boasted that high-placed friends would rapidly get him out of the police station, compared his huge income to their salaries and poured abuse on them.</p>
<p>&quot;In 18 years as a policeman, I had never been so insulted. I could not sleep for two days,&quot; one policeman said.</p>
<p>PSG Chairman Jean-Francois Domergue, testifying in his players's favour, said Loko, who won his 26th international cap for France against England on June 7, had since changed his ways.</p>
<p>The prosecutor asked the court to order Loko to compensate victims and submit to regular medical and psychiatric tests.</p>
<p>&quot;A star athlete should serve as a model for young people,&quot; prosecutor Odile Faivre said. But she admitted that the death of Loko's young son in December 1992 could explain his behaviour.</p>
<p>Tests conducted by police showed Loko had not consumed any alcohol or taken any drugs on the night of his rampage. The results of psychiatric examinations were also normal.</p>
<p>The court will give its verdict on June 25.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
