<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="669023" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Market off but maybe not for long.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Market off but maybe not for long.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stocks were suffering from some long-delayed profit-taking Wednesday but options analysts and traders said the pressure may not last.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's attempting to go down and it will probably fail once again,&quot; said one options dealer in Chicago. &quot;There's some profit-taking.&quot;</p>
<p>He said a moderate exercise of S&amp;P 100 index .OEX call options Tuesday may have put pressure on the market. Nearly 2,000 OEX calls were exercised Tuesday</p>
<p>&quot;It's been an awfully good rally and it looks like people are waiting to buy,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>By about 1115 CDT/1615 GMT, the bellwether Dow industrial average .DJI was down 44 points at about 7,717.</p>
<p>The broader S&amp;P 500 index .SPX was off 5.35 at 889.07 and September S&amp;P 500 futures lost 4.55 to 898.20.</p>
<p>The spot OEX index fell 5.20 to 867.68.</p>
<p>Michael Schwartz, a managing director at Oppenheimer &amp; Co, said it was early to tell whether this week's expiration of June options would put upside or downside pressure on the market.</p>
<p>But he noted that the heaviest open interest in S&amp;P 500 options was in in-the-money calls, a potentially bullish sign.  </p>
<p>&quot;The biggest open interest is all in deep in-the-money calls on the SPX,&quot; he said. &quot;If this statistic maintains itself into Thursday night, it bodes well for a big buy imbalance on the opening&quot; Friday.</p>
<p>OEX options are American-style, which means they can be exercised any time up to expiration but SPX options are European-style, which means they can only be exercised at expiration.</p>
<p>If a lot of deep in-the-money SPX calls remain open through Thursday's close, chances are good they will be exercised Friday morning, which could push the market higher.  </p>
<p>Some investors exercising Friday morning would likely have to buy stock or futures because they would not be covered &quot;or don't want to lose their stock,&quot; said Harrison Roth, a first vice president at Cowen &amp; Co.</p>
<p>He added that typically, whatever happens in the market on an expiration Friday is reversed the following Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I never know what's going to happen but I have a good idea this time,&quot; he said. &quot;There's going to be huge volume.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders have noted that open interest in OEX, SPX and SPX futures options remains fairly high ahead of the expiration, which could boost volume and which some view as bullish.  </p>
<p>The dealer in Chicago said much of Wednesday's major index activity was linked to the expiration.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got some squaring up going on before the expiration,&quot; he said. &quot;Usually it happends on Wednesday now, maybe Thursday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;By Friday, everything will be fairly quiet.&quot;</p>
<p>((Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
