<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="669117" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-YANKEES CF BERNIE WILLIAMS PLACED ON DISABLED LIST.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-YANKEES CF BERNIE WILLIAMS PLACED ON DISABLED LIST.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York Yankees centre fielder Bernie Williams, originally expected to miss only the three-game series with the cross-town rival Mets, Tuesday was placed on the 15-day disabled list with a strained left hamstring.</p>
<p>Williams, who said he &quot;felt something pop&quot; while running out a groundball in the ninth inning of the Yankees' 6-5 loss to Florida Sunday night, will be sidelined for the rest of the month.</p>
<p>The Most Valuable Player of the 1996 American League Championship Series (ALCS), Williams is hitting .317 with 10 homers and 50 RBI in 66 games.</p>
<p>The 28-year-old switch-hitter enjoyed a breakout season in helping the Yankees win the World Series last season. In 1996 he posed career highs with 108 runs, 168 hits, 29 homers and 102 RBI while batting .305.</p>
<p>Williams hit .474 (9-for-19) with two homers and six RBI in the Yankees' five-game ALCS victory over Baltimore that propelled New York into the World Series against Atlanta.</p>
<p>The only player in baseball history to homer from both sides of the plate in the same post-season game, Williams did it for a second time in Game 4 of the first-round playoff series against Texas last season.</p>
<p>He first accomplished the feat against Seattle in Game 3 of the 1995 playoffs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
