<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="669145" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICA IMPORTS OF ZIMBABWE, ZAMBIA MAIZE SEEN UP.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICA IMPORTS OF ZIMBABWE, ZAMBIA MAIZE SEEN UP.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>An expected rise in maize production in Zimbabwe and Zambia, coupled with fewer trade and tariff barriers in Southern Africa, was seen lifting grain imports into South Africa, a conference heard on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Hamish McBain, a director of milling group Tiger Oats Ltd told a maize industry conference that both Zimbabwe and Zambia had the potential to substantially increase maize output over time.</p>
<p>&quot;I see no reason why Zimbabwe and Zambia cannot each produce five million tonnes, although that is something that will happen gradually over time,&quot; McBain told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said that Zimbabwe's average yield per hectare was much higher than that in South Africa, the region's biggest maize producer. As Zimbabwe's exports had never been subsidised as had ocurred in South Africa, consumer prices were also far cheaper.</p>
<p>Possible boons for Zambian maize production growth was a far less erratic climate than South Africa and the availability of large tracts of unused arable land.</p>
<p>At the same time pressure was mounting for the dismantling of trade barriers in the region, enabling the free movement of goods and services between Southern African countries, McBain said.</p>
<p>The 12-member South African Development Community (SADC), to which all three countries belong, last September approved a trade protocol which aims to phase in a free trade area within eight years.  </p>
<p>&quot;Although especially Zambia has not been a good export market in the past...once the South African market is opened up to them, it will become viable for them to produce more than they need. We can therefore look to the likelihood of increased maize imports,&quot; McBain said.</p>
<p>He said that South Africa was likely in future to increase its export of maize in grain form and, especially as, value-added maize products. These could include maize grits for beer brewing to markets in Asia and the Middle East, starches and glucose and speciality meat and dairy products.</p>
<p>Latest forecasts from SADC's food security unit estimate that Zimbabwe, the region's second largest producer after South Africa, will produce a crop of 2.195 million tonnes in the 1996/1997 maize year. This is down 16 percent on last year's harvest following excessive rains.</p>
<p>SADC expects Zambia to produce only 960,000 tonnes, well below last year's 1.41 million tonnes after flooding and a shortage of fertiliser damaged crops. </p>
<p>SADC's estimate for South Africa's 1996/97 maize harvest is 8.21 million tonnes.</p>
<p>-- Nicole Mordant, Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
