<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="66953" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico studying municipal bonds for water projects.</title>
<headline>Mexico studying municipal bonds for water projects.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kozak</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aiming to solve the problem of weak financing for Mexico's water treatment plants, government officials and private sector experts are studying a plan that would allow local governments to issue bonds.</p>
<p>There are a number of daunting barriers to overcome, however, including a lack of standardized financial information, officials said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is something that we are working on. There has been a group formed in the bank to see if these (water) organizations can place bonds in the future...,&quot; said Alfredo Navarrete Martinez, the associate director of finances for Banco Nacional de Obras y Servicios Publicos, also known as Banobras.</p>
<p>Banobras is the Mexican development bank charged with providing long-term credits and support to infrastructure projects, including water treatment.</p>
<p>Mexico has decentralized its water and waste-water treatment authorities over the past few years into &quot;organismos de aqua,&quot; which are run mainly by states and municipalities.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank has been looking at this from the start as a medium- and long-term project. We don't believe that we can succeed in three or six months, rather it is something that will take more time,&quot; Navarrete said in an interview.</p>
<p>The aim is help municipalities reduce their financing costs, and allow markets to make a realistic evaluation of the risk of lending to the municipalities.</p>
<p>The development bank is looking at a number of issues, such as whether demand for the paper would be great enough to ensure liquidity, and whether the bonds might be able to have tax free status such as many municipal bonds do in the United States.  </p>
<p>At the moment, the most likely paper that would be issued would be medium-term, about three years to begin with, an official with Banobras said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are half-way through. One thing that will help is the Afores, (the planned private pension plan) next year,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Also it is important to look at tax implications. The way we have seen it in the United States, is that it is attractive for certain investors. That is something we are exploring as well. It is not just issuing the paper,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There are other issues that have been raised as well.</p>
<p>For example, only 10 to 20 of the Mexican water organizations would likely meet the criteria to have their debt rated, one recent report said.</p>
<p>There are also legal roadblocks to having states or local governments issue foreign denominated debt, but some suggestions, such as the creation of trusts, have been put forward that might allow borrowers to skirt those barriers.</p>
<p>Various federal ministries would also have to sign on.</p>
<p>There are other potential difficulties to overcome.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we have found is that there isn't standardized information about the public finances of the municipalities,&quot; said Navarrete.</p>
<p>What is clear is that there is a need for this type of financing, though.</p>
<p>&quot;We have supported the (bond) proposal, and we think that it one of the best options for financing, which is one of our main problems, along with high interest rates,&quot; said Ricardo Garza Blanc, president of the industry umbrella group, Empresas de Agua y Saneamiento de Mexico, which represents about 320 water groups in Mexico.</p>
<p>-- Mexico City newsroom (525) 728 9559. E-mail at robert.kozak@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020045">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
