<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="669607" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: TVK sees further room for price rise.</title>
<headline>TVK sees further room for price rise.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian chemicals company TVK Rt said on Wednesday the shares were still not expensive and saw further room to rise.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't regard this price as realistic, I think the realistic price is between 3,500 and 4,000 forints, this year obviously,&quot; Sandor Palfi, TVK's Deputy General Director told Reuters.</p>
<p>On Wednesday TVK rallied to new record levels of 3,255 forints in Budapest and $17.75 in London, before retreating to lower levels. In Budapest, over 1.5 million shares or 6.5 percent of TVK's issued share capital changed hands.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday Budapest and London traders said market talks of an imminent payout by the state due from the company's privatisation was the main driving force.</p>
<p>Palfi said he was confident TVK would get its five billion forints plus its accumulated interest but could not pinpoint the time it would happen.</p>
<p>&quot;What we regard final and irrevocable is either to have a signed agreement with (privatisation agency) APV Rt or to have the money on our accounts,&quot; Palfi said. &quot;None of these has occurred yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Palfi said he doubted that expectations of the privatisation payback were be the only reason behind the rise, saying the market has talked about this amount for a long-time.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be surprised if this alone could trigger such a big change,&quot; he said. &quot;Other factors have probably contributed as well.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked what the other factors might be Palfi said: &quot;analysts, investors know TVK, they know on what the company's business mainly depends.&quot; &quot;Now the market is favourable for us,&quot; Palfi added, referring to lower crude oil prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Our main raw material, which account for more than 40 percent of total costs, derives from that (oil).&quot;</p>
<p>Palfi added, that although he thought expectations of the privatisation payout have already been discounted in prices, the stock was still not expensive.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
