<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="669669" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - June 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - June 18.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 7142 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>- Prime  Minister Gyula Horn Tuesday met the representatives of the four largest historical churches (the Catholic, Calvinist, Lutheran and Jewish churches) to discuss the agreement to be signed Friday between Hungary and the Vatican.</p>
<p>- Parliament filled the last two vacant seats on the twelve-member Constitutional Court.</p>
<p>- The Slovak co-chairman of the Slovak-European parliamentary association committee yesterday blamed Hungary for the lack of improvement in Slovak-Hungarian relations.</p>
<p>- Brazil had offered the services of Brazilian construction companies in building a fourth Budapest metro line.</p>
<p>- Karl-Josef Rauber, the recently appointed papal nuncio to Hungary and Moldavia, arrived in Budapest.</p>
<p>- Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir bin Mohamed will pay a working visit to Hungary on June 23-24.</p>
<p>- German Economic Minister Gunter Rexrodt told a news conference in Budapest yesterday that most German investors plan to expand their Hungarian ventures.</p>
<p>- April retail and catering grew by nearly 1 percent to 245 billion forints from the previous month.</p>
<p>- Templeton Emerging Markets fund is suing the retail chain Fotex, on a charge of violating minority shareholders' rights, and of failing to comply with Hungarian regulations.</p>
<p>- The Metropolitan Court yesterday banned the publication, sale, delivery, loaning, free distribution or presentation to the general public of Adolf Hitler's Mein Kampf.</p>
<p>- Andrei Zoujev, who held the post of commercial attache at the Russian Embassy in Budapest until the summer of 1996 is behind bars at the Kaposvar county jail.</p>
<p>VILAGGAZDASAG</p>
<p>- Indonesian Industry and Trade Minister Tunki Ariwibowo is to arrive in Budapest early next week.</p>
<p>NEPSZABADSAG</p>
<p>- Hungary achieved a $19 million surplus with Austria in the first four months of this year, on exports of $680 million, and imports of $661 million.</p>
<p>MAGYAR HIRLAP</p>
<p>- Unilever considers Hungary the base for its expansion in the former communist countries in southeast Europe.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>- The State Privatization &amp; Holding Co. (APV Rt.) has overshot its income projections for the first half year by Ft 35 billion and took in Ft 110 billion by June 11.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
