<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="669823" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil shares end firm in heavy, speculative trade.</title>
<headline>Brazil shares end firm in heavy, speculative trade.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-06-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian shares closed higher in heavy, speculative trade ahead of Wednesday's futures index settlement, with investors buying selective stocks from the power sector, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Bovespa index  .BVSP of the 48 most traded stocks ended up 1.38 percent at 12,119 points. Volume was a hefty 1.207 billion reais ($1.128 billion).</p>
<p>Brokers said speculative trades bolstered the market most of the session.  </p>
<p>&quot;The rise appeared to be a little bit artificial,&quot; one trader said, adding that some profit-taking is likely to take place Wednesday following Monday's options expiry.</p>
<p>&quot;Whoever exercised the options is likely to put some money in the pockets at a certain time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some $2 billion in options were exercised Monday when the exchange registered its second highest volume in its history in a day of options settlement.</p>
<p>Telebras, the underlying stock for the most active options which expired Monday, closed up 1.72 percent at 154.20 reais.  </p>
<p>Investors continued to buy stocks of federal power holding but took profits on other power firms, particularly Cemig and Cia Paulista de Forca e Luz (CPFL), which rallied substantially in the past sessions.</p>
<p>Cemig preferred lost 3.0 percent, closing at 55 reais. CPFL preferred fell 0.58 percent to 172 reais at the close.</p>
<p>Banking stocks also posted losses after recent sharp rises, traders said. Sao Paulo state bank Banespa preferred stock dived 4.08 percent to 25.40 reais, while government bank Banco do Brasil plummeted 6.77 percent to 12.40 reais.</p>
<p>((--Fatima Cristina, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 2485412))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
