<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670061" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Asian traders say LME copper might try resistance.</title>
<headline>Asian traders say LME copper might try resistance.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper prices on the London Metal Exchange (LME) might try to climb above the next resistance point again soon, despite a sense that the metal is overbought, Asian traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a feeling copper is overbought. But no one looks to be selling, except for producers,&quot; said a trader. &quot;It might not be today but copper might try the $2,620 resistance (level) again.&quot;</p>
<p>Another trader agreed, saying: &quot;There's nothing to cool down the strong sentiment. LME stocks are falling. There might be a crisis if it falls through 100,000 tonnes.&quot;</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the stocks were at 122,225 tonnes.</p>
<p>At 0530 GMT, no quote was available for the benchmark three-month copper. It stood at $2,583/84 at 1800 GMT on Tuesday and at $2,582 at the London kerb close after scoring fresh highs at $2,609 last week.</p>
<p>Three-month aluminium was quoted at $1,587/91, slightly above the kerb close at $1,584.</p>
<p>Traders said aluminium looked firm despite some worries that a fall in LME stocks was caused by a build-up in consignment to stocks rather than to end-users.</p>
<p>&quot;Premiums for spot trades remain high. Selling by producers seems to be mostly over,&quot; said a trader. &quot;It might struggle but it will eventually go above $1,600 again.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Commodities +81-3-3432-6179</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
