<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67018" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai PM Banharn's political skills given workout.</title>
<headline>Thai PM Banharn's political skills given workout.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Charles</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banharn Silpa-archa's political skills have been put to the test often during his rocky 14 months in office as Thailand's 21st prime minister.</p>
<p>Duirng his tenure seemingly he has spent more time trying to clear himself of opposition charges, control power struggles within his coalition and stop the infighting within his own Chart Thai party than he has governing.</p>
<p>The premier, 64, whose extensive patronage and support network in the provinces propelled him in July 1995 into Thailand's top political job, faced a no-confidence debate in parliament this week.</p>
<p>The censure motion, solely against Banharn, accused him of condoning corruption, economic mismanagement and plagiarism in his master's thesis.</p>
<p>The opposition also raised doubts about his nationality, but top immigration officials backed with official records his claim that he was Thai-born. The constitution allows only Thai-born citizens to take part in politics.</p>
<p>The House of Representives was expected to vote on the no-confidence motion on Saturday.</p>
<p>A wily politician, Banharn had survived a previous censure debate in May against him and some cabinet members by abruptly ending the debate before opposition could grill him.</p>
<p>Public opinion polls have showed that Banharn's popularity has dropped sharply since his election. This September, he ranked last on a list of nine people Thais preferred to be their prime minister.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no way that I can do everything to make everyone happy all of the time,&quot; Banharn said in a recent interview.</p>
<p>A wealthy and magnanimous, grass-roots man, Banharn was born Tek Siang sea Bae in 1932, one of six children in a humble Sino-Thai family from Suphan Buri town, 150 km (100 miles) northwest of Bangkok.</p>
<p>He began his long climb to the top as an office boy, making coffee and running errands. Later, he and a group of friends started their own construction company.</p>
<p>He was first elected a member of parliament from Suphan Buri in 1976 and has been returned in every election since then. He has traditionally been among the top vote-winners in polls over the past two decades.</p>
<p>Banharn led Chart Thai to victory in the July 1995 election, winning 92 seats in the 391-seat parliament to unseat Democrat Prime Minister Chuan Leekpai. He then forged a seven-party coalition government.</p>
<p>Despite his influence and popularity among rural Thais, the diminutive Banharn ran into problems from the outset with the powerful urban business lobby in Bangkok and the capital city's hostile local media.</p>
<p>Financial markets markets fell several times in the past 14 months on what analysts said was a lack of investor confidence in Banharn's cabinet choices for key economic portfolios and uncertainty over the government's ability to manage the economy.</p>
<p>Banharn's political troubles came to a head in August when one coalition party pulled out, others threatened to do the same and the &quot;young turk&quot; faction of Chart Thai said it could not promise support for the premier in the no-confidence vote.</p>
<p>But Banharn has proved to be an able statesman on various occasions, despite a well-publicised inability to speak any foreign language.</p>
<p>He successfully hosted the summit of leaders from the Association of Southeast Asian Nations last December and the first 25-nation Asia-Europe summit in March.</p>
<p>Banharn and his wife, Jaemsai, have three children. Their daughter Kanchana is also a Chart Thai member of parliament.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
