<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670274" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish president leads search for new government.</title>
<headline>Turkish president leads search for new government.</headline>
<byline>Hidir Goktas</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish President Suleyman Demirel starts consultations on Thursday to find a replacement for Necmettin Erbakan, forced to quit as prime minister by a military-led campaign against Islamists.</p>
<p>Demirel will meet five opposition figures  before nominating a leader to try to forge a coalition government from the splintered parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;You will be seeing me tomorrow (Thursday),&quot; Anatolian news agency quoted a chirpy Demirel as telling reporters in reply to questions on how he would handle the government crisis.</p>
<p>Erbakan, the first Islamist to lead NATO member Turkey, resigned on Wednesday as the first step in a bid to hand power to coalition ally Tansu Ciller, a conservative.</p>
<p>Under the Erbakan plan, Ciller would head a caretaker coalition with the Islamists until early elections later this year. But Ciller, a U.S.-trained economist, is not guaranteed to get the job.</p>
<p>Demirel, a veteran politician whose current post is mostly symbolic, has given no clues as to who he would appoint as prime minister- designate.</p>
<p>Turkish political tradition says the president should give the job to main opposition leader Mesut Yilmaz, whose parliamentary strength is second only to that of Erbakan's Islam-based Welfare Party.</p>
<p>But Yilmaz may struggle to find coalition allies from among the fractious secularist parties.</p>
<p>His conservative rival Ciller would have a better chance of winning a parliamentary confidence vote as the head of a revamped coalition with the Islamists which would be supported by a small, far-right grouping.</p>
<p>Demirel has the power to appoint his own caretaker administration and call elections himself if his appointee fails to come up with a feasible government formula in 45 days.</p>
<p>Erbakan's coalition, set up only a year ago, crumbled in a secularist onslaught led by generals.</p>
<p>&quot;Our country will now be freed of a false agenda and useless, needless tensions,&quot; he said in announcing his resignation.</p>
<p>The military, which has toppled three governments in the last four decades, has publicly pledged its readiness to turn back any threat to Turkey's secular order &quot;by force of arms&quot; -- tough talk that has alarmed close NATO ally the United States.</p>
<p>The mainstream media and business elite have also fed the current anti-Islamist hysteria, sparking enough defections among deputies and ministers from Ciller's conservatives to cost the coalition a majority in the 550-seat parliament.</p>
<p>A new government under Ciller would have the support on paper of 282 deputies, enough to pass a confidence vote. But anti-Islamist members of her True Path Party have threatened to abandon her if she does not make a complete break with Erbakan's Welfare Party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
