<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670292" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar sets up new industrial development bank.</title>
<headline>Qatar sets up new industrial development bank.</headline>
<dateline>DOHA 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar's Crown Prince Sheikh Jassim bin Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani on Wednesday issued a decree setting up a bank to finance medium and small-scale industries in the Gulf state.</p>
<p>The bank -- to be known as Qatar Industrial Development Bank -- will be 50 percent owned by the state and 50 percent by seven other banks and private companies. Its authorised capital would be 200 million riyals which the decree said could be increased to 500 million riyals.</p>
<p>Qatar National Bank, itself half-owned by the government, will hold a 20 percent stake in the new bank. Qatar Navigation and Qatar Insurance will each hold 10 percent, Doha Bank Ltd five percent, the Commercial Bank of Qatar 2.5 percent, Al Ahli Bank of Qatar 1.5 percent and Al Khaleej Insurance one percent.</p>
<p>The bank will finance both new and existing projects on soft terms and help them raise funds and acquire technology from international sources.</p>
<p>It will be managed by an eight-member board, one drawn from each of the eight owners. Its chairman will come from one of the private shareholders.</p>
<p>The bank is expected to open its doors to customers &quot;within a few days&quot;, said an official involved in setting up the bank.</p>
<p>He said the bank had already rented offices and set up computer and other equipment to start operations &quot;any day&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
