<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670391" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Romanian PM presses case for early NATO entry.</title>
<headline>Romanian PM presses case for early NATO entry.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's prime minister took his uphill struggle for early NATO admission to the White House on Wednesday, telling Vice President Al Gore he wanted to find a way to overcome Washington's objections.</p>
<p>Victor Ciorbea told reporters after meeting Gore that Romania would &quot;fight to the very end&quot; to be included in the first round of new members to be invited to enter the Western alliance at a July 8-9 NATO summit in Madrid.</p>
<p>The United States announced last week that it favoured limiting initial expansion to three ex-communist countries -- Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>That left out Romania and Slovenia, though U.S. officials said both had made progress and kept the door open for future rounds of admission. The two countries are supported by several European countries, including Italy, France and Germany.</p>
<p>Ciorbea said he told Gore it was Romania's wish to &quot;solve the problem and not create new problems&quot;.</p>
<p>In Bucharest, Foreign Minister Adrian Severin said Romania would press for quick NATO entry but wanted a partnership with Washington regardless of the outcome of the Madrid summit.</p>
<p>&quot;(Ciorbea's) visit is not meant to generate further disputes or question the decision of the U.S. administration,&quot; Severin told reporters. &quot;It is not criticism of the United States. We respect the weight of the United States as an important NATO member, but we cannot simply be resigned.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the aim of the Madrid summit &quot;should be one of compromise, which should not exclude Romania and its aspirations&quot;.</p>
<p>Romania has portrayed itself as a haven of stability in the Balkans able to secure NATO's southern flank. Severin also repeated that Romania was able to shoulder admission costs.</p>
<p>The country's new centrist leadership, which took office last November after seven years of rule by ex-communists, has tried to put a brave face on its failure to win U.S. approval for &quot;first wave&quot; admission.</p>
<p>Some officials have acknowledged that the country must now try to ensure it wins inclusion in any subsequent wave.</p>
<p>But Ciorbea said Gore was &quot;not able to fix a date&quot; for the next phase of NATO expansion, saying this would have to be decided by the Alliance as a whole.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
