<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670490" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MCI ahead of plan on local US market entry.</title>
<headline>MCI ahead of plan on local US market entry.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>MCI Communications Corp is running ahead of its planned pace of expansion into local phone markets in the United States, company president and chief executive officer Timothy Price said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're a little ahead of the plan. I think we are going to be in 31 markets by the end of the year. We've accelerated the pace of local market entry,&quot; he told reporters following a luncheon here.</p>
<p>Price said MCI was currently in 24 markets.</p>
<p>He also expressed his opposition to any potential merger between AT&amp;T Corp and SBC Communications Inc.  </p>
<p>AT&amp;T Corp chairman Robert Allen raised the possibly of such a merger in a speech earlier this month.</p>
<p>&quot;The speculated combination of AT&amp;T and SBC would be a long pull from a regulatory perspective. We would be very concerned about it,&quot; Price said.</p>
<p>&quot;Putting the Bell company back together again would be like Humpty Dumpty never fell off the wall at all,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S. Federal Communications chief Reed Hundt said last week that the mega-merger remained unthinkable in the view of most antitrust experts.  </p>
<p>Price, who had earlier addressed a luncheon organized by the Executive Club of Chicago, said he also saw few advantages in a merger between his company and a major regional U.S. phone company.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure what they would really bring us that we don't already have with the combination of BT and MCI. Without ruling out any options I also don't know that it would be allowed frankly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>BT and MCI in 1996 agreed to merge to form Concert, a global communications company. The deal awaits U.S. Federal Communications Commisssion approval.  </p>
<p>Price said he was, however, looking for more partners particularly in the Pacific Rim.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't announced a PacRim partner yet. NTT's an attractive partner as are many other potentials,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will actively seek one but in the meantime we are perfectly capable of providing really strong service to the Pacific Rim,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Price told reporters that the amount of time it would take to find partners would depend on the company involved.</p>
<p>&quot;If it were an NTT it wouldn't happen for a while,&quot; he said. Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp is a based in Japan.</p>
<p>((Nigel Hunt 312-408 8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
