<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670468" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Annan welcomes US Senate plan to pay U.N. arrears.</title>
<headline>Annan welcomes US Senate plan to pay U.N. arrears.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan hailed on Wednesday as positive a measure in Congress that would pay most U.S. debts to the United Nations provided certain benchmarks were met.</p>
<p>Annan, speaking at the Heritage Foundation, a conservative public policy research institute, said the benchmarks, however, would cause problems with the other 184 members.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, we would have liked to receive all that we think we deserve and without benchmarks,&quot; he said. &quot;But given where we began and where we were, I think it is progress.&quot;</p>
<p>On Tuesday night, the U.S. Senate overwhelmingly authorised payment of $819 million over three years to meet past-due obligations to the United Nations. It conditioned the payments on structural reforms, budget cuts and trimming U.S. annual dues to 20 percent from the current 25 percent.</p>
<p>Annan welcomed the debate on the Senate floor about the United States' role in the United Nations as unlike anything he had seen in years, calling this &quot;an encouraging thing.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think the discussion and the support was bipartisan. And I believe this is a step in the right direction,&quot; he said. He prefaced his remarks with a joking reference to the Heritage Foundation as the &quot;lion's den,&quot; presumably because of its harsh criticism of some United Nations practices and operations.</p>
<p>Annan said the United States would have to deal with the other 184 member states to work out the details of its payback plan. Before becoming law, the Senate version must be reconciled with a House of Representatives plan and signed by President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it will come as a surprise to you that most of the member states are not enthused about the benchmarks, because the British, the French, the Germans will tell you 'we pay without conditions and without benchmarks,'&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, it will be ideal and wonderful if the member states themselves were to take the political decision that we don't think it will be correct for any member state to pay more than 20 percent,&quot; Annan said.</p>
<p>The current assessment mechanism is based on &quot;objective&quot; criteria such as gross domestic product and population, Annan went on. &quot;So you will have 184 members assessed on an objected criteria and one member state that appears to have taken a political decision. And this leads to a certain tension and dichotomy.</p>
<p>&quot;But I am an optimist, and I think some day the U.N. and the U.S. will go back to the days when they had an excellent relationship ...&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
