<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670599" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Study finds estrogen cuts Alzheimer's risk.</title>
<headline>Study finds estrogen cuts Alzheimer's risk.</headline>
<byline>Randall Mikkelsen</byline>
<dateline>BALTIMORE 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new study of the effects of oestrogen on Alzheimer's disease has found that women who took the hormone had a 54 percent lower chance of contracting the memory-impairing ailment, scientists said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The study, reported in the current issue of the journal Neurology, bolsters earlier research suggesting oestrogen can help prevent Alzheimer's.</p>
<p>&quot;We found that women in our study on oestrogen replacement therapy (ERT) had a 54 percent reduction in the relative risk of developing Alzheimer's disease,&quot; said the lead author of the study, Dr. Claudia Kawas, an associate professor of neurology at Johns Hopkins University.</p>
<p>&quot;If this connection can be clinically confirmed, we would anticipate a significant public health impact,&quot; Kawas said in a statement issued by Johns Hopkins.</p>
<p>Alzheimer's affects about 15 percent of people over age 65 and about half those over 85. It often begins with memory loss and can progress to severe dementia and death. Former President Ronald Reagan suffers from the disease.</p>
<p>The study followed 472 post-menopausal women for up to 16 years. About 45 percent of them had used oestrogen at some point. Of the entire group, 34 women were later diagnosed with Alzheimer's, but only nine of those cases were among women who took oestrogen.</p>
<p>After adjustments for education level, which has previously been linked to Alzheimer's risk, the study found oestrogen treatment reduced the risk by 54 percent.</p>
<p>Oestrogen may help prevent Alzheimer's by stimulating the growth of nerve cells, neutralising anti-oxidants that can damage chromosomes or increasing neurotransmitter levels, the study said.</p>
<p>Oestrogen-sensitive nerve cells, which degenerate because of Alzheimer's disease, exist in the brains of both men and women, the study said. But the effects of oestrogen may be different on women and men, it added.</p>
<p>The study said additional, controlled studies were needed to confirm the benefits of oestrogen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALTIMORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
