<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67068" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China, Tajikistan to step up military cooperation.</title>
<headline>China, Tajikistan to step up military cooperation.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>China and Tajikistan said on Friday they would work to strengthen military contact and speed up talks on troop reductions along the border between them, the Xinhua news agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;In an effort to increase mutual trust and cooperation in the military sphere, (the two countries) will promote the formation and expansion of ties between their military departments,&quot; Xinhua said.</p>
<p>A joint declaration issued by the two neighbours calls for the speeding up of talks to draft an agreement on mutual disarmament along the border between them, Xinhua said.</p>
<p>&quot;The two nations will continue to accelerate the process for formulation and signing an agreement on mutual disarmament at their boundary areas,&quot; the agency said.</p>
<p>Chinese President Jiang Zemin and Tajikistan President Imomali Rakhmonov signed the pact this week, it said. Rakhmonov is to wrap up a five-day visit to China on Friday.</p>
<p>Under the declaration, China and Tajikistan pledged not to enter into any military or political alliances directed at the other nation or to threaten the security of the other, it said.</p>
<p>The two nations will step up cooperation in fighting terrorism, organised crime, smuggling and drug trafficking, it said. The agreement also called for enhancing economic ties and improving transportation and cargo links, it said without giving further details.</p>
<p>China, Russia, Tajikistan, Kazakhstan and Kyrgyzstan earlier this week concluded talks in Beijing on reducing military forces along their common borders, which total 7,640 km (4,750 miles).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
