<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670713" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FOCUS-Olivetti to stay in the red for 1997.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Olivetti to stay in the red for 1997.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>IVREA, Italy 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's Olivetti will stay in the red for the seventh consecutive year this year, the group said on Wednesday, as improvements in its information technology sector fail to offset losses from telecom operations.</p>
<p>Group chief executive Roberto Colaninno told Olivetti's annual shareholders meeting in its home town of Ivrea, near Turin in northwest Italy, 1997 would see a recovery in profitability at its information technology interests.</p>
<p>Olsy (Olivetti Solutions), which makes computer systems for banks and retailers would see &quot;positive results.&quot; Lexikon, which makes printers, copiers and faxes and Tecnost, a 48 percent-owned specialist information systems group,will also be positive.</p>
<p>But Olivetti's telecoms interests, Telemedia and its 35.5-percent stake in mobile phone consortium Omnitel, would sustain losses in 1997. But these losses were in line with budget.</p>
<p>&quot;The positive effects from the results in information technology will not be sufficient to completely cover the losses of the telecoms companies and the costs of the holding company,&quot; he told Olivetti's shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;We anticipate a consolidated result that therefore, represents an important progress towards a return to conditions of economic equilibrium,&quot; Colaninno added.</p>
<p>But he still forecast the group would get as close as possible to breakeven before Omnitel losses and tax payments.</p>
<p>Olivetti has not reported a profit since 1990 and sunk to a net loss of 915 billion lire ($540 million) in 1996 after a record 1.60-trillion lire loss in 1995 as it tried to focus on telecoms and IT and away from personal computers.</p>
<p>The shareholders meeting was the first in nearly two decades without former chairman Carlo De Benedetti, who bowed out last September after he failed to turn a profit.</p>
<p>Last year, Olivetti lost four other top managers in a board room bloodbath, and chairman Antonio Tesone told shareholders on Wednesday the debacle cost the group 14 to 15 billion lire.</p>
<p>Colaninno was then brought in to start his own rescue plan and on Wednesday, he repeated a forecast made last month that Olivetti sales would reach nine trillion lire in 1997 after 8.3 trillion in 1996, with seven trillion coming from IT companies and 25 percent, or two trillion, from telecoms.</p>
<p>Colaninno said in May he expected Olivetti in the first half of 1997 to make a pretax loss, before Omnitel losses, of 264.2 billion against a 350.2 billion loss in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>Colaninno confirmed Omnitel is scheduled to break even in 1998 after starting its mobile phone service in December 1995.</p>
<p>He added talks were continuing with France Telecom and Bell Atlantic over Infostrada, the venture which plans to start Italy's second fixed-line telecoms national network.</p>
<p>But Colaninno declined to say if Bell was planning to pull out of Infostrada as some newspaper reports have suggested.</p>
<p>France Telecom said in April it was buying a 49 percent of Infostrada, while Olivetti and Bell's 67- and 33-percent stakes, respectively, would be diluted as their portions become stakes in a holding company that owns 51 percent of Infostrada.</p>
<p>Shareholders also approved a capital reduction to cut the number of Olivetti shares in issue, after the holding company Olivetti SpA announced a 1996 net loss of 1.4 trillion lire.</p>
<p>Olivetti shareholders will swap 25 old Olivetti shares for 16 new ones in a move to comply with Italian regulations, which say that if a holding company has losses greater than a third of its total capital, it must reduce its capital.</p>
<p>Olivetti chairman Antonio Tesone also announced group vice chairman Giorgio Garuzzo's resignation. Garuzzo joined the group from industrial group Fiat in March last year.</p>
<p>Olivetti shares closed down 0.6 percent at 462.5 lire.</p>
<p>$1=1,696 lire</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IVREA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
