<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670767" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-BAe bids for US fighter at Paris show.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-BAe bids for US fighter at Paris show.</headline>
<byline>Pierre Tran</byline>
<dateline>LE BOURGET, France 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>An announcement by British Aerospace Plc (BAe) to team up with giant Lockheed Martin to bid for a next-generation U.S. fighter sent an adrenaline shot on Wednesday through the Paris air show.</p>
<p>The Joint Strike Fighter is the Pentagon's attempt to squeeze maximum value out of a shrinking budget by buying a common airframe for the U.S. Air Force, Navy and Marine Corps, which all currently fly different aircraft. The British navy is also buying the futuristic fighter.</p>
<p>&quot;With a requirement for over 3,000 aircraft, JSF is the most significant transatlantic military programme of the 21st century&quot; BAe chief executive Richard Evans said in a statement released at the air show.</p>
<p>BAe's decision ends intense speculation over whether it would join Lockheed or rival bidder Boeing Co in developing two prototypes apiece by 2001, with a planned entry into service in 2008.</p>
<p>The JSF is expected to generate at least $100 billion in revenues for the winner over the life of the programme, with one senior U.S. aerospace executive estimating the price tag at $35-40 million price per plane, depending on the version.</p>
<p>While fighter jets scream overhead and lightweight planes dance to the Blue Danube played over loudspeakers in the flying demonstration, down below, executives huddle to cut corporate deals and horse-trade over orders, which are the lifeblood of this intensely competitive business.</p>
<p>In Europe, eyes are rivetted on Lagardere group and telecommunications giant Alcatel Alsthom, the rival bidders in the privatisation of French defence electronics firm Thomson-CSF, launched by the previous conservative government.</p>
<p>The state sell-off is widely seen as key move in a consolidation of French and European defence capacity, needed to confront U.S. competition from the likes of Lockheed Martin.</p>
<p>Lagardere said it was ready to adapt to the new setting since the election of a Socialist-led French government and would continue to pursue a linkup with Thomson-CSF.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the Thomson-Matra merger remains the only answer to the dynamism of the Americans,&quot; Matra High Technology chairman Noel Forgeard told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Will the merger between Thomson-CSF and Matra be done on the same terms? I cannot say. The rules will be set, we will adapt to them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Matra, which is a Lagardere subsidiary, has allied itself with Daimler-Benz Aerospace AG (Dasa) of Germany and British Aerospace Plc in its bid.</p>
<p>But Alcatel chairman Serge Tchuruk told reporters his company's bid was still valid. &quot;Our plan has not lost any of its industrial qualities. There is no reason for it to lose them.&quot;</p>
<p>Alcatel joined with privately-owned Dassault Industries for its bid and has assigned a large role for joint ventures with state-owned Aerospatiale in its business plan for Thomson-CSF.</p>
<p>Orders announced on Wednesday included Brazilian airline TAM's purchase of up to 10 of European aircraft consortium Airbus Industrie's A330-200 widebody twin-engined jets in a deal valued at around $1 billion.</p>
<p>U.S. airline Continental Express also ordered 25 EMB-145 regional jets, worth around $350 million, from Brazilian aircraft maker Embraer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LE BOURGET, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
