<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670732" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Denmark says OSCE role not hinging on Albania poll.</title>
<headline>Denmark says OSCE role not hinging on Albania poll.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish Foreign Minister Niels Helveg Petersen said on Wednesday Europe's security forum had notched up notable achievements this year and the success of his stewardship would not depend on the outcome of Albanian elections later this month.</p>
<p>Petersen, current chairman of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), said he was among the first to call for deployment of a multinational protection force in Albania to help restore a semblance of order after anarchy broke out there in March.</p>
<p>The OSCE is charged with supervising the two rounds of elections in Albania on June 29 and July 6.</p>
<p>&quot;If we are not successful, it is not that we didn't try,&quot; Petersen told Reuters in an interview during a working visit to OSCE headquarters in Vienna.</p>
<p>&quot;It may well be that the situation would be a lot worse if we did not try.&quot;</p>
<p>The success or failure of a country's leadership of an international organisation is often linked to one big event. Switzerland's chairmanship of the OSCE was generally considered a success following Bosnia's first elections last September.</p>
<p>The chairmanship of the OSCE is held by a member of the 54-nation body each year. Denmark is half-way through its one-year stint and it is the turn of Poland in 1998.</p>
<p>Petersen said one of the main achievements of the OSCE this year was the organisation of elections in Chechnya in January.</p>
<p>&quot;In a war-torn country, we saw it was possible to conduct a reasonable election and the outcome was the election of a Chechen government (which has an agreement) with the Russian government,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The OSCE also helped in brokering an accord on the Trans-Dniestr region in Moldova with Russia and Ukraine acting as guarantors, he said.</p>
<p>The organisation had a further role in setting up talks between rival factions in Tajikistan, he added.</p>
<p>With a small bureaucracy and an ever-increasing presence in Europe's trouble spots, the OSCE has drawn criticism for lacking the muscle to resolve crises effectively or for trying to do too much with too few resources.</p>
<p>&quot;We are capable of carrying out a fire brigade function -- getting there early to try to prevent conflicts from spreading,&quot; Petersen said. &quot;But we need more power, more beef.&quot;</p>
<p>However, the foreign minister said he opposed any increase in the OSCE's international bureaucracy or a need to change the consensus voting on which decisions are based.</p>
<p>He said the organisation of municipal elections in Bosnia set for September was making good progress, with two million voters already registered.</p>
<p>&quot;It is running well...but these elections are also extremely difficult given the formidable history among the rival parties,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
