<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670723" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Jospin lays out programme to French assembly.</title>
<headline>Jospin lays out programme to French assembly.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>France learns on Thursday what its new leftist government has in store for it when Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin delivers his first major policy speech to the National Assembly.</p>
<p>In the speech, due to begin at 3 p.m. (1300 GMT), Jospin is expected to explain his plans for fulfilling election campaign promises ranging from creating 700,000 new jobs to eliminating austerity from Paris' path to European monetary union.</p>
<p>The speech is also likely to touch on campaign pledges to raise the minimum wage, shorten the working week, cut sales tax on basic goods and take a new look at privatisations and costly public works projects that conflict with environmental goals.</p>
<p>After his address, Jospin will ask the National Assembly for a vote of confidence in his new government, which took power after trouncing the previous centre-right majority in the June 1 election.</p>
<p>Routine approval is expected for the confidence motion as the leftist government of Socialists, Communists and Greens holds a comfortable majority in the assembly.</p>
<p>But in a possible sign of future weakness within the alliance, the RCV group combining 33 deputies from the Radical, Citizens Movement and Greens parties quarreled for hours on Wednesday over who would represent them in the debate on the motion.</p>
<p>Since only one person from each parliamentary group is allowed to speak during the debate, some in the RCV group protested that outsiders might mistake their spokesman's words for the views of the entire group.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not want the person who will speak to express the point of view of the group,&quot; deputy Georges Sarre told reporters.</p>
<p>Deputy Michel Crepeau, chosen as the RCV group's official representative, responded: &quot;I hope he won't throw bolts or rotten eggs. We agree on so many things.&quot;</p>
<p>Jospin's speech will be read simultaneously in the Senate, the upper house, by Employment Minister Martine Aubry.</p>
<p>But there will be no debate and no vote of confidence in the Senate, which is elected indirectly and retains a centre-right majority unaffected by the recent election.</p>
<p>Jospin, fresh from tough negotiations at a European Union summit in Amsterdam, is likely to discuss his campaign to make employment a key focus of European integration efforts.</p>
<p>He is also expected to announce plans for an audit of public finances, an initiative that some critics say could jeopardise the transition to a single European currency.</p>
<p>Gaullist deputy Patrick Devedjian on Wednesday accused the Socialists of &quot;looking for an excuse to put off the adoption of the euro&quot;.</p>
<p>There has been speculation the audit would find France's deficit to be well above the three percent of gross domestic product set out in a strict reading of the Maastricht treaty for states seeking to join the single currency from 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
