<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670791" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgium loses temper with France in Dassault row.</title>
<headline>Belgium loses temper with France in Dassault row.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian Justice Minister Stefaan De Clerk on Wednesday threatened a diplomatic incident with France in the row between the two countries over bribes alleged to have been paid by French aerospace firm Dassault.</p>
<p>&quot;This has gone on long enough,&quot; De Clerck told parliament. &quot;Now the French authorities must say yes or no to our demand. If it is no it will be unacceptable and will merit an incident of the utmost importance.&quot;</p>
<p>He gave no details.</p>
<p>The Dassault row has been simmering for more than a year over allegations the firm paid 600 million Belgian francs ($17 million) to political parties to secure a contract to fit air defence systems to Belgian F-16 jets in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>Dassault has denied any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>A Liege court issued an international arrest warrant for company head Serge Dassault in May last year and justice authorities have been trying since then to persuade their French counterparts to cooperate in the investigations.</p>
<p>The warrant was suddenly withdrawn last Friday, and news leaked out that investigators had managed to lay their hands on some of the documents they wanted.</p>
<p>But De Clerk's statement proved that the row, that has reached the highest political and diplomatic levels, was far from over as the French justice authorities were still refusing to release 11 key documents on the grounds of national security.</p>
<p>Belgium had hoped for substantial progress with the change of government in France earlier this month, and De Clerck said he had both written to and spoken to his counterpart Elisabeth Guigou on the issue, but so far to little effect.</p>
<p>Judicial relations between France and Belgium have been strained for some while over Belgian attempts to probe bribery and corruption allegations against French businessmen.</p>
<p>Belgian authorities in May 1994 imprisoned Didier Pineau Valencienne, chairman of French electrical engineering group Schneider, for two weeks in a corruption probe.</p>
<p>An international arrest warrent for Pineau Valencienne, issued after he refused to return to Belgium for questioning, was quietly withdrawn about one year later.</p>
<p>The Liege court issued the arrest warrant for Dassault after he refused to attend a hearing there.</p>
<p>European nations do not extradite their nationals, but the warrant did mean that if the ageing and influential industrialist set foot outside France he risked arrest.</p>
<p>Dassault told French radio on Saturday he was willing to testify in Belgium under certain conditions.</p>
<p>Several Belgian political parties are under investigation for allegedly accepting bribes from the French group.</p>
<p>In 1995, NATO secretary general Willy Claes, a Belgian economics minister in the late eighties, was forced to resign over bribes alleged to have been paid to his Socialist Party by Dassault and Italian helicopter maker Agusta Spa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
