<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670808" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch closing share market report.</title>
<headline>Dutch closing share market report.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares closed mostly lower on Wednesday with only a 6.9 percent rise in Philips pushing the AEX share index into positive territory.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market was beginning to become susceptible to profit-taking, looking for features to fuel the recent run which has swept the AEX up from around 800 at the end of May.</p>
<p>The AEX finished 1.98 points up on Wednesday at 849.13 after spending most of the session in negative ground. Dealers said Philips' 8.90 guilders gain to 137.80 had bolstered the AEX by just over 5.00 points. &quot;If it hadn't been for Philips alone this market would be around 3.00 points lower,&quot; said one.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the early tone, when the AEX slipped to a session low of 839.59, had been set by profit-taking as the dollar slipped a little and bonds showed a flat trend.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen the dollar around 1.95 guilders for a long time, the bond market is doing nothing, the Dow is slipping a bit and there's not that much information or news that's giving an indication of why the index should go up more,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>A Reuter survey of Dutch equity analysts on June 11 and 12 showed on average that the AEX was expected to fall more than seven percent from recent levels. Predictions for the AEX at the end of this year ranged between 700 and 850.  </p>
<p>Philips' gain on extended Tuesday's 7.90 guilder rise as it continued to respond to yesterday's news it planned a consumer communications hook-up with Lucent Technologies of the U.S, creating a company with a $2.5 billion a year turnover.</p>
<p>&quot;This is pretty good news for Philips,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;Philips with Lucent really improves the Philips name in the U.S...they've got good scope to really compete in the States. It makes people believe some of those (analyst) targets for a Philips share price of 150 guilders.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers added Philips was also supported on Tuesday by a positive presentation to analysts about its Sound &amp; Vision unit.  </p>
<p>Dutch PTT was up another 1.10 guilders to 79.40, extending Tuesday's 2.60 guilder in response to news it was planning to demerge its postal and telecoms operations via independent listings in the first half of 1998.</p>
<p>One dealer said his brokerage's analyst had estimated the telecoms side of Dutch PTT could be worth around 57.5 guilders a share and the postal side at 27.5 guilders a share.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking at a value of around 85 guilders a share and I've heard other houses are valuing the split at 90-95 guilders,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;One thing is pretty clear, a floor is forming under KPN shares at around the current level.&quot;  </p>
<p>Dealers said financials came in for attention from the profit-takers with ING down 80 cents to 89.10 guilders and Fortis Amev off 90 cents to 80.80 guilders.</p>
<p>PolyGram was down 1.40 guilders to 104.60 in a reaction to a recent big gain on news of its involvement in a movie featuring the hugely successful British pop group the Spice Girls.</p>
<p>Elsewhere among the leaders Royal Dutch was down 2.10 guilders to 399.50 and Unilever was off 1.20 guilders to 399.60. -- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
