<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670850" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: High input costs hurt 96/97 net, India ACC says.</title>
<headline>High input costs hurt 96/97 net, India ACC says.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's leading cement firm Associated Cement Companies (ACC) said on Wednesday its post-tax profit for the year ended March 31, 1997 was hit by a steep rise in input costs and a deceleration in cement demand.</p>
<p>&quot;Unprecedented cost increases in the major inputs such as coal, power as well as increase in the cost of transportation exerted considerable pressure on operating margins,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The company said its net profit fell to 769.2 million rupees in 1996/97 from 2.27 billion rupees in the previous year.</p>
<p>ACC said the second half of the year saw an unprecedented downturn in the industry which led to unremunerative prices in most parts of the country.</p>
<p>&quot;Absence of income from sale of investments, the lower dividend income from Unit Trust of India (UTI) and other income also contributed to the reduction in profits,&quot; a statement said.</p>
<p>ACC's refractory business was also saw a squeeze on margins during the year, it said.</p>
<p>Cement production in 1996/97 rose to 9.03 million tonnes against 8.93 million tonnes in the previous year. Clinker production rose by 4.1 percent to 7.46 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Cement sales (excluding traded third party cement) rose to 9.05 million tonnes against 8.84 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Sale of traded cement rose to 0.6 million tonnes in 1996/97 from 0.54 milloin tonnes a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Similarly, export of cement also showed improvement to touch 0.25 million tonnes from 0.23 million tonnes last year,&quot; the statement concluded.</p>
<p>--Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
