<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="670922" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: FEATURE - Calcutta Chinese to celebrate HK handover.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Calcutta Chinese to celebrate HK handover.</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA, India 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Calcutta's dwindling Chinese community is watching Hong Kong's handover to Beijing with pride -- and mixed feelings about its own place in India.</p>
<p>The Chinese who have dwelt in this eastern Indian city for generations are famous for their restaurants and their hand-crafted shoes.</p>
<p>&quot;Happiness is an expression of the heart. The land (Hong Kong) has come back to us just like Goa came back to India,&quot; Hou Wang Lin, secretary of the city's Chinese Cultural and Entertainment Association, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Goa, a tiny coastal state in western India, was &quot;liberated&quot; by Indian troops from Portuguese rule in December 1961.</p>
<p>Hou said he was elated that Hong Kong was returning peacefully to the embrace of the mainland.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to celebrate on June 30 at 9.30 p.m. (1600 GMT). It will be July 1 in China then,&quot; he said, adding that Chinese astrologers were being consulted for an auspicious time for celebrations to begin.</p>
<p>A PROUD MOMENT</p>
<p>&quot;This is a proud moment not only for the Chinese but for all Asian people,&quot; said Hou, who owns a popular Chinese restaurant.</p>
<p>Hou is a second-generation Calcuttan whose family had roots in China's southern Guangdong province, which borders Hong Kong. &quot;We are the Hakka people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Chinese Association will gather local Chinese for a feast, and its members hope to watch the Hong Kong handover ceremony live on television.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be lots of fireworks, dancing and dinner parties,&quot; Hou said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is good that Hong Kong is going back to mainland China and we hope our relatives who live in Hong Kong won't have problems because of the handover,&quot; said Chen Kho Qui, 44, a leather tannery owner.</p>
<p>&quot;We are worried about the future of our relatives and friends in Hong Kong after the handover,&quot; said Yang Kuo Lien, 57, another tannery owner.</p>
<p>TANNERIES, RESTAURANTS PUT ENCLAVE ON MAP</p>
<p>About 5,000 Chinese live in a small enclave called Tangra, known locally as Chinatown, on Calcutta's outskirts.</p>
<p>Over the past two decades they have transformed what was once a marshy wasteland into a bustling neighbourhood.</p>
<p>The growth of the tanneries and a spurt in Chinese restaurants in the locality were crucial in putting Tangra on the map of India's most populous city.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the best place to have original Chinese food,&quot; said Manik Das, one of the many Calcuttans who drive up to Chinatown on the weekends to queue up outside the Lee restaurant.</p>
<p>The narrow winding road cutting across Chinatown is flanked by open drains that emit the stench of raw hides and the odour of chemicals spewed from the nearby leather tanneries.</p>
<p>New Delhi's Outlook newsmagazine said last month that the Chinese, who own 230 of Tangra's 550 tanneries, have also been hit by a recent Supreme Court ruling that ordered them to move to a planned leather complex on the southern outskirts of Calcutta.</p>
<p>Spurred by such instability, the younger Chinese are hurrying towards the exits and Calcutta's Chinese population has dwindled to about 5,000 from more than 20,000 a decade earlier, residents said. BUT YOUNGER CHINESE WANT TO GO WEST</p>
<p>&quot;They want to go abroad because places like Toronto and Taipei are beautiful,&quot; said Stephen Lee, 20, a third-generation Calcuttan.</p>
<p>Hou said Chinese living in Calcutta faced many problems and were forced to seek greener pastures in the West.</p>
<p>&quot;I still can't get an Indian passport. They (authorities) say I was born under British rule,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>India gained independence from Britain in 1947.</p>
<p>Many young Calcuttan Chinese who travel to overseas universities are attracted by the better quality of life in the West and opt to remain there, Lee said.</p>
<p>Lee's family, which also traces its origin to Guangdong province, runs a restaurant in Chinatown.</p>
<p>&quot;No reaction,&quot; said Lee when asked about his feelings on the Hong Kong handover.</p>
<p>&quot;We have become more Indian than Chinese,&quot; added Chang Min Lee, editor of Overseas Chinese Commerce of India, the community's ailing morning newspaper. &quot;What can I say about the handover?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
