<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="671126" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Waigel says on good track with DASA on Eurofighter.</title>
<headline>Waigel says on good track with DASA on Eurofighter.</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel said on Wednesday the Bonn government was making progess with Daimler-Benz Aerospace AG (DASA) in talks over a temporary financing plan for the Eurofighter combat jet.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that we are on a good track with DASA to guarantee financing,&quot; Waigel told a news conference.</p>
<p>Bonn is trying to plug a two billion mark ($1.2 billion) funding shortfall to pay the 23 billion marks cost price to buy 180 Eurofighters.</p>
<p>It has had to delay approval for ordering the aircraft because of financing problems thrown up by Germany's efforts to meet the criteria for economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>DASA, the German partner in the four-country Eurofighter project, has threatened to stop work if there is no official funding before the parliamentary summer recess.</p>
<p>Trade union leaders at the Paris airshow said on Monday that the delay was putting around 50,000 jobs in Europe at stake and was threatening the whole of Europe's aviation and space industry.</p>
<p>Waigel has already reached an informal agreement with Defence Minister Volker Ruehe that half of the shortfall will come form the defence budget.</p>
<p>On Monday, DASA chief executive Manfred Bischoff told a German daily that his company, a unit of Daimler-Benz AG, could help with financing with early repayments of state prefinancing of its Airbus civilian jet.</p>
<p>-- Kate Kelland, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.725 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
