<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="671153" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: IFO - GERMAN EMU FISCAL DEBATE CLOUDS REAL PROGRESS.</title>
<headline>IFO - GERMAN EMU FISCAL DEBATE CLOUDS REAL PROGRESS.</headline>
<byline>Kate Kelland</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The heated debate in Germany over Maastricht fiscal criteria for economic and monetary union (EMU) is clouding actual progress towards convergence, a leading member of the Ifo research institute said.</p>
<p>Rolf Dumke, the head of Ifo's industrial nations and European integration department, told a conference on Wednesday that the current discussion, which focussed more or less exclusively on the EMU debt and deficit criteria, did not reflect reality.</p>
<p>&quot;The development of the convergence criteria points to a stability culture in Europe,&quot; he said. &quot;To wipe this away as though it were not important is incomprehensible.&quot;</p>
<p>The Maastricht treaty calls on would-be EMU members to reduce budget deficits to at most three percent of gross domestic product and to bring national debt levels down to at most 60 percent of GDP in 1997.</p>
<p>But Dumke said that the so-called monetary criteria, which cover inflation, exchange rates and long-term interest rates, carried far more weight.</p>
<p>&quot;The price stability criteria are by far the most important,&quot; Dumke said, adding that Europe had shown great success in these areas. &quot;Europe is entering a nirvana of common policy.&quot;</p>
<p>Dumke scoffed at Germany's constant concern with the three percent deficit and 60 percent debt criteria which he said were &quot;figures snatched out of the air&quot;.</p>
<p>With fiscal and monetary convergence already showing great progess, Dumke said the stability pact, which was finally ratified by European Union ministers at a summit in Amsterdam on Monday, would help ensure sustainability after the planned introduction of the euro single currency in 1999.</p>
<p>The pact, which includes what Dumke described as &quot;very threatening&quot; sanctions for countries which overstep the fiscal mark, would also reduce the incidence of so-called economic shocks to countries within the euro area, he said.</p>
<p>But he said for the pact to have the greatest stabilising effect, it would be better to have a core group of countries with similar economic and fiscal structures forming the first wave of EMU nations.</p>
<p>&quot;The application of the stability pact could be difficult at the beginning, but (the pact) is a good thing,&quot; Dumke said.</p>
<p>On unemployment, Wolfgang Ochel, also from Ifo's industrial nations and European integration department, said EMU was likely to have a short-term negative impact but would eventually lead to a reduction in the number of people out of work in Europe.</p>
<p>Ochel said greater efficiency stemming from the absence of exchange rate fluctuations, and increased competition in product and wage policy would boost job creation in the long term.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
