<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="671211" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-UK gas watchdog,BG end row, both happy.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-UK gas watchdog,BG end row, both happy.</headline>
<byline>Hans de Jongh</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A long and bitter row over gas transport charges came to an end on Wednesday as industry regulator Ofgas accepted recommendations made by the Monopolies and Mergers Commission (MMC).</p>
<p>The MMC, which acted as an arbiter, called for pipeline operator TransCo, part of BG Plc, to trim charges to gas suppliers by a one-off 21 percent.</p>
<p>This will result in a 29 pound ($47.5) cut in the average British domestic gas bill, which compares with a reduction of 28 pounds Ofgas had originally been looking for.</p>
<p>The watchdog's proposals had been vetted by the MMC since October after BG, which at the time was still called British Gas, rejected them as too severe.</p>
<p>The MMC's recommendations were hailed alike by Ofgas, consumer organisations and the stock market, while even BG was positive about the outcome.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel the MMC has provided opportunities for both sides to move forward with honour,&quot; said BG chief executive David Varney.</p>
<p>But BG employees will likely suffer and trade union GMB said it fears further job losses after 4000 people already left TransCo since early 1996.</p>
<p>BG earlier predicted thousands job losses if Ofgas proposals were implemented, but was tight-lipped this time round, saying it needed more time to fully digest the new pricing review.</p>
<p>BG dubbed the review, which will be implemented in October, as a &quot;tough settlement&quot;, but added it could meet the new targets.</p>
<p>To underline the success of the appeal to the MMC, the utility pointed at its revenues over the next five years. It said they will be 220 million pounds higher than would have been the case if it had agreed to Ofgas' original proposals.</p>
<p>The price regime also involves putting a lower valuation on TransCo's assest than that carried in BG's books.</p>
<p>This has prompted BG to change its accounting principles, will lead to a lower depreciation charge and consequently a profit boost of 250 to 300 million pounds.</p>
<p>BG will consequently revise its dividend policy, finance director Philip Hampton said.</p>
<p>He repeated that the pay-out will be materially lower following February's demerger of the gas supply business. But Hampton added the cut may be smaller than previously anticipated.</p>
<p>&quot;At the time of the demerger we said we would expect the dividend to be reduced materially. This (reduction) might now be somewhat less,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Industry analysts subsequently raised their dividend forecasts and BG shares firmed five pence to 217-1/2 pence.</p>
<p>&quot;They (BG) have come out fighting with a more positive approach on the dividend,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Ofgas chief Clare Spottiswoode, meanwhile, hailed the MMC recommendations as they &quot;upheld the basic principles&quot; of her earlier proposals.</p>
<p>The Gas Consumers Council, which looks after consumers' interests, also welcomed the new price regime, adding it hoped for a &quot;more positive relationship&quot; between Ofgas and BG.</p>
<p>Spottiswoode told Reuters there had already been an improvement. &quot;There has been a change for the better in the past three weeks,&quot; she said,</p>
<p>She added both parties were now constructively working to separate TransCo's transport business from the gas storage operations.</p>
<p>The storage activities will in due course be incorporated in a new company, which won't be regulated. ($ = 0.610 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
