<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67138" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MGE spring wheat ends higher on short covering.</title>
<headline>MGE spring wheat ends higher on short covering.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>MGE spring wheat futures ended higher on short covering and spillover support from CBOT soybeans amid talk of a possible frost event next week in the U.S. Midwest, traders said.</p>
<p>U.S. wheat markets were buoyed by the frost-related rally in CBOT soybeans and by concerns over possible delays in the seeding of winter wheat.</p>
<p>&quot;Chicago moved and we just followed,&quot; a trader said. &quot;There was a lack of selling. Also, all week we saw scaled down commercial-type buying and we saw a little more of that come in today.&quot;</p>
<p>MGE spring wheat closed 1-1/2 to three cents per bushel higher, with Dec up 1-1/2 cents at $4.07-3/4 a bushel.</p>
<p>Traders said Atwood-Peavey bought around 800,000 March bushels. CIS bought 400,000 March and 400,000 Dec, and also sold 400,000 Dec. Wilson sold 800,000 Dec.</p>
<p>Volumes were extremely light. The MGE estimated Friday's spring wheat futures volume at 14.27 million bushels, down from 20.782 million on Thursday.</p>
<p>The only MGE barley futures contract to trade Friday was the nearby Dec, which ended nine cents per hundredweight higher at $7.24.</p>
<p>--Greg Frost, 816 561-8671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
