<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67142" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ADM sues former executive for alleged fraud.</title>
<headline>ADM sues former executive for alleged fraud.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Food giant Archer Daniels Midland Co. sued former executive and whistleblower Mark Whitacre, accusing him of stealing millions of dollars from the company between 1991 and 1995.</p>
<p>The suit, filed Thursday in Illinois Circuit Court in Macon County, Ill., alleged that Whitacre wrote phony invoices and contracts to defraud the company of more than $9 million.</p>
<p>The lawsuit says ADM discovered the fraud in 1995.</p>
<p>Whitacre, who headed the company's BioProducts division, was fired in August, 1995, for allegedly stealing millions of dollars from the company.</p>
<p>He has argued that the money was not stolen, but was part of an off-the-books bonus system, according to press reports.</p>
<p>In the lawsuit, ADM accused Whitacre of having the funds wired to numbered bank accounts in Switzerland and Grand Cayman in the Cayman Islands.</p>
<p>Whitacre acted as a government informant for three years in an ongoing federal anti-trust investigation into possible price-fixing in three food and feed additives.</p>
<p>According to a source familiar with the investigation, the Justice Department is pressing ADM to enter a plea agreement regarding the allegations of price fixing.</p>
<p>That investigation involves allegations that ADM and other producers conspired to fix prices of lysine, a livestock feed additive; citric acid, a food additive; and high-fructose corn syrup, a sweetener used in soft drinks and other foods.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
