<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67149" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.H. asked to redefine econ development program.</title>
<headline>N.H. asked to redefine econ development program.</headline>
<dateline>CONCORD, N.H. 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Hampshire's largest business association Friday said the state must redefine its economic development policies to emphasize education and the &quot;learning ethic.&quot;</p>
<p>The report by the Business and Industry Association said the state can no longer just rely on its traditional economic development strengths of low taxes, a strong work ethic and low labor costs.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this report may surprise some people,&quot; said BIA president John Crosier releasing the results of a year-long research effort on the New Hampshire economy. The survey interviewed more than 700 people in the private and public sectors.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a traditional econonomic development plan. What we have discovered is that we live in a world where a strong learning ethic in Hew Hampshire is as important as a strong work ethic,&quot; Crosier said in a prepared statement.</p>
<p>New Hampshire is the only state in the nation with no general income and sales taxes. It has traditionally stressed that tax policy and philosophy of limited government when competing with other states to attract businesses.</p>
<p>BIA recomended the state strengthen its education and worker training systems and plan for an advanced telecommunications system. Officials were also asked to hold an economic opportunity summit.</p>
<p>The &quot;benchmarks&quot; for measuring economic development should include; quality of life, business climate, entrepreneurial climate and the quality of the workforce, the report recommended.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CONCORD, N.H."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
