<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="671587" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Rinascente sales up 4pct Jan-May.</title>
<headline>Italy's Rinascente sales up 4pct Jan-May.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian retail chain Rinascente, which is controlled by the Agnelli family and France's Auchan, registered a four percent rise in turnover in the first five months of 1997 compared with the same period in 1996.</p>
<p>Jan-May turnover was 2.81 billion lire and it reconfirmed the objective of exceeding turnover of 8.0 trillion this year, Rinascente Managing Director Giovanni Cobolli Gigli said.</p>
<p>&quot;Taking account of the trend in consumption the result isn't bad,&quot; he told reporters at a shareholders' meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Just in May growth was 6.7 percent above all due to a recovery in sales in the textiles sector,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>For its subsidiary chain UPIM, sales growth was 2.4 percent in the first five months, Cobolli said.</p>
<p>Rinascente is controlled by Eurofind, a company jointly owned by Agnelli family holding IFIL, which has 51 percent, and French privately owned retail group Auchan, which holds 49 percent.</p>
<p>The shareholders' meeting also appointed a new board to include French representatives and authorised the board to carry out a share buyback up to 50 billion lire as well as granting it permission to decide on a capital increase up to 600 billion lire.</p>
<p>Luigi Arnaudo becomes chairman and Cobolli was confirmed as managing director alongside Benoit Lheureux. The board was cut to 10 members from 11 and will also included Arnaud Mulliez, son of the founder of Auchan.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +392 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
