<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="671633" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian court frees letter bomb suspect.</title>
<headline>Austrian court frees letter bomb suspect.</headline>
<byline>Janet McBride</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian police suffered a setback in their four-year search for the author of more than 20 letter bombs on Wednesday when a Vienna court ordered the release of a 62-year-old computer expert.</p>
<p>The man, named only as Gerhart P, had been in custody for two weeks on suspicion of penning two letters that claimed responsibility for the bombings.</p>
<p>He walked free after Vienna District Court ruled that the police had insufficient evidence to continue holding him.</p>
<p>&quot;My client has been released on two conditions: he must not take up contact with the media nor with anyone involved in the case,&quot; defence lawyer Harald Schuster said after the hearing.</p>
<p>Police arrested Gerhart P earlier this month in connection with two letters sent to current affairs magazines Profil and News in December 1996 and February 1997. Gerhart P maintained his innocence all along.</p>
<p>&quot;The state prosecutor appears to believe that the author of those two claim letters must be the author of all 10 and, continuing the chain of logic, that the same person may also be the bomber,&quot; Schuster said.</p>
<p>Since December 1993, suspected rightwing extremists have killed four people and maimed 13 in five waves of letter and pipe bomb attacks aimed mainly at foreigners and those working for their integration.</p>
<p>A shady group calling itself the Bajuvarian Liberation Army (BLA) has said it is behind the campaign, which has targeted public figures including former Vienna mayor Helmut Zilk and the widowed step-mother of Transport Minister Caspar Einem.</p>
<p>In the most deadly attack so far, four gypsies were killed in the southeastern town of Oberwart in February 1995 as they tried to remove a racist sign attached to a booby-trap bomb.</p>
<p>Experts remain divided on whether the BLA is a neo-Nazi organisation or a group of middle-aged men obsessed with reuniting German-speaking peoples in Bavaria, the Alps and the Danube River basin.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Karl Schloegl brushed off the latest setback in the long-running police investigation but conceded there was no evidence to suggest Gerhart P was involved with the letter bomb attacks.</p>
<p>&quot;The police will continue their inquiries, using all the means at their disposal,&quot; Schloegl said after the government's weekly cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;We are optimistic,&quot; an interior ministry spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Police have come under fire for their handling of the bombings and their failure to make any prosecutions stick.</p>
<p>Two self-confessed neo-Nazis were detained in 1993 on suspicion of being involved in the first wave of attacks, but they were acquitted in 1995 for lack of evidence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
