<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="671626" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria's Klima welcomes Amsterdam EU deal.</title>
<headline>Austria's Klima welcomes Amsterdam EU deal.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian Chancellor Viktor Klima said on Wednesday a hard-won European Union summit deal tying employment and growth to fiscal discipline had cleared the way for a timely start of Europe's single currency in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clear now that all stumbling blocks for a timely start of the currency union in 1999 have been removed,&quot; he told reporters after the government's weekly cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The European Union has turned from an economic union into a union for employment and social safety as well,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Leaders of the 15-nation EU hammered out a new European treaty after two days of intensive talks at the Amsterdam summit, including an employment chapter and providing for expanded cooperation on asylum, immigration and crime-busting.</p>
<p>Austria, ruled by a coalition of Klima's dominant Social Democrats and the junior conservative People's Party, has long been a proponent of putting greater emphasis on employment issues.</p>
<p>However, the government has shied away from openly supporting original French proposals for an &quot;economic government&quot; for the EU because of its monetary dependence on its German neighbour.</p>
<p>The local currency, the schilling, has for the better part of the past two decades been closely tied to the German mark, effectively putting the Austrian central bank on the powerful German Bundesbank's monetary leash.</p>
<p>&quot;The Austrian position that employment should take on more importance in the treaty has prevailed,&quot; Klima said.</p>
<p>&quot;Amsterdam was an important step in the direction of a union of citizens. Overall, one can be content with the success of Amsterdam,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
