<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="671711" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - June 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - June 18.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>--Despite opposition from some of its European Union partners, Denmark seems to have won important guarantees on the environment in the final EU Amsterdam summit document. The Amsterdam deal also allowed Denmark to uphold its opt-outs on asylum, immigration and cross-border policy within EU but prime minister Poul Nyrup Rasmussen said a national referendum would have to be held in early 1998 on the EU reforms.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>--Danish groupings opposed to Copenhagen's adhesion to the European Union accuse prime minister Poul Nyrup Rasmussen of selling out Denmark's opt-outs to the Maastricht Treaty on closer EU integration at the Amsterdam summit.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS-POSTEN</p>
<p>--Denmark's leading banks fear they will lose billions of crowns of business due to allegedly unfair, state-subsidised competition from German financial institutions. The Bonn government has proposed to Brussels that EU member states should be allowed to issue guarantees for public sector-owned banks' debt repayments.</p>
<p>--Ongoing rises in Danish bond prices in the past three weeks have sent mortgage credit bonds down to their lowest level since spring 1994. 30-year interest rates have fallen by 7.2 percent and 10-year paper has plummeted to its lowest level in 40 years, heralding a possible major switch to lower interest level house loans for many Danes.</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--Thorleif Krarup, chief executive of Unidanmark, Denmark's second biggest bank,  predicts a tighter concentration within the Nordic banking sector, where only some six to seven banks have a Nordic profile today and could possibly cooperate more closely on activities such as brokerage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
