<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="671762" id="root" date="1997-06-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: EU leaders to look at human cloning ban.</title>
<headline>EU leaders to look at human cloning ban.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union leaders said on Wednesday they recognised the importance of research into genetic cloning but would look at ways to prevent the technique being used on humans.</p>
<p>A declaration issued at the end of a two-day summit in Amsterdam, which agreed a new EU treaty, asked EU ministers and the European Commission &quot;to examine how to prevent human cloning&quot; when defining policy on research and patents and when implementing existing programmes.</p>
<p>The leaders also stressed the &quot;willingness of member states to take...all necessary measures to ban human cloning.&quot;</p>
<p>While recognising the &quot;great importance&quot; of genetic research, they said &quot;the protection of human beings and the respect of their integrity&quot; were fundamental principles which also had to be taken into consideration.</p>
<p>The Commission already said late last month that it was studying whether to propose a formal ban on cloning humans. Commission President Jacques Santer said then that EU rules should explicitly exclude human cloning from patent protection.</p>
<p>That followed a report by an EU advisory group on biotechnology ethics which called for a ban on &quot;reproductive&quot; human cloning -- creating a genetically identical human being using cells from a child or adult -- saying the technique was &quot;ethically unacceptable&quot; and a safety threat.</p>
<p>The possibility of human cloning has taken on a more realistic dimension since scientists in Scotland, working with the biotechnology company PPL Therapeutics Plc, cloned a sheep known as Dolly from a single cell of another sheep.</p>
<p>Europe is not alone with its concerns, and U.S. President Bill Clinton on Monday proposed a five-year ban on cloning a human being, saying it was morally unacceptable and could undermine society's respect for human life.</p>
<p>Wednesday's EU declaration said the EU leaders would show &quot;increased vigilance&quot; regarding the ethical risks of genetic cloning, but gave no specific views on the use of the technique on animals.</p>
<p>The EU's Group of Advisers on the Ethical Implications of Biotechnology -- made up of outside scientific, legal and ethical experts -- said cloning of farm animals could have medical, agricultural and economic benefits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
