<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672018" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TENNIS-SELES STRUGGLES BEFORE RAIN HALTS DAY'S PLAY.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SELES STRUGGLES BEFORE RAIN HALTS DAY'S PLAY.</headline>
<byline>Clare Fallon</byline>
<dateline>EASTBOURNE, England 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>World number two Monica Seles struggled in cold, windy conditions against eighth seed Brenda Schultz-McCarthy before rain set in to give her a respite at the Eastbourne women's grasscourt championships on Thursday.</p>
<p>Seles, the defending champion and top seed in the traditional Wimbledon warm-up, was trailing 5-7 2-2 in the quarter-final match when the skies opened and play was halted.</p>
<p>Steady rain continued all afternoon, persuading organisers to postpone the quarter-finals until Friday in the hope of brighter weather. The semifinals are also due to be played on Friday.</p>
<p>Natasha Zvereva of Belarus won the opening set of her quarter-final against Frenchwoman Nathalie Tauziat 7-5 on court two before the rain began.</p>
<p>Play had started three hours late on Thursday because of earlier showers and the delay initially seemed to favour Seles who steamed to a 4-1 lead over the 1.88-metre tall Schultz-McCarthy on Devonshire Park's centre court.</p>
<p>The Dutchwoman is the hardest server on the women's tour but she took time to fine-tune her serve, double-faulting to give away the first break in the fourth game.</p>
<p>But once she had got her serve in full working order she began to trouble Seles and provoked her into errors which led to two breaks and a 6-5 lead for Schultz-McCarthy.</p>
<p>The second set was going with serve until the match was interrupted after 41 minutes of play.</p>
<p>In the other quarter-finals fourth-seeded Spaniard Arantxa Sanchez Vicario plays Romanian Irina Spirlea and Japan's Ai Sugiyama meets second seed Jana Novotna of the Czech Republic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EASTBOURNE, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
