<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672062" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RUGBY UNION-INJURIES FORCE FRANCE INTO LATE CHANGES.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-INJURIES FORCE FRANCE INTO LATE CHANGES.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>France were forced to shuffle their back line on Friday after injuries ruled out centre Christophe Lamaison and fly-half Alain Penaud for Saturday's first rugby union test against Australia.</p>
<p>Richard Dourthe was named in midfield while David Aucagne will take the number 10 jersey for the clash at the Sydney Football Stadium.</p>
<p>Tricolores coach Jean-Claude Skrela made six changes from the side that clinched a memorable Five Nations grand slam triumph with victory over Scotland in Paris in March.</p>
<p>&quot;Lamaison and Penaud would have played (against Australia) but the other players will do whatever they can to make sure their absence makes no difference,&quot; Skrela told reporters.</p>
<p>Dourthe, who will assume goal-kicking duties in Lamaison's absence, was named alongside Thomas Castaignede in the centres.</p>
<p>Lamaison, the hero of France's crucial Five Nations victory over England at Twickenham, was sidelined with a groin injury, while Penaud hurt his shoulder in training earlier this week.</p>
<p>Lock Olivier Brouzet forced his way into the side on the strength of a stirring performance in the tour win against Queensland on Tuesday, ousting Hugues Miorin in the process.</p>
<p>In a change to the front row, Christian Califano, who missed the victory over Scotland at Parc des Princes because of suspension, returned at prop in place of Didier Casadei.</p>
<p>Winger Philippe Bernat-Salles was also recalled, while Philippe Carbonneau was given the scrum-half job ahead of Guy Accoceberry.</p>
<p>&quot;Lamaison and Penaud are not available so we will rely on other players. There is no point complaining about injuries because they are part of modern rugby,&quot; Skrela said.</p>
<p>France have beaten Queensland and ACT, who both fielded weakened sides, and an amateur Victoria team in their three tour matches since arriving in Australia 11 days ago.</p>
<p>Skrela said the preparations for a two-test series against the Wallabies had been far from ideal.</p>
<p>&quot;But these days you have to adapt to short tours and be ready for the intensity of a test match,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Both Queensland and ACT were without their test players after Wallaby coach Greg Smith called his squad together last week.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had some good passages of play in all three tour matches but now we have put it together for the whole of a test match,&quot; Skrela said.</p>
<p>Australia, who named their test line-up on June 8, drafted ACT Brumbies fullback Stephen Larkham into the side three days later after Matt Burke succumbed to a niggling groin injury.</p>
<p>Australia and France will meet again in the second test at Ballymore in Brisbane on June 28.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>France - 15-Jean-Luc Sadourny; 14-Philippe Bernat-Salles, 13-Richard Dourthe, 12-Thomas Castaignede, 11-David Venditti; 10-David Aucagne, 9-Philippe Carbonneau; 8-Fabien Pelous, 7-Olivier Magne, 6-Abdel Benazzi (captain), 5-Olivier Merle, 4-Olivier Brouzet, 3-Christian Califano, 2-Marc Dal Maso, 1-Franck Tournaire.</p>
<p>Australia - 15-Stephen Larkham, 14-Ben Tune, 13-Jason Little, 12-Pat Howard, 11-Joe Roff; 10-Tim Horan, 9-George Gregan; 8-Daniel Manu, 7-David Wilson, 6-Brett Robinson, 5-John Eales (captain), 4-David Giffen, 3-Ewen McKenzie, 2-Marco Caputo, 1-Richard Harry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
