<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672044" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TENNIS-PEN PICTURES OF WIMBLEDON FAVOURITES.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-PEN PICTURES OF WIMBLEDON FAVOURITES.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pen pictures of the men's favourites at Wimbledon, which starts on Monday:</p>
<p>PETE SAMPRAS (U.S.) ATP ranking 1, seeded 1. Age 25, height 1.85m. Grand Slam victories 9: Australian Open 1994 1997, Wimbledon 1993 1994 1995, U.S. Open 1990 1993 1995 1996. The man to beat at Wimbledon, a consummate all-round athlete who can play every shot. Fierce serve and volleyer, although serve has been off-key recently and he was beaten in third round of French Open and in quarter-finals at Queen's Club. Began playing tennis at age of seven and became youngest U.S. Open winner aged 19 years 28 days. Coached by Paul Annacone since Tim Gullikson, his coach and mentor, became ill and died last year.</p>
<p>GORAN IVANISEVIC (Croatia) ATP ranking 4, seeded 2. Age 25, height 1.94m. No Grand Slam victories but twice runner-up at Wimbledon, in 1992 to Andre Agassi and in 1994 to Sampras. Big server who is consequently well suited to grass. Led ace tally last year with a record 1,477 at an average of 15.4 per match. Has reputation for having a quick temper but has been more controlled of late. Had good Wimbledon warm-up at Queen's where he was runner-up to Australia's Mark Philippoussis, another big hitter. Dry sense of humour. Enjoys playing basketball.</p>
<p>YEVGENY KAFELNIKOV (Russia) ATP ranking 5, seeded 3 Age 23. height 1.90m. Grand Slam victory: French Open 1996. Was sidelined for three months with a broken finger in his right hand sustained using a punch-bag in Australia in January. Made a comeback by reaching quarter-finals in Rome and semifinals in Hamburg. Then made the French Open, where he lost to eventual winner Gustavo Kuerten in the quarter-finals. Had a good grass warm-up at Halle where he beat Boris Becker in the semis and Petr Korda in a close final. Can play on any surface and is very strong. Nicknamed Kalashnikov for the ferocity of his strokes. Born and lives in Sochi on the Black Sea where he enjoys fishing. Enjoys watching football and is a Spartak Moscow fan.</p>
<p>RICHARD KRAJICEK (Netherlands) ATP ranking 6, seeding 4. age 25 height 1.96m. Grand Slam victories 1: Wimbledon 1996. Another big man with a huge serve, Krajicek beat Sampras in straight sets in the quarter-finals last year, becoming first Dutchman to win a Grand Slam title. Has suffered in past from tendinitis in both knees but still finished second to Ivanisevic in the ATP ace-list last year with 969. Began playing at the age of four. Son of Czech immigrants, he also enjoys playing golf</p>
<p>BORIS BECKER (Germany) ATP ranking 18, seeding 8, age 29, height 1.90m, Grand Slam victories 6: Australian Open 1991, 1996 Wimbledon 1985, 1986, 1989 U.S. Open 1990. The three-times champion has been dogged by wrist injuries since tearing a tendon in his right wrist in the third round against South African Neville Godwin 12 months ago. He missed the French Open but the seeding committee have taken only minimal notice of his world ranking and seeded him eighth. Has been runner-up at Wimbledon three times since his last title in 1989.</p>
<p>MARK PHILIPPOUSSIS (Australia) ATP ranking 13, seeding 7, age 20, height 1.94m, No Grand Slam victories but tipped by many as a potential champion of the near future. His pre-Wimbledon victory over Goran Ivanisevic in the final at Queen's Club demonstrated his serving ability, although he was beaten in the second round of his only previous Wimbledon appearance. Born in Melbourne of Greek parentage, he is a previous winner of the Wimbledon junior doubles title.</p>
<p>MICHAEL CHANG (U.S) ATP ranking 2, seeding 5, age 25, height 1.75m, Grand Slam victories 1: 1989 French Open. Chang's Wimbledon record shows only one quarter-final appearance in nine visits, but he remains convinced he still has potential on grass. A tireless worker who compensates for his lack of height and power with astonishing speed around the court, Chang was beaten in the first round last year but reached the final at both the Australian Open and U.S. Open, only to be beaten by Boris Becker and Pete Sampras respectively. An avid fisherman, he also breeds tropical fish.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
