<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672196" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Robust July demand, Iraq delays lift N. Sea crudes.</title>
<headline>Robust July demand, Iraq delays lift N. Sea crudes.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crudes were firmer across the board on Thursday, boosted by strong early July demand and uncertainty over when Iraq would resume crude exports under the U.N. oil-for-food deal, traders said.</p>
<p>Forties and Norwegian Ekofisk were in particularly strong demand with at least three cargoes of each grade trading at firmer differentials than the last reported deals, they said.</p>
<p>French refiners featured as the main buyers, paying Dated Brent +20 cents for Ekofisk and Dated +25 cents for Forties.</p>
<p>Dated Brent was also firmer but talk of a trade as strong as Aug Brent -30 cents could not be confirmed.</p>
<p>&quot;There is precious little left in any grade for the first 10 days so if you want barrels you're going to have to pay solid numbers,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>August Brent was unchanged at $17.77 a barrel by 1721 GMT, tracking IPE futures, but 15-day intermonth paper spreads firmed throughout the day.</p>
<p>July/August traded at least three times at -16 cents early in the session, a cent or two firmer than late U.S. dealing on Wednesday, and by late afternoon was talked around -15 cents.</p>
<p>Brent CFDs for June 23-27 jumped six cents from trade at August -31 cents amid a scarcity of the benchmark grade.</p>
<p>Five of the first six cargoes from the July loading programme are in the hands of a European major oil company. The sixth, a July 4-6 loader which turned wet on Thursday, was kept by Wall Street trader Phibro.</p>
<p>Traders said Iraq's refusal to resume exports until the remaining $800 million of revenue from the first 180 days of the U.N. deal has been spent on humanitarian supplies was providing a supportive backdrop.</p>
<p>&quot;The longer the Iraqi delay the tighter everything starts to look,&quot; said a North Sea trader.</p>
<p>-- Mark Thompson, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7930</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
