<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67218" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Election not seen changing Freedom to Farm ag plan.</title>
<headline>Election not seen changing Freedom to Farm ag plan.</headline>
<byline>Charles Abbott</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Republican-written &quot;Freedom to Farm&quot; law -- popular with farmers -- would face only minor tinkering next year even if Democrats take control of the U.S. House, leaders from each party said Friday.</p>
<p>Texas Democrat Charles Stenholm, who probably would chair the House Agriculture Committee if Republicans lose control, said lawmakers would look at modifications like a better crop insurance programs or &quot;risk assurance&quot; against catastrophic plunges in market prices or crop output.  </p>
<p>Despite reservations, President Clinton signed &quot;Freedom to Farm&quot; into law in April, erasing a New Deal-era system that limited crop acreage. In exchange for nearly unlimited power to plant what they want, farmers accepted under &quot;Freedom to Farm&quot; a schedule of guaranteed payments that would decline in size each year through 2002.</p>
<p>Stenholm and Yeutter identified international trade rules as the area for action in the near term, to assure removal of trade barriers to U.S. farm exports.  </p>
<p>If he becomes chairman, Stenholm said, the House committee would be &quot;very involved in the international trade area.&quot; It would keep an eye on new trade negotiations and try to make sure past agreements were heeded.</p>
<p>Yeutter said the White House had ignored ag trade issues for the most part. He said other nations were beginning to use &quot;food safety hinderances&quot; -- disguised barriers -- to block U.S. products.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to have challenge&quot; those techniques, he said.  </p>
<p>Stenholm said the 15 percent tax cut proposed by Republican nominee Bob Dole would drive up the federal deficit and imperil funding for agricultural programs.</p>
<p>Yeutter said Dole's plan was sound and that a Dole administration was a reliable bet to curb unneeded spending.</p>
<p>Democrats will retake House control, Stenholm predicted, but said it would come through election of moderates. A Democratic-led House, he said, &quot;is going to be much more moderate and under a Speaker (Newt) Gingrich,&quot; the Georgia Republican now the speaker of the House.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
