<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672337" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Global ban in ivory trade eased for African states.</title>
<headline>Global ban in ivory trade eased for African states.</headline>
<byline>Cris Chinaka</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A world forum on endangered species lifted a seven-year-old global ban in ivory trade on Thursday to allow three southern African states to conditionally sell ivory to Japan from their &quot;excess&quot; elephant herds.</p>
<p>The 10-day Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species (CITES) backed an &quot;experimental&quot; deal worked out on Wednesday by a 19-member committee after the conference had been bogged down in acrimonious debate over what many saw as demands for loose trade that could endanger elephants worldwide.</p>
<p>Seventy-six countries voted for the proposal and 21 against. There were 20 abstentions in the secret ballot on the proposal by Zimbabwe, Botswana and Namibia.</p>
<p>Botswana would be entitled to sell 25.3 tonnes of raw ivory, Zimbabwe 20 tonnes and Namibia 13.8 tonnes &quot;under an international reporting and monitoring system&quot; in 1999, according to the amended draft.</p>
<p>But it says no ivory trade would be allowed to take place if the convention was not satisfied with the monitoring measures proposed by Zimbabwe, Botswana, Namibia and Japan.</p>
<p>The 138-member CITES also transferred the elephants of the three countries to Appendix II -- a list of endangered species tradeable under control -- from the no-trade Appendix I list.</p>
<p>&quot;But the transfer would include no international trade before 18 months after the transfer to Appendix II comes into effect. Thereafter an experimental quota of raw ivory may be traded with Japan,&quot; the approved amendment says, indicating the quotas each country would be allowed to sell.</p>
<p>On the individual proposals, Zimbabwe's application was approved by 77 votes against 23, and 20 abstentions, Namibia by 74 votes against 22 and 24 abstentions and Botswana by 75 votes against 21 and 24 abstentions.</p>
<p>Zimbabwean officials led some African delegates in singing and dancing after the vote.</p>
<p>Conference chairman David Brackett of Canada called for a straight vote, refusing to open further debate on grounds that it had eaten too much time at the 10-day convention ending on Friday.</p>
<p>But afterwards the U.S. delegate told the conference his country had voted against all the proposals because it strongly believed commercial trade in ivory would endanger elephants not just in southern Africa, but around the globe.</p>
<p>&quot;But we recognise and respect the decision made here and are going to work to ensure that elephants are not exposed to risk,&quot; he said of promises by CITES to ensure rigorous controls.</p>
<p>&quot;For the sake of the elephant we cannot afford to fail,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>European Union states had abstained from voting because they had failed to reach a consensus on the issue, an EU official said.</p>
<p>The United States and some EU members, especially France, had led a strong world lobby -- which included several African states -- against easing the 1989 blanket ban in ivory trade, arguing that it would rekindle poaching and put elephants at risk.</p>
<p>Australia and Israel also opposed reopening trade but Japan and Switzerland backed the proposal, both accusing the rich North of trying to stop sustainable utilisation of wildlife.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe Environment and Tourism Minister Chen Chimutengwende adopted a generally belligerant attitude during the conference, making blanket accusations that some opponents of the ivory trade were doing so on grounds of race.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no other explanation,&quot; he told state Zimbabwe media.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe, Botswana and Namibia have argued for ivory trade, saying that their combined elephant herd of about 150,000 has been growing steadily and was doing so even before the world ban.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NAMIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
