<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672367" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - June 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - June 19.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Thursday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- Gencor Ltd would seperate its precious metal and other mining assets into two world-class companies in August, raising more than $1 billion for expansion and establishing itself as an internationally diversified mining group, chairman Brian Gilbertson said.</p>
<p>- The Johannesburg Stock Exchange saw a record 2.77 billion rand turnover on Wednesday, boosted by about two billion worth of deals brokered by SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>- Diamond sales by De Beers' marketing arm, the Central Selling Organisation rose to a record $2.88 billion in the first half, 4.8 percent up on the same period last year.</p>
<p>- Reserve Bank governor Chris Stals on Wednesday dashed hopes that he would cut the bank rate while money supply and credit extension remained high.</p>
<p>- South Africa's two largest defence projects, the Rooivalk attack helicopter and the air force's guided missiles systems, are to be scrapped and other projects scaled down dramatically, armaments industry sources said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- The JSE had its biggest trading day in history on Wednesday as shares worth just under 2,8 billion rand changed hands. But most of the activity was ascribed to a massive portfolio exchange organised by SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>- Plans for a 2,5 billion rand super retail and leisure centre in Midrand area of Randjesfontein, complete with casino, horserace track, hotel, golf course and 180 000m retail complex, were disclosed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>- The long awaited bill to give administrative autonomy to the South African Revenue Service (SARS) was tabled in parliament on Wednesday under a barrage of criticism from opposition parties claiming the bill did not ensure the SARS became an effective tax-collecting institution.</p>
<p>- Kanteen Koppie, a 110-year-old mine in the Northern Cape which has been declared a national monument, should yield its first diamonds this week after more than 50 years, under a pilot project established by the African United Small Mining Association, a spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAKE BEELD</p>
<p>- Gencor on Wednesday unveiled plans to flex its global investment muscle by listing its base metals group Billiton Plc in London and raise $1 billion in an international equity placement.</p>
<p>- South Africa's Aventura holiday resort operation will be next on the list of state assets to be privatised. Proposals are expected to be discussed in parliament soon.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- The multibillion-rand armaments industry is on the brink of collapse as major contracts, among them the Rooivalk attack helicopter project, face being shelved in the wake of a 700 million rand cut to the defence budget.</p>
<p>- Had a concerned French diplomat not rescued paralysed rugby player Max Brito from captivity in the hands of Ivory Coast withdoctors, the former World Cup winger might never have lived to arrive in Cape Town for a benefit dinner and fundraising banquet held in his honour in the city on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>- Mineral and Energy Affairs Minister Penuell Maduna says he will soon hand President Nelson Mandela and Parliament the findings of an independent probe into alleged abuses of the Strategic Fuel Fund.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
