<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672384" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: NATO displays firepower in Bosnia exercise.</title>
<headline>NATO displays firepower in Bosnia exercise.</headline>
<byline>Danilo Krstanovic</byline>
<dateline>GLAMOC, Bosnia 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The NATO-led peace force demonstrated its military might on Thursday in an exercise in Bosnia intended to show that the alliance was ready to use its firepower to prevent another Balkan war from erupting.</p>
<p>U.S. Apache helicopters blasted targets with rockets, British army artillery boomed and British &quot;Warrior&quot; armoured fighting vehicles rolled towards an imaginary enemy in a valley near the western town of Glamoc.</p>
<p>Operation &quot;Joint Resolve&quot; was devised to provide useful training and to demonstrate that the Stabilisation Force (SFOR) was a &quot;robust force&quot; capable of rapidly reacting to prevent or halt any outbreak of violence, NATO spokesmen said.</p>
<p>Some 700 to 800 troops from the U.S. Aviation Task Force, Norwegian mechanised infantry and British artillery and armoured units participated in the exercise.</p>
<p>Major Paul Thorne of the Fourth Regiment Royal artillery said this week's exercise conveyed a clear message to Bosnia's former warring factions who signed the Dayton peace agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;Mess with Dayton, mess with us and this is what's going to come your way,&quot; Thorne said.</p>
<p>Sarajevo media published scenarios in April predicting another war in Bosnia, with re-armed Moslem-led forces capturing Serb-controlled territory in the northwest where Moslems and Croats were expelled during the 1992-95 conflict.</p>
<p>Western envoys fear that the peace in Bosnia could collapse if NATO troops withdraw as scheduled in June 1998.</p>
<p>NATO countries have yet to decide on a course of action after the mandate for the 31,000-strong force, half the size of the previous Implementation Force, expires in a year.</p>
<p>NATO-led troops have separated rival armies, enforced the storage of heavy weapons, rebuilt roads and bridges and helped remove checkpoints hindering free movement across old front lines.</p>
<p>But international envoys have struggled to enforce political elements of the peace treaty, with nationalist authorities obstructing the return of refugees to conquered territory.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GLAMOC, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
