<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672437" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Lithuania to host regional reconciliation summit.</title>
<headline>Lithuania to host regional reconciliation summit.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish and Lithuanian presidents will host a regional summit in Vilnius in September on reconciliation and cooperation among former Soviet-bloc countries, the two presidents said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We...decided to organise a conference of the region's heads of state to discuss reconciliation and good coexistence among the former communist states,&quot; Lithuanian President Algirdas Brazauskas, said at a joint news conference with Poland's Aleksander Kwasniewski.</p>
<p>Brazauskas, on a two-day visit to Poland, said he had so far invited the presidents of Poland, Finland, Latvia, Estonia, Ukraine, Belarus and Russian President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>Eastern Europe's main dividing line is between former Moscow allies, which shed communism after 1989 and now want to join NATO, and Russia, which opposes the Western military alliance's eastward expansion.</p>
<p>Poland, the Czech Republic and Hungary have been mentioned by the United States as the first batch of East European countries that will be invited to join NATO.</p>
<p>Kwasniewski reiterated his full support for efforts of other former Warsaw Pact members, notably Lithuania, to enter the alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;Poland, which is very happy it will soon start accession talks with NATO and the European Union, is convinced that there is a place for Lithuania in these structures. We will do everything to be Lithuania's advocate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said he also agreed with Brazauskas that Poland and Lithuania should strengthen economic, cultural, customs and military cooperation.</p>
<p>Another burning issue in the region, which might be discussed during the Vilnius summit is the authoritarian rule of Belarus President Alexander Lukashenko, blasted by international human-rights watchdogs but supported by Moscow.</p>
<p>Poland, Ukraine and the Baltic Republics expressed concern earlier this year over actions by Lukashenko, who last November won sweeping powers in a controversial constitutional referendum and has been keeping pressure on political opposition, independent trade unions and the media.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
