<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672447" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: FOCUS-Russia launches new bonds, opens up trading.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Russia launches new bonds, opens up trading.</headline>
<byline>Anna Smirnova</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia modernised its government bond market on Thursday when it launched two new fixed-rate securities and said dealers could trade with clients outside exchange hours.</p>
<p>The moves coincide with the launch of a massive $2 billion Eurobond, which will be modern Russia's third foray onto international markets, and marked further modernisation of a market where yields have fallen in recent weeks to record lows.</p>
<p>The two new bonds, a 2.90 trillion rouble ($503 million) issue maturing in June 1999 and a 1.05 trillion rouble issue maturing in June 2000, pay fixed annual interest of 20 percent.</p>
<p>The new bonds provide a welcome alternative to Russian investors, who have been hoping to switch funds into another new market of fixed-rate debt. The new market, to be launched on Friday, is for restructured regional debt known as &quot;farm bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>Previously, Russia's longest outstanding bond, sold only last Wednesday, matured in mid-June 1999, while the first fixed-rate issue, launched in February, matures in early June 1999.</p>
<p>The first 500 billion rouble fixed-rate bond has been popular with foreign investors because other Russian OFZ bonds have a floating rate determined by the yield of GKO discount Treasury bills maturing when the coupon is paid. As a result, the interest can fluctuate wildly from one coupon to the next.</p>
<p>The new bonds were consolidated from a total of 11 fixed-rate issues, which have never traded but been held in the central bank's portfolio since last year.</p>
<p>Central bank sources, commenting on the new bonds, said two more 10-percent bonds maturing in 2000 and 2002 were issued in March but were still being held in the central bank portfolio.</p>
<p>Demand for the new bonds was steady but not feverish, traders said, with turnover in the two issues on their first day at 150 billion roubles. The central bank made it clear the recent fall in yields below 20 percent was behind the decision to launch the new bonds now.</p>
<p>&quot;There is now an inverse yield curve on the market. In other words, rates on long issues are lower than on short ones. That means market players tend to expect a further fall in yields,&quot; said Konstantin Korishchenko, head of the open market operations department at the Central Bank of Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;How low they go is up to them. It seems that now a yield of 19.5 percent for three years suits them,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The total volume of the new bonds, restructured from federal government credits to the regions, predominantly for agriculture, is only nine trillion roubles, and they pay fixed annual interest of only 10 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;With such a rapid fall in T-bill yields to levels originally predicted for the end of the year, banks pinned their hopes on the farm bonds. But after the Finance Ministry set such a high price on them, the euphoria evaporated,&quot; said Oleg Surkov, Probiznesbank's capital market operations head. &quot;So, the appearance of the new federal paper, with a lower risk, is very timely.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers say the farm bonds are unlikely to siphon off many funds from the GKO T-bill and OFZ government bond market because of their high price, greater risk and low liquidity.</p>
<p>But the new fixed-rate OFZ bonds are particularly attractive to investors who want to lock in the current market yield of about 20 percent on hopes it will fall more.</p>
<p>Dealers said long-term investors, not speculators, will be interested in the bonds. Non-residents, obliged to repatriate funds until year-end at rates influenced by the central bank, can only get a currency yield of about 13 percent for now.</p>
<p>Traders said the decision to allow dealers to trade with clients at specific rates at certain hours off the exchange would not necessarily boost volumes. It will make it easier for dealers to service major clients and to handle large volumes of orders, Korishchenko said.</p>
<p>--Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
