<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672587" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>PARAGUAY: Mercosur aims to add new sectors to customs union.</title>
<headline>Mercosur aims to add new sectors to customs union.</headline>
<byline>Axel Bugge</byline>
<dateline>ASUNCION 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of the Mercosur trade bloc need to incorporate new sectors of their economies into the customs union to deepen their integration, leaders of the South American group said on Thursday.</p>
<p>After a two-day summit in Asuncion, the heads of state of Argentina, Brazil, Paraguay and Uruguay agreed to strengthen the customs union, to consolidate a common trade policy and advance towards the construction of the common market.  </p>
<p>The leaders said fresh initiatives were necessary to keep up the bloc's integration process moving forward.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important to underline that the centre of Mercosur's strategy should focus on the achievement of new issues, like services and government purchases,&quot; Argentine President Carlos Menem said in his speech to fellow heads of state.</p>
<p>The Mercosur bloc, established in 1991, reached a free trade agreement with Chile last year and a similar pact with Bolivia more recently.  </p>
<p>An Argentine working paper obtained by Reuters pointed to the liberalization of the financinal, communications and transport service sectors as key areas. It said Brazil, which had resisted opening the services sectors, has shown a willingness to negotiate for the first time.</p>
<p>Uruguayan President Julio Sanguinetti agreed with the Argentine view. &quot;The signal is this -- deepen the Mercosur, open the discussion of new issues such as services and government purchases ...,&quot; he said at a press conference after the meeting.  </p>
<p>The Argentine paper said Mercosur members should open the market for public tenders for the purchase of goods and public services contracts. It argued for equal access to such tenders for companies from across the bloc.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential market for governmental purchases within the Mercosur is estimated at between $60 billion and $70 billion,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>At the meeting, the presidents also agreed to strengthen political ties with associate members Chile and Bolivia and set a goal of closing free-trade deals with Peru, Ecuador, Colombia and Venezuela before the end of 1997.</p>
<p>((--Mercosur Summit, 595 981 444175))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MRCSL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PARA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="URU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ASUNCION"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PARAGUAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
