<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672611" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>DOMINICAN REPUBLIC: Rights mission cites overcrowded Dominican jails.</title>
<headline>Rights mission cites overcrowded Dominican jails.</headline>
<dateline>SANTO DOMINGO 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Organisation of American States human rights delegation said on Thursday that the Dominican Republic's prisons were badly overcrowded and criticised the slow pace of the nation's justice system.</p>
<p>According to official data, there are 30 prisons in the Dominican Republic designed to hold 6,971 inmates, but they currently house more than 11,000 people.</p>
<p>But the OAS's Inter-American Commission on Human Rights said the most serious problem in the nation's prisons was the amount of time it took for people arrested to be tried.</p>
<p>Prisoners &quot;live in very difficult conditions,&quot; Alvaro Tirado Mejia, an official travelling with the mission, told reporters. &quot;The problem is a result of severe overcrowding and a justice system that does not function as quickly as it should.&quot;</p>
<p>The mission had been in the Dominican Republic since Monday, and operated with the government's cooperation.</p>
<p>The most well known of the nation's prisons is La Victoria near Santo Domingo, where about 3,000 prisoners are being held in a 40-year-old facility intended to hold only 800. La Victoria, constructed during the dictatorship of Rafael Victoria, has seen several riots in recent months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DOMR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAMS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTO DOMINGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DOMINICAN REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
