<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672711" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico says lieutenant of top drug band arrested.</title>
<headline>Mexico says lieutenant of top drug band arrested.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-06-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>An expert in intercepting telecommunications for the powerful Tijuana-based Arellano Felix drug cartel was arrested in San Diego, California, Mexican authorities said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The attorney general's office (PGR) said in a statement that police in San Diego, supported by the PGR, on Tuesday arrested Gabriel Valdes Mainero, also known as &quot;The Crazy Radio&quot; or &quot;The Engineer.&quot;</p>
<p>According to U.S. and Mexican officials, the Arellano Felix brothers operate one of Mexico's leading drug cartels from Tijuana, the border city across from San Diego.</p>
<p>Although the Arellano Felix cartel is not as large as the empire run by rival Amado Carrillo Fuentes, the Tijuana-based cartel is considered to be more violent.</p>
<p>&quot;Gabriel Valdes Mainero is an expert in telecommunications and administered some of the communications systems used by the mentioned criminal organisation, including the illicit interception of private communications, which were used by the organisation to avoid capture,&quot; the PGR said.</p>
<p>Authorities will begin extradition proceedings to bring Valdes Mainero back to Mexico for prosecution on arms trafficking charges, the PGR said.</p>
<p>His brother, Emilio Valdes Mainero, was captured in the United States in 1996 and was being sought for extradition along with Alfredo Hodoyan Palacios, another lieutenant of the Arellano Felix brothers, the PGR said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
