<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67274" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Mediaset sees first half profits leap.</title>
<headline>Mediaset sees first half profits leap.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian television and advertising group Mediaset on Friday reported a sharp 53.4 percent rise in first half 1996 profits as its debts shrank dramatically after the group's flotation on the Milan stock market.</p>
<p>The group which is 50 percent owned by media magnate Silvio Berlusconi's Fininvest empire saw its first half pretax profits rise to 497.4 billion lire ($326 million) from 324.7 billion, while turnover rose a mere 3.7 percent to 1.66 trillion lire.</p>
<p>Mediaset, which controls major Italian independent TV stations Canale 5, Italia Uno and Retequattro and Italy's biggest advertiser Publitalia 80 raised nearly two trillion lire by floating some 20 percent of its shares on the Milan bourse.</p>
<p>By end-June debt had collapsed almost two trillion lire to 285.8 billion lire, while the interest bill the group pays on its debt shrank to 26.5 billion lire from 126.7 billion lire.</p>
<p>Mediaset had already sold around 30 percent of its shares before the flotation to a number of core shareholders such as media groups Kirch and Nethold, and a string of Italian banks and international investment banks.</p>
<p>It said Publitalia revenues rose 6.2 percent in the first half, but added that Mediaset overall revenues were depressed by the high level of Mediaset advertising on its own channels during May and June in the run-up to its flotation.</p>
<p>The company said that its share of the Italian TV market held largely constant at around 42.7 percent compared to 1995.</p>
<p>Analysts said that the figures were largely expected and showed the benefit of the share sales, but many continued to express doubts about the group's future potential due to its lack of exposure to the fast-growing area of pay-TV and its absence of significant exposure outside Italy.</p>
<p>&quot;We are cautious on the stock as its growth prospects do not seem good set against a reviving state broadcaster RAI and tighter TV regulations in the pipeline,&quot; said one media industry analyst with an investment bank in London.</p>
<p>Legislation is passing through the Italian parliament to limit advertising time on Italian TV and the market share of leading TV market players.</p>
<p>The shares were floated at 7,000 lire and started trading on the Milan bourse in early July. They closed on Friday up 0.33 percent at 7,338 lire before the release of the results. (($1.1,524 lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
