<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672743" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's SFO yet to complete report into Maori TV.</title>
<headline>NZ's SFO yet to complete report into Maori TV.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Serious Fraud Office has yet to complete its investigation into the affairs of pilot Maori language broadcaster Aotearoa Television Network, a spokeswoman said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;ATN is still under investigation and no time frame has been indicated (for the release of the report),&quot; SFO spokeswoman Antoinette Miller said, quoting acting SFO director Judge Ron Jamieson.</p>
<p>Sources in parliament had speculated earlier in the week that the report would be completed by today.  </p>
<p>It is expected to be referred to interested parties for comment before being released, including to New Zealand First MP Tukoroirangi Morgan who was a director and presenter at the network.</p>
<p>The registrar of companies is also investigating ATN.</p>
<p>New Zealand First leader Winston Peters has said Morgan's future in the NZ First caucus would be left open until the SFO reported.  </p>
<p>Opposition MPs have called for Morgan to resign after it was revealed he had spent $4000 of ATN money before becoming an MP on expensive clothes. Morgan said he had authority to spend the money, but staff at the station have denied this.</p>
<p>The resignation calls were renewed earlier this month after Morgan admitted seeking payment for a television interview and then misleading Peters about his knowledge of it.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
