<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672725" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - NZ Business weeklies - June 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - NZ Business weeklies - June 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE NATIONAL BUSINESS REVIEW</p>
<p>Cabinet to decide on Peters' wine-box tab: The government is debating whether it will pay Winston Peters' legal fees to allow the Treasurer and New Zealand First leader to be represented at the wine-box judicial-review proceedings. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>No-show snow: Corporate backers such as Mount Cook Group, Telecom and American Express are anxiously watching the weather forecast as they wait to see whether they will recoup millions invested in Queenstown's Mount Cook Line Winter Festival which starts on Saturday. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Police Card system hits further snags: Police are in talks with Telecom over another problem with their Card 111 emergency system, this time involving the caller identification technology on which the system depends to trace calls. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Agriculture now more a rib than backbone of our economy: The importance of farming to the national economy is on a steady decline, according to figures in MAF's annual State of New Zealand Agriculture (Sonza), published this week. Page 5.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Budget paints pretty picture of coalition: Next week's Budget promises to be more significant as a political branding exercise for the coalition government than as an economic document. Page 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Committee examines Wool Board: Agriculture Minister Lockwood Smith has handed the controversy over future funding of the Wool Board to the select committee dealing with producer board reform. Page 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Trendsetting compensation deal for Ngai Tahu close: A benchmark land-claim settlement is believed to have only a few issues to tie down before a full agreement can be reached between the South Island's Ngai Tahu and the Crown over the iwi's 148-year-old grievance. Page 12.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>West Coasters seek share of Timberlands' exotic estate: The government is considering a request from West Coast mayors and forestry interests for Timberlands' $80 million exotic forest estate. Page 14.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT BUSINESS WEEKLY</p>
<p>Float and listing for Sky tv: Sky Television's shareholders are preparing to float the pay-tv operator and list it on the stock exchange. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Hart buys into A$700m lawsuit: Since making his $220 million, 14.9 percent foray into Burns Philp late last week, Auckland entrepreneur Graeme Hart has made no moves to settle with Sir Ron Brierley a A$700 million lawsuit against the Australian food group. Page 3.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Skellerup to restructure: Maine Investments is expected to restructure its subsidiary, the Skellerup Group and sever its troublesome retail arm. Page 6.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Birch breaches spirit of coalition agreement: Finance Minister Bill Birch may have undermined Treasurer Winston Peters's clauses in the coalition agreement. Page 6.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
