<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672721" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>MAN QUESTIONED OVER MISSING TODDLER</p>
<p>The man who was minding missing 14 month old Moe toddler Jayden Leskie, is now being questioned at Moe Police station in Victoria.</p>
<p>Greg Domaszviecz, arrived at the police station shortly before three o'clock (AEST) accompanied by his lawyer, Paul Vale.</p>
<p>He returned to Moe from from Melbourne this afternoon, to talk to detectives investigating the case.</p>
<p>Earlier today police were investigating an overnight break-in at the house where the missing toddler was last seen.</p>
<p>Police are analysing blood samples taken from the house as part of that investigation.</p>
<p>Meanwhile police say bogus information about the abduction has hampered their search for the child.</p>
<p>They say a number of people have supplied misleading details to investigators who have wasted valuable time as a result.</p>
<p>The search for 14 month-old Jaidyn has resumed around Newborough and Moe's Lake Narracan in Eastern Victoria.</p>
<p>Police say they hope the boy is still alive, but can't discount the chance that he's met with foul play.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>RURAL JOBS FORGOTTEN</p>
<p>Federal and State governments have been accused of leaving rural job seekers in the lurch.</p>
<p>Wayne Wharton, from the Kooma Land Corporation in Western Queensland, says no one is looking for alternatives for the thousands of rural workers who have lost their jobs in recent years.</p>
<p>Mr Wharton says governments appear to be pre-occupied with urban unemployment and industrial jobs.</p>
<p>He says if workers from a Geelong car factory or a Newcastle mine were in the same position as rural workers there would be dozens of public servants and social workers looking for alternatives.</p>
<p>Mr Wharton says rural industry has carried the nation for the last 20 years but has hit hard times now.</p>
<p>However he says there seems little interest from government in addressing the issue.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HARRADINE CALLS FOR TAX RELIEF</p>
<p>Independent Senator, Brian Harradine, has called on the federal government to look at tax relief for families affected by the proposed Common Youth Allowance.</p>
<p>Senator Harradine says families will be using taxable income to meet the extra costs incurred because of the new system and he says that should be reviewed.</p>
<p>The proposed allowance will replace Austudy, the dole and other payments for people between 16 and 25 and will be subject to a parental means test for those aged 18 to 20.</p>
<p>Senator Harradine, who holds a deciding vote in the Senate, says the allowance will impose a financial burden on families where members no longer get the dole.</p>
<p>He says the government should seriously consider offering those families some form of tax relief.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>POLITICIANS CRITICISED FOR STIRRING UP FEAR</p>
<p>Queensland's Criminal Justice Commission has urged politicians to take a responsible approach to law and order issues.</p>
<p>The organisation today released a study finding there is no crime epidemic in Queensland.</p>
<p>The CJC's Research Division head, David Brereton, has criticised politicians for stirring up fear over crime rates.</p>
<p>Dr Brereton says parliamentary debate on the issue has been high on emotion and &quot;quick fix&quot; ideas but short on evidence.</p>
<p>Today's report finds there has been no upsurge in crime over the last three years but there has been a dramatic increase in the number of people in prison.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>LAST DITCH APPEAL TO THE QUEEN</p>
<p>A group which has written an open letter to the Queen asking her to raise Aboriginal issues with John Howard says it is not concerned if the move embarrasses the Prime Minister.</p>
<p>Church and community groups have written the letter which appears in London's Independent newspaper.</p>
<p>Group representative Lynne Thorstensen says the Queen is their last recourse to improve the treatment of Aborigines.</p>
<p>Ms Thorstensen says it may be absurd that the Queen is still the Australian Head of State, but it does mean she is the final source of appeal.</p>
<p>She says the the treatment of Aborigines, which the letter describes as a tale of treachery, disease and murder, is so serious it is of international concern.</p>
<p>Ms Thorstensen says the issues are of similar importance to human rights issues in Rwanda and Bosnia.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FARMERS FEEL DISQUIET OVER POLITICAL TRENDS</p>
<p>The National Farmers' Federation says it is viewing the Hanson phenomenon in Australian politics with growing disquiet.</p>
<p>NFF President Don McGauchie has told aspiring rural leaders it does not represent the type of leadership the nation needs.</p>
<p>Mr McGauchie says racism concerns have led one Malaysian property investor to freeze a planned $40 million development and an exporter has agreed to remove &quot;made in Australia&quot; labels because Asian buyers complained the brand had become a liability.</p>
<p>He says while Australians want reassurance, it cannot be achieved by pretending the outside world does not exist.</p>
<p>Mr McGauchie says 30 years ago Australia was in a comfort zone with subsidised production that became uncompetitive but that has canged.</p>
<p>He says the centre of economic activity has also moved and is now in Asia.</p>
<p>Mr McGauchie says Australia needs leaders commited to change for the country's long term benefit.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
