<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672844" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore rubber in RSS3 deals, Bridgestone buys.</title>
<headline>Singapore rubber in RSS3 deals, Bridgestone buys.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading in the Singapore rubber market picked up steam on Thursday in a series of deals for RSS3 rubber as manufacturers bought up their monthly requirements, dealers said.</p>
<p>Bridgestone was also said to have bought a small amount of TSR20 rubber, the third consecutive day they were said to have been in the market although the amounts for the day were modest.</p>
<p>&quot;We did some deals for RSS3 rubber as manufacturers covered their monthly requirements. It was really nothing special. It was just the routine business for these people who wanted to put on some coverage,&quot; a dealer said.  </p>
<p>Traders said activity for the other rubber grades were slim, except for some deals done in TSR20 rubber. &quot;Bridgestone is still buying TSR20 in the market. I think they managed to bid the prices lower,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>The other major consumers remained on the sidelines. &quot;I have not heard of anything from the other guys for so long,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>At 0945 GMT, August RSS3 was seen at 109.25 U.S. cents a kg from 110.25 cents. August RSS1 was indicated at 155.75 Singapore cents (US$1.09) a kg from 157.00 cents.</p>
<p>- (S$1.42 = US$1) Rene Pastor (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
