<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="672982" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCC chief issues warning over AT&amp;T-SBC merger.</title>
<headline>FCC chief issues warning over AT&amp;T-SBC merger.</headline>
<byline>Roger Fillion</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The nation's top phone regulator issued a blunt warning Thursday against a possible merger of AT&amp;T Corp. and SBC Communications Inc., calling such a marriage &quot;unthinkable&quot; because it would hurt competition.</p>
<p>Federal Communications Commission Chairman Reed Hundt outlined his concerns in a major speech on antitrust policy just as No. 1 long-distance carrier AT&amp;T and regional Baby Bell phone giant SBC are believed to be in the midst of merger talks which, if completed, would amount to a $50 billion-plus transaction.</p>
<p>&quot;A combination of AT&amp;T and an RBOC (regional Bell operating company) is unthinkable,&quot; Hundt said in a speech at the Brookings Institution. While Hundt did not refer specifically to an AT&amp;T-SBC merger, his comments clearly targeted such a corporate marriage.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T Chairman Robert Allen -- while not mentioning an AT&amp;T-SBC deal -- last week said in a speech that the possibility of a long-distance carrier merging with a Baby Bell could be &quot;pro-competitive.&quot;</p>
<p>But Hundt, an antitrust lawyer, said the local and long-distance phone market power that would be amassed through such a combination would be &quot;unthinkable.&quot; He added that such a deal &quot;would be exactly the type of horizontal combination that antitrust law frowns upon.&quot;</p>
<p>Although Hundt has announced plans to leave the FCC, analysts said his comments were significant. The FCC chief has close ties to Vice Pesident Al Gore, so his thoughts are believed to reflect Clinton administration worries over a possible mega-merger of AT&amp;T and SBC.</p>
<p>&quot;He is not going to go this far out on a limb if he doesn't believe he has a lot of troops behind him,&quot; said analyst Scott Cleland of Legg Mason Precursor Group, the research arm of the Baltimore-based brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;It certainly reflects the general sentiment of the government -- but not necessarily all of the specifics,&quot; he said of Hundt's speech.</p>
<p>A merger of AT&amp;T and SBC would be the largest in U.S. history. Neither company has commented on whether they are holding talks following the big 1996 law designed to open the communications business to new competition.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T serves more than 80 million residential customers and 10 million businesses. SBC dominates local phone service in a seven-state area stretching from Texas to California.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
