<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673187" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Glynn Wolfe, world's most-married man, dies at 88.</title>
<headline>Glynn Wolfe, world's most-married man, dies at 88.</headline>
<dateline>SAN BERNARDINO, Calif 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Glynn Wolfe, who had the dubious distinction of being listed as the world's most-married man, has died at the age of 88, a county coroner's spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Wolfe, married 29 times and listed in the Guinness Book of Records, died of coronary artery disease at a nursing home in San Bernardino on June 10, spokesman Tom Dewhirst said.</p>
<p>But the 29th Mrs. Wolfe, whom he married in June 1996, will not be there to grieve at his funeral, Dewhirst said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no funeral, no burial service, no headstone, no nothing,&quot; he said, explaining that the widow, Linda Essex-Wolfe, had said the family was indigent and had asked the county to accept disposition of the body.</p>
<p>Wolfe will be cremated and his ashes placed in an unmarked grave in the county cemetery, Dewhirst said.</p>
<p>He died 10 days before he and his wife were to celebrate their first anniversary. Essex-Wolfe was to travel from her home in Indiana to celebrate the event and the couple had planned to reaffirm their vows. They had never lived together.</p>
<p>Their marriage -- it was Essex-Wolfe's 23rd, making her the world's most-married woman --  was a hyped affair arranged by the National Enquirer supermarket tabloid.</p>
<p>Wolfe is survived by 19 children, about 40 grandchildren and 19 great-grandchildren.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN BERNARDINO, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
