<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673113" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kmart stock falls on worries about management turmoil.</title>
<headline>Kmart stock falls on worries about management turmoil.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kmart Corp.'s stock declined Thursday on worries that management turmoil would pressure earnings and postpone a turnaround in sales.</p>
<p>Several Wall Street analysts reduced estimates of Kmart's earnings for the second quarter after the retailer announced Wednesday that Stephen Ross, the head of apparel merchandise, had left the company.</p>
<p>Kmart's shares fell 25 cents to $12.75 in active trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Troy, Mich.-based Kmart said the departure of Ross was a mutual decision, and the retailer had launched a search for his replacement. Meanwhile, Warren Flick, president and chief operating officer of U.S. Kmart stores, was to oversee apparel merchandise management.</p>
<p>&quot;It's good news and bad news,&quot; said Richard Church of Smith Barney. The good news is &quot;they're holding people accountable.&quot; But the bad news, he said, is that KMart suffered because of the mistakes.</p>
<p>Kmart's apparel sales hit the brakes in the first quarter, and the company planned to slash prices on $100 million in unsold goods.</p>
<p>Analysts said the markdowns would hurt Kmart's earnings, and the upheaval in the management ranks could delay a rebound in sales.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch analyst Daniel Barry cut his estimate for Kmart's second-quarter earnings by 2 cents to 8 cents a share. Last year, Kmart earned $34 million, or 7 cents a share, in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;It's easy to liquidate inventory,&quot; Church said. &quot;It takes more time to create a team that's going to make changes in the store.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
