<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673208" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Summit poses vital questions for Denver residents.</title>
<headline>Summit poses vital questions for Denver residents.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>As world leaders descend on Denver for a Group of Seven summit, the &quot;Mile High&quot; city is full of questions that have little to do with high policy -- will ordinary mortals be allowed to drive anywhere? Will the summiteers obey strict no-smoking laws? Will the chairs be big enough for Germany's Helmut Kohl?</p>
<p>Book lovers want to know when they can start returning overdue tomes because the city's spanking new main library is the summit venue and will be very off-limits to borrowers.</p>
<p>Some Denver inhabitants are also asking who goes first, in the gridlock-inducing official motorcades.</p>
<p>Does down-at-heel Russia take precedence over super rich Japan? -- Yes, because Boris Yeltsin is a head of state and Ryutaro Hashimoto is only a prime minister. President Clinton goes first and leaves every event last because he is the host.</p>
<p>Some people are also asking why there are no really big stars for a Saturday night summit gala when as one resident put it, perhaps over-optimistically, &quot;Denver becomes Hollywood.&quot;</p>
<p>The gala for the summit leaders and their aides and spousesfeatures Lyle Lovett, Michael Bolton, Amy Grant, bluegrass fiddler Richard Greene, Eartha Kitt, who was big in the 1950s but not lately, and Kool and the Gang. But there is no mega-star to top the bill.</p>
<p>Most of all, city residents want to know two things: who pays for this $20 million, three-day shindig starting on Friday and should they stay home or dare to try to drive and gawk at the world leaders?</p>
<p>City officials are warning of gridlock on major roads and important routes will be closed periodically for about 12 hours a day during the summit.</p>
<p>Ask a city official where to go if you want to see Kohl or Yeltsin and the answer is: &quot;Go home, watch the television.&quot;</p>
<p>As for who pays -- most of the tab is being picked up by the federal government with contributions from the city and private benefactors.</p>
<p>The money is going for all sorts of things from extra security, a $7 million item, to new drapes for the Phipps Mansion, a red brick stately home with one room totally imported from England, where Clinton will preside over a dinner for the visiting leaders on Friday night. The mansion usually does a roaring trade in weddings.</p>
<p>Organisers say they are being hit with all kinds of unexpected questions -- including a demand for Kohl's measurements from a local paper convinced that the larger-than-life German chancellor won't fit in the conference chairs. He will, the paper was assured.</p>
<p>The organisers also say that the city's strict no-smoking rules in any public buildings will be relaxed for the world leaders, some of whom, like Japan's prime minister, are dedicated smokers.</p>
<p>&quot;If a leader decides to light up, nobody is going to tell him to put it out,&quot; summit organiser and former White House aide Harold Ickes Jr. told the Denver Post. But the rules will apply to lesser mortals.</p>
<p>One final question that some local comics are asking is which world leader will find the city's thin air so hard to take that he will sign anything to go home?</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
