<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673344" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: C.bank head says Czechs not prepared for austerity.</title>
<headline>C.bank head says Czechs not prepared for austerity.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech National Bank governor Josef Tosovksy said on Thursday that initial government austerity efforts were too little, too late, and that the politicians have yet to prepare Czechs for what lies ahead.</p>
<p>Speaking at a meeting of the German-Czech society in Frankfurt, he said central bank reserves used in a failed effort to defend the Czech crown, which was floated on May 27, was a &quot;transition tax paid by the public for a market economy&quot;.</p>
<p>The central bank move to float the currency came after heavy downward pressure from speculators, spurred by a ballooning current account deficit, high wage growth, poor restructuring in Czech industry, and political instability.</p>
<p>Analysts have estimated the central bank used as much as $3 billion in its failed efforts last month.</p>
<p>Tosovsky said that the government's first attempt at cutting domestic demand in April had been inadequate.</p>
<p>&quot;The (April) package proved to be too little, too late,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tosovsky said that chief challenge in restoring stability to the Czech economy was the reduction in domestic demand.</p>
<p>&quot;The reduction of domestic demand will be the most important point, but it will be more painful than it was explained to the public,&quot; Tosovsky said.</p>
<p>After the crown floated the government announced a second package of emergency measures which combined with April measures will cut 45.5 billion crowns from the 1997 original budget.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus has been very critical of the Czech central bank's tightening of monetary policy in 1996 which he said slowed growth on the supply side much more than the demand side.</p>
<p>Tosovsky earlier this week took a thinly-veiled shot at Klaus by saying that promises made a rapid wage growth before the 1996 general election raised expectations too much.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
