<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673340" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: EU looks set to adopt 2005 climate target.</title>
<headline>EU looks set to adopt 2005 climate target.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union environment ministers, hoping to spur momentum in U.N. climate change talks, looked set on Thursday to adopt a 2005 target for promised curbs in polluting gases thought to warm the earth's atmosphere.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems they have agreed more or less on 7.5 percent,&quot; one EU diplomat told reporters after a closed-door session.</p>
<p>The 7.5 percent figure, if agreed, refers to how much the EU would cut its emissions of gases such as carbon dioxide (CO2) from burned fossil fuels, compared with 1990 levels.</p>
<p>Most climate scientists believe increased emissions of so-called greenhouse gases will raise temperatures by trapping more solar energy in the atmosphere.</p>
<p>They predict a variety of possible effects in a warmer world such as higher sea levels, increased geographic spread of tropical disease, drought and more frequent, violent storms.</p>
<p>Environmentalists, the European Commission and several EU countries had rejected the 7.5 percent target beforehand, saying it was so low as to undermine the EU's existing 2010 target.</p>
<p>Environment ministers agreed last March to head for December's climate change talks in Kyoto, Japan, urging industrialised countries to go for a 15 percent cut in 2010.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission's view would be that the decision taken in March was a very clear and strong signal to the other partners leading up to the Kyoto conference,&quot; a Commission official told reporters on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is one thing the Commission does not want the Council to do it is to weaken in anyway that signal. Seven and a half percent, for example, the Commission would see as a very, very weak signal,&quot; the official added.</p>
<p>European businesses, as represented by the employers' organisation UNICE, see higher 2005 targets as adding to the enormous efforts they say are already needed for the 2010 cut.</p>
<p>&quot;UNICE considers that it is inadvisable to set very challenging short-term EU objectives, for example, a 10 percent CO2 reduction by 2005,&quot; it said ahead of Thursday's meeting.</p>
<p>Dutch Environment Minister Margreeth de Boer, whose country holds the EU presidency, rejected charges of weakness at an impromptu news conference on Thursday, .</p>
<p>&quot;I think you are making a mistake when you say that a target of 7.5 percent means that nothing is going to be done. I know some countries who will have a great deal of difficulty meeting (that),&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G156">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
