<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673563" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks rally, bonds firmer, dollar mixed.</title>
<headline>Stocks rally, bonds firmer, dollar mixed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks rallied on Thursday, while bonds edged higher on economic news that reduced chances of an interest rate hike by the Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>The dollar was mixed.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average ended up 58.35 points at 7,777.06, standing just below its record closing high of 7,782.04 set on June 13. The 30-stock blue chip index rallied briefly through 7,800 for the first time, peaking at 7,810.54 before settling back.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks and the NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks both set records.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues swamped declines 1,739 to 783 on active volume of 536 million on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The market also was propelled by an upbeat forecast by Prudential Securities' well-known market bull, Ralph Acampora, who raised his targets for the Dow to 10,000 in the next year.</p>
<p>Investors were already cheering a narrower-than-expected April trade deficit and news that exports jumped to a record high, despite a strong dollar, as well as a surprising jump in weekly jobless claims. The developments were expected to deter the Federal Reserve from moving toward an interest rate rise at its policy-setting meeting in July.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot of buying momentum out there. (Acampora) just keeps on increasing his numbers. That creates a very strong bullish feeling on Wall Street,&quot; said Warren Epstein, director of trading at Richard Rosenblatt.</p>
<p>Acampora, Prudential Securities' director of technical research, advised people to &quot;Remain fully invested -- we expect the stock market to mount an explosive advance during the second half of the year,&quot; he wrote in a report.</p>
<p>Weekly jobless claims rose to 347,000 in the latest week from 339,000 a week earlier, suggesting that the red-hot labour market might be cooling.</p>
<p>The government also said the trade deficit rose 7.8 percent in April to $8.4 billion but noted that exports hit a record level. That could mean bigger profits ahead for U.S. companies who do business abroad, analysts said.</p>
<p>Traders said stocks also benefited from a burst of buying prior to Friday's &quot;triple witching&quot; expiration of futures and options. Some investors who had bet that stocks would fall had to cover their bets and buy them back, even in a rising market.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks rose 8.93 points to 897.99, a record. The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks rose 4.35 to 467.76, a new high.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury bond edged up 3/32, or 93.75 cents on a $1,000 bond, reducing its yield to 6.68 percent from 6.69 percent at Wednesday's close. The price and the yield move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to 114.03 Japanese yen late Thursday from 113.65 yen late Wednesday. It fell to 1.7235 German marks from 1.7333 marks.</p>
<p>Rice futures rose sharply in heavy volume amid growing concern about the impact of the developing El Nino weather pattern off western South America on crops in Asia.</p>
<p>For the second consecutive session, almost all delivery months for rice made life-of-contract highs at the Chicago Board of Trade. The exception, July, rose to a two-month peak of $11.90 per hundred pounds before closing 8.5 cents higher at $11.75.</p>
<p>Wheat futures fell to a 4-1/2 month low of $3.36 as early reports on this year's harvest continued to suggest better- than-expected yields. Wheat for July delivery on the CBOT closed 1-3/4 cents lower at $3.37 a bushel.</p>
<p>Corn prices kept falling on nearly ideal crop weather in the key growing states of the U.S. Midwest. The key new crop delivery month, December, tumbled to a life-of-contract low of $2.43-1/4 and closed down 1-3/4 cents at $2.43-1/2.</p>
<p>Overseas, London's FTSE 100 share fell for the fourth day in a rowm, ending down 3.3 points at 4,653.7. In Tokyo, the Nikkei 225 ended 10 points higher at 20,507.85.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
