<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673658" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Norwood says Alpha unit hurts EPS.</title>
<headline>Norwood says Alpha unit hurts EPS.</headline>
<dateline>SAN ANTONIO 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwood Promotional Products Inc said Thursday its Alpha unit is hurting its earnings per share, and it is therefore exploring alternatives for the unit.</p>
<p>The company said it believe the steps it will take with respect to Alpha will have a net positive impact on its results in fiscal 1998 and beyond.</p>
<p>The company did not provide information on what these steps are.  </p>
<p>The company said Alpha's core promotional products business has exceeded sales and profitability targets, but sales of its non-promotional, or retail, operation have lagged.</p>
<p>The company said earnings per share for the 1997 third quarter would have been $0.62 if results of the Alpha division were excluded. The company's actual earnings per share were $0.52.</p>
<p>The company said it believes Alpha will cost it $0.30 to $0.35 in earnings per share for fiscal 1997 as a whole.  </p>
<p>The company said Alpha's non-promotional product sales are typically characterized by large orders for direct premium markets and convenience stores.</p>
<p>These sales, the company said, have a &quot;much greater&quot; degree of unpredictability than its other businesses.</p>
<p>The company said, therefore, it must begin exploring alternatives regarding the Alpha division.  It said it has instituted a process to do so in the next 45 days.</p>
<p>The company also said it has signed a letter with Merrill Lynch for a new senior secured credit facility of $125 million, which replaces its existing facility of $60 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN ANTONIO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
