<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673702" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: EMERGENCY WEATHER CONDITIONS -  WSC - 18-JUN.</title>
<headline>EMERGENCY WEATHER CONDITIONS -  WSC - 18-JUN.</headline>
<text>
<p>Typhoon Opal continues as a major risk to shipping during the next 24 hours as it moves northward towards Japan. Seas of more than 20 feet, winds up to 120 mph and heavy rains will have a big impact on any shipping in the area. The system is currently located about 535 miles south-southwest of the southern most point of Honshu Japan and well to the east-southeast of Okinawa. It is expected to move to the coast of Honshu in about 30-36 hours. More...  </p>
<p>Typhoon Opal will likely cause major damage to coastal property at and east of the landfall in southern Honshu Japan. Winds up to 120 mph and a storm surge of up to 25 feet will cause this widespread and severe damage. Strong wind gusts are also possible, especially to the east of the storm track. As the system moves northward the winds will diminish but the very heavy to torrential rains will continue. Large areas of Honshu Japan can expect rains of 5 to 15 inches when this system tracks across. This will cause flooding and possible mudslides. Winds will also cause damage but not as severe as areas further south.  </p>
<p>There are no further statements at this time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
