<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673735" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Russia Eurobond sells out amid improved sentiment.</title>
<headline>Russia Eurobond sells out amid improved sentiment.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia borrowed $2.0 billion in the international capital markets on Thursday, and bankers said the successful transaction reflected improved sentiment towards the country.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia was a complete blow-out,&quot; a banker involved in the transaction said. &quot;Sentiment towards Russia has become increasingly more positive, and they (Russians) could have raised even more than they did today.&quot;</p>
<p>The deal, modern Russia's third since its market debut last November, ranks among the largest Eurobonds ever, and dealers reported huge demand for paper after a series of roadshows worldwide.</p>
<p>Reformers Anatoly Chubais and Boris Nemstov's appointments to government has boosted foreign investor confidence that reforms will be pushed through.</p>
<p>Russia doubled both the size and maturity of a dollar bond launched last year and managed to raise funds more cheaply.</p>
<p>Thursday's 10-year bond was launched with a 10.00-percent coupon, a key psychological level. Double-digit coupons are rare in the current low interest rate environment and are particularly attractive to retail investors.</p>
<p>The deal was priced to yield 3.75 percentage points over U.S. Treasuries. J.P. Morgan Securities and SBC Warburg were joint lead managers.</p>
<p>Russia first tapped the international capital markets in November 1996 with a $1.0 billion five-year bond, priced to yield 3.45 percentage points over Treasuries. It was trading at 2.70 points over on Thursday.</p>
<p>In March, it raised 2.0 billion marks ($1.2 billion) via a seven-year bond. Thursyday's deal brought the 1997 total to around $3.2 billion.</p>
<p>Last Friday, Russian deputy finance minister Mikhail Kasyanov told a news conference it would borrow up to $3.5 billion from international bond markets this year.</p>
<p>That figure was based on Russia's also launching a global dollar bond in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;(Thursday's deal) has given Russia the flexibility to be more opportunistic if they want to do another deal this year, partly as pre-funding for 1998,&quot; a banker at a European bank said.</p>
<p>Kasyanov also said Russia would raise $3.0-3.5 billion internationally in 1998. &quot;That is an appropriate amount for us using this source of funding,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Aline van Duyn, London newsroom +44 171 542 8863</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
