<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67371" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian call money ends unchanged, gilt yields down.</title>
<headline>Indian call money ends unchanged, gilt yields down.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call ended Friday in the 10.50-10.75 percent range, unchanged from the day's opening levels, dealers said.</p>
<p>In tight range-bound trade, most of the day's deals were struck between 10.65 and 10.75 percent, they said.</p>
<p>Dealers said call money remained tight despite rumours of an impending cut in cash reserve requirements. The monetary policy for October-April is expected to be announced by the Reserve Bank of India in the first week of October.</p>
<p>Money market dealers said they expected a cut in cash reserve requirements from the existing 12 percent.</p>
<p>Security prices rose on buying pressure, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Market participants seem to be building up positions in short-term securities,&quot; a primary dealer said.</p>
<p>The 13.50 percent 1997 government of India stock traded on Friday at a yield of 13.17 percent against 13.22 percent on Thursday while the 13.50 percent 1998 stock traded at 13.49 percent against 13.54 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers said there was little activity in certificates of deposit (CDs). &quot;Given that most banks are enjoying good liquidity and there is little demand for credit, it makes little sense to pick up CDs at 11 percent,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Commercial paper by top-rated companies were quoted around 13 percent in the primary market, dealers said.</p>
<p>Rates on intercorporate deposits remained steady in the 17-19 percent range for top-rated borrowers, dealers said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
