<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673734" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Activists found guilty of libeling McDonald's.</title>
<headline>Activists found guilty of libeling McDonald's.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Reaney</byline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two penniless activists were found guilty Thursday of libelling McDonald's Corp. and were ordered to pay the hamburger giant 60,000 pounds ($98,000) after the longest trial in English legal history.</p>
<p>The judge found that statements in a six-page pamphlet published by Helen Steel, 31, and Dave Morris, 43, in 1984 that the world's biggest restaurant chain was responsible for Third World starvation, destruction of rain forests and for selling unhealthy food &quot;injured the plaintiff's reputation.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The majority of the defamatory statements I found to be untrue. Others were true,&quot; Judge Rodger Bell said in his nearly two-hour summation of a three-volume verdict on the &quot;McLibel&quot; case, which attracted worldwide attention.</p>
<p>&quot;In my view, the unjustified allegations of blame for starvation in the Third World and destruction of rain forests, and of knowingly selling food with a serious risk of damaging their customers' health are particularly damaging,&quot; Bell told a packed courtroom in London's Royal Courts of Justice.</p>
<p>&quot;On the other hand, there has been an element of justification in relation to the plaintiff's advertising, their responsibility for some cruelty towards some of the animals which are reared and slaughtered for their products ... and low pay,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Because the activists are penniless, it will be up to McDonald's to decide if it will pursue the damages. The Oak Brook, Ill.-based burger chain has said it is not looking to destroy the activists, just to stop them from spreading the allegations.</p>
<p>The judge said that, although a lot of the statements were found to be untrue, the pamphlet did expose some unsatisfactory conditions at the company that were taken into account when assessing damages. Bell said some of McDonald's publicity material was misleading.</p>
<p>The &quot;David-and-Goliath&quot; trial of the part-time barmaid and the unemployed single father accused of libelling the $30 billion-a-year corporation is listed in the Guinness Book of Records as England's longest trial. There has been a longer trial under Scottish law.</p>
<p>The case, which started in 1990, contained 313 days of testimony, eight weeks of closing speeches and six months of deliberation.</p>
<p>Because the case was so complicated -- dealing with testimony from 180 witnesses on topics ranging from food packaging and manufacturing to labour practices, the destruction of rain forests and health issues -- Bell deemed it too complicated for a jury.</p>
<p>While the judge was reading out the summation, he was forced repeatedly to stop and correct himself, so complex were the issues under review.</p>
<p>The case has also been the subject of a two-part television documentary, a 300-page book and countless newspaper and magazine articles. It has spawned support groups and its own Internet Web site, which features 19,000 pages of court testimony.</p>
<p>The case is estimated to have cost 10 million pounds ($16 million). Steel and Morris denied that they defamed the restaurant chain in a six-page pamphlet titled &quot;What's Wrong With McDonalds&quot; and have spent most of the past three years trying to prove it.</p>
<p>The 1984 pamphlet produced by London Greenpeace, a little-known group with no relation to Greenpeace International, alleged that the burger giant promoted an unhealthy diet, ruined the environment, was hostile to unions and exploited children and workers.</p>
<p>After receiving libel writs from McDonald's in 1989, three of the five London Greenpeace leaders apologised. But Steel and Morris were determined to have their day in court.</p>
<p>Their day turned into years. Court proceedings began in June 1994 after 28 pretrial hearings and ended late last year.</p>
<p>Denied legal aid and with no training, the unlikely duo, who were always casually dressed in jeans and sweatshirts, conducted their own defence. By all accounts, they held their own against the impeccably wigged and robed Richard Rampton, one of England's top libel lawyers.</p>
<p>Writer Auberon Waugh described the proceedings in the sombre courtroom No. 35 of London's Royal Courts of Justice as the &quot;best free entertainment in town.&quot; Leading lawyer Michael Mansfield has called it &quot;the trial of the century.&quot;</p>
<p>Before the verdict, the two activists had vowed to appeal and said they might take their case to the European Court of Human Rights, claiming England's libel laws are oppressive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
