<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673779" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK National Audit Office 1430 GMT report - key facts.</title>
<headline>UK National Audit Office 1430 GMT report - key facts.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's National Audit Office will report on the Labour government's new assumptions underlying the public finances at 1430 GMT on Thursday.</p>
<p>Following are key facts about the report:</p>
<p>* The review was commissioned by Chancellor of the Exchequer Gordon Brown on May 20. He has made changes to some of the key economic assumptions and accounting conventions made by the previous government. The NAO will assess the validity of these changes.</p>
<p>* The NAO will address three new economic assumptions -- economic growth, inflation and unemployment -- and two conventions -- the use of assumed future privatisation proceeds in the accounts, and the so-called &quot;spend-to-save&quot; scheme. (The previous government estimated it could recoup 6.68 billion pounds of tax revenue if it spent 796 million pounds over the next three years clamping down on tax evasion).</p>
<p>* The National Audit Office is an independent body which carries out financial audits of most parts of central government as well as around 50 value-for-money studies for government departments each year. It is funded by parliament, not the Treasury.</p>
<p>* The head of the NAO, Sir John Bourn, is the Comptroller and Auditor General, a senior House of Commons official.</p>
<p>* Following are key economic forecasts from the 1997/98 budget presented by Conservative Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke last November (percentage changes on a year earlier unless otherwise stated):</p>
<p>	  1997-98   1998-99   1999-00   2000-01   2001-02</p>
<p>GDP	 3.5	  3.0	 2.5	 2.5	2.5</p>
<p>RPIX	2.5	  2.0	 2.0	 2.0	2.0</p>
<p>Unemply</p>
<p>(in mlns) 1.8	  1.7	 1.6	 n/a	n/a</p>
<p>P/P	 2.0	  1.5	 1.0	 1.0	1.0</p>
<p>NOTE: P/P means privatisation proceeds and figures are in billion stg. RPIX is underlying retail price inflation (excluding mortgage interest payments).</p>
<p>-- Rosemary Bennett +44 171 542 7715</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
