<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="673876" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Coffee turns hot commodity in UK crime wave.</title>
<headline>Coffee turns hot commodity in UK crime wave.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Soaring world prices for coffee have turned the jar of instant into a prime target among British shoplifters.</p>
<p>Police and lawyers said coffee theft was rampant in some inner cities so that jars were being placed out of reach or stocked discreetly by supermarkets.</p>
<p>&quot;People who are in multiple debts are stealing coffee because it is relatively easy to sell or use as repayment to money lenders in lieu of cash,&quot; said Harry Fletcher, assistant general secretary of the National Association of Probation Officers.</p>
<p>He said there had been a marked increase in coffee theft in London and several other big cities.</p>
<p>Tom Ward, a lawyer in Scotland who has represented several people accused of stealing coffee, said a big jar costing seven sterling or about $11.50 and could be re-sold at half the price.</p>
<p>Detective Sergeant Alistair Morris, a police officer in Greenock, Scotland, said: &quot;It is a problem elsewhere I would imagine.&quot;</p>
<p>The spate of coffee theft followed an increase in retail prices after world futures for the beans doubled since January.</p>
<p>Supply disruptions from Colombia and concerns over a lower crop in Brazil, the biggest producer, with a rush of buying by roasters (processors) who were running low of stocks, fuelled the rally that attracted eager speculative interest.</p>
<p>Some of the cost has been passed on to consumers. Nestle, the leading British instant coffee maker, has put up its retail prices twice this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
