<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674054" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lilly, Interneuron in Prozac treatment pact.</title>
<headline>Lilly, Interneuron in Prozac treatment pact.</headline>
<dateline>LEXINGTON, Mass. 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eli Lilly and Co and Interneuron Pharmaceuticals Inc said Thursday they entered an agreement regarding a use patent for Lilly's antidepressant Prozac (fluoxetine hydrochloride).</p>
<p>Lilly will license from Interneuron the U.S. patent and worldwide patent application rights covering the use of fluoxetine to treat disturbances of appetite and mood associated with premenstrual syndrome (PMS). Prozac currently is not approved to treat this indication.  </p>
<p>Under the agreement, Interneuron will receive upfront fees, milestone payments and royalties based on potential sales of Prozac in the United States to treat premenstrual syndrome. In exchange, Lilly will receive exclusive patent rights from Interneuron.</p>
<p>&quot;...(T)he licensing of this patent will allow us to pursue clinical studies which evaluate the effectiveness and safety of Prozac in treating symptoms of premenstrual syndrome, a condition that afflicts millions of women during childbearing years,&quot; Gary Tollefson, a vice president of Lilly Research Laboratories, said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an important strategic step in our efforts to explore the potential clinical value for Prozac in medical disorders where need exists for improved therapeutic alternatives,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Prozac remains the world's most widely prescribed brand-name anti-depressant, Lilly said. Prozac is available in more than 100 countries for the treatment of depression. It has also been cleared for marketing in 44 countries for the treatment of obsessive-compulsive disorder and in 40 countries for the treatment of the eating disorder bulimia nervosa.</p>
<p>&quot;The patent rights to the use of fluoxetine in treating premenstrual syndrome are contained in Interneuron's broad patent portfolio licensed exclusively from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology,&quot; Glenn Cooper, president and chief executive officer of Interneuron, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Interneuron Pharmaceuticals is a diversified biopharmaceutical company engaged in the development and commercialization of products for neurological and behavioral disorders.</p>
<p>Lilly is a global research-based pharmaceutical corp. headquartered in Indianapolis, Ind.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEXINGTON, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
