<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674020" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Aetna mulls sale of Hartford mall.</title>
<headline>Aetna mulls sale of Hartford mall.</headline>
<dateline>HARTFORD 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Life and healthcare insurer Aetna Inc said Thursday it might sell the Civic Center mall in downtown Hartford, because it has lost $56 million operating the property since it opened in 1975.</p>
<p>&quot;We're considering ideas, and we're going to begin a formal process to selectively market the mall,&quot; Aetna spokesman Fred Laberge told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the company has hired Boston real estate marketing firm McCall &amp; Almy Inc to conduct a review.</p>
<p>There is no specific asking price for the 210,000-square foot mall, Laberge said.  </p>
<p>The Civic Center mall is one of Hartford's best-known landmarks, and one of the few remaining retail centers in a downtown that has struggled with urban blight.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had a couple of ideas generated already, and some informal talks with proponents of alternate uses for the mall,&quot; Laberge said. &quot;We're shopping for concepts, and trying to see what could work and what's in the best interests of Aetna and the city.&quot;</p>
<p>One proposal is to expand the Connecticut Sports Museum and Hall of Fame, in a complex that would include Walt Disney Co's cable sports broadcaster ESPN as a tenant, Laberge said.  </p>
<p>The city owns the land on which the mall sits, and Aetna has a long-term lease for use of the land. Aetna owns the mall, while the city owns the adjoining Civic Center Coliseum and exhibition halls.</p>
<p>Aetna's decision was unrelated to last month's departure of the National Hockey League's Hartford Whalers for North Carolina, Laberge said.</p>
<p>He said the company decided to act because it has received several proposals for alternate uses of the mall. Laberge said there is no time frame for possible sale of the property.</p>
<p>((--Hartford newsroom (860) 727-0224))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
