<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67414" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow snaps losing streak, S&amp;P 500 sets record close.</title>
<headline>Dow snaps losing streak, S&amp;P 500 sets record close.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dow industrials snapped a three-day losing streak, and the S&amp;P 500 rose to a record close Friday as triple-witching futures and options expirations lent an upward bias to stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;We had some good strength on blue chips and Nasdaq and a hint of profit-taking as the day came to a close,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average closed 20.72 points higher at 5,888.46, just shy of Monday's all-time high finish of 5,889.20, after hitting 5,897 earlier. For the week, the Dow rose 49.94 points.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues led declines 1,414 to 902 on very heavy volume of 514 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange, swollen by the expiration of September futures and options.</p>
<p>It was the most active NYSE session since July 16's record 680 million shares.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's index of 500 stocks rose 4.02 to 687.02, topping Monday's record close of 683.98. The index was up 6.48 on the week.</p>
<p>Technology stocks continued to prop up the market, with the tech-studded Nasdaq Composite index up 7.60 points at 1,219.69 -- moving in fast on June 5's all-time high finish of 1,249.15. The index edged up 31.02 from last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a triple-witching market that had a positive bias,&quot; said Eugene Peroni, chief technical analyst with Janney, Montgomery Scott.</p>
<p>Bleir said a &quot;standout was the transports which had been sorely lagging. But it's still 10 percent off all-time highs.&quot; The Dow Jones Transportation average climbed 36.81 points or 1.78 percent to 2,100.71.</p>
<p>The index was led higher by gains in AMR Corp., up 2-1/2 to 83-1/2, Delta Air Lines, up 2-1/4 to 72-5/8, Federal Express, up 2-5/8 to 77-1/2, and Norfolk Southern, up 2 to 89-3/8.</p>
<p>Wall Street will be waiting for Tuesday's meeting of the Federal Reserve's policy-setting Federal Open Market Committee. Many Wall Street analysts expect a modest increase in short-term interest rates to head off inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury bond edged up 1/32, reducing its yield to 7.04 percent from 7.05 percent at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>Technology stock provided good leadership for the market, said Thom Brown, a managing director at Rutherford, Brown &amp; Catherwood.</p>
<p>Hewlett-Packard rose 5/8 to 49, Dell Computer was up 3-3/8 to 86-1/2, Netscape rallied 5-3/8 to 50-7/8 from recent weakness, and bellwether Intel rose 3/8 to 97-3/8.</p>
<p>Among individual stocks, Applied Analytical Industries Inc., a contract research organisation, surged 5-5/8 to 21-5/8 in its first day of trading. Houston Exploration, a unit of Brooklyn Union Gas, rose 1-1/2 to 17 in its Wall Street debut.</p>
<p>Hughes Electronics rose 2-1/2 to 60-1/4 and Panamsat lost 1/8 to 27-5/8 after the companies, as expected, announced plans to merge their satellite services operations into a new publicly held company.</p>
<p>Grupo Televisa SA, which has a 40.5 percent stake in Panamsat, rose 1/8 to 29-7/8 in U.S. trading.</p>
<p>Aksys lost 3-3/8 to 11-3/4 after news the FDA requested more information on its personal haemodialysis system for kidney failure to review its safety and efficacy.</p>
<p>Ventritex rose 3 to 18-5/8 after the FDA approved its Contour implantable defibrillators, used to slow down too-rapid heartbeats.</p>
<p>Lehman Brothers rose 1-1/8 to 22-3/4. Oppenheimer said Lehman was a strong buyout candidate. A Lehman spokeman was not available for comment.</p>
<p>The NYSE composite rose rose 1.83 to 365.77, a record. The average price per share rose 19 cents. The index rose 2.07 from last Friday.</p>
<p>The American Stock Exchange index was off 0.24 at 565.20, down 5.06 on the week.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 6,736.199, up 34.463, or 0.51 percent. It was up 34.462 on the week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
