<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67419" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gold, silver prices fall to three-year lows.</title>
<headline>Gold, silver prices fall to three-year lows.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold and silver prices fell to the lowest levels in three years Friday as the outlook for mild inflation reduced the demand for precious metals.</p>
<p>Hog prices jumped to contract highs as meat packers boosted production to meet supermarket demand for National Pork Month in October.</p>
<p>Soybean futures rose after forecasters said frost next week may hurt some of the Midwest crop.</p>
<p>Investors had little incentive to buy gold because inflation remained low, the Federal Reserve was poised to move pre-emptively to raise interest rates, and the U.S. stock and bond markets were trending higher.</p>
<p>Moreover, &quot;there is some concern Russia is having difficulty meeting its budget and may need to sell more commodities to raise revenue,&quot; said Everen Securities analyst Todd Henrichs.</p>
<p>At the Commodity Exchange, December gold ended down $1.70 at $383.90 an ounce after falling to a three-year low earlier at $383.30. December silver ended down 7.7 cents at $4.863 per ounce, after hitting three-year low earlier at $4.840.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Mercantile Exchange, October and December hog prices closed at the highest levels in a month as meat packers began aggressively buying hogs this past week to boost pork production.</p>
<p>&quot;Packers want to fill the (pork) pipeline -- it seems pretty empty right now,&quot; said Scott Shepard with Cargill Investor Services.</p>
<p>Hog prices were sharply higher at Midwest cash markets Friday, and CME traders forecast steady gains at cash markets next week as meat packers continue aggressively buying hogs.</p>
<p>October hogs rose to contract high of 57.350 cents per pound in late trading and closed up 1.175 cents at 57.300. December hogs closed up 0.450 cent at 57.100, after setting a contract high of 57.500.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade soybeans closed higher as forecasts for frost next week renewed concerns much of the late-planted crop will not survive to maturity. Soybeans for November delivery closed up 6 cents at $7.95-1/4 per bushel.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a little oversold and there are still the frost fears. But it's still a waiting game to see what happens,&quot; said Steve Bruce of E.D. and F. Man International.</p>
<p>Several meteorologists forecast the possibility for frost early next week in the northern portions of the Midwest. The season's first frost normally occurs in early October, but weather maps suggest one next week.</p>
<p>At the New York Mercantile Exchange, oil futures erased most of their early losses, with crude and heating oil settling higher.</p>
<p>Crude oil for October delivery expired 9 cents higher at $23.63 a barrel, but went off the board well below last Friday's settlement of $24.51 a barrel.</p>
<p>Gasoline lagged the rest of the oil market. October gasoline, shaking off an early upside move, settled 0.23 cent lower at 61.09 cents a gallon. October heating oil rose 0.65 cent to 67.42 cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
