<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674385" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK GENERAL NEWS - JUNE 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK GENERAL NEWS - JUNE 19.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek general press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--Prime Minister Costas Simitis yesterday briefed his ruling party PASOK executive on the results of the Amsterdam summit and treaty, saying Greece was pleased with the outcome. Particularly significant for Greece, he said, were provisions on safeguarding external borders, the inviolability of borders and political solidarity.</p>
<p>--Turkish Foreign Minister and likely new prime minister Tansu Ciller let loose volleys at Greece again yesterday, saying there was no documented proof that the islands and islets of the Aegean belonged to Greece. Responding to recent comments by the Greek president on the &quot;Greekness&quot; of the islands, Ciller said the statements were an indication of &quot;expansionist desires&quot;.</p>
<p>--Air-conditioned public buildings will be open to the public today for refuge from temperatures expected to rise above the forecast 39 degrees. Precautionary measures against the heat and smog are the name of the game as hospitals will be operating on skeleton staff due to a six-hour work stoppage.</p>
<p>ELEFTHEROTYPIA</p>
<p>--Government and unions faced off yesterday at their meeting to discuss changes to the social pension system, with the government insisting on the implementation of a 1992 law which unionists say will hurt workers' pension rights.</p>
<p>--Greek troops stationed in Albania with the multinational protection force came under fire yesterday from armed bandits, the first time they have been attacked since deployment. One Albanian attacker was killed.</p>
<p>--Margaret Chant Papandreou, the former wife of late PASOK founder and president Andreas Papandreou, reveals she has written a book about their life together.</p>
<p>TA NEA</p>
<p>--The pressure of annual school and university examinations claimed the life of an 18-year-old girl yesterday and forced another to attempt to end her life after both failed their year.</p>
<p>--Leading PASOK cadres remember Andreas Papandreou as the first anniversary of the former prime minister's death nears.</p>
<p>ELEFTHEROS TYPOS</p>
<p>--Dimitra Liani-Papandreou wept as she attended an event on Crete yesterday to mark the first anniversary of the death of her late husband.</p>
<p>ETHNOS</p>
<p>--A 47-year-old father of two accused of sexually abusing his 12-year-old daughter killed himself yesterday shortly before a television channel was to screen an expose of his story. The man was to be tried on July 3.</p>
<p>--Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
