<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674333" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: PRESS DIGEST - Malta - June 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malta - June 19.</headline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the leading stories in the Maltese press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>- State agency says the government should re-negotiate key issues in the Manoel Island tourist project. A mostly-Maltese consortium wants to build an upmarket tourism and leisure complex on a small island close to Malta's most important tourist resort. A letter of intent was signed with the Maltese government three years ago, but the government's Management Efficiency Unit said a fresh evaluation of the value of the property should be made and talks reopened before the government transfers any land.</p>
<p>- Malaysian businessman R Tan Hua Choon, who already owns 21.3 percent of Lombard Bank (Malta), wants to buy more shares. He will need approval by Maltese authorities and the other shareholders before being allowed to do so.</p>
<p>L-ORIZZONT</p>
<p>- Police investigate Order of Knights for fraud following a request from Germany. It involves the Byzantine Order of the Holy Sepulchre.</p>
<p>IN-NAZZJON</p>
<p>- With system of excise duties to replace VAT coming into force on July 1, Vince Farrugia, director-general of the Association of Retailers, said no one understood how it worked.</p>
<p>- Malta Drydocks chairman Noel Zarb Adami criticised by the Nationalist Party and the General Workers' Union after failing to reach agreement on compensation for widows of nine dockyard workers killed in an accident at work two years ago. Dockyard offer has been rejected by the widows.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
