<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674532" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks open down after Dow, gold dip.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks open down after Dow, gold dip.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian stocks backed further away from their recent record run to open lower on Thursday after another drop on Wall Street and a slump in the price of gold.</p>
<p>Dealers said the fall in the local market was to be expected after four successive record closes ended on Wednesday and the Dow index recorded its third straight drop. Gold also fell to its lowest point for almost four years.</p>
<p>At 10.15 a.m. (0015 GMT), the All Ordinaries Index was down 8.4 points to 2,665.0 in busy trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It should come down, it's had a pretty good run,&quot; Intersuisse Ltd head of equities Andrew Sekely said of the All Ordinaries Index.</p>
<p>&quot;A little bit of a pull-back is healthy and that's what we're seeing happening,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nickel producer QNI had a busy morning after the announcement on Wednesday of its merger with South African mining house Gencor Ltd's nickel unit.</p>
<p>By 11.00 a.m. (0100 GMT), shares in QNI, Australia's second largest nickel producer, were up seven cents at A$2.75 on trade of about six million shares.</p>
<p>Some brokers said before the opening the Gencor deal valued QNI shares at A$3.40 to A43.50 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm surprised that they're not trading at a higher level. We think the announcement makes for a stronger company,&quot; said Ivan Mitchell, a broker from Brisbane brokerage Nevitts Ltd.</p>
<p>Other brokers and analysts said institutional investors digesting the deal overnight had decided the deal appeared more favourable to Gencor than QNI.</p>
<p>The market continued to react indifferently to Carpenter Pacific Resources NL's latest drilling results which the company claimed showed a potential Porgera-sized gold deposit at Mt Kare.</p>
<p>At 11.18 a.m. (0118 GMT) Carpenter shares were four cents down at A$0.34 after 2.2 million shares were traded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
