<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674505" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Ansett plans briefing, sees flat group result.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Ansett plans briefing, sees flat group result.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Carrier Ansett Australia said on Thursday it expected a break even result for the Ansett group in the year ending June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>Ansett said it expected to make an announcement about an alliance with other airlines on Friday.</p>
<p>In a statement, Ansett said it would hold a joint media briefing with Air New Zealand and Singapore Airlines on Friday at 10.45 a.m. (0045 GMT) in Melbourne.  </p>
<p>&quot;The consolidated Ansett group is talking about break even,&quot; general manager, international, of Ansett Australia Craig Wallace told reporters.</p>
<p>Wallace said the break even result followed a similar performance in 1995/96 and represented the foundation for the Ansett group's goal of driving profitability to acceptable levels within three years.</p>
<p>&quot;What it is doing is setting the base,&quot; Wallace said.</p>
<p>He cited Ansett executive chairman Rod Eddington's goal of achieving acceptable returns on investment over three years and making major changes to put the airline on a sound footing.  </p>
<p>Media reports this week said Singapore Airlines Ltd is in talks to become an equal partner with News Corp Ltd and Air New Zealand Ltd in Ansett Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne Newsroom 61-3 9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
