<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674823" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan urges brokerages not to recommend stocks.</title>
<headline>Taiwan urges brokerages not to recommend stocks.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's securities watchdog, the Securities and Exchange Commission, said on Thursday it had urged brokerages not to forecast market trends or recommend buying or selling stocks in public.</p>
<p>&quot;We sent a letter to the securities brokerage association on Wednesady to reiterate rules that brokerages should not allow their staff to forecast market trends and recommend buying or selling certain stocks in public or on media,&quot; a commission spokeswoman told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>She said brokerages were allowed to forecast market trends and recommend stocks only in their offices to their clients.  </p>
<p>The move came after the Taiwan stock index surged on Wednesday for the fifth straight session, inching up to a seven-year closing high of 8,713.49 points.</p>
<p>The index turned briefly lower as word of the brokerage policy circulated, but with 50 minutes left, at 0310 GMT, the index was rallying again, up 50.87 points, or 0.58 percent, at 8,764.36.</p>
<p>The commission had made similar moves in April trying to cool off the red-hot stock market.</p>
<p>&quot;Apparently, the SEC is trying to cool off the rallying stock market,&quot; said Nomura Securities research chief Ben Lee.  </p>
<p>&quot;But since sentiment is so bullish now that after a short consolidation, the index is still seen in a firming trend to test 9,000 points in the near future,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>-- Taipei newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
