<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674912" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Clashes in Hebron, Israel wounds Arab in Gaza.</title>
<headline>Clashes in Hebron, Israel wounds Arab in Gaza.</headline>
<dateline>HEBRON, West Bank 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stone-throwing Palestinians clashed with Israeli troops on Thursday for a sixth day on the confrontation line between Israeli- and PLO-run sectors of the West Bank town of Hebron, witnesses said.</p>
<p>In the Gaza Strip overnight, an Israeli army patrol at a Jewish settlement bloc in the Gaza Strip shot and wounded a Palestinian in the leg, Israeli military sources said.</p>
<p>The army said it was checking the reports.</p>
<p>The shooting and the running clashes underscored rising tensions over a three-month impasse in PLO-Israeli peace moves and expansion of Jewish settlement in the West Bank, Gaza Strip and Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>An Egyptian mediation drive to revive substantive talks between Israel and the Palestinians, broken off when the Jewish state began work on a new settlement in Arab East Jerusalem, has so far failed to bear fruit.</p>
<p>Dozens of youths in Hebron, some masked in black and white checkered Arab headdresses, hurled stones and bottles at Israeli troops guarding some 400 Jewish settlers who live in fortified enclaves in the heart of the town of 100,000 Palestinians.</p>
<p>Witnesses said Israeli troops fanned out across rooftops and balconies and in Hebron's narrow alleyways to brace for another day of clashes in which scores of Palestinians have been wounded by Israeli rubber bullets and tear gas.</p>
<p>Israel handed 80 percent of Hebron to Palestinian rule under an interim peace deal in January but kept troops in the heart of the city to protect the Jewish enclaves.</p>
<p>In Gaza, military sources said an Israeli patrol at the Gush Katif settlement saw two Palestinians near the settlement area's fence and called on them to halt. When the two did not respond, the patrol fired in the air and then at the two men, wounding one of them.</p>
<p>The sources said both Palestinians fled to territory under Palestinian Authority jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has accused the Palestinian Authority of orchestrating the unrest. The Authority rejects the charge, saying that Netanyahu's settlement policies lie at the root of the violence.</p>
<p>Israel demands a PLO crackdown on militants in order to resume talks. The Palestinian Authority wants Netanyahu to call a halt to settlement activity.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HEBRON, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
