<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674929" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Cohen's Gulf tour aimed at creating tension - Iran.</title>
<headline>Cohen's Gulf tour aimed at creating tension - Iran.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran said on Thursday a visit by U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen to its Arab neighbours in the Gulf aimed at creating tension in the region.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Mahmoud Mohammadi said comments against Iran by Cohen during this week's tour were part of Washington's &quot;poisonous propaganda&quot; against Iran.</p>
<p>&quot;The Foreign Ministry spokesman described the comments by the U.S. defence secretary...as a continuation of the poisonous propaganda by the U.S. against the Islamic republic of Iran aimed at creating a sense of anxiety in the region,&quot; the official Iranian news agency IRNA reported.</p>
<p>&quot;Mohammadi added that Iran places a great importance on the security of the Persian Gulf and considers security and cooperation among the countries in the Persian Gulf region as a must to this end,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>&quot;He noted that the increased presence of foreign forces in the Persian Gulf and the unchecked sales of weapons to the region are the main obstacles in the way of establishment of security,&quot; IRNA said.</p>
<p>Cohen ended his visit to Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Bahrain, the United Arab Emirates and Oman on Wednesday after assuring them of Washington's commitment to their security and to containing Iraq and Iran.</p>
<p>He also vowed that the U.S. military would remain in the Gulf as long as Iraq and Iran presented a threat to the world's biggest oil supply.</p>
<p>But he said the United States was not headed towards a clash with Iran unless Tehran started it and he warned the Islamic republic against any attempt to halt shipping in the Gulf.</p>
<p>The United States accuses Iran of sponsoring state &quot;terrorism&quot; and has expressed mounting concern since the 1991 Gulf War about what it describes as Iran's growing military capability and its aims in the region.</p>
<p>Iran, which denies the terrorism charges, opposes the U.S. military presence in the Gulf and says Washington falsely accuses Tehran of threatening regional security in order to scare its Gulf Arab allies into buying more American weapons.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
