<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674992" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian OLOs wait for data for new life.</title>
<headline>Belgian OLOs wait for data for new life.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Belgian bond market resumed its holding pattern in early Thursday dealings, waiting for the latest batch of German and U.S. data to try and find some direction.</p>
<p>But dealers were not optimistic that either the German Ifo business sentiment index or U.S. jobless and trade numbers due later would give the market what it wanted.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had lots of data in the past few weeks and it has had very little impact,&quot; one trader commented. &quot;But lets wait and see today.&quot;  </p>
<p>The shape of the curve was steady, one trader said, with the spread between two and five year paper around 80 basis points, five-to-10 around 140 basis points and 10-to-15 around 47 basis points.</p>
<p>One dealer said volume in the market was thin, meaning small orders could easily move parts of the curve, but overall the picture was holding stable.</p>
<p>By 0750 GMT the benchmark 10-year OLO yield had fallen slightly to 5.79 from 5.80 percent as the Belgian market moved higher with Bunds. The spread over equivalent German paper was steady at eight basis points.</p>
<p>-- Nick Antonovics, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
