<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674962" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Madrid stocks start higher, volatility possible.</title>
<headline>Madrid stocks start higher, volatility possible.</headline>
<text>
<p>MADRID, June 19 (Reuter) 0845 GMT - Madrid stocks were up in early trade on Thursday, helped by bond gains and a thin market, dealers said.</p>
<p>Trade may well be volatile, they added, and focus will be on key U.S. data this afternoon and EMU-affecting news from France. * General index opens up 2.18 points, 0.38 percent, to 579.98 * Ibex up 37.22 points, 0.56 percent, to 6,656.92 * Utilities especially strong, still recovering from recent weakness in technically-orientated trade. * Gas Natural up 1.9 pct to 32,010 after shareholders approved a four-for-one share split and after the firm gave analysts a positive outlook in a presentation.  </p>
<p>BBV was up 0.8 percent to 11,250 pesetas ahead of the expected approval of a three-for-one share split and a capital increase charged to reserves.</p>
<p>Tabacalera gained 0.5 percent to 7,720 pesetas after Wednesday's shareholders' meeting and the announcement of its purchase of a 20 percent stake in duty-free retailer Aldeasa.</p>
<p>Due later are first quarter current account data from the U.S., as well as the Philadelphia Fed survey.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
