<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="674980" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French government removes Paris police chief.</title>
<headline>French government removes Paris police chief.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's new left-wing government on Thursday removed the head of Paris criminal police, who was suspended for refusing to help a corruption probe into conservative Paris mayor Jean Tiberi.</p>
<p>Olivier Foll, 58, was transferred to the less sensitive post of police inspector general. A decree published in the official gazette said he was replaced by Patrick Riou, 50, formerly the spokesman of the national police headquarters.</p>
<p>The decree, prepared by Interior Minister Jean-Pierre Chevenement, was countersigned by President Jacques Chirac, who was Paris mayor until 1995 when Tiberi, his deputy and close associate, took over.</p>
<p>The case was a test of the &quot;cohabitation&quot; between the conservative president and the Socialist-led government.</p>
<p>The previous conservative government kept Foll in his job in an open challenge to courts which had suspended his investigative capacities.</p>
<p>The supreme court in February upheld a six-month suspension on Foll after he ordered his men to refuse to help an investigating magistrate search Tiberi's home last year.</p>
<p>Magistrate Eric Halphen was looking for evidence in a far-reaching investigation into alleged illicit funding of Chirac's Gaullist RPR party through rake-offs on public housing contracts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
