<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675040" id="root" date="1997-06-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TOBACCO-HEALTH-GLOBAL.</title>
<headline>TOBACCO-HEALTH-GLOBAL.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tobacco companies have long given up on the United States as a top market and are targeting the developing world -- and the health consequences are already clear, health experts and anti-smoking campaigners say.</p>
<p>Eastern Europe and Asia, particularly, offer big profits, they say. Such countries, where smokers are not yet exiled to street corners and outside doorways, are already paying the health price, they add.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a question of their turning their attention to the developing world. They already did,&quot; said Neil Collishaw, one of the World Health Organisation's top experts on smoking.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate about two thirds of the deaths currently are in the developing world,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>But he said those numbers will switch dramatically, so that by the mid-2020s 70 percent of all tobacco-related deaths would be in developing countries.</p>
<p>Their comments came as U.S. cigarette makers were locked in talks with the top law officers from individual states on compensation for smoking-related ilnesses and tougher restrictions on tobacco sales and advertising.</p>
<p>Last month Christopher Murray of the Harvard School of Public Health and WHO's Alan Lopez said that by 2020 smoking-related diseases would be the leading cause of death in the world.</p>
<p>They predicted there would be 8.4 million smoking-related deaths a year in 2020 compared with three million in 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;The largest increases in the epidemic of tobacco mortality will be in India, China and other Asian nations and the Pacific Islands, where attributable deaths will increase from 1.1 million to 4.2 million,&quot; they wrote in the Lancet medical journal.</p>
<p>WHO predicts cancer cases will at least double globally during the next 25 years as people in developing countries take up unhealthy habits such as smoking. It said coronary heart disease -- for which smoking is a main risk factor -- was now the world's biggest killer disease.</p>
<p>&quot;As tobacco consumption is increasing in many developing countries, the lung cancer epidemic seems certain to continue and grow,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>It said 85 percent of lung cancer cases in men around the world were due to smoking, 46 percent in women.</p>
<p>And it is not just the smokers who are affected. Last month a 10-year study published by Harvard University scientists found second-hand smoke doubled a person's risk of heart disease.</p>
<p>&quot;There may be up to 50,000 Americans dying of heart attacks from passive smoking each year,&quot; said Dr Ichiro Kawachi, who directed the research.</p>
<p>Other research has also linked &quot;environmental tobacco smoke&quot; with disease, although this is hotly disputed by tobacco companies.</p>
<p>On Tuesday anti-smoking campaigners from 19 countries, including Britain, Australia, France, Canada, Cameroon, India and Taiwan, urged that any U.S. settlement with tobacco companies take the rest of the world into account.</p>
<p>&quot;Approximately 85 percent of the annual three million tobacco-related deaths occur outside of the United States,&quot; they wrote. &quot;And while smoking and tobacco use rates are relatively flat or declining in the United States, they are rising elsewhere, especially in the developing countries.&quot;</p>
<p>Dr Judith Mackay, of the Asian Consultancy on Tobacco Control, said she had calculated the cost of smoking to the territory and found hospital costs alone were around $100 million a year.</p>
<p>&quot;That's without the social costs like fires and so on,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Smoking is blamed for helping lower the average life expectancy of Russian men to 58 -- at least 15 years lower than that of men in Western Europe. WHO estimates that two-thirds of all Russian men smoke.</p>
<p>Last month the United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF) said young people in the developing world were the most promising target for tobacco companies and called on governments and the World Trade Organisation to ban all advertising aimed at children and teenagers.</p>
<p>&quot;The tobacco companies know that their best customers are those they snare early in life,&quot; UNICEF Executive Director Carol Bellamy said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
