<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675214" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper ends sharply off after downside test.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper ends sharply off after downside test.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper ended sharply lower after an unexpectedly successful downside test triggered stops, leaving some of longs, hitherto lulled by strong nearby fundamentals, caught unaware, dealers said.</p>
<p>Most-active July COMEX copper settled 4.05 cents weaker at 118.10 cents a lb, traded 122.60 to 118.00 cents. Spot June went out 3.50 cents weaker at 118.50 cents, with September off 3.35 cents at 116.10 cents.</p>
<p>Earlier in the session dealers said there appeared to be a bid to test the downside and flush out the longs, though some felt reassured this would fail because of the widening backwardation on LME and July to September spread on COMEX, dealers said.</p>
<p>There was also talk of disillusionment among funds at the failure of July COMEX to break convincingly above 123.00 cents a lb, or $2,600 a tonne in LME three months contract.</p>
<p>&quot;One school of thought is they just tired of punching and decided to try to test the other side, found there was no support and it snowballed big time,&quot; Rich Hirsch of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell said.</p>
<p>There appeared to be no fresh fundamental news behind the drop, dealers said. There was talk of possible Chinese copper sales on the way, though some dealers cautioned this may just be a ploy to spook the market lower to buy copper more cheaply.</p>
<p>Overall, the nearby fundamental picture still looked solid, traders said, with the on-going strike at Inco in Canada, and shipment problems at Ok Tedi in Papua New Guinea.</p>
<p>LME stocks also fell a hefty 1,800 tonnes Friday to 121,550 tonnes.</p>
<p>The LME cash to three months backwardation eased by close to $110/$120, down from the day's high of about $130.</p>
<p>((Huw Jones, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
