<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675459" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Sea crude differentials steady, end-week trade thin. [CORRECTED 18:55 GMT]</title>
<headline>N.Sea crude differentials steady, end-week trade thin. [CORRECTED 18:55 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crude differentials held steady in quiet trade on Friday but a fall in outright values was a spur for paper values to weaken, traders said.</p>
<p>After heavy business on Thursday players appeared to have paused to collect their thoughts, with some hoping for more clarity over the situation in Iraq and others looking to next week's meeting of OPEC oil ministers in Vienna.</p>
<p>Physical trade was limited to the Oseberg grade, with a July 15-17 loader done at dated Brent +13 cents and a July 16-18 passed on twice at +15 and +16 cents to allow a major to build a million barrel cargo. (Corrects by deleting reference to Poland, corrects buyer, and adds clarification on possible Brent deal).</p>
<p>The major holding most of this month's wet Brent may have passed one cargo to a trader with a short into Poland but this could not be confirmed, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a typically slow Friday afternoon but at least the differentials appear to be stable,&quot; said one trader. &quot;But three deals is not bad after such a busy week.&quot;</p>
<p>Of the four Brents nominated loading dates on Friday, one was clocked and three otheres were kept ahead of the five o'clock deadline.</p>
<p>There appeared to be little reaction to news one cargo out of the July Flotta programme had been cancelled. But traders said the uncertainty over when Iraq will recommence crude exports under the U.N. oil-for-food programme was lending some background support.</p>
<p>Iraqi officials have said Baghdad will not resume exports until the remaining $800 million of revenue from the first 180 days of the U.N. deal had been spent on humanitarian supplies.</p>
<p>Players were keeping an open mind on next week's OPEC meeting, but doubted it would succeed in cutting back crude supply.</p>
<p>One major confirmed plans to ship two or three VLCCs, mainly of Oseberg, out of Europe in July, with at least two of the vessels bound for Asia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
