<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67557" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK Catholics &quot;betrayed&quot; over bishop's love child.</title>
<headline>UK Catholics &quot;betrayed&quot; over bishop's love child.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Roman Catholic Church said on Friday it felt betrayed by a runaway bishop who fathered a love child in a deeply embarrassing sex scandal.</p>
<p>Bishop Roderick Wright, who vanished nearly two weeks ago from his Scottish diocese with a divorcee, dealt the church a second body blow when a 15-year-old boy tearfully admitted to millions of television viewers that he was the cleric's secret son.</p>
<p>Sobbing over the father he had met for just two months in his whole life, Kevin Whibley said: &quot;It's too late now. I don't even want him if he comes.&quot;</p>
<p>His mother Joanne spoke angrily of the secret love for a priest she kept buried for so long. &quot;I have lived a lie and so has he,&quot; she said in a BBC television interview on Thursday.</p>
<p>Their revelations shook the Roman Catholic establishment to its foundations and again raised questions about the enforced celibacy of priests. Church leaders were appalled by the heartache inflicted on mother and child by one of their clerics.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been mistreated badly and that is regrettable. I feel as betrayed as anybody in all of this,&quot; said Scotland's Cardinal Thomas Winning, who received Wright's resignation at the weekend. The Vatican accepted it formally on Thursday.</p>
<p>Wright, 55, vanished at the same time as 40-year-old divorcee and mother of three Kathleen Macphee. He has apologised to her family but said nothing of his past.</p>
<p>That prompted 48-year-old Joanne Whibley finally to go public about the guilty secret she harboured for 15 years.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not want this trivialised, this pathetic story. I would want it to serve some purpose,&quot; she said, her face crumpling in anguish.</p>
<p>Kevin Whibley, bombarded all his life with questions about the identity of his father, said his personal tragedy highlighted the need for the church to abandon its opposition to celibate priests.</p>
<p>Wright was a priest in a remote area of Scotland when he first met Joanne. He instructed her in the Catholic faith and threatened to flee to Peru if she exposed his secret.</p>
<p>&quot;I wept for the mother and child and the way in which they have been treated,&quot; Winning, leader of Scotland's 750,000 Catholics, told The Herald newspaper in Glasgow.</p>
<p>Cardinal Basil Hume, archbishop to 4.4 million English and Welsh Catholics, said the church had been gravely damaged by the scandal which highlighted the need to give priests better training for their vocation.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure there are other cases and we should be very, very vigilant ... I am amazed and admire the great majority of priests who do live out their celibacy, often with a struggle but pretty heroically,&quot; he told Sky Television.</p>
<p>Pope John Paul is implacably opposed to any change in church law. The Vatican insists on celibacy from its priests and nuns, saying the church's consecrated members must be celibate in order to devote themselves completely to God and their work.</p>
<p>Whibley's hurt, anger and confusion mirrored the identity crisis suffered four years ago by the lovechild of runaway Irish priest Eamon Casey, the errant bishop of Galway.</p>
<p>The boy's mother was American divorcee Annie Murphy whose revelations profoundly shocked deeply conservative and predominantly Catholic Ireland.</p>
<p>In her autobiography &quot;Forbidden Fruit,&quot; she wrote of their first night of passion: &quot;I witnessed a great hunger. This was an Irish famine of the flesh. He was a man releasing energies and feelings pent up for 25 years of his adult life.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
