<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675537" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bombardier unit hopeful on contract talks.</title>
<headline>Bombardier unit hopeful on contract talks.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bombardier Inc's de Havilland unit is hopeful that contract talks with its 3,800 unionized workers will conclude successfully before the Monday morning strike deadline, a company official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been considerable progress made, but there are still several sub-issues that have got to be worked through,&quot; Bombardier Aerospace group spokesman Colin Fisher told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It is planned that talks will continue throughout the weekend and we're optimistic about reaching a settlement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Canadian Auto Workers, which represents 3,800 of the 6,326 workers at Toronto-based de Havilland, said on Friday that it received a new contract offer from the company. The CAW set a strike deadline for 1000 EDT on Monday if the two sides failed to reach an agreement.</p>
<p>CAW spokeswoman Jane Armstrong said the new contract offer was a request that the union revise its position, but the union also expected to continue bargaining through the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect bargaining around-the-clock through the weekend,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>Fisher declined to specify the outstanding issues, but Armstrong said the union was opposed to the company's demand that workers accept a five-year contract. The union also wanted improved wage and pension compensation, she said.</p>
<p>The Downsview plant makes the de Havilland Dash-8 family of turboprop regional aircraft and is responsible for the final assembly of the new Bombardier Global Express long-range business jet.</p>
<p>Fisher said that de Havilland was optimistic there would be a settlement before the Monday deadline, but in case of a strike, the plant would keep operating with non-unionized employees.</p>
<p>Armstrong said the CAW settled contracts without a strike at de Havilland only once in eight rounds of bargaining over the years. The CAW went on a one-week strike at de Havilland in 1994, about a year after Montreal-based Bombardier acquired control of the company from Boeing Co, she said.</p>
<p>((Robert Melnbardis, Reuters Toronto bureau 416-941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
