<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67569" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dlr ends mixed in Europe as FOMC countdown starts.</title>
<headline>Dlr ends mixed in Europe as FOMC countdown starts.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar remained sidelined in European trading as traders remained fixated on next week's Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting in the U.S. and focused on the mark's slide on its European crosses.</p>
<p>Convergence trades were back in vogue, depressing the mark amid growing bullishness about monetary union as European Union finance ministers meet in Dublin today and Saturday. The French franc rose to two-month highs below 3.39 per mark. Traders said options-related orders accelerated the franc's rally. One European corporate was said to have triggered a stop-loss involving the sale of over one billion marks.  </p>
<p>&quot;The mark is generally weak on the crosses, but it was the surging French franc that grabbed the market's attention,&quot; said Philippe Delmotte, a corporate trader at Bank of Boston.</p>
<p>Mark weakness helped the dollar reach a high of 1.5185, where it hit a walll of sales, said Delmotte. &quot;There's a firm cap on the mark there, and the ranges might not be broken in the run-up to the FOMC meeting next week,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>At 1429 GMT, the dollar was at 1.5154/60 marks and 109.79/89 yen versus 1.5155/58 and 109.39/44 at the European close on Thursday. The French franc was at 3.3884/88 per mark compared with 3.4045/50.  </p>
<p>Some traders estimated trading volume in mark/French franc at almost three times that of dollar/mark, which normally sees the bulk of foreign exchange trade.</p>
<p>The informal meeting of European finance ministers in Dublin today and Saturday is expected to frame an agreement on the post-EMU European exchange rate mechanism. A stability pact to ensure fiscal discipline among EMU participants is also scheduled for discussion.</p>
<p>&quot;The EMU theme is dominant in the forex market, and anything that's good for EMU is bad for the mark,&quot; said Giorgio Radaelli, international economist at Lehman Brothers.  </p>
<p>Several official comments ahead of the Dublin meeting also showed the heightened political determination to support the EMU process, analysts said.</p>
<p>French Finance Minister Jean Arthuis and his German counterpart Theo Waigel co-wrote an article in the International Herald Tribune today which said both countries are now &quot;more than ever convinced&quot; EMU will happen on time and be a success.</p>
<p>&quot;There might still be some wrangling over how rigid the stability pact should be but the political determination to make EMU work can't be ignored,&quot; said Radaelli.  </p>
<p>The market is still preoccupied with next Tuesday's Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting, and opinion is still divided over the possible outcome. A Reuter poll showed that 17 out of 30 polled expected a rate rise on September 24.</p>
<p>Some argue that retail sales below expectations and benign inflation data might prevent a credit tightening at this stage. Others point to signs of tightening labour markets and wage pressures as justifying a rate rise.</p>
<p>&quot;This division is making the market quite nervous - too nervous to take a decisive position on the dollar,&quot; said Delmotte at Bank of Boston.  </p>
<p>Traders said dollar buying for yen to cover part of a $7.0 billion aid package to India helped dollar/yen higher. Japan is the largest donor with 135 billon yen.</p>
<p>It is still about half a yen below Wednesday's levels, before it weakened sharply on news of an almost 43 percent surge in the U.S. trade deficit in July.</p>
<p>Dealers said 109.90 yen, former support and now resistance, capped the dollar. Japanese markets will be closed for a public holiday on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Astrid Zweynert London newsroom + 44 171 542 7792</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
