<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675658" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian OTC market sees busier week to June 20.</title>
<headline>Croatian OTC market sees busier week to June 20.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks trading on an over-the-counter market firmed slightly in a busier week from June 16-20, after president Franjo Tudjman secured another five-year mandate in Sunday's election, the Varazdin market said on Friday.</p>
<p>The leading seven-stock VIN index inched up 0.1 percent to 9,729 points as 10 active issues rose, eight fell, seven were flat and nine traded for the first time.</p>
<p>Volume jumped to 52,526 shares from last week's 14,598. Of these, 1,456 were sold in direct deals and only reported by brokers. Turnover rose to 5.1 million kuna from 3.5 million.</p>
<p>The most active stock was lumber manufacturer Cesma-iverica Bjelovar which made its market debut on Thursday, selling 34,898 shares at 60 kuna each. It accounted for 35 percent of the week's total trade.</p>
<p>Chocolate maker Kras firmed 8.91 percent to 440 kuna, with 1,226 shares, contributing to 9.0 percent of the total OTC trade this week.</p>
<p>Food processor Podravka had an 8.0 percent share in Varazdin market trade, with 1,617 shares sold. It closed at 280 kuna, down 1.41 percent.</p>
<p>The stock was the most active issue on the central bourse on Friday with 3,877 units sold. But it was on the losing side, ending eight kuna lower at 275.</p>
<p>Brewery Karlovacka pivovara led gainers, adding 12.12 percent to 370 kuna on volume of 195 shares.</p>
<p>The brewery, majority owned by Chile's Cervecerias Unidas was also the hot stock on Zagreb bourse on Friday, rising 15 kuna to 420 on volume of 1,124 shares.</p>
<p>Varazdin's biggest decliner was Bjelovarska Banka which closed the week at 4,150 kuna, down 17 percent.</p>
<p>Full closing results are available each afternoon on page OTCVAR. -- Laura Lui, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
