<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675602" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African shares seen trending upwards next week.</title>
<headline>S.African shares seen trending upwards next week.</headline>
<byline>Paul Harris</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African shares, freed from the vagaries of this week's futures contract close-out, are expected to resume a rising trend next week, portfolio managers said on Friday.</p>
<p>Stocks were traded cautiously in the run up to the close-out with many players sitting on the side-lines, but underlying positive sentiment is now expected to shine through.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the next few weeks, I think you will be able to look back and see the index higher than it was at the start of the week,&quot; said Malcolm Chapman, general manager at Absa Asset Management.</p>
<p>Next week will see a raft of economic data released that will give some firm guidance for the market as May numbers for CPI inflation, M3 money supply, private credit and trade balance all emerge.</p>
<p>Barring nasty surprises economists expect the market to glean largely positive direction from all the data.</p>
<p>Another spur to share prices is a recent upsurge in foreign interest in the Johannesburg Stock Exchange (JSE).</p>
<p>This was dramatically illustrated by a gigantic overseas deal by broker SBC Warburg which pushed almost two billion rand ($443.8 million) worth of stocks through the market on Wednesday. Dealers said the move probably represented an entire portfolio being moved offshore.</p>
<p>Portfolio managers said international investors were seeking value away from Wall Street and other major financial centres and casting glances at emerging markets such as South Africa.</p>
<p>The JSE has been largely ignoring New York's movements and so has attracted quite a bit of foreign attention.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not cheap yet, but we are better value than we were before. People are looking for markets that are not correlating strongly with the Dow and we fit the bill,&quot; Chapman said.</p>
<p>The interest of foreign investors has not yet turned into a flood, but it is seen as an encouraging sign. &quot;They are not going up to a full weighting (in South African equities) but they are definitely topping up,&quot; another portfolio manager said.</p>
<p>However, gold shares are still set to be the black sheep of the JSE next week as they sink further on a renewed bout of panic over the ailing bullion price.</p>
<p>The already-bombed out index has plumbed new depths this week and is at its lowest level since March, 1993.</p>
<p>Another possible hiccup on the horizon could be concerns over the July 1 relaxation of exchange controls which may trigger flows of capital out of the country.</p>
<p>Worries over this have been hitting the rand and the local bond market, but portfolio managers pointed to a recent firming in both areas as a sign these fears may never materialise.</p>
<p>News on Thursday of a $1.5 billion Reserve Bank revolving credit facility also calmed nerves as it will give South Africa some hefty ammunition to deal with any outflows.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a good move, but I wouldn't be surprised if the Reserve Bank doesn't have to go anywhere near it,&quot; one portfolio manager said.</p>
<p>On the equities front next week will see year results from food to pharmaceutial firm Premier Group Ltd on Wednesday and from tobacco and investment company Rembrandt Group Ltd on Thursday. Both firms are seen posting healthy earnings rises.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003 ($ = 4.506 South African Rand)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
