<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675795" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Kazakhstan to auction 2-yr T-bills from June 30.</title>
<headline>Kazakhstan to auction 2-yr T-bills from June 30.</headline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kazakhstan will start auctioning two-year Treasury bills from June 30, with full access to non-residents, Deputy Finance Minister Sauat Mynbayev said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the time is ready to introduce longer-term paper and we will start with two-year bills,&quot; Mynbayev told a news conference. He said the first monthly auction would take place on June 30. &quot;The volume will be about 200 million tenge ($2.6 million),&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Mynbayev said the yield would be around 20 percent to be paid twice a year. The former Soviet republic already issues three-month, six-month and 12-month MKM bills.</p>
<p>&quot;Slowly the market is moving to the longer term and yields are falling,&quot; Mynbayev said. The average yield on three-month MKM discount treasury bills rose slightly this week to 10.97 at auction on June 17 from 10.64 the previous week.</p>
<p>But overall, yields have halved in recent weeks, driving domestic banks out of the market -- annual inflation for this year is officially reckoned at 17 percent -- while foreign investors have turned to other markets to shop for better returns.</p>
<p>Country risk for longer term paper is also a factor for foreign buyers, according to ABN AMRO Bank Kazakhstan's chief treasurer, Oleg Tsurkan. &quot;About half my foreign clients say one year and no more,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Almaty Newsroom +7 3272 509410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
