<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675908" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Religion divides Colombian Indian group.</title>
<headline>Religion divides Colombian Indian group.</headline>
<byline>John Lyons</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Centuries after the first missionaries arrived in South America, a group of evangelical Christians in Colombia's northern Cesar province say they have been tied to wood beams and forced to kneel on burning rocks because of their religious beliefs.</p>
<p>The group include about 2,000 members of Colombia's indigenous Arhuaco community who have traded the sacred coca leaves of their ancestral religion for the evangelical tambourines and songs of the Pentecostal church.</p>
<p>&quot;Because they don't know the true word of God, they say we have no right to stay on the reservation,&quot; evangelical leader Cesar Nino told Reuters by telephone, referring to the traditional Arhuaco leadership.</p>
<p>In recent months his group's evangelical church has been chained shut and its members tortured by Arhuaco leaders imposing traditional forms of punishment for religious heretics, he said. &quot;We live under constant threat. Our brothers and sisters have been jailed and burned with hot rocks. But the greatest punishment is that they won't let us practice our religion in peace.&quot;</p>
<p>About 300 Arhuaco members of the United Pentecostal Church of Colombia descended from two mountain reservations this month to stage demonstrations and demand that authorities in Cesar's capital city, Valledupar, enforce a clause in Colombia's constitution guaranteeing religious freedom.</p>
<p>But Arhuaco leaders, who do not deny meteing out harsh forms of punishment, say their culture is at stake and want traditional law to prevail on the reservations of the Sierra Nevada. &quot;We are not going to accept any class of sect or other religion different from our own on the reservation,&quot; Arhuaco leader Vincente Villafane told Reuters.</p>
<p>After a week of meetings in Cesar both sides said they were far from any accord. A governor's spokesman said the regional prosecutor may be called in to settle the dispute.</p>
<p>The Arhuaco, a group of more than 12,000 who inhabit the Sierra Nevada de Santa Marta mountains, have a reputation for holding fast to their traditional nature worship and staunchly opposing the intrusion of Western religions.</p>
<p>In the past the Arhuacos have forcibly removed Christian missionaries from the sierras and they unswervingly enforce Arhuaco law, Oscar Gutierrez, a spokesman for the National Organisation of Colombian Indians (ONIC) in Bogota, said.</p>
<p>&quot;It doesn't surprise me,&quot; he said. &quot;They have taken more drastic measures and been more sucessful in maintaining their culture than other groups.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
