<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675962" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Kissinger sees stable future for Hong Kong.</title>
<headline>Kissinger sees stable future for Hong Kong.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former U.S. secretary of state Henry Kissinger said on Friday he felt Hong Kong would be secure as an autonomous region of China after the British colony is handed back to Beijing this month.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe the Chinese leaders mean what they say,&quot; he said in a dinner speech during a visit to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Communist China has embraced a policy of &quot;one country, two systems&quot; and agreed to let Hong Kong keep its capitalist system in place for 50 years.</p>
<p>Kissinger, who helped forge a rapprochement between the United States and China in the 1970s, said upsetting the balance in Hong Kong would serve no one's interests.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe it will be a smooth transition and if not, it will be due to unintended accidents by all sides,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said if an &quot;accident&quot; occurred, the main question would be how the parties involved would react.</p>
<p>Britain, which has ruled Hong Kong for more than 150 years, will hand over the colony to China in a midnight ceremony on June 30.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
