<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="675902" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru prepares for the consequences of El Nino.</title>
<headline>Peru prepares for the consequences of El Nino.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru declared a state of emergency in nine of its 24 regions on Friday to speed preparations for the natural disasters the El Nino weather pattern is expected to cause later in the year.</p>
<p>The government also set up a special emergency committee, joining together four ministries, and earmarked $19 million to get ready for droughts in the south, flooding in the north and other usual effects of El Nino.</p>
<p>A decree in the official daily El Peruano said the emergency measure applied to the northern regions of Tumbes, Piura, Lambayeque, La Libertad and Ancash and the southern regions of Arequipa, Moquegua, Tacna and Puno.</p>
<p>The state of emergency is needed &quot;to prevent the effects of the possible climatic changes that the imminent presence of the Nino phenomenon will cause,&quot; the decree said. &quot;It is necessary to adopt the necessary measures and actions to counteract the foreseeable natural disasters.&quot;</p>
<p>Local meteorologists say there are strong signs the weather system -- which occurs every two to seven years and is caused by a warming of waters in the Pacific -- is starting. But its strength will not be known until August.</p>
<p>If Peru experiences El Nino this year, the effects would last about 18 months and are likely to be strongest from December to March, experts say. The climatic changes could devastate agricultural crops, drive fish away from normally rich waters and provoke landslides.</p>
<p>The last time Peru was seriously affected by El Nino was in 1982-83, when at least 300 people died in floods and landslides and the economy shrank 12 percent because of widespread damage.</p>
<p>The weather phenomenon can also affect crops and homes in the southern United Sates, northeastern Brazil, southeastern Africa and the west Pacific.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
