<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676010" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Self-chill can will benefit Mankind, inventor says.</title>
<headline>Self-chill can will benefit Mankind, inventor says.</headline>
<byline>Nick Edwards</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The self-cooling can at the centre of a row about global warming will ultimately benefit, not harm, the environment, the chairman of the company that invented it said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to benefit mankind, trust me,&quot; Mitchell Joseph, chairman and chief executive of the California-based Joseph Company, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Joseph, speaking after his can scooped two top prizes at the can manufacturing industry's premier Cannex '97 trade show in Singapore, said his invention would create a whole new industry in self-cooling technology.</p>
<p>&quot;All the companies in the world that are into anything natural are on our doorstep saying, 'we've had things on the back shelf for years that we could never use, but because of this creation we can form a new industry',&quot; Joseph said.</p>
<p>The self-chilling can, which reduces the temperature of its contents by 30 degrees Fahrenheit (15 degrees Celsius) in about 90 seconds, scooped the awards for innovation of the year and can of the year at Cannex '97.</p>
<p>Its cooling effect comes from a refrigerant gas contained in a cannister inside the main can and released when a button at its base is pressed.</p>
<p>Most attention has focused on the potentially damaging effects the gas could have on the earth's ozone layer if the technology was used in even 10 percent of the 180 billion beverage cans produced world-wide every year.</p>
<p>The gas, HFC 134a, a hydrofluorocarbon, was developed as an alternative to chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs), but is thought by some to be more damaging.</p>
<p>Can industry experts believe the market for the can is only about 0.004 percent of total production. The Joseph Company believes demand is about 30 to 36 million cans per year.</p>
<p>Environment ministers in the European Union said on Thursday they would investigate how the can could harm the world's ecosystem and might consider banning products that use the gas.</p>
<p>Joseph said he had not followed the discussions in Europe but recognised there was concern about the gas.</p>
<p>He said he aimed to hold a news conference in the U.K. &quot;in the next couple of months&quot; to reveal a new gas.</p>
<p>The Joseph Company said the can, still under development, could be in full production by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The firm said it had developed prototype cans for the U.S. military and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) that the firm said planned to use it to chill desserts for astronauts on the next space shuttle mission in November.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
