<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676051" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: More insurance failures like Nissan unlikely - MOF.</title>
<headline>More insurance failures like Nissan unlikely - MOF.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Ministry of Finance (MOF) does not think other life insurance firms will fail like Nissan Mutual Life Insurance Co, Makoto Fukuda, director of Finance Ministry's Insurance Department, told reporters on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think what has happened to Nissan Life will happen again. I cannot see behavior in other firms such as was shown in Nissan Life. There are no such firms,&quot; Fukuda said.  </p>
<p>The Life Insurance Association of Japan said on Friday that life insurers will establish a new company to liquidate Nissan Mutual Life, as part of a framework to deal with huge losses at the failed firm. The association has been serving as an interim caretaker for Nissan Life since its failure on April 25.</p>
<p>MOF ordered Nissan Life on April 25 to halt all operations except for servicing existing customers, as the insurer suffered heavy losses through excessive stock and real estate investments in the late 1980s &quot;bubble era&quot; of inflated asset prices. It was the first failure of a life insurance firm in post-war Japan.</p>
<p>Fukuda said that MOF had received the outline of the plan from the association and approved it.  </p>
<p>The new firm which will take over Nissan Life's policies will be able to operate profitably unless there are unexpected developments in the financial markets, such as a sharp fall in stock prices, Fukuda said.</p>
<p>The firm will have low running costs, switch its funds into stable and interest-bearing financial instruments and also cut the guaranteed return to its policyholders. These moves should be enough to make the firm profitable, although it may take several years, Fukuda said.</p>
<p>However, should the company post losses, the ministry believes the insurance industry will deal with it on its own accord, Fukuda said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this scheme is based on the premise that the insurance industry is going to take the risk,&quot; Fukuda said, when asked about any possible future losses.</p>
<p>Nissan Life's liabilities exceeded its assets by around 300 billion yen. The Policyholders Protection Fund, comprised of contributions from life insurers, will inject 200 billion yen into the new company and the remaining 100 billion yen will be covered by profits the new company is expected to make over a five-year period.  </p>
<p>Under the framework developed by the association, the new company taking over Nissan Life's policies will cut the guaranteed return to policyholders to 2.75 percent.</p>
<p>Nearly half of Nissan Life's assets consist of policies held by individuals that guarantee a return of 5.5 percent, according to industry sources.</p>
<p>Fukuda said he did not think it was necessarily unfair that the guaranteed returns were being cut, which would become more in line with current interest rate levels. He also said that the cut in guaranteed returns was inevitable in order for the new firm to be able to operate profitably.  </p>
<p>The ministry hopes to submit bills to establish a system to deal with failed insurers during the regular session of the parliament in 1999 at the latest, he said.</p>
<p>Further discussions are needed on whether public funds should be used in the system, he said.</p>
<p>Fukuda added that it was necessary to consider ways to improve disclosure of insurers' businesses, including their solvency margins.</p>
<p>Asked why MOF did not halt Nissan Life's operations earlier, as it knew about the firm's losses years ago, Fukuda said the ministry's decision to support Nissan Life's restructuring plans at that time was not wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;Nissan Life failed from stock investments in the end. Perhaps our instructions to improve its business were not sufficient. That is regrettable,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He also said that the ministry did not make a wrong decision when it gave approval for the high-yielding insurance product which Nissan Life sold in excessive amounts, as the guaranteed return was in line with economic conditions at that time.</p>
<p>Fukuda said it was up to each insurance firm on how it wanted to market its products.</p>
<p>Asked if policyholders were responsible for choosing to buy policies from Nissan Life, Fukuda said that it was difficult to comment on this.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
