<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676020" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippines seen making more corn, wheat orders.</title>
<headline>Philippines seen making more corn, wheat orders.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine buyers are expected to shop for up to 100,000 tonnes corn and 75,000 tonnes of wheat next week if prices drop to lower levels, Manila grains traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>A group of Philippine feed millers, including Swift Foods Inc, plan to import 50,000 to 100,000 tonnes Chinese or U.S. yellow corn for August arrival, said Edward Acosta, vice president for the feeds division of Swift.</p>
<p>Philippine feed millers, hog and poultry raisers have so far ordered 105,000 tonnes of U.S. and Chinese yellow corn for July arrival since the start of the month due to a domestic shortage of the crop.</p>
<p>Traders said local corn buyers are starting to book orders for arrival in the second half of the year due to the drop in tariff from 100 to 80 percent starting July 1 as part of Manila's commitment to the World Trade Organisation.</p>
<p>The main Philippine corn crop harvest is not due to start until July.</p>
<p>Philippine hog and poultry raisers have projected a shortage of one to two million tonnes of corn this year.</p>
<p>Six flour millers are also expected to be in the market next week to meet short term wheat requirements, traders said.</p>
<p>Three of the millers, which rejected this week bids for the supply of 35,000 tonnes U.S. wheat for July arrival, are expected to be back in the market next week.</p>
<p>The three other millers are also expected to buy another 40,000 tonnes for either July or August arrival.</p>
<p>&quot;If the price of western white wheat breaks $150 per tonne and dark northern spring wheat falls to $180 per tonne, I will buy,&quot; an executive in one of the flour mills said.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Philippine flour millers bought 40,000 tonnes U.S. wheat for July arrival.</p>
<p>Traders said the firms, including Purefoods Corp, bought a total of 19,000 tonnes western white wheat at $156 to $157 per tonne FOB.</p>
<p>The firms also bought 12,000 dark northern spring wheat with 13.5 percent protein content at $179 to $180 per tonne FOB and 9,000 tonnes dark northern spring wheat with 14 percent protein content at $181 to $182 per tonne FOB.</p>
<p>Prevailing flour and corn prices in Manila in pesos:</p>
<p>					     June 18	     June 13</p>
<p>Hard flour wheat per 25 kg	   290		   290</p>
<p>Soft flour wheat per 25 kg	   260		   260</p>
<p>Retail price of yellow corn per kg 9.64		  9.64</p>
<p>Retail price of white corn per kg  9.62		  9.64</p>
<p>--Dolly Aglay (63 2) 841-8936, Fax 817-6267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
