<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676056" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Yilmaz nominated to squeeze out Turkish Islamists.</title>
<headline>Yilmaz nominated to squeeze out Turkish Islamists.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Bell</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's president on Friday handed secularist Mesut Yilmaz the difficult task of forging a new coalition to keep the embattled Islamists out of power.</p>
<p>&quot;The president gave Yilmaz the responsiblity to form a government that will defuse the current tension in the country,&quot; President Suleyman Demirel's office said in a statement.</p>
<p>Yilmaz, 50, will now have to patch together an alliance from squabbling secularist leaders to replace the collapsed coalition of Necmettin Erbakan, modern Turkey's first Islamist leader.</p>
<p>Erbakan, hounded by the anti-Islamist army, stepped down this week in what he thought would be a smooth transfer of power to his pro-Western deputy that would let the Islam-based Welfare Party stay in office.</p>
<p>But the presidential appointment has raised the prospect of the Islamists returning to the opposition benches.</p>
<p>&quot;The president's behaviour was wrong,&quot; Erbakan said in comments broadcast on the NTV television channel. &quot;The worst thing about it is that the parliamentary majority has not been taken into account,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yilmaz has just 129 MPs in the 550-seat parliament compared to Erbakan's proposed government alliance, led by coalition ally Tansu Ciller, which can show 282 deputies -- at least on paper.</p>
<p>But Demirel, a veteran of political in-fighting, relied on Turkish political tradition and turned to Yilmaz as leader of the second-biggest faction in parliament after Erbakan himself.</p>
<p>Yilmaz, a staid conservative, was confident he could hammer together a cabinet list by June 30 to lead the country to early polls next spring.</p>
<p>&quot;In nine days, that is the second Monday from now, I will give the government list to the president,&quot; he said. He was not expected to invite the Islamists into a new coalition.</p>
<p>Two leftist parties have said they were prepared to back Yilmaz in an &quot;Islamist-free&quot; coalition, but Yilmaz would still require substantial defections from a rival conservative party, led by his personal rival Ciller.</p>
<p>Yilmaz said he would meet the leaders of the other secularist parties including Ciller, next Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Hope for a new start for the country has been born,&quot; Cumhur Ersumer, a spokesman for Yilmaz's Motherland Party told a news conference before the formal announcement. &quot;(The Motherland Party) is ready to take over the duties of the administration.&quot;</p>
<p>Yilmaz, prime minister twice since 1991, went to Ankara's main Kocatepe mosque for Friday prayers after Demirel's invitation. A bouquet of flowers sent by a well-wisher stood outside the Yilmaz family home, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The Istanbul stock market index, battered by recent political chaos, ended up 2.56 percent on hopes Yilmaz would get the nod from Demirel. Trading ended before Yilmaz was nominated.</p>
<p>Anatolian news agency said armed forces chief General Ismail Hakki Karadayi arrived at Demirel's residence an hour after the Yilmaz appointment for talks with the president.</p>
<p>The army has a long history of intervention in politics, deposing three governments in the last four decades before playing a key role in forcing Erbakan out.</p>
<p>Top commanders have branded religious activism as &quot;public enemy number one&quot; for NATO member Turkey. The generals had become increasingly critical in recent weeks of Erbakan's attempts to water down Turkey's strict secularism.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
