<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676289" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Romania wants early NATO entry - Ciorbea.</title>
<headline>Romania wants early NATO entry - Ciorbea.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea said on Friday his country will press to win an invitation to join NATO at an alliance summmit next month despite U.S. opposition to immediate membership for Romania.</p>
<p>But Ciorbea added before talks with U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen that Bucharest was convinced it would eventually become a part of the alliance even if it was not invited at the July 8-9 summit in Madrid.</p>
<p>&quot;We will try to act until the time of the Madrid meeting to have a very wise decision taken there. This is our duty towards our own people and towards those who support us,&quot; Ciorbea told reporters.</p>
<p>He stressed that his meetings in Washington this week with Cohen and other U.S. leaders were chiefly to enhance bilateral relations with the United States and not to cause tension.</p>
<p>&quot;We are here to look for solutions ... not to create new problems in the NATO pact,&quot; the prime minister said.</p>
<p>The United States said last week it favoured including only Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic to become members in a first round and opposed Romania and Slovenia despite support from other allies to include the five countries in the first round.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to be perfectly clear,&quot; Cohen told reporters on Friday. &quot;The United States did not say 'no' to Romanian membership in NATO last week, it said 'not yet.'&quot;</p>
<p>Cohen said the meeting on Friday was to discuss such issues as increased bilateral exchanges of military and civilian officials to help Romania continue on the road of democratic and military reform.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been saddened by the (U.S.) decision,&quot; Ciorbea said. &quot;At the same time, obviously we are very interested to develop a strategic partnership between our two countries which will cover all possible aspects -- political, economic, commercial and military.&quot;</p>
<p>Ciorbea met on Wednesday with with Secretary of State Madeleine Albright and Deputy Secretary of State Strobe Talbott, who sought to soothe Bucharest's disappointment.</p>
<p>He also met on Wednesday with Vice President Al Gore to press his country's case.</p>
<p>Washington has insisted that the first round be limited to three states but says that NATO membership should remain open to any European country into the indefinite future.</p>
<p>That is at odds with France, Italy and others who want to also include Romania and Slovenia in the first wave. Since the alliance operates by consensus, the Clinton administration is confident its stance will prevail.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
