<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676359" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Russian Patriarch attacks proselytism by rivals.</title>
<headline>Russian Patriarch attacks proselytism by rivals.</headline>
<byline>Elizabeth Fullerton</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Patriarch of the Russian Orthodox Church, faced with deepening rifts within his own church, spoke out strongly on Friday against efforts by rivals to woo followers away.</p>
<p>&quot;Proselytism is a big problem for us today,&quot; Patriarch Alexiy II told a news conference during a five-day visit to Austria.</p>
<p>&quot;There can be no place for proselytism in the relations between the churches,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Russian Orthodox Church earlier this month called off a proposed meeting between Alexiy and Pope John Paul, which would have been the first of its kind since the Great Schism split Christendom in 1054.</p>
<p>Alexiy said the churches had not had sufficient time to agree on a common document, which he said must reject proselytism, or conversion of followers from one religious movement to another.</p>
<p>He noted that such a historic meeting would have to be well prepared in advance.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we can name a date for such a meeting. We are continuing our dialogue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Polish Pope, spiritual leader of the world's 960 million Roman Catholics, has expressed a wish to travel to Russia, where eastern Christianity was introduced less than a century before the Schism.</p>
<p>But the Russian Church, sensitive to the influx of rival religions in recent years, has so far opposed such a visit.</p>
<p>Tensions persist between the two denominations following the 1991 break-up of the Soviet Union, which sparked a race to fill the spiritual vacuum created by communism.</p>
<p>&quot;After 70 years of state-run atheism, which alienated people from their faith, our most important task is to revive men's souls and our missionary work, not in other countries but amongst our own people,&quot; Patriarch Alexiy said.</p>
<p>The breakaway Orthodox church in Ukraine was a source of grief to many, he said.</p>
<p>In Ukraine, where different branches of the Orthodox church are competing with each other as well as with a strong Greek Catholic church, relations are particularly fraught.</p>
<p>The Patriarch earlier met Austrian President Thomas Klestil and called for Austria and Russia to coordinate efforts to create peace and stability instead of new divisions.</p>
<p>&quot;We must eliminate the last remnants of the Cold War from memory and build up a common European house,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Alexiy is visiting Austria to attend the Second European Ecumenical Conference beginning on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
