<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676410" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch shares jump to new high after option expiry.</title>
<headline>Dutch shares jump to new high after option expiry.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares jumped to a new record on Friday after June option expiry took effect at 1400 GMT. The AEX share index closed at 862.20 points, 5.61 points higher than the previous record close.</p>
<p>Dealers said the steady dollar and bond market lent some support. High tech stocks were in demand after the sector performed well in the U.S. last night.</p>
<p>Baan and ASML rose strongly. Software firm Baan gained 6.00 guilders to close at 125.00, after briefly touching all time high of 125.40. Semiconductor maker ASML gained 5.60 guilders to 107.60.</p>
<p>Unilever rose after detailing expansion plans.</p>
<p>Food group Unilever said earlier it aimed to expand its margarine business in Russia. It rose 8.90 guilders to a new record close of 408.80 guilders.</p>
<p>Entertainment group Polygram was another stock jumping to a new record after announcing news it was planning to sell off its tape business. Polygram closed 3.80 guilders higher at 110.00.</p>
<p>Dealers also noted a growing interest for stocks that had been underperforming the market. &quot;KLM, Bolswessanen, KNP BT and Heineken are slowly attracting more buyers,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>The dealer added that investors were starting to look for bargains in an relatively expensive market.</p>
<p>The main share index, the AEX, started at about 640 points at the beginning of this year. This means that the index has increased over 35 percent since the start of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The share business is like a bubble at the moment,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;The bubble seems to become bigger and bigger, without popping.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that some investors were turning towards KPN as the stock looked safe after the group announced it would split the firm in a postal and a telecoms arm. KPN shares slipped half a guilder today to 82.30. But for the whole trading week it still gained over six guilders.</p>
<p>Shipping and road transport group Nedlloyd gained 2.20 guilders to 55.50, after broker Van Lanschot issued a buy recommendation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
