<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676442" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>India: Major Indian parties unite on choice of president.</title>
<headline>Major Indian parties unite on choice of president.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Vice President Kocheril Raman Narayanan on Friday won the backing of the country's three main political groupings for his bid for presidency, assuring his victory in next month's election.</p>
<p>The main opposition Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) decided to back Narayanan's candidacy hours after he registered to run for office, flanked by the prime minister and the Congress party's leader in a show of unusual political solidarity.</p>
<p>The ruling United Front and Congress, its main ally, agreed on Monday to endorse Narayanan as their joint presidential candidate in the indirect election set for July 14.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral and Congress president Sitaram Kesri were joined by at least five cabinet ministers as Narayanan filed his nomination papers.</p>
<p>The presence of leaders from Gujral's United Front coalition and Congress lent an aura of invincibility to Narayanan, a journalist-turned-diplomat and former Congress minister who is certain to become India's first low-caste president.</p>
<p>Under the Indian parliamentary system, the president is the titular head of state and has few real powers compared to the prime minister, who is the head of government.</p>
<p>But the constitution empowers the president to pick the prime minister of the world's most populous democracy.</p>
<p>In the past 13 months after inconclusive general elections, President Shankar Dayal Sharma has had to name three prime ministers at the head of coalition governments.</p>
<p>Wary of each other in many areas, the United Front and Congress amiably joined hands this week to back the vice president.</p>
<p>They last stood shoulder to shoulder in public to block the BJP's bid for power after it emerged as the single largest party following last year's general elections.</p>
<p>With all three parties' backing, Narayanan is assured of winning the election, which will involve voting by members of the federal parliament and the assemblies in the 26 states.</p>
<p>The BJP's ruling partner in Maharashtra state, the Shiv Sena, has thrown its support behind the outspoken former election commissioner, T.N. Seshan. But its votes will be swamped by the three main groupings.</p>
<p>Since India became a republic in 1950, the presidency has been held by 10 people -- seven upper-caste Hindus, a Sikh and two Moslems. The presidential term of office is five years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
