<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676590" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian dollar opens flat in light trading.</title>
<headline>Canadian dollar opens flat in light trading.</headline>
<text>
<p>FORECAST RANGE   1.3860/1.3890	    ASIAN CLOSE     1.3871</p>
<p>RESISTANCE 1.3800   SUPPORT 1.3950	HI 1.3880   LO  1.3871</p>
<p>CANADA OPEN  1.3873/78    HI 1.3880     EUROPE OPEN     1.3825</p>
<p>PREV CLOSE   1.3874/79    LO 1.3871     HI 1.3884   LO  1.3874</p>
<p>---------------------MARKET COMMENT--------------------------</p>
<p>* Canada's dollar opened flat on Friday at C$1.3873</p>
<p>(US$0.7208) in light trading after the currency was sidelined in overnight trading, dealers said.</p>
<p>* They said a lack of economic data out of Canada and the United States would likely confine the currency to a narrow range of C$1.3860 (US$0.7211) and C$1.3890 (US$0.7199).</p>
<p>On Thursday, an expected Canada dollar sell-off on the back of disappointing economic data showing Canada's trade surplus shrinking from the previous month failed to materialize.</p>
<p>Instead, the currency gained back some of the losses</p>
<p>sustained this week, rallying to C$1.3875 (US$0.7207) before</p>
<p>the end of trading.</p>
<p>The comeback followed a disastrous trading session on Wednesday when the Canadian dollar sunk to C$1.3930 (US$0.7176) after breaking through weak technical support, which triggered a spate of stop-loss orders.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing we can say is that this has been a disappointing week for the Canadian dollar,&quot; Farrill said.</p>
<p>&quot;There hasn't been anything numberwise to suggest why we should be selling Canadian dollars, yet we're substantially lower than where we were last week,&quot; Farrill added.</p>
<p>On the crosses, the Canadian dollar rose to 82.54 yen from Thursday's 82.20 yen and jumped to 1.2441 marks from Thursday's 1.2422 marks.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
