<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676547" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian PM asks junior minister to resign -agencies.</title>
<headline>Indian PM asks junior minister to resign -agencies.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral has asked a junior minister accused in a $280-million corruption scandal to resign, local news agencies said on Friday.</p>
<p>They said Gujral had written to junior Rural Areas and Employment Minister Chandradeo Prasad Varma seeking his resignation from the council of ministers. Varma is one of several dozen accused in a fodder scandal in Bihar state.  </p>
<p>On Tuesday the Bihar governor authorised federal police to prosecute Varma and the state chief minister, Laloo Prasad Yadav, in the corruption scandal.</p>
<p>The Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI) had required permission from the state governor to pursue legal proceedings against Yadav and Varma, who are among 55 officials and politicians named by federal police in the case.</p>
<p>Both Yadav, who is president of Gujral's Janata Dal party, and Varma have said they are innocent in the scandal, which dates back to the 1980s and involved the alleged siphoning off of animal welfare funds.</p>
<p>The scandal has stoked tension in the Janata Dal, which is the biggest group in Gujral's 15-party United Front coalition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
