<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676612" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Heartstream heart device sales disappoint.</title>
<headline>Heartstream heart device sales disappoint.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nine months after a burst of publicity surrounding the approval of its pioneering external heart defibrillator, Heartstream Inc. said Thursday that sales have been less than electrifying.</p>
<p>&quot;It's rolling out slower than we had anticipated,&quot; said Gary Onn, chief financial officer of the Seattle-based firm in an interview following remarks to investors here at a Piper Jaffray conference.</p>
<p>Potential buyers of the company's lead product -- the ForeRunner automatic external defibrillator, or AED -- are taking longer than expected to make purchase decisions and competing products have emerged. Heartstream is also discovering that it must establish new distribution channels.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a missionary sell ... Every order is a struggle,&quot; Onn said.</p>
<p>Meantime, shares in the five-year-old company have declined steadily since hitting an all-time high in September of $17.50. In Thursday on Nasdaq, Heartstream shares rose 12.5 cents to $8.375.</p>
<p>&quot;The market addressed by the ForeRunner has the potential to develop into a very large business,&quot; said Piper Jaffray medical technology analyst Arch Smith.</p>
<p>&quot;The major hurdle for Heartstream stems from the fact that at this point in time there is no established distribution channel for these innovative devices into the new target locations. These will have to be carved out over time through the efforts of the company and its competitors,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>The ForeRunner AED is a hand-held medical device that packs into a four-pound plastic box all the battery power and circuitry needed to administer a potentially life-saving electric shock to someone suffering from sudden cardiac arrest, the leading cause of death in the United States.</p>
<p>The routine is familiar from television medical shows -- the patient's heart stops, the nurse hands the doctor the paddles, the doctor shouts &quot;clear&quot; and presses the paddles onto the patient's chest, jolting the heart to life.</p>
<p>The problem is that 90 percent of sudden cardiac arrests occur outside the hospital. Portable defibrillators have been carried for years aboard paramedic trucks and ambulances, but they were complex, bulky and often arrived too late.</p>
<p>So, there was much excitement in September when the U.S. Food and Drug Administration approved the ForeRunner -- a lightweight, low-cost and simple-to-use device that Heartstream said it planned to sell for use in police cars, airliners, stadiums, factories and other places for emergency use by almost anyone, not just trained medical personnel.</p>
<p>The FDA approval was accompanied by a recommendation for widespread public deployment of AEDs from the American Heart Association. American Airlines, a unit of AMR Corp., in November agreed to buy 300 ForeRunners and to become the first U.S. airline to carry AEDs aboard its airplanes.</p>
<p>Heartstream began shipping ForeRunners in November. In February, the firm announced several sales agreements, but when first-quarter sales came in at about $1.2 million, a disappointed Wall Street sold the stock off sharply.</p>
<p>Industry analysts are projecting 1997 sales of about $10 million and continuing net losses. Onn declined to comment on those estimates.</p>
<p>Competing AEDs, which are all heavier and less sophisticated than the ForeRunner, have hit the market. Physio-Control International Corp., Laerdal Medical Inc. and SurVivaLink Corp. are among rival AED makers and are benefitting from having more marketing experience than Heartstream.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of our competition are enjoying a little more success than they had expected,&quot; Onn said.</p>
<p>Heartstream expects the release next month of an academic study that will show biphasic waveform defibrillation to be more effective than monophasic waveform, Onn said. Of all the AEDs on the market, only the ForeRunner offers biphasic waveform, which is standard on implantable defibrillators.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
