<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676608" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Upbeat Clinton sets agenda for G7 summit.</title>
<headline>Upbeat Clinton sets agenda for G7 summit.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton, riding high on the success of the U.S. economy, set his agenda for a summit of industralized nations on Thursday by urging them to abandon old ideas and take up the tools that helped America relaunch itself.</p>
<p>With the leaders of Germany, France, Italy, Britain, Russia, Japan and Canada en route or arriving in this &quot;mile high&quot; Rocky Mountain city for a three-day summit starting on Friday, Clinton made clear in a scene-setting speech that he intended to preach about U.S economic triumphs.</p>
<p>But even before the summit started the United States and Japan were disagreeing about the extent of the U.S. role in deregulating key sectors of the Japanese economy.</p>
<p>U.S. officials said Washington would play an advisory role, but Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto said it would be neither advisory nor supervisory, adding, &quot;We have no intention of being supervised.&quot;</p>
<p>For his part, Clinton complained at a meeting with Hashimoto about Japan's persistent trade surplus with the United States despite Tokyo's assurances it would work to reduce it.</p>
<p>Japan also threw a wrench into President Boris Yeltsin's plans to have this summit anoint Russia as its eighth member. Hashimoto said he could not accept a full Russian role until Moscow gave back four north Pacific islands it seized from Japan at the end of the Second World War. against any emergency including a chemical weapon attack.</p>
<p>In his speech shortly after arriving for the 23rd annual G7 meeting, Clinton stressed normal trade relations must be maintained with the huge country conspicuous by its absence from the exclusive summit club  -- China.</p>
<p>&quot;We should not attenuate normal trade relations with a country just because we disagree with it. We should find ways to honestly articulate our disagreements ... but we shouldn't imperil 170,000 American jobs today and a big chunk of America's future ... by cutting off normal trade relations,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>Congress will vote later this month on whether to extend most favored nation (MFN) trade status with China for another year.</p>
<p>In a speech at a high-tech television facility in the Denver suburb of Littleton, Clinton said the U.S. economic boom over which he has presided was created by a new approach to economics based on balancing the budget, investing in education and expanding trade.</p>
<p>Just four years ago, Clinton was roundly criticized at his first economic summit for an economy that was stagnating under the weight of massive budget deficits.</p>
<p>Now he was ready to boast: &quot;We host our partners at a time when America's economy is the healthiest in a generation and the strongest in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>He credited &quot;a new American economic approach that required us to puncture myths and push past yesterday's failed debates ...(enabling) us to move earlier and more strongly than most other nations into the new global economy.</p>
<p>&quot;All the countries in the world face the same choices we do. They have to decide: can they reduce their deficit and still invest in their people? Can they target people programs, can they maintain a social safety net? Can they still grow their economy and reduce spending? You bet they can.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton is underlining his country's strength at a time when European nations are battling high unemployment and Japan is emerging from years of economic woes.</p>
<p>But while Clinton laid down his hopeful scenario for the three-day summit, some critics predicted the meeting would produce few breakthroughs on a host of international problems.</p>
<p>&quot;The risk is the summit will be a mile high and a foot deep .. There's not much in the way of initiatives,&quot; said former State Department official Robert Hormats, a veteran organizer of past G7 summits and now a Goldman Sachs official.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
