<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67675" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Beirut's SOLIDERE shares rally in week.</title>
<headline>Beirut's SOLIDERE shares rally in week.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>SOLIDERE shares rallied in the week ended on Friday in an upbeat Beirut Secondary Market but dealers said that a period of profit-taking may stall the rise of the stocks next week.</p>
<p>A shares, distributed to former holders of property rights in the central Beirut disctrict SOLIDERE is rebuilding, rose 6.7 percent on the privately-operated BSM to $115.625 from last Friday's $108.5.</p>
<p>B shares, issued in a $650-million subscription in January 1994, rose 5.5 percent to $117.50 from $111.375.</p>
<p>But rises of more than two percent daily in the A and B shares in the first two days ended on Wednesday and since then both shares rose half a percentage point or less over the previous day's close.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we're witnessing a period of profit-taking,&quot; one dealer told Reuters. &quot;People who bought the shares at say $105 are selling to get their profit. When the rally began there was only demand for the shares, no supply but now we see supply.&quot;</p>
<p>The dealers said the rally which began 12 days ago was fueled by expectations SOLIDERE will launch a $150 million GDR issue in October allowing non-Arab investors access to the market and the election victory of billionaire Prime Minsiter Rafik al-Hariri and allies which boosted confidence in the economy.</p>
<p>SOLIDERE has declined to comment on the reports that it will issue the Global Depositary Receipts which followed market rumours in Beirut.</p>
<p>Dealers said that the profit-taking would probably stall the rise of the shares, keeping them to a minimum, next week.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we will witness a period of stagnation next week. But if and when SOLIDERE announces the GDR issues I expect a jump in the prices,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Weekly turnover on the BSM rose to 75,134 from 43,995 shares last week and value soared to $8,634,534 from $4,692,973.</p>
<p>On the official Beirut Stock Exchange (BSE), prices of Ciments Libanais fell 4.55 percent to $1.3125 from $1.375 last week and Eternit closed unchanged at $1.9375.</p>
<p>The Lebanon Invest Share Price Index (LISPI) rose 1.02 percent on the week to 85.13 and the BLOM Stock Index (BSI) rose 4.59 percent during the week to 995.54. Both indexes cover both markets.</p>
<p>SOLIDERE is due to move its shares from the BSM to the official bourse on September 30, adding some $2 billion to the BSE capitalisation currently calculated at less than $400 million.</p>
<p>Total weekly turnover on the official exchange (BSE) was 5,200 shares compared with last week's 8,700 shares. There was no trade throughout the week in Ciments Blancs' and shares or Uniceramic's.</p>
<p>- Haitham Haddadin, Beirut editorial (9611) 645456 353078</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
