<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676866" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WORLD BONDS-Markets to cool after sizzling rallies.</title>
<headline>WORLD BONDS-Markets to cool after sizzling rallies.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Thorpe</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>International debt markets are approaching a brick wall after powering ahead on a burst of optimism over European monetary union and U.S. interest rates, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>Major markets on both sides of the Atlantic look set to retreat after the recent gains but Treasuries look the least vulnerable.</p>
<p>&quot;The risks near term are that we could get stronger U.S. growth coming through over the third quarter and that could cause the market to sell off,&quot; David Brickman, European economist at Yamaichi Int'l in London. &quot;In Europe, the risks are on the fiscal front.&quot;</p>
<p>Treasuries have galloped ahead since the middle of April when data began to show the U.S. economy easing from the breakneck speed of the first quarter.</p>
<p>Expectations of a rate rise at the July 1-2 Federal Open Market Committee Meeting (FOMC) faded and the yield on the benchmark long bond slid to around 6.692 percent from a peak of around 7.30 percent on April 14.</p>
<p>In Europe, Germany and France put European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) back on track by attaching a resolution on employment to a pact designed to ensure fiscal responsibility after the planned January 1, 1999 EMU start date.</p>
<p>Italian and Spanish bond futures racked up new all-time highs, while German futures hit a contract high and French and British futures came close. The cash market has done equally well with 10-year German cash yields dipping to a low of around 5.67 percent on Monday, the lowest level in a month.</p>
<p>But Graham McDevitt, head of bond strategy at Paribas Capital markets, expects that is about all markets can achieve for now.</p>
<p>Treasuries have fully unwound U.S. rate rise speculation and the short end was particularly overstretched, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The chances are we are going to consolidate or in fact head lower,&quot; he said. &quot;The market is in a good mood now but at the beginning of July we do have the FOMC and we do have another employment report and that will set the tone for the summer.&quot;</p>
<p>McDevitt said Italian bonds however, could continue to forge ahead against Bunds after the 10-year yield gap hit a record low of 120 basis points this week. He saw the spread fairly valued at 75 to 100 basis points if EMU was a certainty.</p>
<p>&quot;On Bunds there is a very good chance we've settled into a range,&quot; he said. &quot;We still feel the fiscal situation in Germany is problematic and that should weigh on the market but the current shape of the yield curve and the benign economic environment is continuing to support.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, Brickman said the state of government finances in continental Europe would soon begin to rankle markets again as it became clear Germany and France would have trouble meeting the 3.0 percent deficit-to-GDP target under the Maastricht Treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all very well saying we can have flexibility in the Treaty for EMU but there has got to be a limit to that flexibility,&quot; he said. &quot;I don't think above 3.5 percent is close enough.&quot;</p>
<p>News on the health of France's finances should come in mid-July when an audit was due but a mini-budget was not expected until after the summer break. Meanwhile Germany has to find a way to close a total gap of some 50 billion marks for 1997 and 1998.</p>
<p>Phyllis Reed, European bond strategist at BZW in London, said French Prime Minister Lionel Jospin would have a difficult time coming up with the goods on both the deficit and jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;How in the world is he going to produce a budget that produces a budget deficit forecast anything like 3.0 percent of GDP,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>BZW advises investors move into Treasuries, forecasting the 10-year T-note/Bund gap to gradually narrow to 40 to 50 basis points by the end of the year and to close on an 18-month view.</p>
<p>That gap was quoted at 76 basis points at 1038 GMT.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
