<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676855" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent stagnant before weekend, contango widens.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent stagnant before weekend, contango widens.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent futures were unmoved in quiet trade at midsession as the market nudged back and forth in a tight range before the weekend and next week's OPEC meeting.</p>
<p>August Brent was two cents lower at $17.76 a barrel by 1115 GMT, but its contango to September widened by about eight cents to nearly 20 cents. July gas oil was level at $159.50 a tonne.</p>
<p>Brokers said technicals were determining price movements in a market bereft of news. They cited a tight trading range with support at $17.68 and resistance at $17.98.</p>
<p>But a break from that range could spark a major move, with players relieved to break off the constraints of current levels.  </p>
<p>&quot;I can see the market will get a bit bored with these levels and you've got the risk of any move out of the range being big and violent,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The expiry of the NYMEX July contract at the close on Friday was seen as a possible catalyst of a move.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market would probably get jittery before the meeting of OPEC ministers in Vienna on June 25.</p>
<p>But they were not expecting any drastic news from the 11-member cartel and said it would probably just &quot;roll over&quot; the current production quota.</p>
<p>Trade in gas oil was thin and the levels unchanged, though dealers said the market looked negative below key support at $160.00</p>
<p>-- Paul Carrel, London newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
