<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="676933" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Banks regain momentum on Beirut Stock Exchange.</title>
<headline>Banks regain momentum on Beirut Stock Exchange.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank shares regained momentum on the Beirut Stock Exchange in the week ending Friday, driven by Banque Audi's midweek surge to a new high.</p>
<p>Two banks rose and the third listed bank stock was steady, but a fall by Solidere, which accounts for $2 billion of total market capitalisation of $2.4 billion, held back overall market performance despite an increase in turnover.</p>
<p>The LIBX bank index rose 3.22 percent to 158.73 but the LISPI general index fell 1.22 percent to 88.33 and the BLOM general index fell 0.93 percent to 923.49.</p>
<p>Market turnover rose to 917,885 shares for a value of $12,590,502 from 710,563 shares and $6,376,190 last week.</p>
<p>Brokers were bullish after bank shares emerged from two weeks of sideways trading.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was searching for direction and it found one, an upward trend. I expect very active trade next week,&quot; a broker who asked not to be identified told Reuters.</p>
<p>Banque Audi jumped to an all-time high of $25.125 in mid-week but fell back to $24.875 on Friday, seven percent above last week's closing of $23.25.</p>
<p>&quot;Audi definitely contributed a lot. There was also a lot of over-the-counter activity on Byblos Bank shares which in turn affects trade in bank stocks on the exchange,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>Byblos A and B shares were bought at $7.5 and $7.75 on Friday from $6.88 and $7.13 respectively a week earlier. The long-awaited listing of the stock is expected in September, according to bank officials.</p>
<p>The broker said the recent rise of Audi's Global Depository Receipts to $27 on the Luxembourg Stock Exchange was likely to reflect on Beirut prices of the underlying share next week.</p>
<p>Of the other listed banks, Banque Libanaise pour le Commerce rose to $18.5 from $18 and Bank of Beirut was unchanged at $3.9375.</p>
<p>Solidere A fell to $10.25 from $10.5 while Solidere B shares remained unchanged at $10.75.</p>
<p>&quot;The shares will eventually go up. The company GDRs are trading at $16 in London,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>Ciments Libanais was active throughout the week at an unchanged price of $1.28125. On Monday, a block of 200,000 shares traded off the floor at $1.3125.</p>
<p>&quot;Ciments Libanais is still in consolidation. It is going to go up,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>Eternit, which traded 1,000 shares during the week, fell to $1.875 from $2. Ciments Blancs fell to $4.125 from $4.75 on May 29 when they were last traded.</p>
<p>There was no trade in the fourth listed industrial firm Uniceramic.</p>
<p>- Zeina Soufan (9611)  745308  745307  602057</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
