<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="677086" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fla. judge delays sentence in vandals-manslaughter case.</title>
<headline>Fla. judge delays sentence in vandals-manslaughter case.</headline>
<dateline>TAMPA, Fla 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Florida judge put off until Friday a decision on whether to order a new trial for three friends convicted of manslaughter for the theft of a stop sign that led to a fatal crash last year.</p>
<p>If the motion for a new trial is rejected, Judge Bob Anderson Mitcham is expected to impose sentence on the three.</p>
<p>Christopher Cole and Thomas Miller, both 20 and Nissa Baillie, 21, were convicted last month of stealing the sign from an intersection near Tampa in February 1996. Before the sign could be replaced, three teenaged boys were killed at the intersection when their car was hit by a truck.</p>
<p>Judge Mitcham said he would consider the case overnight and hoped to make a ruling Friday morning. If he rejects the motion for a new trial, he is expected to sentence the defendants to at least 27 years in prison.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very difficult case,&quot; Mitcham said.</p>
<p>The three defendants denied they stole the sign from the site of the accident, but admitted they stole other signs. They were arrested after they threw stolen stop signs into a river, police testified.</p>
<p>It is believed to be the first case in which there was a manslaughter conviction for the theft of a traffic sign.</p>
<p>Attorneys for the defendants argued during a nine-hour hearing that ended late Thursday that a new trial should be ordered because a key prosecution witness, Larry Jarrard, recanted his testimony that the defendants told him they took the stop sign the day before the accident.</p>
<p>Jarrard testified Tuesday that he lied at the trial because he was threatened by Florida state prosecutor Leland Baldwin. She denies making any threats.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAMPA, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
