<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="677217" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Jean-Francois Revel named to Academie Francaise.</title>
<headline>Jean-Francois Revel named to Academie Francaise.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philosopher and columnist Jean-Francois Revel, 73, has been elected to the prestigious Academie Francaise, the French language watchdog said on Friday.</p>
<p>Revel, the iconoclastic author of some two dozen works of philosophical and political thought, was editor of the weekly L'Express magazine from 1978 to 1981 and is currently a columnist for the weekly Le Point.</p>
<p>Among his best known books are &quot;Ni Marx ni Jesus&quot; (Neither Marx nor Jesus), written in 1970 and today a compulsory text for French high school students, and &quot;La Tentation Totalitaire&quot; (The Totalitarian Temptation), written in 1976.</p>
<p>Revel, a militant anti-Communist and Resistance activist during World War Two, is married to the columnist Claude Sarraute.</p>
<p>The Academie Francaise, whose 40 members are known as &quot;immortals&quot;, jealously guards the purity of the French language and brings together its most distinguished writers and thinkers.</p>
<p>Revel was elected to the chair left vacant last November by the death of biologist Etienne Wolff. Members are appointed for life.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
