<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="677265" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spiegel CEO, president to retire early.</title>
<headline>Spiegel CEO, president to retire early.</headline>
<dateline>DOWNERS GROVE, Ill. 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spiegel Inc., which posted a first-quarter loss and has begun an overhaul of its flagship catalogue, said Friday its president and chief executive, John Shea, would take early retirement.</p>
<p>Shea, who will retire July 3, had previosly planned to leave the company next March on his 60th birthday, it said.</p>
<p>But Shea decided now was an appropriate time to leave because the expansion of Spiegel's Eddie Bauer division has been successful and a reorganization of its flagship Spiegel catalogue already was underway, Spiegel said in a statement.</p>
<p>Spiegel, based in Downers Grove, Ill., also said it formed an office of the president that included three existing Spiegel executives.</p>
<p>Harold Dahlstrand, a board member and senior vice president of human resources, will serve as chairman of the office of president, it said. Michael Moran, general counsel, and James Sievers, chief financial officer, also were named to the office.</p>
<p>Last year, Spiegel lost $13.4 million, or 12 cents a share. During the first quarter, the company's loss more than doubled to $31 million, or 28 cents a share.</p>
<p>In April, the company said it would overhaul the merchandise offerings and the layout of its Spiegel catalogue.</p>
<p>John Irvin will remain president and chief executive of Spiegel catalogue, the company said. Likewise, Richard Fersch and George Ittner will remain president and chief executive of the company's Eddie Bauer and Newport News units respectively.</p>
<p>Spiegel markets fashionable apparel and home furnishings through catalogues and more than 450 speciality retail stores.</p>
<p>Its stock was unchanged at $6.625 on Nasdaq at midday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOWNERS GROVE, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
