<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="677523" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai bourse rally on finmin talk seen as brief.</title>
<headline>Thai bourse rally on finmin talk seen as brief.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks rallied on Friday on reports that low-profile banker Thanong Bidaya may be the country's new finance minister, but brokers and analysts said the rise was likely to be short-lived.</p>
<p>The battered bourse -- which closed at a new 98-month low on Thursday -- advanced 2.78 percent by the midday break, ending after eight consecutive days of heavy losses.</p>
<p>Buying was partly fuelled by news that Thanong, chief executive of Thai Military Bank Plc, would fill the finance portfolio left vacant by Amnuay Viravan, who resigned on Thursday over differences with political rivals.</p>
<p>Technical factors were cited as another reason for what was only the bourse's second advance this month.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a technical rebound induced partly by a slight psychological boost now that the finance portfolio uncertainty is cleared,&quot; said Dhana Siam, a broker at Danai Tunyanitichai. The advance did not necessarily reflect full market approval of Thanong, he added.</p>
<p>The composite SET index's rose 12.92 points to 477.69 by the Friday lunch break after losing 101.62 points this month alone. The gains were the index's second advance this month.</p>
<p>Analysts voiced broad-based expectations that the rally would be brief given the long list of economic and political hurdles faced by the country.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see real buying signals from our local and foreign investors. The gains look suspiciously like a smokescreen that can easily evaporate. We advised our clients to stay on the sidelines,&quot; said the marketing head of a major Thai brokerage firm who declined to be named.</p>
<p>Amnuay held the post for less than seven months and was the fifth Thai finance minister to resign in three administrations since 1995.</p>
<p>A broker at Dhana Siam Finance and Securities Plc described the rally as a technical rebound from sharp declines this week aggravated by Amnuay's departure.</p>
<p>&quot;Thanong still needs to take time to assert himself as a finance minister,&quot; said Donaldson Hartman, from Salomon Brothers Inc.</p>
<p>Analysts said that on top of deepening property and finance sector problems, Amnuay's resignation renewed speculation that Thailand would eventually be forced to devalue its currency, the baht.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh pledged on Thursday he would retain policies adopted by Amnuay, and the Bank of Thailand would continue its determined defence of the baht.</p>
<p>But analysts said Thanong's expected appointment later on Friday and Chavalit's growing political reliance on his main coalition partner, the Chart Pattana Party, could prompt him to soften the baht policy.</p>
<p>Chart Pattana, led by former premier Chatichai Choonhavan, is known for its past liberal and expansionary policies.</p>
<p>Another broker at Poonpipat Finance and Securities Plc said the new finance minister would virtually have no time to prepare for the first parliamentary debate on the government's proposed 1997/1998 (October/September) budget next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Thanong is acceptable although his qualifications do not stand out. He is a second or third-tier choice on the list of prospective candidates that Chavalit has,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
