<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67757" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ghosts of Korean War haunt United States.</title>
<headline>Ghosts of Korean War haunt United States.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A document hidden in a presidential library, two Romanians who got lost sightseeing and chilling Congressional testimony from a former Czech general may be lifting the veil off some of the darkest secrets of the Korean War.</p>
<p>Did North Korea keep hundreds of Americans prisoner after the end of the Korean War in 1953? Did it also subject some of them to brutal Nazi-like medical experiments and amputations?</p>
<p>And are there still American POWs alive in the sealed-off Stalinist state that today mixes hostility towards South Korea with overtures to the West for trade and aid?</p>
<p>These are questions the Pentagon, Congress and the families of 8,000 men listed as missing in the Korean conflict are asking, and the answers they are getting are widely disparate.</p>
<p>To Republican Congressman Robert Dornan, whose House of Representatives Military Personnel sub-committee has been holding hearings on the issue, the answers to all the questions are a simple and stark &quot;Yes.&quot;</p>
<p>The conservative congressman told Reuters this week that he planned to fly to North Korea later this year to try to convince Pyongyang to free the remaining Americans he believes are there -- a number he estimates at about 15.</p>
<p>&quot;I will press these people to come clean. There will be no recriminations. I'll tell them it's not your fault. ... It's something your fathers and grandfathers did, a sins-of-the- fathers-type thing,&quot; Dornan said.</p>
<p>He added that if he fails he will advocate a naval blockade of North Korea to &quot;isolate them.&quot; Asked if he could win President Bill Clinton's backing, he said, &quot;It would be one way for Clinton to erase that draft dodger specter.&quot;</p>
<p>Investigators say that they have traced two Romanians whose bus got lost in North Korea in 1979 and turned up at a collective farm at which several American &quot;farmers&quot; were seen.</p>
<p>The Romanians were told the men were captured in the war. Recently a North Korean defector claimed in a newspaper interview to have seen elderly white and black men in a secret prison camp and to have been told the same thing.</p>
<p>But Defence Secretary William Perry says there is no evidence that North Korea is still holding American prisoners.</p>
<p>Dornan's committee this week released newly declassified documents from the Dwight Eisenhower Presidential Library that showed that the Pentagon knew in 1953 that possibly up to 1,200 Americans were alive and not released by North Korea.</p>
<p>Eisenhower, the documents said, tried to do everything short of war to get the men. Dornan said the president did not make the information public for fear of whipping up war hysteria at home that he could not contain.</p>
<p>At a Dornan subcomittee hearing this week, Czech defector General Jan Sejna said his native country built a hospital for the Russians in North Korea in which grotesque experiments were performed on American POWS, including amputations.</p>
<p>&quot;Czechoslovakia also built a crematorium in North Korea to dispose of the bodies and parts after the experiments were concluded,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>During the Vietnam War, Sejna, a former first secretary of the Czech Defence Council who defected in 1968, said he was involved in transferring a group of American POWs from Vietnam to Russia for experiments that would test chemical and biological war agents and the effects of atomic radiation.</p>
<p>Not everyone believes Sejna, who now works for the U.S. Defence Intelligence Agency. But his defenders say he has passed several lie detector tests. Dornan said he should be given truth serum to clear up any doubts.</p>
<p>James Sanders, who with Mark Sauter wrote &quot;Soldiers of Misfortune,&quot; a book about soldiers missing in Korea and Vietnam, says he is positive government archives have documents on the medical experiments. He said there may even be testimony from soldiers who were subjected to such tortures and were released in one of two major prisoners exchanges.</p>
<p>He said he also believes that Vietnam held back releasing several hundred U.S. soldiers because the United States would not pay ransom for them. Dornan put the number of prisoners he believes were not released at only a handful in Vietnam but said hundreds were unaccounted for in Laos.</p>
<p>Gary  Ledyard, a professor of Korean history at Columbia University, says of the POW controversy, &quot;It is very hard to say such things are not conceivable with North Korea but why would such things have been in their interests?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
