<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="677753" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore May non-oil domestic exports dip.</title>
<headline>Singapore May non-oil domestic exports dip.</headline>
<byline>Doreen Siow</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore said on Friday its non-oil domestic exports fell one percent in May compared to the same month of 1996, well below market expectations.</p>
<p>Many economists had forecast exports would rise in nominal terms by something closer to April's 5.9 percent -- the first increase after five consecutive months of falls.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of 10 Singapore-based economists on Thursday produced an average forecast of a 3.5 percent year-on-year rise in nonimal terms.  </p>
<p>But analysts and economists said on Friday that while May exports looked soft, the Singapore economy was still on track for a recovery in the second half, led by the key electronics sector.</p>
<p>&quot;It is slightly worse than expectations. It looks like the fall was mainly due to parts for office and data processing equipment, which are low-end items,&quot; said Amanda Choy, assistant economist at Soc-Gen Crosby.</p>
<p>But, she added: &quot;Semi-conductors are still doing very well,&quot;  </p>
<p>Liew Yin Sze, an economist with J.M. Sassoon, noted that the stock market dropped after the figure was announced, with the Straits Times Industrial Index ending the morning session 17.91 points down at 1,985.06</p>
<p>&quot;But there is no need for extreme pessimism. Some expect too much in the short term but I think the economy is on track for recovery in the second half,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Liew said that while exports of disk drives were a bit soft, semi-conductor exports were strong, registering an increase of more than 12 percent.  </p>
<p>The government's Trade and Development Board (TDB) said in announcing the news figures that the May decline was less severe than the 4.1 percent contraction in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, April and May data taken together showed that non-oil domestic exports inceased by 2.4 percent as compared with the corresponding two months last year,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Re-exports in May grew by 9.4 percent, reflecting strong growth in electronic products, in particular re-exports of integrated circuits to Europe, Japan and Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Imports grew by 6.9 percent, the highest growth since April 1996, the TDB said.  </p>
<p>Exports to the United States, Singapore's largest trading partner, fell by 3.1 percent. Exports to Japan, another major trading partner, fell 33.1 percent.</p>
<p>But exports to the European Union rose 7.8 percent and to neighbouring Malaysia they were up 10.6 percent.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-870-3-80)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
