<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67779" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Garcia Abrego not heard on wiretaps - FBI agent.</title>
<headline>Garcia Abrego not heard on wiretaps - FBI agent.</headline>
<byline>Jeff Franks</byline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Government agents using wiretaps taped thousands of hours of conversation between members of the Gulf drug cartel in Mexico and the United States, but never recorded alleged drug kingpin Juan Garcia Abrego or heard his name mentioned, an FBI agent testified on Thursday.</p>
<p>Special agent Peter Hanna, taking the stand in Garcia Abrego's drug-trafficking trial, said members of the Gulf cartel were taped surreptiously almost continously starting in 1989, which led to numerous arrests and seizures of cocaine and money.</p>
<p>Under cross-examination by defence attorney Tony Canales, he admitted that Garcia Abrego, who was on the FBI's 10 Most Wanted list, never once surfaced in the wiretaps.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not been able to identify his voice among those we've intercepted,&quot; Hanna told the eight-man, four-woman jury in U.S. District Judge Ewing Werlein's court.</p>
<p>&quot;Did anyone ever mention my client's name?&quot; asked Canales.</p>
<p>&quot;Oh, by name, I would find it highly ... no,&quot; Hanna said. He and other federal agents testified that drug traffickers often use nicknames or no identification at all in telephone conversations.</p>
<p>The 52-year-old Garcia Abrego, born in south Texas, is accused of running a massive drug empire from northern Mexico that once shipped up to a third of the cocaine used in the United States.</p>
<p>He was arrested in Monterrey, Mexico, Jan. 14 and flown to Houston for prosecution on 22 federal counts of drug trafficking, money laundering and bribery and faces several life sentences if convicted. He has pleaded not guilty.</p>
<p>In opening arguments on Tuesday, Canales said Garcia Abrego was not the head of the Gulf cartel, as shown by his not being taped or spoken of in the wiretaps. More than 10,000 conversations were recorded during the government's lengthy investigation, he said.</p>
<p>Also under cross-examination by Canales, Hanna said Garcia Abrego's fingerprints had not been found on any documents seized in drug busts. His prints were seen on a map he drew for FBI agent Claudio de la O showing the bases of other drug-traffickers in the U.S.-Mexico border region, Hanna said.</p>
<p>De la O testified on Wednesday that he taped conversations between him and Garcia Abrego and met with him several times in 1986 when he was attempting to infiltrate his operations by acting as a corrupt agent.</p>
<p>He said Garcia Abrego provided him information about drug dealers, which de la O believed was an attempt to wipe out rivals in the lucrative narcotics trade. He also said that Garcia Abrego operatives had given him $170,000 in bribes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
