<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="677801" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China shuts brokerage subsidiary in new crackdown.</title>
<headline>China shuts brokerage subsidiary in new crackdown.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's securities authorities have ordered Shenzhen J&amp;A Securities Co Ltd to close down one of its Hong Kong subsidiaries found involved in illegal share trading, J&amp;A officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>Under orders from Beijing, Shenzhen J&amp;A has shut J&amp;A Financial Services Ltd, set up in Hong Kong in late 1995, for using 300 million yuan borrowed from Guangshen Railway Co Ltd in share speculation, the officials told the Hong Kong-based newsletter China Securities Bulletin.</p>
<p>Shenzhen J&amp;A's chairman Zhang Guoqing has issued a letter of apology to all staff for the misconduct, and vowed to let his salary be cut by 30 percent over the next six months, the officials said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Shenzhen-based Securities Times reported on Friday that Beijing had also ordered Shenzhen J&amp;A, one of China's top brokerages, to halt share trading on its own account for six months.</p>
<p>Last week, Beijing announced punishments for a string of domestic brokerages and listed firms for illegal activity on the country's volatile stock markets.</p>
<p>It ordered the dismissal of Guangshen Railway's chairman Ge Wenan and chief accountant Zeng Xianshao after it improperly used part of a 300 million yuan investment for share trading.</p>
<p>Beijing also ordered the removal of Haitong Securities chairman Li Huiying as well as Kan Zhidong, president of the nation's top brokerage Shenyin &amp; Wanguo Securities, and Ma Qingquan, president of China Everbright Securities, for illegally obtaining funds from banks.</p>
<p>In addition, it decided to sack He Yun, chairman of Shenzhen Development Bank Ltd, China's only bank with a domestic exchange listing, after the bank was found to have used bank funds to trade its own shares.</p>
<p>The central government also fired Shen Ruolei, head of the Shanghai branch of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China for extending huge amounts of credit to securities houses to trade on the stock market.</p>
<p>(US$1=8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
