<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67782" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Four-legged bomb-detectors still best, official says.</title>
<headline>Four-legged bomb-detectors still best, official says.</headline>
<byline>Peter Szekely</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Although federal officials are looking at the latest bomb-detection technology as part of a $429 million plan to beef up airport security, they had nothing but raves for the old-fashioned, four-legged version.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now, the best technology for detecting explosives remains a dog's nose,&quot; Brian Michael Jenkins, deputy chairman of a presidential panel on aviation security, said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The panel, which is headed by Vice President Al Gore, has recommended spending $9 million to assign 115 more bomb-sniffing dogs to airport security duty, more than doubling its canine army, Jenkins told the House of Representatives Science Committee.</p>
<p>More praise for pooches came from Keith Fultz, assistant comptroller general of the congressional General Accounting Office (GAO).</p>
<p>&quot;Dogs are considered a unique type of trace detector because they can be trained to respond in specific ways to the smell of explosives,&quot; Fultz said in testimony prepared for delivery to the House committee.</p>
<p>But praise for man's best friend notwithstanding, the presidential panel also wants to invest in more expensive cutting edge technology and test it out in combination with other systems, Jenkins said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an experiment with no downside,&quot; he said. &quot;Some combinations will be highly effective, some undoubtedly less so, but all airports involved will reap some security benefits. No airport's security will be less.&quot;</p>
<p>The $429 price tag to fund all of the panel's proposals includes $147 million to put more FBI agents on counter-terrorism duties and is part of a Clinton administration $1.1 billion anti-terrorism plan that needs congressional approval to get funding.</p>
<p>The GAO lauded the panel's recommendations but said they did not go far enough. It recommended that Congress set airport security goals for the Federal Aviation Administration and that the FAA keep Congress informed of its progress.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the persistence of long-standing vulnerabilities and the increased threat to civil aviation, we believe that corrective actions need to be undertaken immediately,&quot; said Fultz. &quot;These actions need a unified effort from the highest levels of the government to address this national issue.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the panel's more controversial recommendations were the use of so-called profiles to select certain passengers for closer scrutiny and FBI fingerprint checks for all airline and airport employees with access to secure areas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
