<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="677926" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: TIFFE Euroyen edge lower in quiet Tokyo trade.</title>
<headline>TIFFE Euroyen edge lower in quiet Tokyo trade.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The benchmark three-month December euroyen futures contract edged lower by the end of Tokyo morning trade, pressured by weaker Japanese government bonds (JGBs) amid a dearth of fresh factors, traders said.</p>
<p>Many operators appear to holding to the sidelines ahead of the Group of Seven (G7) summit, due to start later today, as well as next week's Bank of Japan (BOJ) &quot;tankan&quot; survey and JGB auctions, one city bank trader said.</p>
<p>At midday, the December contract stood at 99.08, down 0.02 from Thursday, after moving narrowly from 99.06 to 99.08. Volume was an extremely light 8,961 contracts.  </p>
<p>Volume in the March contract rose to 15,828, a signal that a benchmark shift may be approaching.</p>
<p>The benchmark is said to have officially shifted when volume in a forward contract exceeds that of the current benchmark for a second successive day of Tokyo trade.</p>
<p>Some traders said activity in connection with the March contract was mainly speculative, as operators grew frustrated by a lack of movement in December.</p>
<p>JGBs dipped on pressure from an overnight slide that saw the key September contract fall as low as 123.85, although it later recovered to end Tokyo morning trade at 123.90  </p>
<p>&quot;Moves in the euroyen market today seem to be mainly confined to book-squaring,&quot; one city bank trader said.</p>
<p>Little impact was detected from comments out of Denver from U.S. President Bill Clinton, who voiced concern to Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto about Japan's rising trade surplus.</p>
<p>U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky said the U.S. will not dictate to Japan on deregulation, but will negotiate.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not much new in these statements, and as a result there has so far been little impact,&quot; the city bank trader said.  </p>
<p>The Bank of Japan (BOJ) drained 100 billion yen from the market in the face of a net surplus of 200 billion yen, a slightly more generous move than was expected by the market.</p>
<p>Overnight call money was being traded at 0.50 percent before the operation but moved to 0.48-0.49 afterwards.</p>
<p>In the longer end of the money market, around 40 billion yen of three-month certificates of deposit (CDs) were issued at 0.60 percent and 40 billion yen of two-month CDs at 0.59 percent, unchanged from Thursday. In the interest rate swap (IRS) market, the three-year IRS rate was quoted at 1.52/1.56 percent against 1.51/1.55 percent on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
