<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678145" id="root" date="1997-06-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: ATHLETICS-CHRISTIE EXITS WITH ANOTHER WIN.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-CHRISTIE EXITS WITH ANOTHER WIN.</headline>
<byline>Phil Minshull</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH 1997-06-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Linford Christie of Britain marked his final appearance in the European Cup with a record 16th victory in the competition.</p>
<p>The 37-year-old Christie powered away from the 30-metre mark to win the 100 metres in 10.04 seconds, equalling his European Cup record set last year in Madrid. It was also the fastest time run by a European this year.</p>
<p>The 1992 Olympic 100m champion was pushed hard for most of the race by Geir Moen of Norway who was second in 10.18.</p>
<p>Andrey Fedoriv of Russia also finished quickly to finish third in a new personal best of 10.19.</p>
<p>Christie has now won the European Cup 100m on eight consecutive occasions.</p>
<p>&quot;The name of the game is to go out there and rise to the occasion,&quot; said Christie after the race.</p>
<p>&quot;To go out there and get a standing ovation from the crowd was the icing on the cake.&quot;</p>
<p>Christie will contest the 200m on Sunday to try to add to his impressive record.</p>
<p>Spain were the surprise leaders in the men's competition after the first day thanks to two individual victories, from Fermin Cacho in the 1,500 metres and Arturo Ortiz in the high jump.</p>
<p>Russia were level with them on 52 points but were pushed into second place because they had only one individual winner, Kiril Sosunov in the long jump.</p>
<p>Germany, the competition favourites, were third just one point behind and only five points cover the first five nations.</p>
<p>Cacho, like Christie a 1992 Olympic gold medallist, unleashed a devastating burst of speed 40 metres from the line to win in three minutes 37.79 seconds.</p>
<p>Italy's Gennaro Di Napoli was second in 3:37.81, just two hundredths of a second in arrears.</p>
<p>&quot;It did not look good for me 300 metres from the line. I was only lying fourth. Fortunately some of my Barcelona finishing spurt was left over,&quot; said Cacho</p>
<p>German victories provided the other highlights of the men's events.</p>
<p>Heinz Weis won the hammer with 81.42 metres, the third best throw of the year.</p>
<p>Dieter Baumann, the 1992 Olympic 5,000 metres champion, came out on top in a duel over 3,000 metres with Manuel Pancorbo of Spain.</p>
<p>After a sprint down the finishing straight Baumann won in a new championship record of 7:41.08 with Pancorbo second in 7:41.60.</p>
<p>The women's competition is lead by Russia with 67 points with Germany second on 63 and Ukraine a distant third on 49.</p>
<p>Russia's Inna Lasovskaya, a silver medallist in Atlanta, won the women's triple jump in a European Cup best of 14.91 metres, the third best leap of the year.</p>
<p>Gabriela Szabo of Romania set a women's 5,000m Cup best of 15:02.68, winning a sprint for the line with Roberta Brunet of Italy, the recent Mediterranean Games champion, who finished in 15:02.87 , also inside the previous best.</p>
<p>Anzelha Balakhonova of Ukraine cleared 4.25 metres to win the pole vault, the first time the event has been included in the women's competition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
