<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678130" id="root" date="1997-06-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LIGHT COMPANIES DOWNPLAY PHILIPS TECHNOLOGY OFFER.</title>
<headline>LIGHT COMPANIES DOWNPLAY PHILIPS TECHNOLOGY OFFER.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Paul</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lighting companies were not turned on by an offer from Philips Lighting Co. Thursday to share its fluorescent lamp technology in a bid to stave off an environmental rule that could trim its market advantage.</p>
<p>Philips Lighting, a unit of Philips Electronics NV , announced an offer to show its competitors, including General Electric Co. and Osram Sylvania Inc., a unit of Siemens AG , the technology for its low-mercury fluorescent lamps.</p>
<p>While the companies had not actually been approached yet by Philips, they considered the offer unnecessary.</p>
<p>&quot;As we have equivalent technology, we're a little bit puzzled,&quot; said Peter Bleasby, director of industry relations for Osram Sylvania.</p>
<p>Unlike lights with higher levels of mercury, the Philips Aldo lights do not have to be treated as hazardous waste and can be dumped in municipal landfills.</p>
<p>The Aldo lights have 80 percent less mercury than the industry average, according to the company.</p>
<p>Mercury is a major problem because when it gets into water from air emissions or leaching, it collects in fish tissue, which people eat.</p>
<p>It is considered most dangerous for pregnant women and children.</p>
<p>Philips is concerned that the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency is going to propose a new rule for fluorescent lamps which will ease disposal requirements and eliminate the advantage of producing the lower-mercury lamp.</p>
<p>&quot;We think by doing this (offering the technology), no company should have an exclusion that allows mercury to enter the ecosystem,&quot; Larry Wilton, president and CEO of Philips Lighting Co., said at a press conference.</p>
<p>Osram Sylvania and GE said they both already are producing low-mercury lights. However, they are not shifting their whole lines to the new technology as Philips is doing.</p>
<p>GE has been selling a light since January that it said passed the U.S. standard for lights that do not need to be disposed of as hazardous waste.</p>
<p>GE's vice president of product management, George Murphy, added that the Philips offer was &quot;a little unusual,&quot; since the company already has a cross-licensing agreement to look at other companies' technology.</p>
<p>The 500 million lamps that are disposed of annually have about 70 tons of mercury in them. By contrast, coal-fired power plants annually emit about 3000 tons of mercury into the air, according to the Alliance to Save Energy.</p>
<p>Alliance to Save Energy president David Nemtzow said the environment would be better off if Philips had focused on making more energy-efficient light bulbs that would help curb power plant emissions.</p>
<p>&quot;They're saying they're environmentally friendly, but they're only telling you half the story,&quot; said Nemtzow, pointing to industry-wide efforts to block federal standards for light bulb efficiency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
