<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678152" id="root" date="1997-06-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TENNIS-NOVOTNA AND SANCHEZ VICARIO TO MEET IN DELAYED FINAL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-NOVOTNA AND SANCHEZ VICARIO TO MEET IN DELAYED FINAL.</headline>
<byline>Clare Fallon</byline>
<dateline>EASTBOURNE, England 1997-06-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arantxa Sanchez Vicario battled through the quarter-finals and semifinals of the Eastbourne women's grasscourt tournament on Saturday and then decided she needed a night's rest before the final against Jana Novotna.</p>
<p>With a backlog of matches after two days of rain, organisers had hoped to cram in the final three rounds of the tournament on Saturday.</p>
<p>But they left the decision on the timing of the final to Sanchez Vicario who, exhausted after beating Irina Spirlea in the quarter-finals and hard-hitter Brenda Schultz-McCarthy in Saturday's second semifinal, asked not to be sent straight back on court. Novotna agreed.</p>
<p>The final will be played at 1100 local (1000 GMT) on Sunday, weather permitting.</p>
<p>Novotna, who beat Natasha Zvereva 6-7 6-0 7-5 in the earlier semifinal, had at least had an hour's rest while Sanchez Vicario beat Schultz-McCarthy 7-5 6-1.</p>
<p>Schultz-McCarthy, the eighth seed, had beaten defending champion Monica Seles 7-5 7-5 earlier on Saturday in a quarter-final which began on Thursday and was then postponed because of the rain.</p>
<p>Second seed Novotna struggled all day with windy conditions and her own inability to kill off her opponents when presented with golden opportunities.</p>
<p>Her first engagement on Saturday was to resume her quarter- final against Japan's Ai Sugiyama which was interrupted by rain on Friday with the Czech 6-2 6-5 up and the score at 15-15.</p>
<p>Three more points would have clinched victory for Novotna but she took the hard route, failing to convert a matchpoint and then hitting a double fault to surrender a break which took the second set to the tiebreak.</p>
<p>A double fault followed on another matchpoint and Sugiyama won the tiebreak 8-6.</p>
<p>The third set saw Novotna playing perfect serve-and-volley tennis one minute and hitting ghastly errors the next before a break of serve in the 10th game finally gave her victory.</p>
<p>But the win did little for her self-belief and she was even more erratic against Belarussian Zvereva in the semifinals, surrendering a 5-3 lead in the opening set and, after a one-hour rain break, being broken three times as she served for the set.</p>
<p>Zvereva won a first-set tiebreak 9-7, went down to love in a second set which saw one game go 11 times to deuce before Novotna converted her eighth breakpoint and saved four more matchpoints in the third set before Novotna won 7-5.</p>
<p>Zvereva had beaten Frenchwoman Nathalie Tauziat 6-4 5-7 6-4 in the quarter-finals. Tauziat later withdrew from a doubles match with a pulled thigh muscle and was expected to consult doctors at Wimbledon on Sunday.</p>
<p>Top seed Seles, whose quarter-final had been suspended on Thursday at 7-5 2-2 to Schultz-McCarthy, had trouble with her serve and admitted she still had some work to do to prepare for Wimbledon next week.</p>
<p>&quot;There are little things that I need to adjust for me to improve,&quot; said the American who admitted she was sorely missing her father and coach Karolj who is seriously ill with cancer in the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EASTBOURNE, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
