<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678256" id="root" date="1997-06-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian minister seeks suspension in video scandal.</title>
<headline>Russian minister seeks suspension in video scandal.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's justice minister said on Saturday he had asked President Boris Yeltsin to remove him from office temporarily amid a scandal over a video film alleged to show the minister in a night-club sauna.</p>
<p>&quot;I have asked the president of the country, B.N. Yeltsin, to suspend me from my duties as a minister until all the circumstances (of the controversy) have been clarified,&quot; Valentin Kovalyov said in a statement issued by his ministry.</p>
<p>The request was a most unusual step in Russian politics and came after the monthly newspaper Sovershenno Sekretno (Top Secret) published grainy photographs taken from the video which it alleged showed Kovalyov in a sauna with women.</p>
<p>A government spokesman, Igor Shabdurasulov, told Reuters that Yeltsin was aware of the controversy but was unlikely to get a copy of the statement before Monday because he was taking part in a world summit of leading industrialised nations in Denver until Sunday.</p>
<p>Shabdurasulov said Kovalyov had spoken to Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin by telephone about the allegations.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Chernomyrdin) considers the minister's response to be appropriate under the circumstances,&quot; Shabdurasulov said, referring to the statement. He added that Kovalyov remained a minister until Yeltsin replied.</p>
<p>The justice minister said his main aim in seeking to be suspended from office was to preserve the reputation of the Russian government. But he also said he would defend his own &quot;good name, honour and dignity&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not aware of anything I have done that I should be ashamed of,&quot; Kovalyov said.</p>
<p>In a country long known for official secrecy, few, if any, government ministers have been forced to resign due to scandals.</p>
<p>Kovalyov, a 53-year-old former law professor and a member of Russia's Security Council, became justice minister in January 1995.</p>
<p>The Top Secret paper, which is sensationalist but well-connected, said the video dated back to September 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
