<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67820" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgium under pressure, not threat from scandals.</title>
<headline>Belgium under pressure, not threat from scandals.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium, reeling from its multiple scandals of child sex abuse, political murder and judicial warfare, is taking a serious look at itself but is not on the verge of collapse, political analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Belgium is not in any danger of disintegrating from these events,&quot; Helmut Gaus, Professor of Political Science at Ghent University, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We have in Belgium a Federal state with two seperate entities -- Flemish and Walloon. This sort of artificial state, is exactly the same thing that Europe is creating,&quot; Gaus, a well-respected author on politics and society.</p>
<p>The death of four young girls at the hands of a paedophile kidnap and car theft gang, the linked arrest of a chief detective and the charge of murder against a former government minister in another case have shaken the country to the core.</p>
<p>Add to that evidence of bitter rivalry between Belgium's different police forces and within the judiciary -- deflecting investigations and keeping crucial information from the right hands -- and the brew begins to bubble.</p>
<p>Stir in a series of deadly attacks on security vans, a string of unsolved murders stretching back a decade, widespread corruption, allegations that organised crime is running rampant from drugs to the diamond industry and farming, and it becomes hard not conclude that Belgium is in terminal decline.</p>
<p>&quot;What has happened is undoubtedly very serious. The problem is that we are incapable of talking about serious problems that are happening at the same time without exagerating on the one side their gravity and on the other the links between them,&quot; political analyst Xavier Mabille said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is true that there is organised crime in Belgium, as in other countries...The fact that it all came at the same time gives a rather curious image of Belgium,&quot; Gaus said.</p>
<p>&quot;If they had all come at different times there would not have been so much interest. The timing has not been good for objectivity,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Both analysts accepted the country has not only linguistic divisions between the Dutch-speaking Flemings and the French- speaking Walloons, but also cultural, social, historic, economic and political gulfs that have always and will always exist.</p>
<p>&quot;These events could have happened in Flanders as much as in Wallonia,&quot; Gaus said of the so-called Dutroux affair of child abduction, abuse and killing and the arrest of Alain Van der Biest for murdering Socialist Party patriarch Andre Cools.</p>
<p>&quot;Some politicians use these facts to put separatism back on the political agenda, but I think the man in the street in Liege, and in Ghent and in Antwerp doesn't believe that this has anything to do with the Walloon/Flemish question,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Gaus accepted that Belgium's political and judicial systems needed a serious overhaul and had done for some time.</p>
<p>&quot;There you have to take this compromise mentality in the Belgians. They don't adapt their institutions to new circumstances until something happens,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If nothing happens and they try to start changing part of the institutions they would make a lot of enemies. So they don't do anything until forced to.</p>
<p>&quot;They use the fact now to reorganise the whole system. Many politicians at the end of the 80s were aware of the lack of efficiency in the judicial system but they didn't dare to change that all because there was no obvious reason,&quot; Gaus added.</p>
<p>The scandals have already prompted the government to announce a complete review of the legal system and triggered calls for an end to patronage appointments of judges and magistrates.</p>
<p>They have also raised questions about the future of the country, questions that Gaus and Mabille insist are misdirected.</p>
<p>&quot;The changes that will come through the system will not be beneficial for Belgium as a whole, but they will be good for justice. Belgium as a whole, that is a strange construction you know. It only exists for foreigners,&quot; Gaus concluded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
