<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678349" id="root" date="1997-06-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Top U.N. arms inspector arrives in Iraq.</title>
<headline>Top U.N. arms inspector arrives in Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Hassan Hafidh</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1997-06-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior United Nations arms official arrived in Iraq on Saturday amid charges Iraq has been obstructing U.N. inspectors searching for prohibited weapons.</p>
<p>Charles Duelfer, Deputy Chairman of the U.N. Special Commission UNSCOM in charge of overseeing elimination of Iraq's prohibited weapons, said after arriving in Baghdad that he had &quot;some difficult issues&quot; to discuss with Iraqi officials.</p>
<p>Rolf Ekeus, the chairman of UNSCOM, has complained to the U.N. Security Council that Baghdad had prevented U.N. inspectors from entering three sites and had endangered U.N helicopters and their crews assisting U.N. ground teams.</p>
<p>Duelfer said Iraq was still concealing weapons of mass destruction that Baghdad must destroy under terms of the ceasefire that ended the 1991 Gulf War, which drove Iraqi troops from Kuwait.</p>
<p>&quot;We are convinced that there are prohibited things that Iraq is concealing from us,&quot; Duelfer told reporters.</p>
<p>UNSCOM must certify Iraq has no weapons of mass destruction before the United Nations will lift trade sanctions imposed on Iraq for its 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>Duelfer said he would met on Saturday with Iraq's Presidential Adviser General Amir al-Sa'di and other Iraqi officials. He planned to leave Iraq on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our problem is that we are convinced that there are prohibited things which Iraq is concealing, so we have no choice but to go after those locations where we think they may be concealed,&quot; Duelfer said of their confrontations over searches.</p>
<p>Britain failed on Friday to obtain a Security Council vote banning Iraqi officials from travelling abroad without permission until Baghdad cooperates with U.N. arms inspectors.</p>
<p>Britain's ambassador Sir John Weston said envoys from both countries would consult privately with other members, presumably China, Russia, France and Egypt who have reservations on the draft resolution.</p>
<p>The new measures would ban travel by members of the Iraqi army, police and intelligence services as well as the civilian defence and military industrial commission unless authorised by the council's sanctions committee. They also would suspend a regular council review on stringent trade sanctions imposed on Iraq until Baghdad cooperates.</p>
<p>Over the past year the council has been split on strong action against Iraq, with the United States losing ground among members of the original coalition that drove Iraqi troops from Kuwait in 1991.</p>
<p>Chief U.N. arms inspector Rolf Ekeus said this week Iraq was in &quot;clear violation of council resolutions.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If Iraq is allowed now to decide what we should inspect, when we should inspect it, I think the value of the whole mechanism set up after the Gulf War would be put into question,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ekeus, who will leave UNSCOM on July 1 and will be succeeded by Australian U.N. envoy Richard Butler, speculated it &quot;may be because we are changing leadership that Iraq is now trying to change the ground rules somewhat.&quot;</p>
<p>Iraqi Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz, in a letter to the council, said access to some sites had been denied because of concern the inspections were to &quot;detect the arrangements made for the security of Iraq, its leadership and the personnel involved.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
