<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678495" id="root" date="1997-06-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Annan to consult on peacekeepers for Congo.</title>
<headline>Annan to consult on peacekeepers for Congo.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Goodman</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-06-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Security Council on Saturday authorised Secretary-General Kofi Annan to consult with potential troop-contributing countries, mainly from Africa, about sending an advance peacekeeping force to violence-ridden Congo, Annan said.</p>
<p>This followed informal consultations on a letter he sent the council about a request from Gabon President Omar Bongo, who has been mediating talks between the rival Congo factions.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people have been killed in fighting which erupted June 5 between forces of Congo President Pacal Lissouba and followers of former Marxist ruler Denis Sassou Nguesso.</p>
<p>The warring factions agreed on Friday to extend a truce for a further week, just hours after France pulled out the last of its soldiers from Brazzaville, the capital. They had helped evacuate nearly 6,000 French and other foreign nationals.</p>
<p>In his letter to the council Annan said that &quot;given the gravity of the crisis and the experience of the international community in dealing with similar situations,&quot; it was estimated the initial size of the force should be no fewer than 1,600 to 1,800, plus support units totalling 400 to 800 and U.N. military observers.</p>
<p>&quot;A force of that size would have the capacity to secure the airport, it being understood that wider deployment would require greater strength,&quot; Annan wrote.</p>
<p>He said one option would be for a multinational force authorised by the Security Council. Another option would be a U.N. peacekeeping force, under U.N. command.</p>
<p>Speaking to reporters after the council consultations. Annan said: &quot;I think the council has agreed with me that the situation is urgent and we should do whatever we can to assist.</p>
<p>&quot;So we will be consulting the governments in the region who have indicated that they are prepared to contribute to a force to try and stabilise the situation and ensure that there is a ceasefire.&quot;</p>
<p>Annan said he would report back to the council with details of the availability of troops, the structure and mandate of the proposed force, and how it would be financed.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage, it is exploratory consultations with the governments concerned,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The aim would be first to send in an advance force quickly, which could then be built up with reinforcements from other countries.</p>
<p>&quot;But even for the advance force to go in, we need to understand that the ceasefire will hold and the parties are determined to seek political conciliation before we move it in. Initially the consultations will focus on the advance party,&quot; Annan added.</p>
<p>He also said his consultations would show whether a regional force or a U.N. force would be more viable.</p>
<p>Governments which had offered troops so far were from the African region, but &quot;it is not excluded that governments from outside Africa will join the force,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
