<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678412" id="root" date="1997-06-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Landmark tobacco pact faces tough road.</title>
<headline>Landmark tobacco pact faces tough road.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>Jubilant state attorneys general have trounced the tobacco industry with a record-breaking $368.5 billion settlement, but whether the landmark pact can remain intact is far from certain.</p>
<p>After the celebrations end and the dust settles, the top state legal officers will have to watch their hard-won work picked apart by a White House task force and then by Congress.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton, who is hosting the annual summit of industrialized nations in Denver, had not yet had a chance to review the agreement, White House spokesman Mike McCurry told reporters on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are just now beginning the process of evaluating the document based on what we know about it. I think it's going to be quite some time before we can say anything definitively about our views,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The agreement is being sharply criticized as inadequate by some prominent health figures as well as Minnesota Attorney General Hubert Humphrey III, who has been at odds with his colleagues during the three months of negotiations.</p>
<p>Former U.S. Surgeon General C. Everett Koop on Saturday called the $368.5 billion settlement &quot;paltry&quot; and warned there were serious flaws in the pact.</p>
<p>A fierce opponent of the tobacco industry who succeeded in forcing health warnings to be put on cigarette packets, Koop said in a CNN interview that the agreement was far from being a great triumph for the attorneys general, health advocates and the anti-tobacco lobby.</p>
<p>&quot;They are talking about it as a marvelous achievement. I would put it in the sense of a marvelous effort. The achievement is yet to come,&quot; he said. &quot;Whether that effort becomes an achievement depends a lot on Congress.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he feared the agreement would be watered down on Capitol Hill and that tobacco industry lawyers would find loopholes to exploit.</p>
<p>In Minnesota, Humphrey told a news conference on Friday that he fully intends to bring his lawsuit to trial against the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement as I understand it is woefully inadequate,&quot; Humphrey said.</p>
<p>Humphrey is one of the 40 attorneys general that sued the industry to recoup Medicaid costs of sick smokers.</p>
<p>The National Association of Attorneys General is holding its annual spring meeting in Jackson Hole, Wyoming, beginning on Sunday night and it is expected that Humphrey will raise objections to the settlement with his colleagues there.</p>
<p>The monetary package would be used to settle the state Medicaid suits, individual smoking suits and certain class actions.</p>
<p>Under the accord, the industry would also agree to be regulated by the Food and Drug Administration, would sharply curb advertising and marketing of cigarettes and be subjected to penalties if youth smoking is not reduced.</p>
<p>Although the agreement marks the first time the tobacco industry has agreed to make health care, regulatory and litigation concessions, criticisms of the accord will add to the concerns of the White House and members of Congress who greeted Friday's announcement with caution.</p>
<p>&quot;The Constitution does not have any provision for the Congress to delegate (decision-making) to a private group in a secret meeting,&quot; House of Representatives Speaker Newt Gingrich said.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll be glad to look at what they think their settlement is ... Whether or not that becomes law will be a function of the congressional committees, the hearing process,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some of the harshest critics of the industry, including California Democratic Rep. Henry Waxman and New Jersey Democratic Sen. Frank Lautenberg, said the accord was a &quot;positive first step&quot; but they might try to make it tougher.</p>
<p>However, when the attorneys general announced the plan on Friday, they said they would not consent to changes in key parts and would instead fight their lawsuits.</p>
<p>&quot;While we invite improvement of what we've done ... if the fundamental steps that we have taken with respect particularly to ensuring no more youth access, to ensuring no more marketing to children, and to ensure the full FDA authority over nicotine ... if that is compromised, we ... will continue to fight in our litigation in our respective courts,&quot; said Washington State Attorney General Christine Gregoire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
