<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678511" id="root" date="1997-06-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greece issues smog warning as temperatures soar.</title>
<headline>Greece issues smog warning as temperatures soar.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-06-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's environment ministry issued a smog warning to Athenians on Thursday after hundreds of people were rushed to hospital with pollution-related ailments.</p>
<p>&quot;Because weather conditions favouring air pollution are expected to continue tomorrow, the public is urged to limit car transportation and avoid physical labour outdoors,&quot; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>The medical emergency centre said 708 people had been rushed to hospital in 24 hours by early Thursday, many with respiratory and heart problems or following fainting incidents.</p>
<p>Temperatures have soared to unusually high levels in the Greek capital this week, reaching as high as 40 degrees Celsius (104 Fahrenheit)on Thursday. The Greek Meteorological Service said the mini-heatwave would last until Sunday.</p>
<p>Cars are often banned from the centre of Athens, one of Europe's most polluted capitals, when smog reaches emergency levels. The ministry said most pollutants on Thursday were below danger levels and did not order a ban on cars.</p>
<p>Athens, a city of around four million people, is surrounded by mountains which trap fuel emissions from cars. In the summer of 1988 hundreds of people, mostly elderly, died during a heatwave coupled with heavy smog.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
