<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678771" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Iron Lady haunts Boy Wonder of British politics.</title>
<headline>Iron Lady haunts Boy Wonder of British politics.</headline>
<byline>Lyndsay Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The new chairman of Britain's battered Conservatives denied on Sunday that &quot;Iron Lady&quot; Margaret Thatcher was boss of the party again, saying &quot;boy wonder&quot; William Hague was his own man.</p>
<p>Party chairman Cecil Parkinson, an arch-Thatcherite, said the 36-year-old leader of the opposition Conservatives had his own style, even if he did share Thatcher's ideals and was her choice to lead the party after its crushing election defeat.</p>
<p>&quot;He's a very individual person who'll make his own mark. He has his own style, he believes in the same things as Margaret Thatcher, but he's going to be his own man,&quot; said Parkinson on BBC television.</p>
<p>&quot;We've chosen a leader. We've all got to unite behind him.&quot;</p>
<p>Parkinson was party chairman more than 14 years ago, playing a key role in Thatcher's 1983 election victory. He remains close to the former premier, who ruled Britain with an iron grip for 11 years before an exasperated party turfed her out in 1990.</p>
<p>Yet Parkinson denied his return to the political front line -- coupled with Thatcher's appearance at Hague's victory party and Hague's selection of Euro-sceptics to top jobs -- signalled a shift either to the far-right or back in time.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the composition of the new shadow cabinet you see all strands of opinion in there,&quot; he said. &quot;It's an interesting mix here of youth and experience.&quot;</p>
<p>Parkinson admitted Hague's first appointments prompted talk of &quot;a right-wing takeover, but you'll see that William has very cleverly merged all the competing interests.&quot;</p>
<p>Yet critics dub the new Conservative leader &quot;Hague the Vague&quot; and say he was brazen in his opportunistic shift to the right during the race to be party leader.</p>
<p>What he really stands for, they say, remains unclear.</p>
<p>Yet Parkinson sought to launch a new Conservative doctrine of &quot;Hagueism&quot; to rival the far-right, free-market philosophy of &quot;Thatcherism&quot; that transformed Britain in the 1980s.</p>
<p>He admitted Hagueism &quot;doesn't sound very good at the moment&quot; but predicted Britain would soon get used to the balding young man who is best known for addressing Thatcher and 5,000 Conservative activists while still a precocious schoolboy.</p>
<p>British television has played and re-played the speech with glee for the arresting portrait it offers of a pudgy child of the 1970s with the ideas of an adult, resonant voice of an ageing Yorkshireman and the confidence of a true Thatcher acolyte.</p>
<p>Thatcher described the teenaged Hague as &quot;possibly another young Pitt&quot; and said the grown-up version &quot;stands for the things I believe in&quot; when she endorsed him to be party leader.</p>
<p>Thatcher says she is delighted &quot;her man&quot; won -- albeit winning control of a diminished party more used to fighting itself than outside forces -- yet her support could backfire.</p>
<p>Already, an acerbic British press has belittled Hague for his young age and old outlook, portraying &quot;Nanny&quot; Thatcher as the powerful hand that rocks the boy wonder's cradle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
