<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678715" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Japan confident in economic recovery -- Kato.</title>
<headline>Japan confident in economic recovery -- Kato.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-06-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Takatoshi Kato, Japan's Vice Finance Minister for international affairs, said on Sunday that Japan is confident in the current situation of the Japanese economy.</p>
<p>Asked about short-term measures to reduce Japan's external surplus, Kato told Reuters Financial Television that private demand in Japan is strong enough to sustain current economic recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident about the current basis of Japan's economic recovery,&quot; Kato said.</p>
<p>He said Japan does not expect its external surplus to increase significantly in the medium term.</p>
<p>He was commenting on an economic statement released on Saturday by the leaders of the Group of Seven industrial nations.</p>
<p>The statement stipulated that Japan has the objective of achieving strong domestic demand-led growth and avoiding a significant increase in its external surplus.</p>
<p>Kato said the statement should not be taken as a demand by the G7 countries for Japan's increased efforts to expand domestic demand. He said that was the objective set by Japan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
