<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678731" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rubin backs cigarette tax hike for child programs.</title>
<headline>Rubin backs cigarette tax hike for child programs.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-06-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin on Sunday supported an increase in cigarette taxes to pay for expanded health care for children.</p>
<p>&quot;We had been under the impression that was deemed a violation of the budget agreement,&quot; Rubin told CBS television's &quot;Face the Nation&quot; program. &quot;If it's not a violation of the budget agreement, then the idea of using the tobacco tax for children's health or other children's programs seems a good idea.&quot;</p>
<p>The Senate Finance Committee last week approved increasing the federal cigarette tax by about 20 cents per pack from the current 24 cents, to raise about $15 billion over five years. Part of that money will be used for corporate tax breaks.</p>
<p>&quot;That is a waste,&quot; Rubin said.</p>
<p>The cigarette tax increase was part of wide-ranging tax cut legislation approved overwhelmingly by both Democrats and Republicans on the Senate Committee.</p>
<p>Rubin said the Senate panel's version of the tax bill represented an improvement from tax-cut legislation passed earlier by the House Ways and Means Committee. But he added that the Clinton administration was still concerned that the benefits in the Senate bill remain tilted to the better-off.  </p>
<p>In the television interview, Rubin reiterated the administration's opposition to indexation of capital gains for tax purposes, but he stopped short of threatening a veto if that proposal was contained in final legislation sent to President Clinton for his signature.</p>
<p>The House Committee's version of the tax bill contains such a proposal. The Senate's does not.</p>
<p>Rubin also made clear that the administration does not support Republican budget proposals that would force affluent seniors to pay higher deductibles under the government's Medicare health program.</p>
<p>The Senate Finance Committee last week unanimously approved wide-ranging budget legislation that included means-testing for Medicare and and a gradual increase in the eligibility age for the program from 65 to 67.</p>
<p>&quot;Means testing is a very complicated question,&quot; Rubin said, arguing that it should be studied in the context of a longer-term review of the Medicare program, and not included in legislation to balance the federal budget.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
