<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678786" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada's Finance Minister cautious on surplus projections.</title>
<headline>Canada's Finance Minister cautious on surplus projections.</headline>
<byline>Heather Scoffield</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-06-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada was hobbled by a &quot;one- legged&quot; economic recovery over the past few years, but it now has both feet on the ground and is ready to run, Finance Minister Paul Martin told Reuters this weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;In the last four years, we've had a one-legged recovery, essentially based on exports,&quot; Martin said in a phone interview from Denver, where he had just finished meeting with his G7 counterparts.</p>
<p>&quot;The second leg is now clearly kicking in,&quot; he said, pointing to improving consumer demand and retail sales. Retail sales climbed 1.1 percent in April but dropped 0.8 percent in March.</p>
<p>Martin won international praise at the G7 summit for his work in wrestling with the Canadian deficit. When his Liberal government first took office in 1993, the deficit totaled about C$42 billion ($30.3 billion), putting Canada's credit ratings and international confidence at risk.</p>
<p>Now, as the Liberals begin their second term in office after their re-election earlier this month, Prime Minister Jean Chretien has said the deficit will be eliminated within two years and is likely to come in well under C$16 billion ($11.5 billion) for the 1996-97 fiscal year.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything is on (Martin's) side,&quot; said Scotiabank economist Aron Gampel in a phone interview from Toronto. &quot;He's within spitting distance of balancing the books.&quot;</p>
<p>The question now is how to spend a budget suprlus, he said.</p>
<p>Canadians, especially the new Liberal caucus, have switched from focusing on deficit reduction to concentrating on how to spend the surplus -- a debate that had been silenced until now by almost three decades of deficits.</p>
<p>But the finance minister downplayed high hopes for the future.</p>
<p>&quot;To think that we're going to come from where we were four years ago into massive surpluses immediately is simply not realistic,&quot; Martin said. &quot;Those surpluses will grow, but initially they'll be quite small.&quot;</p>
<p>He cautioned that his main aim in his government's new mandate is to first eliminate the deficit at the same time as investing in research, development, the alleviation of child provery and job creation. Canada's unemployment rate of 9.5 percent is almost double that of the United States.</p>
<p>Canada's Liberals said during their election campaign that they would spend half of any budget surplus on social programs and the other half on tax cuts or debt reduction.</p>
<p>Martin would not say whether he would favor tax cuts over debt reduction, but he reiterated that he aims to keep the country's debt on a steady downward path.</p>
<p>The debt, projected to be 74.4 percent of GDP in the 1996-97 fiscal year, should continue to drop, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I'm concerned, the range (of debt as a percentage of GDP) should be between 20 and 60 (percent),&quot; he said, declining to be more precise.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason I don't want to go further than that is that what we want to do is make sure that this track is going steadily further down.&quot;</p>
<p>Martin will likely be helped by a solid pickup in economic growth in the next two years, economists said.</p>
<p>Growth in the Canadian economy has been sluggish in recent years, with weak consumer confidence offsetting high export levels. But economists are projecting 3.5 percent growth for 1997 and about three percent for 1998.</p>
<p>Martin said the G7 summit gave him hope that the U.S. demand for Canadian exports would continue to be strong, while Japanese demand would improve, allowing Canada's export sector to lead GDP growth in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no reason to believe that our export strength is not going to continue,&quot; Martin said. &quot;That being said, it is also very clear that our domestic economy is picking up substantially. That obviously speaks very well for our economy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
