<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678811" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia govt upbeat on economy, faces battles ahead.</title>
<headline>Russia govt upbeat on economy, faces battles ahead.</headline>
<byline>Gareth Jones</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian leaders stole much of the limelight at the Denver summit of the Group of Seven richest nations with their upbeat assessment of the country's economic prospects, shared by many in the West.</p>
<p>But despite rising foreign investment, bullish share prices and easier credit, President Boris Yeltsin's new reformist team still face formidable obstacles in their efforts to drag Russia's economy out of the doldrums.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time we are on the real eve of economic growth...and I am sure that 1998 will be the first year of Russian economic growth,&quot; reform guru, First Deputy Prime Minister Anatoly Chubais, told reporters in Denver on Sunday.</p>
<p>The G7, the exclusive club comprising the United States, Japan, Germany, France, Britain, Italy and Canada, hailed Russia's new reform drive and U.S. President Bill Clinton announced Moscow would join the Paris Club of creditor nations.</p>
<p>This will allow Russia to win repayment of some debts extended to Soviet allies, most of them in the developing world.</p>
<p>The decision crowned a week of triumphs for Yeltsin's team that also included the launch of Russia's third eurobond, worth $2 billion, and parliament's tentative approval of a more liberal tax code seen as crucial for Russia's recovery.</p>
<p>There are encouraging signs in the macroeconomic picture.</p>
<p>Inflation, in triple digits little more than a year ago, is continuing to slow, with the year-on-year rate hitting a record low 14.6 percent in May.</p>
<p>Ministers are aiming for an annual figure of five percent in 1998 and hope to push yields on government securities down to 12 percent from around 20 percent at present, making credit more easily available for much-needed investment.</p>
<p>Russian entrepreneurs have long complained that high real interest rates and cumbersome taxes are strangling production.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are seeing now is the stabilisation that people had predicted after last year's presidential election,&quot; said economist Alasdair Breach of the Russian European Centre for Economic Policy, an institute sponsored by the European Union.</p>
<p>The expected recovery of confidence in Russia's prospects failed to take place after Yeltsin's re-election because of his poor health. But the president, who had open heart surgery last November, has now reemerged as the main guarantor of reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investment is now the key. Money cannot come from elsewhere as domestic savings are very low and the government is having to cut spending to plug its budget deficit,&quot; said Breach.</p>
<p>The budget deficit poses the biggest threat to Russia's efforts to stabilise its economy after seven consecutive years of slumping production.</p>
<p>On Monday the State Duma, the lower house of parliament, dominated by Yeltsin's communist foes, is due to vote on hefty spending cuts needed to offset disastrously low tax revenues.</p>
<p>The cabinet says it will push ahead with the spending cuts regardless of how the Duma votes on Monday but it also faces fierce parliamentary opposition to its plans to cut costly housing subsidies and a range of Soviet-era social benefits.</p>
<p>Ministers have declared open war on individual and corporate tax debtors in their bid to replenish the state coffers.</p>
<p>Last week Chubais announced bankrutpcy proceedings against Nizhnevartovskneftegaz, the main production unit of Tyumen Oil, one of Russia's biggest oil groups by output, which owes the government some 1.17 trillion roubles ($200 million).</p>
<p>Another debtor, Noyabrskneftegaz will issue millions of dollars worth of new shares to pay off its debts.</p>
<p>The government's budgetary woes have given fresh impetus to its privatisation drive, with tranches of firms in the lucrative energy and telecommunications sectors earmarked for sale.</p>
<p>Next month an auction open to foreigners will be held for a 25 percent stake in Svyazinvest, the monster telecommunications holding company that controls most regional telecom firms. The cabinet hopes the sale will raise over $1 billion.</p>
<p>The government, which recently had to put off to 1998 its forecast of a return to economic growth this year, hopes its mixture of sell-offs, spending cuts and tax reforms will help restore stability to Russia's economy and vindicate foreign investors' confidence in its medium-term prospects.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
