<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678839" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>Young hero dies with brother, sister in arms: An 11-year-old boy who heroically tried to save his younger brother and sister from their burning home in Northland on Saturday night died with them in his arms. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Budget 'won't deliver on health': The Labour Party is predicting Thursday's Budget will not deliver promised increases in health funding. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>'Win-win' aviation alliance: An international alliance between Air New Zealand, Singapore Airlines, Ansett Australia and Ansett International on Friday will give each airline strategic advantages. Page 11.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>Man killed in city shooting: Second man hurt at family party: A man was killed and a male relative seriously injured in a shooting at a South Auckland family gathering on Sunday night.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Cushing paid by Peters in libel action: The Deputy Prime Minister Winston Peters has paid his $125,000 defamation bill to businessman Selwyn Cushing.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Government bulk funding allies slammed over &quot;posh&quot; threat: The government's allies in the fight over bulk funding of schools have been accused of planning to live up on taxpayer's money at a &quot;posh&quot; country retreat.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
