<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678810" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin returns from summit to political battle.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin returns from summit to political battle.</headline>
<byline>Gareth Jones</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-06-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin, buoyed by his gains at a summit of rich countries in Denver, returns to Moscow on Monday to resume his battle with political foes over the course of Russia's market reforms.</p>
<p>Yeltsin won a strong endorsement of his policies from the leaders of the Group of Seven (G7) industrial democracies, whose three-day summit helped deepen Russia's integration into the capitalist world's main economic institutions.</p>
<p>Russia will join the Paris Club of creditor nations, which will allow it to win repayment of some debts extended to Soviet allies, most of them in the developing world.</p>
<p>The G7 -- which includes the United States, Japan, Britain, Germany, France, Italy and Canada -- also pledged to support Moscow's drive to join the World Trade Organisation and the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD).</p>
<p>Russia is not a formal member of the G7 but Yeltsin's attendance at all but one of the events at this year's summit underlined his success in forging closer ties with Moscow's erstwhile ideological foes.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia won the maximum it set out to achieve at the summit of the G8 (as Russian officials now call the gathering), perhaps even a bit more,&quot; Interfax news agency quoted Alexander Livshits of the presidential administration as saying in Denver.</p>
<p>But it was far from clear whether Yeltsin's communist and nationalist opponents in the State Duma, Russia's lower house of parliament, would be impressed by his performance at the summit.</p>
<p>On Monday deputies were due to debate hefty spending cuts which the government says are needed to restore order to Russia's chaotic state finances.</p>
<p>Communist deputy Viktor Ilyukhin told NTV commercial television on Sunday the Duma would give the government's recommendations a &quot;critical evaluation&quot; and said his faction might vote against the whole package of proposed cuts.</p>
<p>Ministers have made clear that they will press on with the so-called sequestration plans regardless of the outcome of Monday's vote, which has already been postponed three times.</p>
<p>The Duma wants to distance itself from the cuts, which it says will hurt the poorest members of society most.</p>
<p>It is also resisting the government's plans to slash housing subsidies and a wide range of Soviet-era social benefits.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin weighed into the fray on Sunday, saying the cuts were painful but necessary. &quot;Without this reform we cannot improve the country's economy. We want to carry out this reform to make things better, not worse.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking in Denver on Sunday, First Deputy Prime Minister Anatoly Chubais, the cabinet's chief reformer, admitted that nearly a quarter of Russians were living below the poverty line.</p>
<p>But he said the government's measures, including a more liberal tax regime and less bureaucratic waste, would usher in an era of rising living standards from 1998.</p>
<p>The prospects of winning the battle for the budget cuts seemed to brighten after the government's success last week in pushing through the Duma the first reading of its tax code.</p>
<p>Chubais and his liberal team see the code, which already forms the basis of the 1998 budget, as a vital instrument in reversing seven consecutive years of economic decline.</p>
<p>In their efforts to win over deputies, ministers have hinted that Yeltsin might dissolve parliament and call early elections if they continue to block reforms.</p>
<p>On Sunday hardline communist Anatoly Lukyanov said such a move would only unite all deputies in opposition to Yeltsin.</p>
<p>And a meeting of the Communist Party's Central Committee on Saturday sounded a defiant note, urging people across the country to go on strike in protest against the government.</p>
<p>It also expressed outrage at Yeltsin's proposed referendum on whether to move Soviet state founder Vladimir Lenin's embalmed body from its Red Square mausoleum and bury it in St Petersburg.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
