<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678934" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>OMAN: Experts propose 40 Mideast desalination projects.</title>
<headline>Experts propose 40 Mideast desalination projects.</headline>
<dateline>MUSCAT 1997-06-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>International experts working on an ambitious project to cut the cost of desalinated water in the Middle East and North Africa said on Sunday they had proposed 40 projects to ease water shortage in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;Recommendations were made for 40 projects covering nine different technology areas totalling an estimated $3 million over the first year,&quot; Eric Jankel, director of the Muscat-based Middle East Desalination Centre (MEDREC), said in a statement.</p>
<p>A group of 20 experts who make up the Research Advisory Council (RAC) formed in May by MEDRC -- one of many projects spawned by the Middle East peace process -- concluded a three-day meeting on Thursday on methods of producing cheaper water in the region.</p>
<p>Jankel said tenders are scheduled to be issued in September or October and first awards to be made by December 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of the projects have to do with energy costs as this accounts for a major portion of the cost of desalination,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The meeting was the first to be held by the experts from Oman, Egypt, the United Arab Emirates, Italy, Kuwait, the Palestinian Authority, the United States, Jordan, Israel, France, Japan, South Korea and Germany.</p>
<p>Water, one of the region's most precious resources, is not only scarce but a bitter point of contention between Israelis and Palestinians as well as between other regional states.</p>
<p>Water desalination is vital for the largely arid countries of the Middle East, but its costs are prohibitive for most. Many governments bear most of the cost of desalination, which experts say accounts for just 5.75 percent of regional water resources.</p>
<p>Middle East countries largely depend on scarce rainfall and non-renewable underground water, they say.</p>
<p>The United States, Oman, Japan and Israel have committed $3 million each to MEDRC. South Korea has contributed $600,000. The European Union is planning to donate $3.6 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEAST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUSCAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="OMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
