<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67898" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Pechiney stock lifts on cost-slashing.</title>
<headline>Pechiney stock lifts on cost-slashing.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pechiney shares rose on the back of news that the French aluminium company plans to lower costs by four billion francs by end 1998 with up to 5,000 job cuts.</p>
<p>Analysts said the restructuring plan lifted the stock but those gains could be pared quickly because of doubts about the plan and a relatively poor outlook for the group.</p>
<p>The stock was up 2.3 francs or 1.08 percent, at 215.6 francs at 1159 GMT after hitting a high earlier of 218.4 francs.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very rare to see such a major plan implemented in such a short time, so the risk is high,&quot; said one market analyst.  </p>
<p>&quot;I doubt it will be possible to produce four billion francs in savings between now and the end of 1998. There'll undoubtedly be delays and extra expenses,&quot; said another analyst.</p>
<p>The cost-cutting plan was announced after the bourse close on Thursday and about 39 percent of the savings are to come on the jobs side, with the plan expected to cost two billion francs largely written as provisions in the 1996 accounts.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook is also a black spot for the group,&quot; said another analyst. Aluminium prices are low and the development in U.S. beverage cans faces stiff competition.&quot;</p>
<p>Without accounting for the Challenge provision, the group expects a lower year profit in 1996 than the pro-forma 1995 figure of 732 million.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
