<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="678953" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli shares end mixed volatile trade.</title>
<headline>Israeli shares end mixed volatile trade.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-06-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli shares closed off their highs on Sunday in volatile trading as investors took profits, traders said.</p>
<p>The benchmark Mishtanim index of the top 100 shares gained 0.18 percent, or 0.52 points, to 296.91 on all-share turnover of 265 million shekels against 208 million shekels on Thursday, the last day of trading before the Israeli weekend.</p>
<p>The Maof 25 blue chip index closed 0.48 percent lower at 304.06.</p>
<p>&quot;The session opened with heavy demand and the market rose across the board. The Maof gained 0.94 percent and the Mishtanim rose by 1.11 percent, almost touching 300 for the first time,&quot; said Eli Nahum, head of trading at Zannex Securities.</p>
<p>He said early trading was led by a sharp rise in Teva Pharmaceutical Industries, which ended 6.5 percent higher at 22,746 agorot on volume of 16.3 million shekels after its Nasdaq-traded American depository receipt (ADR) rose by 7.8 percent over Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;During the day investors started taking profits and the indices started falling,&quot; Nahum said. &quot;The market made a big move, so the correction might continue over the next few days.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The heavy-capitalisation stocks pushed the market downwards, but it seems that this was only a very much needed correction. The consolidation might continue on Monday but the trend is still very positive,&quot; said a trader at United Mizrahi Bank.</p>
<p>The most active share was Bank Hapoalim, which fell 2.75 percent to 783 agorot on volume of 17.7 million shekels.</p>
<p>Koor Industries gained 2.0 percent to 33,739 agorot on turnover of 7.8 million shekels.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.44 shekels)</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211 x233</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
