<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="679037" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Key points in G7 Denver economic statement.</title>
<headline>Key points in G7 Denver economic statement.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-06-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following is a list of key points in the Group of Seven economic statement from the Denver summit.</p>
<p>GOALS: sustainable non-inflationary growth, job creation, restoring sound public finances, promoting open markets, supporting global financial stability and integrating developing countries into the world economy.</p>
<p>ECONOMIC HIGHLIGHTS: G7 inflation remains low, growth solid, and either sustainable or increasing, shrinking budget deficits, impressive emerging markets growth.</p>
<p>ECONOMIC CONCERNS: high unemployment in some countries, need for long-term fiscal and financial system soundness, need for structural reforms in labor and product markets.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES: asked finance ministers to continue close cooperation on economic policy and in the exchange markets.</p>
<p>EMU: welcomed European efforts at single currency but said a well functioning euro should be underpinned by sound macroeconomic and structural policies.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES: noted long recovery and job creation, cited need to guard against inflation, balance federal budget and boost savings.</p>
<p>JAPAN: needs to spur strong domestic demand-led growth, avoid significant increase in its external surplus, deregulate and enact structural fiscal reforms.</p>
<p>FRANCE, GERMANY, ITALY: need to restore strong employment growth and fiscal health, need structural reforms to promote job creation, need to streamline government, including reform of tax and social security systems.</p>
<p>UNITED KINGDOM: needs to control inflation and continue budget deficit cuts. Recommended education and welfare reform.</p>
<p>CANADA: noted very low inflation and impressive deficit reduction, strong recent growth should lead to job creation.</p>
<p>RUSSIA: welcomed reforms launched this year, including tax reform plan, efforts to promote competition and fight crime and corruption.</p>
<p>UKRAINE: urged economic reforms and more hospitable investment climate. Noted immediate reform progress needed to ensure access to international aid. Urged development of private business sector, energy reforms. Endorsed multilateral fund for closing Chernobyl reacor and pledged $300 million from G7 members.</p>
<p>WORLD TRADE ORGANIZATION: high priority given to expanding membership, urged WTO financial services agreement by yearend.</p>
<p>GLOBAL MARKETS: urged enhanced international regulatory cooperation, called for assistance to developing nations to strengthen their financial systems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
