<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="679005" id="root" date="1997-06-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: UAE and Germany sign investment promotion deal.</title>
<headline>UAE and Germany sign investment promotion deal.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-06-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany and the United Arab Emirates have signed a bilateral investment promotion and protection pact, Germany's ambassador to the UAE said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The signing of the agreement, which was initialed earlier this year, had been delayed due to the resignation and new formation of the UAE's government in March, Martin Schneller told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It was signed yesterday (Saturday),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Thanks to this agreement, we will definitely see greater German investment in the UAE,&quot; Schneller said. &quot;The agreement's goal is to increase the trade volume from Germany to the UAE and, of course, from the UAE to Germany.&quot;</p>
<p>The ambassador said 1996 figures showed German exports to the UAE stood at 2.1 billion marks ($1.21 billion) while UAE exports to Germany hovered at 213 million marks ($123 million).</p>
<p>In 1995, UAE-German bilateral trade reached almost 2.6 billion marks.</p>
<p>On a visit to the UAE in March, German Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt said the Gulf was becoming increasingly important for Germany. He said German industry had been traditionally strong in Iran, but the focus had shifted from Iran to Saudi Arabia and the other Gulf states. ($1=1.73 marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
