<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="67972" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rates vigil set to paralyse UK stocks next week.</title>
<headline>Rates vigil set to paralyse UK stocks next week.</headline>
<byline>Tony Roddam</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a week when Britain's key stock index set record highs, investors on Friday turned a nervous eye to policy meetings next week which could signal interest rate prospects in coming months.</p>
<p>Monday's meeting between British finance minister Kenneth Clarke and Bank of England Governor Eddie George, and Tuesday's meeting of the U.S. Federal Reserve's policy committee, will be watched for any change in rate policy, traders and strategists said.</p>
<p>The FTSE-100 fell just short of cracking 4,000 on Friday, hitting a record 3,994.1 on the quarterly expiry of futures and options -- an event often prompting market volatility when players take positions for the coming three months.</p>
<p>But the index promptly erased its week's gains, shedding around 30 points from its peak amid worries about interest rates.</p>
<p>Strategists said the index still had energy in reserve to challenge its all-time highs, citing funds' heavy cash reserves and continued strength in corporate results.</p>
<p>But short-term, few investors would dare to press ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;We could still see 4,000 points next week but only after those meetings,&quot; said Roger Monson, equity stragegist at Daiwa Europe. &quot;I cannot anticipate major movement early in the week.&quot;</p>
<p>With strong UK money supply growth and retail sales booming, strategists said Clarke would not press for another rate cut. But uncertainty would nonetheless nag at the market.</p>
<p>&quot;A cut is very unlikely but not completely impossible,&quot; said Robert Giles, strategist at Credit Lyonnais Laing.</p>
<p>But strategists agreed U.S. rates were set to rise 25 basis points, a move Monson said would provoke a nervous shudder on the FTSE but could then see the market push onwards.</p>
<p>Dealers agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;I firmly believe this market is going up, at least in the short term,&quot; said the head equity trader at one top investment bank. &quot;There is too much cash around and there is no reason for it to go down. On any dip people are coming in to buy.&quot;</p>
<p>But players were loathe to predict spectacular gains.</p>
<p>Richard Jeffrey, strategist at Charterhouse Tilney, noted that equities were looking fully valued with the FTSE 100 virtually at 4,000 points.</p>
<p>&quot;While this does not rule out further progress this year, we believe that higher ground will be hard to defend,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>If the upside appeared limited, the downside risk remained small with the corporate outlook favourable, experts said.</p>
<p>Giles noted that some company profit estimates were being pared back for 1996 but were being maintained for 1997.</p>
<p>In addition, worries about a possible Labour government -- which had harried the market earlier this year -- were abating.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's perception of political risk has changed...we had actually expected the market to be far more worried about politics and that doesn't seem to be the case,&quot; Giles said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market was on a more sober footing than the week's frantic dallying with its highs might suggest. Friday's expiry, which daunted many investors, turned into a damp squib.</p>
<p>&quot;There were some people squaring up to each other but not a lot of business done. It was more like handbags at five paces,&quot; said the head equity trader.</p>
<p>Major companies reporting next week include Inchcape, Tarmac, Barratt Developments, Guinness and Redland.</p>
<p>Data next week includes final UK gross domestic product for the second quarter on Tuesday and U.S. durable goods data on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
