<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68061" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Silver loses ground, but gold holds mostly steady.</title>
<headline>Silver loses ground, but gold holds mostly steady.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silver prices sunk lower on Thursday and flirted with the psychological $5.00 an ounce level, dragging down the rest of the precious metals.</p>
<p>Gold's losses were limited, however, and it closed in London just $0.50 lower than on Wednesday at $382.85 an ounce.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold isn't doing too badly,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The gold market was anticipating a price surge after speculators took positions favouring a go-ahead for the sale of International Monetary Fund gold which failed to materialise.</p>
<p>Prices eased last week after U.S. investment funds took short positions ahead of IMF meetings on the plan, playing on fears prices would drop if fresh gold supply hit the market.</p>
<p>But the IMF has failed so far to agree a plan to sell five million ounces of gold from its reserves to aid poor countries.</p>
<p>&quot;At some point the funds are going to have to react. And then everyone's going to cover like crazy,&quot; a dealer said, adding that the gold price could soar to $388 an ounce.</p>
<p>Silver's position had also weakened over the past week as prices hovered within 10 cents above the $5.00 level. A sell-off on New York's futures market on Thursday afternoon took it sharply lower, to close at $5.01 per ounce, down eight cents.</p>
<p>Palladium, a rare white metal used in the electronics, auto and dental industries, followed silver lower to test its key $120 an ounce support level. It ended at $119.55, down $1.60.</p>
<p>Platinum also shed gains from a rally the previous day to end $2.20 lower at $388.70.</p>
<p>Some analysts were concerned that weakness in silver and platinum might undermine a recovery in the gold price.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver at around $5.00 and platinum at $390 makes many people very nervous,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;Expectations for gold to move higher in a better demand environment depend on the behaviour or silver and platinum,&quot; he added, emphasising that falls in either of these metals could erode gold's upward potential.</p>
<p>Analysts noted that in the longer term, gold was moving into the peak demand season, covering Christmas buying in the West and post-monsoon and wedding buying in Asia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
