<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68065" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Hyder builds on infrastructure for growth.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Hyder builds on infrastructure for growth.</headline>
<byline>Jo Winterbottom</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eight months after debuting as one of Britain's nascent multi-utilities, Hyder Plc is keeping its water and electicity core but looking to its infrastructure expertise for future extra dividend growth, according to chief executive Graham Hawker.</p>
<p>&quot;Our regulated businesses have the potential to continue providing strong dividend growth in the medium term. However we want to use our substantial skill base in a way which ensures long term superior returns,&quot; Hawker said in an interview.</p>
<p>Pricing for Britain's privatised water and electricity firms is set by industry watchdogs Ofwat and Offer respectively, with the next reviews due in the year 2000.</p>
<p>Hyder was formed when Welsh Water took over South Wales Electricity (Swalec) in an 872 million pound ($1.36 billion) deal which was completed in January.</p>
<p>The company has already predicted cumulative cost savings from both the merger and ongoing cuts of 275 million pounds by the turn of the century, with eight million pounds coming through in the first year.</p>
<p>EXPANSION FROM INFRASTRUCTURE</p>
<p>Hawker is clear that the company will focus on its strengths in water and electricity and expansion will come from its growing infrastructure consultancy business, Hyder Infrastructure Developments, formerly known as Acer.</p>
<p>&quot;That's what we are good at, we are good at handling businesses which many would consider boring old utilities and the regulation that goes with being a monopoly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For Hyder, utilities would also cover areas such as transport infrastructure, he added.</p>
<p>Cost cuts from the merger will help Hyder to sustain dividend growth and although Hawker is not making any firm commitments, indications are that last year's 11 percent real term rise is a level the company would like to maintain.</p>
<p>Analysts have been led by Hyder's suggestion that it has a track record of not paying out dividend increases it does not regard as sustainable.</p>
<p>But it is in the infrastructure business internationally that the company sees the possibility for long term generation of additional profit growth.</p>
<p>WELSH INTERNATIONAL</p>
<p>Hyder, named from the Welsh word for &quot;confidence&quot; and the Greek for water, reports in both English and Welsh but considers itself an &quot;international Welsh company&quot;, Hawker said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are determined that our broader infrastructure investments will be materially income-generating by the year 2000. We need shareholder confidence in this, so we must be able to make money out of them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the year ending March 31, 1996 Hyder saw turnover of 138 million pounds from its infrastructure business out of a total 757 million pounds but operating profits amounted to just 1.4 million pounds out of a total 140.6 million pounds.</p>
<p>The former Acer business provides engineering and environmental consultancy and is seen by Hawker and his team as a way of identifying high quality infrastructure investment opportunities to use the company's basic skills.</p>
<p>In Australia, it was instrumental in developing the scheme for the 900 million pound by-pass road system for Melbourne, where in addition to the design fees, Hyder now has a 6.5 percent stake in the concession to build and operate the road.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important to understand that Hyder won't take on the construction. That is better left to construction companies,&quot; Hawker said.</p>
<p>&quot;But we are good at procuring construction, that is something we do every day in our water and electricity business,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said Hyder would look internationally but would focus on projects where it felt it had a competitive edge.</p>
<p>COY ON LARGE SCALE INVESTMENTS</p>
<p>Within Britain, Hawker is coy on the subject of another large scale investment after the acquisition of Swalec. But he was quite clear that shareholder value is the driving force and that balance sheet capacity is the key issue.</p>
<p>Hyder is looking to restructure its investment in CableTel, a telecommunications company in which it inherited a 30 million pound 40 percent stake through Swalec.</p>
<p>The company also aims to take part in trials to supply gas to domestic customers ahead of liberalisation of the market in 1998. Hawker said such a move would make strategic sense, as the company is already supplying water and electricity.</p>
<p>But it would also be a defensive move, he added, to protect its existing electricity supply business from encroachment by either gas supply companies or electricity firms pushing gas.</p>
<p>CUSTOMERS SHOULD ALSO HAVE REWARDS</p>
<p>All of this should add up to benefits for shareholders, but customers should also reap rewards, Hawker said.</p>
<p>He points out that customers have benefited from cost savings over the last five years, with rebates and price increases below regulatory limits.</p>
<p>In addition, Hyder is spending 38 million pounds of voluntary investment on the environment over and above the one billion pounds committed by the water utility business.</p>
<p>&quot;We have consistently gone the extra mile with customers,&quot; he said, adding that environmental concerns from Welsh water consumers had been taken into account in the company's plans.</p>
<p>Hawker says the company's belief is that it should act in a way that balances the interests of its various constituents and that this in the end will secure shareholder value.</p>
<p>&quot;Successful companies are those that provide the services or products that customers desire at prices which represent value for money and monopolies should be no exception,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>POLITICAL FOOTBALLS</p>
<p>That view comes in the face of much public criticism of the industry in general over &quot;fat cat&quot; salaries for directors, high-priced takeovers and the failure of some water companies to maintain non-essential supplies during last summer's drought.</p>
<p>Opposition politicians have also hit out at the emergence of multi-utilities such as Hyder, United Utilities and Scottish Power.</p>
<p>They see these mergers as indications that the Conservative government's privatisation has merely allowed private companies to reshape the utility sector to their own advantage.</p>
<p>The Opposition Labour party has vowed to curb the perceived excesses by imposing a &quot;windfall&quot; tax on the firms if it wins power in a general election, which must be held by May 1997.</p>
<p>The market view is that the proposed tax is largely reflected in the share price already.</p>
<p>Hawker suggested an election would bring one clear benefit for utilities.</p>
<p>&quot;Peace. Politicians have been using utilities as a football. Whatever party wins power, perhaps all these politically-based stories will end and real achievements of the utilities will become clearer,&quot; he said. ($1=.6415 Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
