<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="680613" id="root" date="1997-06-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Morocco, Polisario start U.N.-led W.Sahara talks.</title>
<headline>Morocco, Polisario start U.N.-led W.Sahara talks.</headline>
<byline>Richard Waddington</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-06-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morocco and its Western Sahara foes, the Polisario Front, began high-level direct talks in Lisbon on Monday which the United Nations hopes will break a stalemate over the future of the former Spanish colony.</p>
<p>The two sides, who fought a 16-year bush war over the vast, mineral-rich territory, were meeting for the first time in the presence of United Nations mediators, led by former U.S. secretary of state James Baker.</p>
<p>The United Nations successfully brokered a ceasefire in 1991 but has since failed to implement a proposed referendum on the future of the 250,000 square km (100,000 sq mile) territory because Morocco and the Algeria-backed Polisario cannot agree on who should be allowed to vote.</p>
<p>Baker, asked by U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan last March to spearhead a new bid to resolve the dispute, held separate talks with Moroccan and Polisario envoys in London earlier this month to set up the Lisbon meeting.</p>
<p>Baker met Prime Minister Abdellatif Filali, head of the Moroccan delegation, and Mahfoud Ali Beiba, his counterpart in Polisario's self-proclaimed republic in Western Sahara. The officials made no comments before the three-day talks began.</p>
<p>&quot;The significant thing about (the Lisbon) meeting is that for the first time, the U.N. will be present,&quot; said one diplomatic source close to the discussions.</p>
<p>Morocco, which controls four-fifths of the territory with its potassium mines and rich Atlantic fishing grounds, hosted a meeting with the Polisario in Rabat last September but U.N. officials were not present.</p>
<p>The talks made no significant progress.</p>
<p>But Baker said in London that both sides were showing new signs of flexibility on the question of the referendum. &quot;This does not mean we will succeed. But at least it means we are back on track,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Polisario, which wants an independent state, has been holding out for only those resident in the territory before the Spanish left in 1976 to be allowed to take part in the ballot.</p>
<p>Morocco, which claims the territory as its own, wants the voting extended to tens of thousands of people who have moved there since.</p>
<p>The three days of talks, which will also be attended by representatives of Algeria and Mauritius, are being held behind closed doors in a fortress on the outskirts of Lisbon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPSAH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
