<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="680668" id="root" date="1997-06-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Ex-spymaster sues Pakistan govt over U.S. arrest.</title>
<headline>Ex-spymaster sues Pakistan govt over U.S. arrest.</headline>
<byline>Raja Asghar</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-06-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former Pakistan military spymaster sued the government on Monday over the controversial arrest of a man accused of a deadly shooting outside CIA headquarters in the United States.</p>
<p>The move by retired Lieutenant-General Hameed Gul, a former chief of the military Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI), came as the chief executive of Baluchistan province condemned both the U.S. and Pakistani governments for arresting Mir Aimal Kansi, a native of Baluchistan.</p>
<p>Gul filed a petition in Punjab province's Lahore High Court challenging what he called an unlawful snatch of Kansi in Pakistan by agents of the U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) in violation of the Pakistani extradition law, legal sources said.</p>
<p>They said the court's bench in the nearby city of Rawalpindi had yet to set a date for hearing the petition, in which Gul prayed for Kansi's return to Pakistan and punishment of those involved in the allegedly illegal arrest.</p>
<p>&quot;This (Kansi's) arrest and his transfer to them (the United States) cannot be condemned enough,&quot; Baluchistan Chief Minister Akhtar Mengal told the provincial assembly in the provincial capital Quetta earlier on Monday.</p>
<p>Kansi, 33, is accused of killing two Central Intelligence Agency workers and injuring three others in a shooting spree outside CIA headquarters in Langley, Virginia, on January 25, 1993, before escaping to Pakistan.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif's government has kept silent on the arrest since the FBI announced it in Washington on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Islamabad government is under fire from several religious and nationalist parties for its apparent collusion in the U.S.-led operation to spirit the wanted man out of Pakistan.</p>
<p>But opposition leader Benazir Bhutto on Saturday lent cautious support to Kansi's capture. Her government, forced from power last November, had also tried to arrest Kansi without success, she said in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>Kansi was reported to have been grabbed from a hotel in the Punjab provincial town of Dera Ghazi Khan in the early hours of June 15 by FBI agents, backed by Pakistani security men.</p>
<p>He was then flown from Islamabad to the United States in a U.S. military plane, apparently without a court hearing or any formal extradition procedures.</p>
<p>Mengal, who heads a coalition of several Baluchi nationalist and religious groups, accused the federal government of taking orders from the United States and said it might not have been informed before Kansi was actually arrested.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt that we carry out American orders,&quot; Mengal said. &quot;Our foreign policy, budget and even appointments at certain government posts are made at their behest.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The CIA is whisking away our people and our government is unaware of it,&quot; Mengal's senior minister Amir Zaman said.</p>
<p>The FBI said on Tuesday that Kansi had been delivered by unidentified Afghans and was brought back to the United States to face trial. It gave no details about the man's seizure and would not say if any of those involved would collect a reward of up to $2 million offered for the fugitive.</p>
<p>Gul, who was deeply involved in joint U.S.-Pakistani efforts to fund and arm Afghan guerrillas fighting Soviet troops in the 1980s, alleged on Sunday that Kansi had illicit links with the CIA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
