<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68122" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Coles says no comment on Lew, Bartels.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Coles says no comment on Lew, Bartels.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Retailer Coles Myer Ltd said on Friday it had no comment to make on a report that Deputy Chairman Solomon Lew had threatened legal action against Coles Myer and that Coles' independent directors had decided to accelerate their plan to replace chief executive Peter Bartels.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no comments regarding the story in The Age and The Sydney Morning Herald,&quot; a Coles spokeswoman told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;If there are going to be any comments, they'll come from the chairman,&quot; the spokeswoman said. Chairman Nobby Clark was not immediately available for comment.  </p>
<p>The report carried by The Age and The Sydney Morning Herald did not have any attribution.</p>
<p>The newspapers said Coles Myer expected to receive Federal Court writs later on Friday from Lew's Premier Investments Ltd .</p>
<p>&quot;The legal actions are intended to prevent Coles from reading Australian Securities Commission evidence about the now notorious Yannon transaction,&quot; The Sydney Morning Herald said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Lew camp is arguing that Coles has settled its civil action over Yannon and no longer has any right to read the transcripts,&quot; the newspaper said.  </p>
<p>Coles Myer said last month it had settled its dispute with Lew and Premier over the 1990 Yannon transaction and would receive A$12 million in compensation.</p>
<p>The Yannon deal was a financial transaction which cost Coles A$18 million and benefited a company associated with largest shareholder and deputy chairman Solomon Lew by a similar sum.</p>
<p>The deal was at the centre of a dispute between the company and sacked finance director, Philip Bowman.</p>
<p>The furore over Bowman's sacking eventually led to Lew's demotion from the position of executive chairman. Lew has about 14 percent of Coles Myer shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
