<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682399" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Van Gogh landscape sells for 8.8 million pounds.</title>
<headline>Van Gogh landscape sells for 8.8 million pounds.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A watercolour landscape by the Dutch artist Vincent van Gogh sold for 8.8 million pounds ($14.7 million) on Tuesday, making it the most expensive modern painting sold in Europe since 1990, auctioneers Sotheby's said.</p>
<p>&quot;Harvest in Provence&quot; (La Moisson en Provence) had not been seen in public for almost 50 years when it was unveiled by Sotheby's before the sale.</p>
<p>It was bought by an anonymous telephone bidder.</p>
<p>The most expensive modern painting ever sold in Europe is Picasso's &quot;Les Tuilleries&quot;, which made 12.5 million pounds seven years ago at a London auction.</p>
<p>Art prices soared in the 1980s when paintings became seen as an upmarket investment, but they were badly hit by the recession of the early 90s.</p>
<p>&quot;Harvest in Provence&quot; is considered one of Van Gogh's most important works.</p>
<p>It is a watercolour version of an oil painting of the same subject which hangs in the Van Gogh museum in Amsterdam and was painted in June 1888, during one of the stormiest periods of the artist's tragic life.</p>
<p>Van Gogh, who lived from 1853 to 1890, entered an asylum a few months after finishing the pen and ink painting.</p>
<p>The work, showing a rural scene near Arles in southern France, was bought by a gallery in Paris in 1901 and spent World War One in a Berlin gallery.</p>
<p>In the late 1920s it was bought by a British collector who was its last owner. ($ = 0.598 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
