<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682427" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE gas oil ends flat, Brent falls on Iraqi export.</title>
<headline>IPE gas oil ends flat, Brent falls on Iraqi export.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE gas oil closed unchanged on Tuesday as the gas oil market shrugged off losses on Brent futures following news that Iraq expected to resume oil exports in the next seven to 10 days.</p>
<p>&quot;It was pretty quiet in the gas oil pit,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been very sluggish today. It hardly reacted,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>The July contract closed at the unchanged price level of $160.25 a tonne having posted a low of $160.00 and a high of $162.00 during the session.</p>
<p>August Brent took more of a battering from the Iraqi oil export news. It was trading 15 cents lower at $17.83 a barrel at 1707 GMT having traded at slightly higher levels prior to the news concerning the resumption of the Iraqi oil exports.</p>
<p>Iraqi oil minister Amir Rasheed told reporters in Madrid that Iraq expected to start exporting oil from the second six month tranche of its oil-for-food deal with the United Nations in the next week to 10 days.</p>
<p>Iraq sold $2 billion worth of oil in the first six months of the year to May 30 under the deal.</p>
<p>News that Nigeria was reported to be ordering the immediate import of 33 cargoes of petroleum products due to an acute fuel shortage in the country had little effect on the futures markets.</p>
<p>Interest in the OPEC meeting due to start in Vienna on Wednesday faded into the background following the Iraqi news.</p>
<p>Traders said they would be monitoring news out of the meeting although few expected anything radical.</p>
<p>Most oil players expected OPEC oil ministers to rollover the current 25.03 million barrels per day output ceiling. -- London Newsroom, +44 171 542 7714.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
