<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682519" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Anglo slams planned S.African labour law.</title>
<headline>Anglo slams planned S.African labour law.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's biggest company, Anglo American Corp of South Africa Ltd, on Tuesday slammed &quot;inappropriate&quot; labour legislation which it said would destroy rather than create jobs.</p>
<p>Chairman Julian Ogilvie Thompson said in his annual chairman's statement that the government's failure to implement reforms to make the labour market more flexible was hurting employment prospects and the Basic Conditions of Employment Bill would exacerbate the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;Aside from negatively affecting unit labour costs and South Africa's international competitiveness, such legislation is quite inappropriate if job creation is to be a major economic priority,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ogilvie Thompson reiterated recent criticism from business over proposals in the bill which he said would lead to a shorter working week, higher overtime rates and further regulatory burdens on employers.</p>
<p>South African business and labour have clashed on the planned labour legislation, with the country's largest labour federation calling a one-day national stoppage earlier this month to drive home its claims.</p>
<p>But despite his criticism over the labour bill, Ogilvie Thompson was broadly complementary about the achievements of Nelson Mandela's government over the last three years, saying it had &quot;performed creditably in the face of enormous challenges&quot;.</p>
<p>He praised the macroeconomic Growth, Employment and Redistribution strategy unveiled last year and this year's disciplined budget, but added that tackling South Africa's notoriously high crime was a precondition of economic success.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
