<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682566" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa's Comgold to unbundle, list Holistic unit.</title>
<headline>S.Africa's Comgold to unbundle, list Holistic unit.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mining firm Commonwealth Gold (Comgold) said on Tuesday it is to partially unbundle its shareholding in its Holistic Resources unit and seek to list the firm on the South African bourse and an international exchange.</p>
<p>The move follows a joint-venture agreement between Comgold, an arm of Amalia Gold Mining and Exploration, and the Liberian government to rehabilitate and develop the entire Liberian metals, minerals and hydrocarbon industry.</p>
<p>The development vehicle for the project will be Liberia Resources Corp (LibeResCo) -- which is 60 percent owned by the Liberian government and 25 percent indirectly owned by Holistic.</p>
<p>Comgold said the deal would see Holistic's market value leap from the reintroduction of official trading in Liberian gold and diamonds.</p>
<p>&quot;Comgold's directors consider it appropriate that shareholders be able to hold a direct interest in Holistic Resources enabling them to benefit from the rapid capital appreciation of both companies,&quot; the firm said.</p>
<p>&quot;Plans to list Holistic Resources on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange (JSE) and another international exchange are well advanced,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Comgold will distribute on a one-for-one basis 250 million Holistic Resources shares to Comgold shareholders registered by June 31.</p>
<p>About 450 million Holistic shares will continue to be held by New South Africa Mining which will be listed on the JSE and Comgold will retain 200 million Holistic shares to be held on a long-term basis.</p>
<p>Comgold sealed the deal with Liberia on June 16.</p>
<p>&quot;LibeResCo holds all the rights to develop Liberia's gold, diamond, iron ore, bauxite and offshore oil and gas,&quot; Comgold said in a statement.</p>
<p>Apart from the iron ore mines, which were the world's third largest supplier of iron ore until 1989, when an eight-year civil war disrupted the industry, Liberia's mining sector is largely underdeveloped.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
