<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682565" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria's Abiola clocks up three years in detention.</title>
<headline>Nigeria's Abiola clocks up three years in detention.</headline>
<byline>James Jukwey</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's detained presidential contender Moshood Abiola marked three years in detention on Tuesday with no sign that his release could come soon.</p>
<p>He was arrested in 1994 after proclaiming himself president in defiance of military ruler General Sani Abacha.</p>
<p>&quot;Abiola was not discussed,&quot; a government official said after talks by military brass in the capital Abuja on Monday. The discussions focused on a fuel shortage that has gripped the country.</p>
<p>Abiola's detention anniversary, like that of the annulled June 12, 1993, presidential vote he is widely believed to have won, passed with only moderate media mention.</p>
<p>But political commentators believe Abiola will become an issue next year when the country is scheduled to go to the polls to elect a president, the climax of Abacha's three-year programme for transition to democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;The crunch time will come when General Abacha has to hand over because Abiola's supporters will demand to know what happens to his own mandate,&quot; said Bola Olugbade, a former governorship contender in Abiola's stronghold in the southwest.</p>
<p>The Yoruba-speaking southwest is Abiola's home region, where many people still clamour for what they call &quot;actualisation&quot; of the 1993 vote.</p>
<p>Several former political associates openly campaign for Abacha to shed his uniform and contest the presidential election.</p>
<p>But the opposition says the transition will fail unless Abiola is freed and his election validated.</p>
<p>&quot;The fate of Nigeria is today bound hands and feet with whatever happens to Abiola,&quot; said the Campaign for Democracy pressure group in a statement to mark the detention anniversary.</p>
<p>Abiola was charged with treason but the trial has stalled on technicalities since August 1994 when the judge withdrew. This was also the last time Abiola was seen in public.</p>
<p>Although riots and strikes which greeted Abiola's arrest have long since died down, Nigeria remains in crisis over the vote annulment.</p>
<p>Fuel scarcity has hit the oil-rich West African nation, its economy is mired in recession, and unemployment is high while the programme for transition to civilian rule remains suspect.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are witnessing today in this country can all be traced to June 12,&quot; says Peter Adebiyi of the National Democratic Coalition, the umbrella opposition group formed in 1994 to help Abiola claim his &quot;mandate&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;NADECO once again calls for the release of Chief M.K.O. Abiola and all political detainees, the forming of a government of national unity headed by Abiola, to effect the necessary change in our society that will set this country on the path of greatness,&quot; NADECO said on the anniversary of Abiola's arrest.</p>
<p>The government insists Abiola committed a serious offence against the state when he proclaimed himself president and that the judicial process must take its course. It also says the poll he contends that he won was inconclusive.</p>
<p>For a long time there was no word about Abiola, who is held in Abuja.</p>
<p>Then in May, after rumours began circulating that he was dead, his personal doctor Ore Falomo was allowed to see him.</p>
<p>Falomo said after their 90-minute meeting that Abiola was in good health and his living conditions had improved.</p>
<p>&quot;I met him alive, very well and in high spirits, the level of which I have not seen him in the last two years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Before the poll annulment, Abiola was a close friend of Abacha and some political sources have talked of a deal whereby Abiola would be freed next year to share power with Abacha to ensure peace and stability in the multi-ethnic nation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
