<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682649" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia RTS index closes at record 412.32.</title>
<headline>Russia RTS index closes at record 412.32.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Russian Trading System index of 22 leading shares closed at a record 412.32 on Tuesday, or 2.93 percent up on Monday's record 400.59 closing.</p>
<p>Total market turnover on Tuesday, the fifth record-setting trading session, was a robust $65.6 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything is rising and I cannot see any signals of a fall,&quot; a Regent European Securities trader said. &quot;This is not a speculative rise, but a rise on fundamentals.&quot;</p>
<p>LUKoil ordinaries were the gain-leaders with prices rising to $18.71 from $17.99 at Monday's close, slightly off a daily high of $19.15.</p>
<p>But some traders said the market was getting overheated and a small correction was possible despite falling liquidity.</p>
<p>&quot;Practically all paper has reached new levels,&quot; said deputy head of ICFI Bank's securities department Alexei Abdurakhimov, adding prices would have to fall for new sales to begin.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is so high because people have sold 90 percnet of what they had,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Long distance carrier Rostelekom, which has languished on the stock market, partly over uncertainty over an auction of Svyazinvest telecoms holding company which controls Rostelekom, ticked up to $3.875 from $3.865.</p>
<p>Russia said this week the Svyazinvest auction would take place on July 25.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is waiting for the Svyazinvest auction,&quot; the Regent European Securities trader said. &quot;Foreigners see it as a sign of how much the Russian market is open for foreign investment.&quot;</p>
<p>--Olga Popova, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
