<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682601" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - June 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - June 24.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers on Tuesday</p>
<p>morning. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not</p>
<p>vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>FRONT PAGE POLITICAL NEWS</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- The Polish Liquid Fuels Chamber (PLFC) has sent an open letter to President Aleksander Kwasniewski asking him not to sign the agricultural sector fuels bill which envisages sales of diesel oil to farmers at lower than market prices. According to the PLFC the law will result in illegal fuel sales to non-farmers.</p>
<p>- Poland and the Czech Republic signed an agreement on cooperation in veterinary and pesticide practices which are part of the Central European Free Trade Agreement (CEFTA).</p>
<p>ECONOMIC AND MARKET STORIES</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- The provincial economic court in Gdansk has prolonged the commercial activity of the bankrupt Gdansk shipyard until the end of 1998, a yard board member, Bogdan Oleszek, said.</p>
<p>- Over 40 percent of Poland's small and medium size businesses are in the big city areas of Katowice, Warsaw, Szczecin and Krakow, employing 41.8 percent of the sector's workers.</p>
<p>- The Legislation Monitoring Centre (OMIL) said the act on standards supervision of foreign trade in agricultural products legislated at the start of 1997 is damaging on many grounds and should be cancelled.</p>
<p>- The listed Exbud construction holding wants to buy the PZPS plywood plant in Pisz, north-eastern Poland, Exbud said.</p>
<p>- Thomson Multimedia will launch a television assembly plant in Zyrardow, central Poland, in January 1998. The plant will assemble 500,000 televisions annually, Thomson Multimedia said.</p>
<p>- Around 320 pharmaceutical makers are in operation in Poland. International investors including Merck &amp; Co, Marion Roussel, ICN, Rhone Poulenc, Gedeon Richter, Pliva and Enterprise Investors have expressed interested in purchasing some of the industry's leading plants.</p>
<p>- France's Caisse Nationale de Prevoyance (CNP) has doubled its stake in Polisa Zycie SA life insurance firm to 46 percent.</p>
<p>- A shareholders meeting of Kredyt Bank on July 17 will change the bank's name to Kredytowy Bank Polski and approve the fusion of Kredyt Bank and Polish Investment Bank (PBI).</p>
<p>- The board of Bank Gospodarki Zywnosciowej (BGZ) agricultural sector bank will use 390 million zlotys from 1996 net profit to cover losses made in previous years and spend two million zlotys on the modernisation of training centres.</p>
<p>DZIENNIK PRAWA I GOSPODARKI</p>
<p>- Leszek Juchniewicz, the former deputy treasury minister, has been appointed Energy Regulation Office president.</p>
<p>- The Orix Polska leasing firm, a joint venture of Japan's Orix and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD), has officially started operations in Poland. The company's share capital was increased from eight million zlotys to 17 million zlotys.</p>
<p>- Poland is number 50 on the so-called Davos list of the world's most attractive investment opportunities, Business Centre Club deputy president Jeremi Mordasiewicz said.</p>
<p>- Poland's GSM mobile phone operators have contracted over 300,000 subscribers in the first nine months of activity.</p>
<p>- The Wroclaw branch of the CPN petrol processor and trader has launched environment-friendly Bio-diesel oil production.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- Glaxo Wellcome plans to take part in the privatisation of the Starogard and Poznan pharmaceutical plants, it said.</p>
<p>- Austria's Raiffeisen Zentralbank Oesterreich recommended buying Bank Handlowy shares at up to 39 zlotys per share in a report dated June 11.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- The listed Echo Investment will build a business centre complex in central Lodz worth up to $40 million, the company said.</p>
<p>-The listed Wolczanka garment maker will invest 7.6 million zlotys in facility modernisation and development in 1997, Wolczanka's president Ryszard Polanski said.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
