<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682743" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - June 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - June 24.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Slovenia's Tuesday morning newspapers:</p>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>-  Slovenian President Milan Kucan, looking back on six years of independence in the former Yugoslav republic, said on Monday the country had made much progress but crucial questions remained unsolved.</p>
<p>- Slovenian Prime Minister Janez Drnovsek met his Italian counterpart Romano Prodi on Monday in New York at a conference of the UN General Council and talked about Slovenia's efforts to join NATO.</p>
<p>- Janez Podobnik, Slovenia's parliamentary president, said on his visit to the European council's parliament that future cooperation with the EU and NATO was of vital importance to the tiny Alpine country.</p>
<p>- U.S. Senator Bob Dole will meet Slovenia's Foreign Minister Zoran Thaler, parliamentary speaker Janez Podobnik and President Milan Kucan, during a visit to Slovenia on Tuesday.</p>
<p>- U.S. aircraft carrier John F. Kennedy entered Slovenian territorial waters on Monday for a three-day visit.</p>
<p>- Employees of commercial television station TV3 started a strike on Monday, demanding payment of salaries for the last six months.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- A cross-party agreement on cooperation over Slovenia's efforts to join the EU is expected to be signed on Tuesday. The constitutional court ordered parliament to change the constitution, before ratification of the EU association accord.</p>
<p>VECER</p>
<p>- A group of internet users protested against a decision by Slovenian Telecom's to hike telephone prices by 8.6 percent, which they say is an increase of about 170 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
