<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682809" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HAITI: At least six dead in Haiti violence.</title>
<headline>At least six dead in Haiti violence.</headline>
<dateline>PORT-AU-PRINCE, Haiti 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Escalating violence between drug traffickers, police and armed groups in the northern city of Cap-Haitien has killed at least six people since the weekend, U.N. police sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Local residents said vigilante groups armed with knives and machetes were patrolling streets questioning passers-by.</p>
<p>Cap-Haitien is known to be one of several Haitian ports used to transship drugs from Central and South America and the Dominican Republic to the Bahamas and the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a demonstration after this guy escaped from prison, with some 200 people throwing rocks and molotov cocktails at us,&quot; an American police trainer working for the United Nations said. &quot;There was even a little attack on us.&quot;</p>
<p>Three alleged drug traffickers were killed and one wounded in a shootout with police near the port on Saturday night. The wounded man was taken to a hospital, where he was interrogated by police, but he was shot and killed on Monday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Someone just came right into the hospital and shot him,&quot; the police source said. He did not know if the man was killed by members of his own trafficking ring or by local vigilantes.</p>
<p>The civilian police officer reported at least two other bodies had been found since Sunday, one hacked by machetes and the other shot dead. Police did not release the identities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT-AU-PRINCE, Haiti"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HAITI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
