<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="682877" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: TIMELINES-Today in History - June 25.</title>
<headline>TIMELINES-Today in History - June 25.</headline>
<text>
<p>** BIRTHDAYS **</p>
<p>The author of the popular novels &quot;Animal Farm&quot; and &quot;Nineteen Eighty-four&quot;, GEORGE ORWELL, was born as ERIC BLAIR in 1903.</p>
<p>The architect who gave us Australia Square and the MLC Centre in Sydney, HARRY SEIDLER, was born in 1923.</p>
<p>Australian Olympic athlete JUDY POLLOCK was born in 1940.  </p>
<p>American singer/songwriter, CARLY SIMON, was born in 1945. She and her sister LUCY appeared as the 'Simon Sisters' in 1964. She was married to singer JAMES TAYLOR for 10 years from 1972. The hit songs she wrote included &quot;You're So Vain&quot;, &quot;Nobody Does It Better&quot; and the James Bond movie-theme &quot;The Spy Who Loved Me&quot;.</p>
<p>New Zealand singer TIM FINN, who formed the group 'Split Enz' before going solo in 1983, was born in 1952.  </p>
<p>Australian cricketer IAN DAVIS was born in 1953.</p>
<p>British musician, GEORGE MICHAEL (GEORGES PANAYIOUTOU), who initially achieved pop music fame as part of the group 'Wham', was born in 1963.  The group's hits included &quot;Wake Me Up Before You Go-Go&quot; (1984) and &quot;Freedom&quot; (1984/85), and the band split in 1986.</p>
<p>			 ** EVENTS **</p>
<p>    1630 :	The table fork was introduced to America by</p>
<p>Governor JOHN WINTHROP, who brought the first fork from England in a leather case.</p>
<p>    1797 :	Admiral NELSON was wounded in battle and had to</p>
<p>have his arm amputated.</p>
<p>    1867 :	Barbed wire was patented by LUCIEN B.SMITH of</p>
<p>Ohio.  </p>
<p>    1870 :	Queen ISABELLA II of Spain abdicated.</p>
<p>    1876 :     At the Battle of the Little Big Horn, or the</p>
<p>Greasy Grass as the Sioux called it, Sioux and Cheyenne Indians led by Chief CRAZY HORSE routed the U.S. 7th Cavalry led by Colonel GEORGE ARMSTRONG CUSTER. CUSTER died along with his company of 264 men in what was known as &quot;Custer's Last Stand&quot;.</p>
<p>    1903 :	Scientist MARIE CURIE announced the discovery of</p>
<p>radium.  </p>
<p>    1910 :    The first performance of &quot;The Firebird&quot;, a ballet</p>
<p>by IGOR STRAVINSKY, took place in Paris.</p>
<p>    1925 :	The first car telephone went on display in</p>
<p>Germany.</p>
<p>    1932 :	In cricket, the first Test match was played</p>
<p>between India and England at Lord's. The Indian team lost by 158 runs.  </p>
<p>    1942 :     Major General DWIGHT EISENHOWER was appointed</p>
<p>commander of U.S. forces in Europe; on the same day, General Sir CLAUDE AUCHINLECK became commander of the British Eighth Army in North Africa.</p>
<p>    1950 :	The Korean War began with Communist North Korea</p>
<p>invading the Republic of Korea in the south. There was constant tension in the country from the end of World War Two, after the establishment of the militarised line on the 38th parallel.  </p>
<p>    1951 :	A landmark in television history with the</p>
<p>broadcast of the first colour program on the CBS network in the United States.</p>
<p>    1953 :     The notorious British murderer of Ten Rillington</p>
<p>Place, JOHN CHRISTIE, was sentenced to death for killing six women.  </p>
<p>    1962 :	Italian film actress SOPHIA LOREN was charged</p>
<p>with alleged bigamy. LOREN'S husband of six years, film producer, CARLO PONTI, was still considered under Italian law to be married to his previous wife.</p>
<p>    1964 :	In Sydney the National TB and Chest Association</p>
<p>put up the proposal that cigarette packets carry cancer warnings.</p>
<p>    1968 :    British comedian TONY HANCOCK was found dead in a</p>
<p>Sydney hotel room after committing suicide.  </p>
<p>    1969 :	The longest-ever singles match at Wimbledon of 5</p>
<p>hours and 12 minutes was played between PANCHO GONZALEZ and CHARLIE PASERELL.</p>
<p>    1987 :	American actress, JOAN COLLINS, obtained a 45</p>
<p>second divorce from her Swedish husband PETER HOLM.</p>
<p>    1991 :	The last Soviet troops stationed in</p>
<p>Czechoslovakia left the country, 23 years after the Warsaw Pact invasion.  </p>
<p>    1991 :	Croatia and Slovenia declared independence from</p>
<p>Yugoslavia, plunging the federation into a violent breakup.</p>
<p>    1996 :	A bomb blast tore through a Saudi Arabian</p>
<p>military complex housing foreigners, killing 19 Americans and injuring nearly 400.  </p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS.)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
