<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="683271" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Arco Chemical plans $150 mln/yr cost cuts.</title>
<headline>Arco Chemical plans $150 mln/yr cost cuts.</headline>
<dateline>NEWTOWN SQUARE, Pa. 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>ARCO Chemical Co said Tuesday it has began a cost-cutting plan that is expected to save the company $150 million annually.</p>
<p>The key part of savings will come from the reduction of from 800 to 1,100 employee and contractor positions over the next few years, on a worldwide base of 5,300 positions, it said.  </p>
<p>The company said the cost cuts are to be substantially in place by 1999 and are part of a broad plan disclosed in May by Alan Hirsig, chief executive officer, at the ARCO annual meeting of shareholders.</p>
<p>The plan seeks to shareholder value, increase efficiency, and achieve a double-digit percentage reduction in the company's fixed and controlled costs, which are roughly $750 million a year, according to an ARCO statement.</p>
<p>The company said it expects to take a special charge to earnings later in 1997 to account for the costs of the program. The amount of the charge has not been determined.  </p>
<p>&quot;Once we are through this transition, we will emerge as a company that is better prepared to grow, even more agile in its decision-making, and clearly focused on building value for shareholders,&quot; said Hirsig.</p>
<p>The company said a number of changes have already been implemented as part of the program. Those changes aim to speed commercialization of growth opportunities, minimize raw material and logistics costs, reduce working capital, and better meet customer needs.</p>
<p>It said it has also merged manufacturing and engineering functions to achieve production economies.</p>
<p>The restructuring effort will continue through the end of 1998, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWTOWN SQUARE, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
