<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="683269" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bangor Hydro gets part of rates sought.</title>
<headline>Bangor Hydro gets part of rates sought.</headline>
<dateline>BANGOR, Maine 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangor Hydro-Electric Co said Tuesday the Maine Public Utilities Commission granted the utility a portion of the temporary rate increase it sought.</p>
<p>Bangor Hydro explained it was seeking an immediate rate adjustment due to the company's financial condition and to the uncertainties created by the extended outage at Maine Yankee, a nuclear power plant in which the company has a seven percent interest.</p>
<p>The company said the commission authorized an increase of about one-half the amount the company had sought.</p>
<p>The increase would produce additional annual revenue of about $5 million, which is an increase of about 3.8 percent effective July 1.</p>
<p>In authorizing the increase, the commission order the change to be implemented in a way that ensures there will be no increase in company earnings, and therefore no benefit for stockholders, Bangor Hydro said in a statement.</p>
<p>This will be accomplished by accelerating the paydown of one or more of the company's existing obligations. In essence, this means the revenues will be used to pay existing obligations that the company and customers are already obligated to pay, but on a somewhat faster schedule.</p>
<p>The temporary increase will be applied to general tariffs, but will not be applied to negotiated contracts or the electric heat rate because those prices are based upon the competitive market for customers with alternatives.</p>
<p>Bangor Hydro's request for a general rate increase is still pending and will not be completed until early 1998. It is expected the order in this temporary case will be taken into account in the pending case.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610107">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGOR, Maine"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
