<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="683379" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot natgas prices extend gains on heat.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot natgas prices extend gains on heat.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot natural gas prices continued to strengthen Tuesday as warmer-than-normal weather stretched across the U.S., market sources said.</p>
<p>Louisiana Gulf Coast prices firmed about two cents to the high-$2.20s per mmBtu, while south Texas prices rose by a similar amount to the low-$2.20s.</p>
<p>Above-normal temperatures are forecast to continue throughout most of the eastern half of the U.S. this week, though a brief bout of thunderstorms is expected to pressure temperatures later this week in parts of the Midwest, according to Weather Services Corp.  </p>
<p>In the East, New York city gate prices gained another two to five cents to the low-$2.60s as temperature highs in the area neared 90 degrees F amid partly cloudy skies.</p>
<p>In the Midwest, prices were also up about two cents to $2.10-2.13, while Chicago city-gate prices still hovered around $2.40.</p>
<p>Some traders said they were expecting Midwest prices to soften slightly later this week in anticipation of heavy rains and the resulting drop in cooling demand.</p>
<p>In West Texas, Permian prices edged about two cents higher to about $2.07-2.12, while southern California border prices remained strong at $2.25-2.27.</p>
<p>Early July prices in the Permian basin were talked at $2.06-2.07, which would be even with June indices.</p>
<p>((--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
