<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="683631" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Waigel says Germany needs Eurofighter.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Waigel says Germany needs Eurofighter.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel said on Tuesday the Eurofighter should play a vital role in Germany's defence, but stopped short of saying he had sewn up financing for the multi-billion mark project.</p>
<p>Waigel made no comment on talks earlier with Daimler-Benz Aerospace AG (DASA), German partner in the four-country combat jet project, on paying for the 180 Eurofighters Bonn wants to buy.</p>
<p>But, asked whether Germany would buy the multi-role jet, he answered: &quot;I believe so, yes.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that the Eurofighter is absolutely necessary for our defence,&quot; Waigel told reporters.</p>
<p>And, in remarks directed to the project's partners in Britain, Italy and Spain, Waigel said that Germany would live up to its earlier pledges to back Eurofighter.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an international project where, in my opinion, Germany must not lose the confidence&quot; of its partners, Waigel told reporters before a meeting of deputies from Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrat (CDU/CSU) parliament faction.</p>
<p>Germany's Eurofighter partners are fretting at the delay to a firm order by Bonn for Eurofighter, and DASA chief executive Manfred Bischoff has said the holdup to serial production was costing his company a million marks a day.</p>
<p>But Waigel, struggling to contain state borrowing to join Europe's single currency, has been unable to raise the full 23 billion marks for Germany's batch of Eurofighters yet.</p>
<p>Waigel struck a recent informal deal with Defence Minister Volker Ruehe to split a financing gap of two billion marks down the middle.</p>
<p>He has sought to meet his side of the bargain by clawing back one billion marks in pre-financing loans paid to DASA to help develop the company's Airbus civilian aircraft operations.</p>
<p>Ruehe said negotiations over Eurofighter financing were continuing, and the first top-level government meeting on setting the 1998 defence budget was due this Thursday.</p>
<p>Defending his departmental budget against further pressure to save, Ruehe said Germany's 340,000-strong army needed to be solidly financed, as did major defence procurement projects.</p>
<p>He also ruled out any possible reduction in the number of Eurofighters Germany would buy.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that this project makes sense, and it will come when I get the means to pay for it,&quot; Ruehe told reporters.</p>
<p>Eurofighter's partners include DASA, a unit of auto giant Daimler-Benz AG, British Aerospace, Alenia of Italy and state-owned CASA of Spain.</p>
<p>DASA declined to comment on Tuesday on the talks on funding Eurofighter, but on Monday dismissed as speculation reports it would pay back more than one billion marks in Airbus aid early.</p>
<p>A spokesman said DASA was only prepared to repay state funding linked to Airbus sales which was originally earmarked for repayment after the year 2001. DASA opposes returning 10.7 billion marks in state funds which is due to be repaid out of profits out of its Airbus operations after 2002.</p>
<p>-- douglas.busvine@reuters.com (Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097 150)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640047">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
