<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="683734" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India, Pakistan keep focus on peace.</title>
<headline>India, Pakistan keep focus on peace.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>India on Tuesday rallied behind an agenda for peace talks with Pakistan that analysts called a balanced commitment to ending half a century of enmity.</p>
<p>Foreign policy experts cautioned that the dialogue was in its nascent stages and no one was expecting a quick fix.</p>
<p>While both sides agreed at high-level talks in Islamabad that ended on Monday to tackle the thorniest issue, Kashmir, no mutually acceptable solution was yet on the horizon, they said.</p>
<p>But the diplomats' efforts won widespread backing, even from a leader of the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) which has long cast a jaundiced eye on talks with Pakistan.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in favour of continuing the dialogue,&quot; senior BJP member Krishan Lal Sharma told Reuters.</p>
<p>Asked if his party was upset that India had agreed to discuss Kashmir, Sharma said: &quot;We are not disappointed. There is no harm in it. There should be no precondition.&quot;</p>
<p>Newspapers were unanimously supportive of the decision by the two nations, which have fought three wars since 1947, to set up working groups to tackle all outstanding issues.</p>
<p>&quot;A Good Beginning&quot;, &quot;A New Beginning&quot;, &quot;A Hopeful Start&quot; read headlines.</p>
<p>The Hindu called it &quot;perhaps the best 50th birthday present that the two estranged neighbours in the subcontinent, India and Pakistan, can give each other&quot;.</p>
<p>The Pioneer said the agreement was &quot;a measure of the new maturity that suffuses the respective political establishments&quot;.</p>
<p>Analysts said that maturity was reflected in the handling of the Kashmir issue, the spark for two of the nations' three wars.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very clinical attempt to accommodate both sides' mutually intractable claims,&quot; said former foreign secretary J.N. Dixit, who led India's negotiating team at failed talks in 1994.</p>
<p>Those talks, like others in the past, broke down over Kashmir. Pakistan had wanted the two sides to make progress on resolving their competing claims over the Himalayan region before tackling other issues. India had balked at focusing exclusively on Kashmir and wanted an open-ended dialogue.</p>
<p>The joint statement was a compromise as it cited Jammu and Kashmir as a separate issue but listed other areas of concern to be addressed in working groups &quot;in an integrated manner&quot;.</p>
<p>Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif said it was the first time that India had recognised Kashmir as disputed. &quot;It is a major breakthrough in Indo-Pakistan relations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Indian analysts pointed out that Pakistan had agreed to discuss a range of other issues including peace and security -- shorthand for their military standoff -- terrorism, drug trafficking and economic cooperation.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan would interpret it as a concession, but to India it is an acknowledgement of the importance of Kashmir, peace and security, confidence-building, terrorism all put together,&quot; said Bhabani Sengupta, executive director of the Centre for Research on International Change.</p>
<p>&quot;That means Pakistan, too, has made a concession.&quot;</p>
<p>Sengupta said neither side had yet budged over Kashmir, which has been divided between the two since shortly after they won independence in 1947. &quot;It's going to be a long haul, but the fact we continue to talk is far more important than to expect results now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jasjit Singh, director of the Institute for Defence Studies and Analyses, said he expected both sides in coming months to zero in on side agreements, perhaps putting an end to a chilly military standoff on the Siachen glacier in the Himalayas.</p>
<p>The only foreseeable compromise on Kashmir, he said, was for both sides to accept the line of control that has split the region for nearly 50 years to become permanent border.</p>
<p>Sengupta and Singh discounted worries that political changes in either country could soon derail the peace initiative. More worrisome, according to Singh, was Pakistan's ailing economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan's stability, integrity and its strength are in our interest,&quot; Singh said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
