<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68383" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - September 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - September 20.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top stories from selected Singapore newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE STRAITS TIMES:</p>
<p>- South Korean troops shoot dead seven North Korean spies in separate gunbattles.</p>
<p>- Taiwan fails to win a UN seat and UN officials decline to accept a $160,000 &quot;political&quot; donation.</p>
<p>- United Engineers, the Goei family and Hong Joo Company top bidders in Urban Redevelopment Authority auction of five conservation shophouses.</p>
<p>- Sumitomo Corp admits losses from massive copper trading scandal at $2.6 billion from the original estimated $1.8 billion.</p>
<p>- Amcol Holdings will not report its interim results when normally due as ongoing investigations into company affairs have not been completed.</p>
<p>THE BUSINESS TIMES:</p>
<p>- Lippo Group's Riady family reassures shareholders of their commitment to the country and amend a controversial 900 billion rupiah restructuring plan.</p>
<p>- WTO ministerial meeting will not launch new round of world trade talks nor set target for achieving global free trade.</p>
<p>- Architect Albert Hong helps out businessman Oei Hong Leong against Sukamto Sia's hold in Hongkong-listed Sum Cheong International.</p>
<p>- City Developments and Centrepoint Properties Ltd may reap more compensation of about Singapore $55 million from the government's acqusition of their Woodlands sites.</p>
<p>- Developer Lim Kah Ngam is looking into possibility of redeveloping its Hotel Equatorial site and decides to revalue investment properties.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom 65-8703080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
