<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684090" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Beirut bank stocks jump as market heats up.</title>
<headline>Beirut bank stocks jump as market heats up.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most leading shares rose on the Beirut Stock Exchange on Tuesday and two banks hit record highs amid positive expectations of mid-year bank results.</p>
<p>The LIBX bank index rose 2.17 percent to 163.02. The LISPI general index rose 0.70 percent to 89.08 and the BLOM general index rose 0.82 percent to 931.28.</p>
<p>Market turnover was 189,860 shares for a value of $1,763,174 against 190,974 shares on Monday for a value of $1,731,180.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is heating up. There is a lot of demand on almost all shares. Activity is increasing and the market has really found direction,&quot; a broker who asked not to be identified said.</p>
<p>Banque Audi rose to a new record of $26 from $24.875 while its Global Depository Receipts traded at $27-$27.5 on the Luxembourg Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Banque Libanaise pour le Commerce also hit a record $18.875 from $18.5 and Bank of Beirut held steady at $4.</p>
<p>This brought the rise of Audi, BLC and BOB shares since their market debuts a few months ago to 73 percent, 68 percent and 84 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;With BOB, one can see fundamentals. As for BLC, it is moving slowly but positively. The gap between the prices of Audi and BLC in terms of price earnings ratio is becoming very big. BLC should be trading at $21,&quot; the broker told Reuters.</p>
<p>Solidere A rose to $10.375 from $10.25 while B were steady at $10.75. Demand for both shares on the first fixing totalled 350,469 shares against a supply of 98,591 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand on Solidere is increasing while supply is shrinking,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>The company's GDRs are trading at $15.5-$16 in London.</p>
<p>Of the four listed industrial firms, Ciments Libanais was unchanged at $1.2812 on trade of 25,000 shares.</p>
<p>- Beirut editorial  (9611)  745307  745308  602057</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
