<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684088" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>TUNISIA: Tunisia removes taxes on import of trucks.</title>
<headline>Tunisia removes taxes on import of trucks.</headline>
<dateline>TUNIS 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Tunisian government on Tuesday said that it has eliminated customs fees and VAT taxes, and cut paperwork on the import of trucks as part of its efforts to encourage investment in the sector.</p>
<p>A transport ministry report sent to Reuters said that import of commercial vehicles no longer required authorisation, and new standards on weight and length of vehicles, close to those of the European Union, adopted.</p>
<p>The government said legislation adapting road haulage to international standards was to be adopted soon by the Tunisian parliament.</p>
<p>Two thirds of Tunisia's trade is currently made via sea to Europe, the report said. In 1996, total traffic was 16 million tonnes, 10 million of which were with Europe, two million tonnes with Maghreb states, and four million tonnes with the rest of the world, it said.</p>
<p>The share of the 17 Tunisian international road hauliers was was only eight percent of the total, it added.</p>
<p>The report said that partnership between Tunisian operators and foreign investors was to be encouraged particularly now foreign investment is totally free in Tunisia, given the country's proximity to Europe and developing transport infrastructure.</p>
<p>&quot;International road transportation has a potential for a strong growth in Tunisia particularly that foreign and mainly European investment in the Tunisian industry such as textiles, leather and shoes, mechanical and electric components, develops a flow of trade exchanges,&quot; the report added.</p>
<p>Tunisia has bilateral road transport agreements with France, Italy, Britain, Switzerland, Belgium, Germany, Sweden, Portugal, Spain, Poland, Finland, Hungary, Austria, Egypt, Libya and Jordan.</p>
<p>Talks were going on for similar agreements with Algeria and Morocco.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUNIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TUNISIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
