<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68406" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Margin loan concerns seen weighing on Seoul bourse.</title>
<headline>Margin loan concerns seen weighing on Seoul bourse.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Persistent concerns about an overhang of huge margin loans are expected to pressure the Seoul stock market throughout Friday, and brokers said large-caps would lead the index fall.</p>
<p>&quot;Possible heavy selling from margin account holders will continue to cast a gloom on the market. Without fresh money flowing into the market, consolidation will centre in large-cap shares,&quot; said Kim Wan-hee of Dongsuh Securities.</p>
<p>But brokers said selective small-caps would be in demand.</p>
<p>The composite stock index closed on Thursday 8.95 points lower to 773.15.  </p>
<p>Brokers said selling from margin accounts would focus on shares of electric and electronics, banks, construction and securities houses.</p>
<p>But they said North Korean infiltration drama would have no significant impact on the market.</p>
<p>A North Korean infiltrator signalled he was ready to surrender after a fierce gunbattle with South troops on Friday. So far 18 of about 20 North Korean agents have been shot dead and one was captured alive.</p>
<p>-- YEOM YOON-JEONG (822) 72 75647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
