<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684148" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. House set to vote on China trade relations.</title>
<headline>U.S. House set to vote on China trade relations.</headline>
<byline>Donna Smith</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>- On the eve of a House of Representatives vote on China's most favored nation trade status, supporters made a last-minute push on Monday to persuade lawmakers to retain normal trade ties with Beijing.</p>
<p>The full House is set to vote on Tuesday on a resolution sponsored by Rep. Gerald Solomon, a New York Republican, that would overturn President Bill Clinton's decision to renew normal trade relations with China for another year. Advocates of maintaining China's MFN status said they believed lawmakers would back the president.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we're going to prevail, and we are going to continue with MFN for China, which is the appropriate thing to do so that we can continue to have some influence on moving China in the right direction in the years ahead,&quot; Bill Archer, the Texas Republican who chairs the House Ways and Means Committee, told reporters on Monday.</p>
<p>Administration officials have said they are optimistic lawmakers will support MFN. But the White House was taking no chances, making a final appeal to lawmakers by releasing statements of support from past Presidents George Bush, Gerald Ford and Jimmy Carter.</p>
<p>The ex-presidents acknowledged that Washington had differences with China on a number of issues but argued that revoking MFN was not in the interest of the United States and said such a move could backfire.</p>
<p>&quot;Witholding MFN is not a sensible approach to resolving our differences,&quot; Bush wrote to Clinton. &quot;Quite the contrary, I am convinced that withholding MFN, or even conditioning its application to China, would be severely counterproductive.&quot;</p>
<p>Former Secretaries of State George Shultz, Lawrence Eagleburger, Alexander Haig, James Baker, Henry Kissinger and Cyrus Vance made a similar argument.</p>
<p>&quot;MFN revocation would effectively cut off trade between our two countries and thereby deal a devastating blow to our overall relationship,&quot; they wrote. &quot;It would undermine the progress we have made working with China on critical issues, from stability on the Korean Peninsula to stemming the flow of illegal aliens and narcotics.&quot;</p>
<p>Ten former secretaries of defense also pleaded for MFN and engagement.</p>
<p>And U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky issued a statement saying she welcomed the fact that China last week began importing U.S. sweet cherries for the first time.</p>
<p>&quot;China's importation of sweet cherries is a hopeful step in our ongoing efforts to increase market access for U.S. agriculture exports,&quot; Barshefsky said. The first shipment of cherries arrived in China from Washington state on June 20.</p>
<p>Under U.S. law, the president must decide each year whether to grant China MFN, and Congress has the right to disapprove his decision. Without MFN, duties on imports from China would soar to an average of 44 percent from a current level of about 6 percent. Most favored nation status is enjoyed by almost every other country.</p>
<p>Some members of Congress have been reconsidering support for MFN because of reports of Chinese human rights abuses, nuclear technology and missile transfers, and allegations that Beijing tried to influence U.S. elections by illegal campaign contributions. Lawmakers have also expressed concern about the fate of Hong Kong after it returns to Chinese rule on July 1.</p>
<p>Opponents of MFN made final appeals too.</p>
<p>&quot;The truth is America has dedicated over two decades to the policies of engagement and the results have been far from compelling,&quot; Sen. John Aschcroft, a Republican from Missouri, said. He said China closed its markets to U.S. goods while the United States took in more than 30 percent of China's exports, creating a trade deficit of almost $40 billion last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
