<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684436" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - Copper to face resistance, seen lower.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Copper to face resistance, seen lower.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p> 3 MONTH     CLOSE  * SUPPORT * RESIST * RSI14 * MA10 * MA30</p>
<p> COPPER     2509/12 *  2465   *  2600  *  49   * 2567 * 2512</p>
<p> ALUMINIUM  1588/90 *  1565   *  1600  *  43   * 1595 * 1619</p>
<p>---------------VIEWS FROM THE MARKET - June 24-----------------</p>
<p>Copper faces resistance above $2,500 a tonne after Monday's downside correction and is vulnerable to test support around $2,465, traders and chart-watchers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Aluminium after an upside chart close on Monday may probe higher levels, though market operators will closely monitor the movements of copper.  </p>
<p>COPPER - The technical picture has been damaged by the downside move on Monday and prices could now move towards support at $2,460/65 a tonne, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;With the technical indicators crossing down out of the overbought region in line with the market's downward break look for further underlying tests of support below $2,500,&quot; Martin Squires of LME brokers Rudolf Wolff said. Squires pegged his initial downside target at $2,460.</p>
<p>Harry Creates of Amalgamated Metal Trading (AMT) said if $2,485 fails to hold falls to $2,461 and $2,445 could be seen.</p>
<p>On the upside first resistance is expected at $2,525.</p>
<p>&quot;On the upside a close above $2,535 is needed to relieve downward pressure and target the April uptrend at $2,550,&quot; Creates said.</p>
<p>At 0700 GMT three months LME copper was quoted at $2,508/13, little changed from Monday's late London close of $2,509/12.</p>
<p>ALUMINIUM - An upside chart close on Monday could see prices move towards resistance at $1,600 a tonne, though any aggressive downside moves in copper could easily dent sentiment, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;A positive close on the chart, with the appearance of a bullish engulfing pattern suggesting a move higher,&quot; LME brokers Brandies said.</p>
<p>&quot;The technical indicators have picked up as we look to strike higher to target $1,600/10 resistance,&quot; Squires of Rudolf Wolff said.</p>
<p>On the downside support is expected at $1,575 and a fanline around $1,568.</p>
<p>At 0700 GMT three months aluminium was quoted at $1,587/90, versus $1,588/90.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542-8075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
