<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684524" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia gas industry blasts new competition code.</title>
<headline>Australia gas industry blasts new competition code.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's gas industry on Tuesday attacked a new competition code being prepared for the nation's emerging gas market as a threat to profitability.</p>
<p>On the eve of a landmark meeting of gas-market players on Wednesday to sign off on a draft code, the Australian Gas Association (AGA) said the new document was in some ways worse than an original draft released eight months ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We think 'Mark II' as it stands, yes, is a major infringement of the industry's property rights and earnings capacity,&quot; AGA chairman Greg Harvey told Reuters.  </p>
<p>&quot;That's where we think the present draft has gone backwards,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The code seeks to set up a regulatory framework which allows gas to be traded freely and fairly via Australia's gas pipelines, most of which are owned by private-sector operators.</p>
<p>The code was to have been finalised by mid-1996, but gas producers, distributers and users, as well as state and national governments, have failed to reach complete agreement, stalling progress toward the goal of a national spot market in gas.</p>
<p>The original draft code, released in September, was rejected by the AGA as heavy handed and sent back to the drawing board.  </p>
<p>The AGA, which represents gas producers and the big ulitities which own gas piplines, said the original code handed too much power over access arrangements to regulators.</p>
<p>The AGA's Harvey, who is a member of the official Gas Reform Implementation Group overseeing the code's development, on Tuesday said he had similar criticisms of the latest draft.</p>
<p>&quot;It's our assets that are on the chopping block,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The question really revolves around what matters the regulator should be allowed to take into account in determining values and reference tariff rates,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>A source close to the official reform group's discussions said that, unlike the original draft code, the new draft seeks to establish access tariffs via a competitive bidding process.</p>
<p>But Harvey said regulators were still in ultimate control of access arrangements under the new draft code.</p>
<p>&quot;Our concern is that in trying to speed up the process, insufficient attention is being given to the fundamentals of this whole third-party-access process...,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are finding the powers of the regulator enshrined in a way the industry finds very disturbing.&quot;  </p>
<p>The gas reform group has set itself a new timetable of end-1997 for the implementation of the code, an essential step before a truly competitive gas market can develop in Australia.</p>
<p>The group plans to publish the code for public comment and consultation from late next week, but a gas industry source said it was unlikely the code would succeed without AGA support.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the code has been agreed by the group,&quot; the source said. &quot;There are a few areas that still haven't been resolved. Tomorrow's meeting will hopefully resolve these.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-3 9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
