<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684736" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China seen on track for 10 pct GDP growth in 1997.</title>
<headline>China seen on track for 10 pct GDP growth in 1997.</headline>
<byline>Bill Savadove</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>China is on track for gross domestic product (GDP) growth of at least 10 percent in 1997, well over the official target of eight percent, but there is no cause for alarm, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>High economic growth meets Beijing's political agenda and will be matched by low inflation, so there is little danger of overheating, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;This year is a special year due to the return of Hong Kong and the party congress, so 10 percent is good,&quot; said Liao Quan, senior economist for Standard Chartered Bank in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>The British colony of Hong Kong reverts to Chinese rule at midnight on June 30 and Beijing wants to showcase to the world a powerful country with a booming economy.</p>
<p>The Communist Party of China will also hold a major meeting late in the year -- the first such gathering since the death of Deng Xiaoping -- which it hopes will mark the late leader's legacy with a rosy economic picture. With the end of the first half drawing near, analysts are predicting GDP growth of between nine and 10 percent for the first six months of 1997, in line with forecasts.</p>
<p>But the economy will receive a boost later in 1997 from expected easier credit, which could push the year-on-year growth in GDP to over 10 percent for the second half and the whole year, they said.</p>
<p>China's GDP rose 9.4 percent in the first quarter of 1997 compared with 9.7 percent for all of 1996. The official target for 1997 is eight percent as part of a campaign to cool an economy showing signs of overheating.</p>
<p>&quot;China has a track record of underestimating growth,&quot; said Kevin Chan, assistant director of research for ING Barings in Hong Kong. &quot;The official number is a symbolic number.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;People see around nine percent (for 1997) as an optimal number, especially now as you have low inflation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Beijing is scheduled to announce economic indicators for the first half on July 18, a State Statistical Bureau official told Reuters. He declined to give official targets.</p>
<p>But the bureau's chief economist, Qiu Xiaohua, in April forecast GDP growth of 9.5 percent for the first half year and 10 percent for all of 1997.</p>
<p>The main force driving the economy in the first half was export growth, analysts said. China posted a trade surplus of $13.92 billion in the January-May period, with exports soaring 26.4 percent on the year to $65.48 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is expecting a stronger second half based on credit easing,&quot; Chan said. &quot;Everything is pointing toward easing credit in China, but the main obstacle is the stock market.&quot;</p>
<p>Low inflation has fuelled expecations China's central bank will ease credit in the second half, either through a cut in the bank reserve ratio or a reduction in interest rates.</p>
<p>China's retail prices rose 0.8 percent in May compared with the same month in 1996, while consumer prices rose 2.8 percent.</p>
<p>Government worries that the fledgling stock markets are racing out of control could delay credit easing, due to fears money would pour back into shares, analysts said.</p>
<p>But pressure from state enterprises and listed companies starved for cash would add impetus for the government to ease credit, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government set the prime target (for GDP) at eight percent but actually they are expecting higher than that,&quot; said Standard Chartered's Liao. &quot;Even if growth is higher there's no threat of inflation.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
