<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684819" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs higher by noon on talk of weak tankan.</title>
<headline>JGBs higher by noon on talk of weak tankan.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cash JGBs and futures rose by Tokyo noon on Tuesday on speculation that the Bank of Japan's &quot;tankan&quot; corporate sentiment survey would provide further signs that Japan's economic recovery may be faltering, traders said.</p>
<p>The key September was at 124.11 at midday, up from 123.91 on Monday.</p>
<p>The September rose to a high of 124.30 on widespread talk that a senior BOJ official had suggested in a closed meeting with some Japanese bank managers on Monday that the tankan results would be weak, traders said.  </p>
<p>There was also talk that a long-term bank, which may have attended the meeting with the BOJ official, received a large amount of seven-year interest rate swaps.</p>
<p>This appears to have induced buying of JGB futures for hedge purposes by traders who paid seven-year swaps.</p>
<p>In early trade, JGBs were also buoyed by talk that JP Morgan, which had previously made optimistic forecast for the tankan, revised it down, traders said.</p>
<p>JP Morgan's chief economist in Tokyo, Jesper Koll, told Reuters on Tuesday that he had not revised a forecast of plus four for the tankan's manufacturers' diffusion index.  </p>
<p>The yield of the benchmark 182nd 10-year JGB was at 2.370 percent, down from Monday's 2.390 percent.</p>
<p>The fall in Tokyo stocks following the overnight tumble on Wall Street also helped JGB prices.</p>
<p>-- Yoshiko Mori, Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-8676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
