<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="684898" id="root" date="1997-06-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: FEATURE - Arafat's PLO under fire for election delay.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Arafat's PLO under fire for election delay.</headline>
<byline>Daniel Sternoff</byline>
<dateline>GAZA 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Islamist editor Ghazi Hamad reached into his pocket and unfolded a crisp document stamped with the Palestinian Authority letterhead -- a &quot;secret plan&quot; to undermine the Islamic opposition to President Yasser Arafat.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a secret plan of the Authority, a report sent to Arafat,&quot; the plain-talking Hamad told Reuters in the tidy offices of al-Risala, an Islamist opposition newspaper in the PLO-ruled Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>For Hamad, the report is proof that Arafat's recent delay of long-awaited local elections reinforces a fear that support for the Islamist opposition group Hamas is rising at his expense.</p>
<p>&quot;It is from the security apparatus about how they can succeed in preventing Hamas from participating or winning in local elections,&quot; Hamad said.</p>
<p>The Palestinian Authority (PA) said in June it would delay elections for 374 municipal and village councils in the West Bank and Gaza that were due in August -- the first such polls to pit Hamas against Arafat's ruling Fatah faction.</p>
<p>The last local elections were held more than two decades ago under Israeli occupation.</p>
<p>The delay of the polls -- earlier postponed last October -- has raised charges of electoral manipulation.</p>
<p>CONFIDENT HAMAS TO RUN IN LOCAL POLLS</p>
<p>Hamas boycotted the first Palestinian Legislative Council elections in January 1996 in protest against the Israel-PLO peace deal which formed the self-rule parliament. The result: Fatah scooped up threequarters of the council's 88 seats.</p>
<p>But Hamas has announced it would field candidates in the municipal polls, seeing them as a means to deliver public services and strengthen grassroots Islamic social institutions.</p>
<p>Judging by the results of recent student and professional elections in the West Bank and Gaza -- barometers of Palestinian political winds given all-faction participation -- the electoral battlefield is nearly even between Hamas and Fatah.</p>
<p>The Palestinian economy has been mired in a deep three-year depression and Palestinian opinion polls reflect rising outrage over reports of corruption and misuse of public funds.</p>
<p>For Hamad, the &quot;secret report&quot; which he said contained a smear campaign warning that an Islamist victory would lead to Algerian-style chaos, is proof that the Palestinian Authority (PA) is running scared.</p>
<p>&quot;Arafat is now facing political troubles because the peace process is dead. The Palestinian people mistrust the Authority and the peace process. He is afraid that with all the talk about corruption in the PA, people will not support them,&quot; Hamad said.</p>
<p>Outside Hamad's window in Gaza's Qarqash quarter hangs a mural depicting a fountain pen waving a bold green banner emblazoned with the Moslem declaration of faith -- &quot;There is no God but Allah&quot; -- in black Arabic calligraphy.</p>
<p>CHARGES PLO SEEKS TO BOLSTER POWER, NOT DEMOCRACY</p>
<p>PA local government minister Saeb Erekat blamed Israel for the delay in the elections, saying polls would not be held until Israel completed phased troop withdrawals from rural areas of the West Bank, slated to end in mid-1998.</p>
<p>Israel has not implemented the first of three phased redeployments, due in March under an Israel-PLO peace deal. The PA, expecting to take control of some 30 percent of the West Bank, rejected Israel's offer of less than a tenth of the area.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't take the risk of holding elections under occupation and our local elections are the first in Palestinian history under Palestinian rule,&quot; Erekat said.</p>
<p>Most West Bank Palestinian villages lie in areas under Israeli security rule and Palestinian civil jurisdiction. With Israel-PLO peace moves in paralysis, a question mark now hangs over the gradual transfer of these areas to full PLO control.</p>
<p>Independent lawmakers and leftist factions back Islamist charges that the PA is more interested in maintaining power than in bolstering Palestinian democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;The incumbent regime would like to take it easy and be careful. I don't think it wants to willingly enable the opposition group to prevail,&quot; said Gaza lawmaker Ziad Abu Amr.</p>
<p>&quot;I suspect the executive Authority will choose a time that is quite amenable to its prospects,&quot; Abu Amr said, noting that council elections had also been delayed until after PLO police replaced Israeli troops in most West Bank cities.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to counter-balance this by some ruling law that these municipal elections cannot be manipulated to the interest of some group or another.&quot;</p>
<p>APPOINTMENT, NOT POLLS</p>
<p>The PA argues that elected municipal councils would be toothless and that planning and zoning would be impossible without having full control of surrounding lands -- a fair argument, critics concede.</p>
<p>In the meantime the local government ministry has been forming &quot;temporary&quot; local councils by fiat rather than by the ballot.</p>
<p>&quot;This year was supposed to be the year of local elections and instead they are forming new municipalities,&quot; Gaza lawmaker Raywa Shawwa told Reuters. &quot;I am afraid that they are hiding something.&quot;</p>
<p>Abu Amr said the interim local councils were designed as vehicles for dishing out political perks.</p>
<p>&quot;They are formed to establish some credibility and networking which would enhance their (the PA's) prospects in future elections,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>PA officials reject the charges. &quot;These are temporary councils...they will all vanish when we have elections,&quot; said Hazem Abu Shanab of the local government ministry in Gaza.</p>
<p>Lawmakers fighting to deepen democratic norms are impatient.</p>
<p>&quot;We know the world is ignoring our rights but we also know something wrong is going on. I don't want to blame the Authority but we need things to be better,&quot; Shawwa said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
