<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68522" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks mixed in early trading.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks mixed in early trading.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks opened firm but quickly retreated on Friday morning, as investors remained hesitant to push the market higher ahead of the weekend and next week's U.S. Federal Open Market Committee Meeting, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone's waiting for the FOMC meeting,&quot; said Gary Wong, sales director at Vickers Ballas. &quot;The bond market's giving mixed signals, and so are economic data reports.&quot;</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index put on nearly 40 points at the opening, but soon turned down to trade 12.31 points lower at 11,574.37 in early morning. Turnover was HK$899 million after 45 minutes</p>
<p>The market opened higher after HSBC Holdings, which is listed on both the Hong Kong and London exchanges, traded as high as 12.12 stg in London overnight after closing in Hong Kong on Thursday at HK$140.50.</p>
<p>&quot;That's a new high for HSBC&quot;, said a local broker. The share's record high to date is HK$142.00, set earlier this week. HSBC was up HK$0.50 at HK$141 in early trade.</p>
<p>Despite the hesitation before the FOMC and the profit-taking following recent gains, brokers remained bullish.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is preparing to go up,&quot; the local broker said. &quot;There is limited downside.&quot;</p>
<p>The FOMC meeting, the Federal Reserve's policy-setting meeting, is scheduled for Tuesday, September 24.  A Reuter's survey of 30 U.S. based economists revealed that 17 believed the Fed would raise rates in September.</p>
<p>Despite investor caution, the interest-rate sensitive finance sector was leading the market with an advance of 0.25 percent on the back of HSBC shares, compared with a decline of 0.20 percent for the Hang Seng.</p>
<p>HSBC subsidiary Hang Seng Bank was down HK$0.25 to HK$79.25, while Bank of East Asia rose HK$0.10 to HK$28.60.</p>
<p>&quot;For continued (finance) sector outperformance, we need Hang Seng Bank and or Bank of East Asia to make new highs,&quot; said John Schofield, regional technical analyst at Nava SC Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;There was good early interest in laggards in the utility sector, particularly China Light and Hong Kong Telecom, said Wong.</p>
<p>China Light continued a week-long rally, putting on HK$0.20 to HK$35.60, while Hong Kong Telecom eased HK$0.10 to HK$13.25 on thin turnover of HK$23.6 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
