<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68523" id="root" date="1996-09-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan parliament likely to be dissolved on Sept 27.</title>
<headline>Japan parliament likely to be dissolved on Sept 27.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's parliament is likely to be dissolved on September 27, Minister of International Trade and Industry Shunpei Tsukahara told reporters on Friday.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto agreed on Thursday with the leaders of the two junior parties in his ruling coalition to convene an extraordinary session of parliament on September 27, which was widely expected to lead to an early general election.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is very probable that the parliament will be dissolved (at the beginning of the session),&quot; Tsukahara said.</p>
<p>Politicians, in frequent leaks to the media over the past two weeks, have said Hashimoto would dissolve parliament on the first day of the session and hold general elections on October 20.</p>
<p>Most observers say the prime minister, who has the sole right to dissolve parliament, is balancing competing demands from his Liberal Democratic Party, which is keen on early polls, and its coalition partners, who want to put off elections until next year.</p>
<p>Polls are not mandated until July 1997, but the LDP favours going before voters as early as possible before April, when an unpopular rise in the consumption tax, approved by the Hashimoto government, takes effect.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
