<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="685243" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: SOCCER-JAPAN HEAD FOR PLACE IN FINAL ASIAN ROUND.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JAPAN HEAD FOR PLACE IN FINAL ASIAN ROUND.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Barring an unlikely 10-goal defeat in their last first-round match, Japan clinched a place in the final round of the Asian qualifying competition for next year's World Cup finals when they beat Nepal 3-0 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Two goals from striker Kazuyoshi Miura and one from Akinori Nishizawa gave Japan their fifth successive group four victory to take them on to a maximum 15 points and a goal tally of 30-0.</p>
<p>The only factor that would stop their progress would be a highly-unlikely defeat by 10 or more goals to second-placed Oman in their final qualifier on Saturday.</p>
<p>Oman, who beat Macao 2-0 on Wednesday, have 12 points from five matches and a goal tally of 13-1. Their only defeat was a 1-0 loss to Japan.</p>
<p>Nishizawa set Japan on their way to victory when he scored just before halftime, knocking in a rebound after a goalmouth scramble. Japan had to wait until the 73rd minute to increase their lead when Miura, who scored six goals in Sunday's game against Macao, curled in a free kick from outside the penalty area.</p>
<p>In the 87th minute, Miura scored a second, his 50th goal for Japan.</p>
<p>Oman kept alive the faintest of mathematical possibilities of reaching the final round with their 2-0 win over Macao, who have twice been beaten 10-0 by Japan during the series.</p>
<p>Mohamed Al Araimi and Ahmed Ali Hassan scored a goal each towards the end of each half respectively after Macao defender Iong Kin Chong was sent off for violent play after just 12 minutes.</p>
<p>Only the group winner will advance to the 10-nation final round to be held in late October and early November for three berths in next year's World Cup finals in France.</p>
<p>Asia's fourth-place finisher will move to a playoff match with the Oceania zone winner, either Australia or New Zealand, for a possible fourth berth in the finals.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NEPAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
