<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="685422" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: G20 clearing bank planners see room for FX niches.</title>
<headline>G20 clearing bank planners see room for FX niches.</headline>
<byline>Adam Cox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>- The designers of a planned global bank to settle deals in the $1.2 trillion per day currency market believe their system can work side by side with other practices in the market, project planners told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A group of major banks, known as the Group of 20 (G20), is expected to issue a statement towards the end of the week, unveiling what some believe will be plans for a global settlement bank.</p>
<p>While London bankers have identified a number of hurdles for the project, one G20 banking source said the new system could work along with other practices such as bilateral and multilateral netting or with potential niche areas such as settling for differences rather than total cash transactions.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be forex trades that have to be settled and the best way will be CLS (Continuous Linked Settlements),&quot; the banker said.</p>
<p>Continuous Linked Settlements, a system which the G20 is proposing to handle currency trades, is effectively a method whereby deals are concluded when payments on both sides are simultaneously made.</p>
<p>The G20, formed in 1994, includes ABN Amro, Bank of America, Bankers Trust, Barclays Bank, Banque Nationale de Paris, Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi, Chase, CIBC, Citibank, Credit Suisse, Deutsche Bank, Dresdner Bank Fuji Bank, HSBC Holdings, J.P. Morgan, National Westminster, Royal Bank of Canada, Swiss Bank Corp, Societe Generale and UBS.</p>
<p>On a global scale, advocates say CLS would eliminate settlement risk, the type of risk that gives central bankers nightmares.</p>
<p>It is also often known as systemic risk or &quot;Herstatt risk&quot; after German bank Bankhaus Herstatt was shut down in 1974 and caused gridlock in the forex market due to uncompleted payments.</p>
<p>Recent years have seen the development of systems for netting foreign exchange settlement risk.</p>
<p>Exchange Clearing House (Echo), created by a group of European banks, and Multinet in the U.S. operate netting systems which group foreign exchange deals and arrive at net amounts, either bilaterally or multilaterally.</p>
<p>Some 90 percent of the currency market is estimated to be done for position rather than for banks to actually have the funds on hand. So another new practice could be a &quot;contract for differences&quot;.</p>
<p>This would be where banks agree on a means of trading only the difference in value between two amounts, each in a different currency, rather than trading the full amounts. Bankers say creating such a system has complications of its own, such as the need to establish benchmark market indices and to overcome differences in legal practices in various countries.</p>
<p>While such systems can reduce the net risk in deals, the G20 system is based on the idea of retaining currency settlements but eliminating the inherent risks by making them instantaneous.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the development of netting and similar practices) doesn't eliminate the real need for cash to move from some parties to others,&quot; the G20 banker said.</p>
<p>He refuted comments from some bankers that costs of the G20 system were rising or would be expensive. He added that those involved in the project were probably discussing it at the highest levels at their banks. &quot;I'd be surprised if this hasn't gone to the chairman or the board at every institution.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 6784</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
