<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="685440" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks resist Dow's drop to close mixed.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks resist Dow's drop to close mixed.</headline>
<byline>Lydia Zajc</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto's stock market closed mixed on Wednesday, but avoided Wall Street's 68-point drop, aided by strength in the heavyweight gold and banking sectors.</p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange's key 300 Composite Index added 24.12 points to reach 6515.08. But falling issues edged out rising ones 517 to 483, while 296 finished flat.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell 68.08 points to end at 7689.98.</p>
<p>Fred Ketchen, director of equity trading at ScotiaMcLeod, said Toronto was buoyed by rising corporate profits and takeover moves. Two of Canada's largest banks surprised investors on Tuesday with takeover interest in trust and insurance companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks chugged ahead yet again,&quot; Ketchen said.</p>
<p>The influential gold sector also benefited from a possible reversal in gold bullion prices, which may have hit bottom after months of losing ground, Ketchen added.</p>
<p>Toronto's 14 sub-indexes were split evenly between winners and losers. Declining groups were led by consumer products, transportation and base metals.</p>
<p>Golds and banks added more than 1 percent each.</p>
<p>Trading was robust with 102 million shares changing hands, worth C$2.2 billion ($1.58 billion).</p>
<p>In individual issues, Bank of Nova Scotia extended Tuesday's surge, adding 1.65 to a 52-week high of 61.70.</p>
<p>Rating agency Standard &amp; Poor's affirmed the ratings of Canada's fourth largest bank on Wednesday after Tuesday's news that it offered to acquire National Trustco Inc. in a C$1.25 billion ($899 million) cash and stock deal.</p>
<p>National Trustco-related firms E-L Financial Corp. and Economic Investment Trust Ltd. soared. E-L Financial jumped 35 to 210 and Economic Investment rose 9 to 109, both in light trading.</p>
<p>Royal Bank of Canada slipped 0.05 to 63.10. Canada's largest financial institution is in takeover talks with London Insurance Group, whose shares rose 1.15 to 27.45.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
