<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="685569" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary BUX jumps to 3rd high in a row.</title>
<headline>Hungary BUX jumps to 3rd high in a row.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>1125 GMT - The BUX index soared to a third successive closing high of 6,779.59 points, up 182.31 points or 2.76 percent, according to preliminary figures.</p>
<p>* Nineteen stocks ended higher, eleven lower and nine steady.</p>
<p>* Volume of traded stocks and compensation coupons amounted to 2,964,617 units.</p>
<p>A bull run on the Budapest Stock Exchange, fuelled by benign macroeconomic news, gained momentum on Wednesday and drove the BUX index to a third successive record high, traders said.</p>
<p>The index finished at a preliminary 6,779.59 points, up 182.31 points or 2.76 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly Tuesday's good news, the reduction of monthly crawling peg devaluation to one percent (from 1.1 percent from August 15) and Hungary's upgrading, is behind the rally,&quot; said Andrea Keresztesi of ABN-AMRO Hoare Govett.</p>
<p>Investor appetite pushed several leading stocks to new record highs.</p>
<p>Among them were the highest capitalised oil and gas company MOL which surged to 4,350 forints before closing at 4,335, up 245; OTP Bank which rallied to 4,955 forints before closing at 4,900, up 220; and the two chemicals, TVK and BorsodChem.</p>
<p>Traders said MOL was apparently benefiting from Monday's announcement raising quarterly wholesale gas prices by 13.5 percent.</p>
<p>Keresztesi and other traders earlier said fresh foreign capital seemed to have come into the country.</p>
<p>Final turnover figures were not yet available but it was outstanding, partly bolstered by position closing on the futures market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think many investors closed positions, buying BUX futures back and selling stocks,&quot; Keresztesi said. Position closings bolstered turnover and reduced prices only temporarily.</p>
<p>Last prices in BUX futures were above Tuesday's settlement prices, with September BUX closing at 6,990 points, compared to Tuesday's settlement price of 6,855.</p>
<p>One trader said some profit-takings would be a logical step for Thursday's session but seeing unsatisfied demand this was not sure to happen.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
