<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="685539" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Sasani leaps after headline EPS in profit.</title>
<headline>Sasani leaps after headline EPS in profit.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in South African entertainment firm Sasani jumped over 12 percent in early trade following the release of 12 month results showing headline earnings bouncing into profit.</p>
<p>Sasani shares hit an early high of 128 cents. By 0745 GMT shares had tipped off their highs to 118 cents -- a gain of four cents or 3.5 percent making them one of the biggest percentage early gainers on the Johannesburg bourse.</p>
<p>Volumes were high at 468,400 shares traded.  </p>
<p>&quot;It on the back of the results,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Sasani earlier reported headline earnings per share for the 12 months ended March 31, at 3.4 cents profit from a 2.2 cent loss a year ago.</p>
<p>The entertainment and communication group earlier this month bought local advertising agency Msomi Hunt Lascaris for an undisclosed sum.</p>
<p>Sasani has changed its year end from March 31 to June 30 following the acquisition of the Video Lab and The Movie Camera Company which both have years ending on June 30. Next published results will cover the 15-month period ending June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
