<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="685644" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania's wheat crop, exports unchanged - official.</title>
<headline>Romania's wheat crop, exports unchanged - official.</headline>
<dateline>FUNDULEA, Romania 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania still hopes to bring in 7.07 million tonnes of wheat this year, up from last year's 3.1 million, and to export 2.4 million tonnes, despite damage to crops by storms, an official said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true that the rains caused serious damage to the grain crops. But we still count on a wheat crop of 7.07 million tonnes, as announced previously,&quot; Adorian Kovacs, State Secretary at the Agriculture Ministry, told Reuters on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Kovacs made the remarks after a conference marking the start of harvesting.</p>
<p>On Monday, the ministry said heavy rain, hail and floods damaged wheat and maize on almost 100,000 hectares last week. The bad weather came shortly after it forecast the wheat crop at 7.07 million tonnes, down from a previous eight million tonne estimate but more than double last year's 3.1 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Actually, when we made the forecast for 7.07 million tonnes we had in mind some possible losses due to bad weather,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kovacs said the export estimate of 2.4 million tonnes had not been revised. &quot;If the weather stays fine we can harvest the wheat crop without problems. I think Romania could export up to 2.4 million tonnes this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said getting in the crop would not be hampered by the chronic shortage of combine harvesters. The ministry has signed agreements with private and state farms in border regions with Hungary, Ukraine and Moldova to hire combines to speed up harvesting and avoid losses.</p>
<p>Last year, Romania had a poor wheat crop of some 3.1 million tonnes due to bad weather and a late winter. In 1995 it harvested a bumper crop of 7.8 million tonnes and sold about 1.3 million. --Adrian Dascalu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FUNDULEA, Romania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
