<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68575" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-NEW BOY BERGER THE HERO AS LIVERPOOL TROUNCE CHELSEA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-NEW BOY BERGER THE HERO AS LIVERPOOL TROUNCE CHELSEA.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>English league leaders Liverpool thrashed previously unbeaten Chelsea 5-1 in a top-of-the-table match at Anfield on Saturday with a display which confirmed them as true championship contenders.</p>
<p>Two outstanding goals from new Czech striker Patrik Berger, who took his tally to six in a week, highlighted a rampant Liverpool performance.</p>
<p>Berger scored twice after coming on as a substitute against Leicester last week and two more for the Czech Republic in midweek.</p>
<p>He struck twice in seven minutes on either side of halftime as Liverpool ran riot against Ruud Gullit's team, who started the day in third place.</p>
<p>Robbie Fowler (15), Andy Myers (44 own goal) and John Barnes (57) added the others as Liverpool, who have not won the title since their record 18th success in 1990, stayed top.</p>
<p>Frenchman Frank LeBouef scored a consolation for Chelsea with an 85th minute penalty.</p>
<p>Newcastle moved into second place, two points behind, after winning 1-0 at Leeds United thanks to a 59th minute goal from Alan Shearer. </p>
<p>The result left news Leeds manager George Graham beaten for the second time in his two matches in charge. Leeds had a miserable afternoon with former England defender Carlton Palmer sent off after 30 minutes.</p>
<p>Arsenal went third with a 2-0 win at Middlesbrough. The goals came from John Hartson in the third minute and Ian Wright, who netted his 101st league goal for the Gunners after 27 minutes.</p>
<p>Defending champions Manchester United, who started the day in second place, slipped down the table after drawing 0-0 at Aston Villa.</p>
<p>West Ham won 2-0 at Nottingham Forest despite having Swiss defender Marc Reiper sent off. Sunderland beat Coventry 1-0 and Sheffield Wednesday drew 0-0 with Derby.</p>
<p>Bottom-of-the-table Blackburn drew 1-1 with Everton, who had Scottish striker Duncan Ferguson sent off after 88 minutes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
