<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="685874" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOWARD SUGGESTS APEC LEADERS TACKLE UNEMPLOYMENT</p>
<p>The Prime Minister, John Howard, has raised the prospect of Asia-Pacific leaders tackling the issue of unemployment at their annual meetings. In his talks with U-S President Bill Clinton later this week, Mr Howard will be discussing strategies for the Asia-Pacific Cooperation Forum meeting to be held towards the end of the year.</p>
<p>Mr Howard has told ABC radio he wants future APEC meetings to focus on common challenges, such as infrastructure development. </p>
<p>He suggests future meetings discuss common employment challenges and the flexibility of financial markets within APEC.</p>
<p>&quot;All of these things are ones on which the member states of APEC have common experiences to pool,&quot; Mr Howard said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HOWARD TOUGHENS STANCE ON UNIFORM GREENHOUSE EMISSIONS</p>
<p>The Prime Minister, John Howard, has toughened his stance on uniform greenhouse gas emission targets even further, declaring there will be no compromise from Australia. </p>
<p>Australia is refusing to support the targets despite pressure from Britain, with Mr Howard warning uniform targets would damage the economy and lead to cuts in wages.</p>
<p>The rift on the issue between the two countries has widened, although they have agreed discussions will continue.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister is expected to face similar pressure from the United States to accept some form of common target.</p>
<p>Mr Howard says Australia's national interest will be damaged if it goes along with what the Europeans, in particular, are arguing for. </p>
<p>&quot;I will just continue to put Australia's case and if at the end of the day we are not successful in obtaining accommodation, the arrangement will not be something that we we can be part of,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PILOTS WORRIED ABOUT SAFETY OF MANY AUST AIRPORTS</p>
<p>The Australian Aircraft Owners and Pilots Association claims Air Services Australia changes could lead to serious accidents at airports throughout the country. </p>
<p>Important details about airstrips are being removed from documents which pilots are required to carry with them.</p>
<p>Rural and small airport owners throughout the country several years ago were given the option of de-licencing aerodromes to cut down on inspection costs.</p>
<p>Many took the opportunity.</p>
<p>But now Air Services Australia is dropping important details in the Enroute Suppliment Australia pilot guide which shows runway lengths and the type of surface.</p>
<p>Aircraft Owners and Pilots Association President, Boyd Munroe, says this seriously compromises safety. </p>
<p>Mr Munroe says pilots are compelled to carry the document whenever they fly and now the most important piece of information about an airfield has been taken out of it.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PORT ARTHUR TO MAKE A FRESH START FOLLOWING MASSACRE</p>
<p>After more than a year of turmoil, Port Arthur is to make a fresh start to recovery. </p>
<p>The bitterness in the Tasman community, suppressed since the massacre of 35 people in April last year, has surfaced in the report of the Tasmanian Government's Special Commisoner Max Doyle.</p>
<p>Much of the anger has been directed at the former board with allegations they were more concerned with limiting legal liability than the welfare of staff.</p>
<p>The report details allegations of financial conflicts of interest, mismanagement and staff harassment.</p>
<p>The board, most of whom have resigned already, will be replaced by four administrators. </p>
<p>There will be a comprehensive review of what the site needs, security concerns will be addressed and there's to be a special debriefing to help those affected by the shootings.</p>
<p>Mr Doyle also recommended a rehabilitation coordinator be appointed to help the recovery, and $250,000 be set aside for people in urgent need.</p>
<p>As well, the Director of Public Prosecutions will investigate why a slide door at the Broad Arrow Cafe, where 20 people were shot, could not be opened by people wanting to escape during the massacre. </p>
<p>Mr Doyle was told seven people who had attempted to flee through the door were shot.</p>
<p>Mr Doyle compared the massacre with the Vietnam War, with veterans after 30 years still affected by trauma.</p>
<p>The chairman of a Joint Parliamentary Committee and Tasmania's Tourism Minister, Ray Groom, has accepted the recommendations, saying the renewed discussion about the problems besetting Port Arthur should help the recovery.</p>
<p>The Chief executive officer of the Port Arthur Authority, Craig Coombes, says trying to attach blame through an inquiry into the door problem is pointless. </p>
<p>However Mr Doyle says he's merely responding to community demands.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>OPTUS SHELVES MOBILE PHONE BASES AFTER LEUKEMIA FEARS</p>
<p>Optus has decided to postpone a plan to erect two Mobiletelephone bases in Sydney's north, until new sites are selected.</p>
<p>Residents have told the Council they're concerned about possible links between leukemia in children and low level radiaiton from the bases. </p>
<p>Local residents have opposed the planned sites in North Sydney and Neutral Bay, since Optus first lodged its application with North Sydney Council.</p>
<p>The residents claim the communications carrier has been unable to guarantee the low level radiation emissions from the bases, are not linked with leukemia in young children.</p>
<p>North Sydney Mayor Genia McCaffery says the Council was particularly opposed to the North Sydney site because of it's proximity to schools and day care centres.</p>
<p>She says to gain Council's approval, any future applications by Optus would need to be for more appropriate loations. </p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TELSTRA ACCEPTS FALL IN INTERCONNECTION CHARGE</p>
<p>Telstra says it accepts as a necessary requirement of deregulation, a 35 per cent cut to a key charge it levies on others in the telephone business.</p>
<p>Interconnection fees will fall when the market is deregulated from July the first, a move it is hoped will bring lower prices and improved service to users. </p>
<p>The Australian Competition and Consumer Commission has set the fees, which Telstra can charge other carriers and service providers, for six months.</p>
<p>It originally wanted a 50 per cent cut, but came down to 35 after lobbying by Telstra.</p>
<p>The ACCC says new industry players will still be better able to compete effectively under the new charging regime.</p>
<p>Service providers have been unavailable for comment.</p>
<p>After six months, the charges will be determined by commercial negotiation, but a spokesman for Telstra says prices overall are likely to keep falling, with competition. </p>
<p>The Commission will release other statements on pricing, competition, and guarantees of access to Telstra, in coming days.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>GOVT ACCUSED OF WINDING BACK CLOCK ON WOMEN</p>
<p>Women's organisations are accusing the Federal Government of forcing women into leaving the workforce.</p>
<p>Presenting the fourth in the series of Whitlam lectures, feminist and social writer, Dr Anne Summers, said the Government's cuts to women's services and child care are making it too difficult for women to stay at work. </p>
<p>She says the progress of women over the past 20 years is being eroded.</p>
<p>Dr Summers says women could end up staying at home not because they want to, but because the wages they are getting in a deregulated wages system are lower, meaning work ceases to be financially worthwhile.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
