<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68582" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: CRICKET-PAKISTAN THRASH INDIA TO LEVEL TORONTO SERIES.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-PAKISTAN THRASH INDIA TO LEVEL TORONTO SERIES.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Sahara Cup series cricket tug of war will be decided by a fifth and final match after Pakistan scored an emphatic 97-run victory over India on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Pakistanis levelled the series at 2-2 with a disciplined performance which featured a fine return to form by Ijaz Ahmed (90) and some exceptional bowling from skipper Wasim Akram (two for 11) and spinner Saqlain Mushtaq (three for nine).</p>
<p>Ahmed, the player of the match, helped Pakistan recover from a precarious 91-4 in the 20th over to compile 258-8 on a wicket which offered the bowlers some encouragement.</p>
<p>India was never in the running after a fine opening spell from Akram. They lost openers Nayan Mongia (0) and Sachin Tendulkar (3) with only nine runs on the board and had the staggers at 64-6.</p>
<p>A rear-guard 47 runs from Ajay Jadeja was nowhere near enough as Saqlain and Aamir Sohail (none for 36 off ten) bowled tightly to prevent any Indian revival.</p>
<p>Salim Malik mopped up the tail (two for six) to dismiss India for 161 and present Pakistan with a confidence builder going into Sunday's decider.</p>
<p>&quot;We are getting better day by day,&quot; Akram said after the match. &quot;Our bodies were stiff before but they are loose now.&quot;</p>
<p>The capacity crowd of 5,000 at the Toronto Cricket, Skating and Curling Club were treated to some vintage Ijaz Ahmed. The 28-year-old combined with punishing right hander Inzamam-ul-Haq for an 86-run partnership just when Pakistan was looking vulnerable.</p>
<p>He brought up his 50 off 74 balls and looked set for a fifth career one-day century.</p>
<p>However an attempted cut off an Anil Kumble top spinner was the wrong shot and Ahmed was bowled for a series-saving 90.</p>
<p>India had to score at a rate of 5.2 runs an over and after losing their openers cheaply they were always going to struggle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
