<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="685961" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian tobacco stocks fall, fear slower growth.</title>
<headline>Indonesian tobacco stocks fall, fear slower growth.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of cigarette maker PT Hanjaya Mandala Sampoerna and Gudang Garam have fallen this week on investor concern over a slowdown in the growth in the industry, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Sampoerna was down 225 rupiah to 8,700 rupiah on a volume of 2.2 million shares on Wednesday, while Gudang Garam closed unchanged at 9,575 rupiah after touching a low of 9,375 in active trading of 1.1 million shares.</p>
<p>The two blue chip stocks have fallen 5.7 percent and 3.04 percent respectively since Monday.</p>
<p>Analysts said negative sentiment on tobacco stocks was due to concern that growth in the industry had been slowing down.</p>
<p>They said the proposed U.S. legal settlement with American tobacco firms had had little impact on the local market.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market has just realised that both companies are in a mature industry,&quot; Goei Liaw Hong, head of research Socgen Crosby, said.</p>
<p>He said taken a bearish line on cigarette stocks since last September as he believed their potential for growth was small.</p>
<p>However, he said the cigarette industry's growth would be around six percent this year and Sampoerna's market share had risen to 12.1 percent in 1996 from 3.5 percent in 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a significant growth for Sampoerna which driven by sales volume,&quot; Hong said, adding that a number of analysts had forecast continued profit growth as a result of this.</p>
<p>He anticipated 1997 net profit of 470 billion for Sampoerna, lower than market concensus net profit of 520 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;The downside trend for Sampoerna seems to be continued as it was traded at a price earnings of 17 to 18 times,&quot; he said, adding that fair price for Sampoerna was 8,000 rupiah.</p>
<p>Hong said he expected 1997 net profit of Gudang Garam of 795 billion rupiah, while the market concensus was 782.2 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>However, he said, Gudang Garam's potential growth was small as its already controlled about 47 percent of the market in 1996.</p>
<p>David Jap, analyst with Vickers Ballas Tamara also said he anticipated the industry would be slow and expected a net profit of 502 billion rupiah for Sampoerna's net profit in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;So far, I have no plans to revised down my 1997's net profit target of 502 billion as I believe its sales would be better in the second-half,&quot; Jap said, adding that his expectation for 1997 was conservative.</p>
<p>--- Helen Lumban Gaol, Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
