<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686001" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan to beef up anti-terrorist force-police chief.</title>
<headline>Japan to beef up anti-terrorist force-police chief.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan needs a stronger anti-terrorist strike force to counter possible guerrilla attacks similar to the one on the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima, Japan's new police chief said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Yuko Sekiguchi, the new head of the National Police Agency, told a news conference that the 200-member Police Special Assault Team (SAT) would be given helicopters and indicated they would train with the country's military.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to heighten our preparedness to be able to rescue the victims of (guerrilla) groups which mount attacks like the bazooka assault on the Lima residence,&quot; Sekiguchi said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am providing SAT with helicopters, which they have not had until now,&quot; said Sekiguchi, who took over as the country's top police officer on March 31.</p>
<p>Sekiguchi refused to say if the force would be given new weapons and if it would be prepared to carry out operations overseas.</p>
<p>But he said it might receive military training.</p>
<p>&quot;Closer cooperation with the Self-Defence Forces (military) is also part of meeting any threat to public safety,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sekiguchi also said the number of police intelligence officers stationed in Japanese embassies would be increased.</p>
<p>Japan now has 80 of those officers stationed at 62 embassies, he said.</p>
<p>SAT was created to deal with hostage-takings, hijackings and other terrorist acts shortly after Tokyo's humiliating 1977 capitulation to Japan Red Army guerrillas holding a jetliner at Dhaka airport in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>SAT's first real operation did not happen until June 1995 when it stormed an All Nippon Airways Boeing 747 at Hakodate airport in northern Japan, rescuing all 364 hostages and arresting a middle-aged hijacker.</p>
<p>Soon after April 24 when Peruvian commandos stormed the residence held by the Peruvian guerrillas, Japanese government officials said Japan must beef up its anti-terrorist force.</p>
<p>All but one of the 72 hostages were rescued in the Lima operation that ended the siege which began in December. Two commandoes and all 14 guerrillas also died in the attack.</p>
<p>Top government spokesman Seiroku Kajiyama said last month that Japan should form a new anti-terrorist team, using both police and military officers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
