<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686006" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Ringgit weakens on strong offshore dollar bids.</title>
<headline>Ringgit weakens on strong offshore dollar bids.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The ringgit weakened against the dollar in Asian trading, breaking through the 2.5200 level on strong bids for the dollar by offshore players.</p>
<p>Dealers said lack of central bank presence helped push the dollar/ringgit to a high of 2.5235.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/ringgit remains biddish and could test the 2.5250 level during London time,&quot; said a dealer with a European bank in Kuala Lumpur. &quot;There was some profit-taking earlier but offshore players are bidding again around 2.5230.&quot;</p>
<p>At 1000 GMT, ringgit was quoted at 2.5232/42 a dollar. It closed at 2.5195/5205 in Kuala Lumpur on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Fearing intervention by Bank Negara, offshore players were earlier cashing in their profits after clearing stop-losses above 2.5200, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said that though no central bank presence has been detected so far, it was likely to support the ringgit around 2.5250 level.</p>
<p>Dealers said the ringgit remained under pressure due to continued demand demand by offshore parties ahead of the mid-year book closing.</p>
<p>Dollar/ringgit bids are expected to appear more strongly later, particularly with no sign of short-end swaps firming up, they said.</p>
<p>-- Syed Azman (603-206 2323)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
