<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686184" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Arkansans dismayed by latest twist in Clinton probe.</title>
<headline>Arkansans dismayed by latest twist in Clinton probe.</headline>
<dateline>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton's home state responded with bipartisan dismay and anger Wednesday at reports Whitewater prosecutor Kenneth Starr was delving into Clinton's alleged extramarital affairs.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see any reason for this line of inquiry to continue, and I talk mostly to Republicans,&quot; said Arkansas Republican Party Chairman Lloyd Stone. Allegations of sexual adventures by Clinton are &quot;yesterday's news,&quot; Stone added.</p>
<p>&quot;I think he's gone off the deep end,&quot; said John Hall, a Little Rock trial lawyer who clashed with the president when he was governor of Arkansas. &quot;I suppose the next question is whether I slept with Bill Clinton.&quot;</p>
<p>The comments followed a Washington Post report that FBI agents and prosecutors working for Starr questioned Arkansas state troopers recently about their knowledge of extramarital relationships Clinton may have had while he was governor.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Arkansas State Police, Wayne Jordan, acknowledged some of Clinton's former security officers had been subpeoned by Starr and would, &quot;as always, honour any subpoena from a legitimate law enforcement investigation.&quot;</p>
<p>None of the troopers known to have been assigned to Clinton as bodyguards could be reached Wednesday for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;These so-called romances of Clinton's have absolutely no bearing whatsoever on Starr's investigation,&quot; said Pat Walsh, a retired Little Rock broadcasting executive who said he had &quot;never voted for Clinton in my life.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I doubt Clinton would make pillow talk about loans and land deals and deeds,&quot; Walsh snorted.</p>
<p>But Ruth Whitaker, a longtime Republican activist in Fort Smith, Arkansas, was not so sure.</p>
<p>&quot;I know Starr's investigation is being called a witchhunt but I'm not persuaded to agree,&quot; Whitaker said. &quot;I'm sure there's a good reason for the subpoenas. Starr must have something.&quot;</p>
<p>David Williams, a Little Rock trial attorney whose law practice includes two Whitewater-related cases, disagreed.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it shows Starr is at a dead end,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an effort to critic-proof the report the special prosecutor is getting ready to write,&quot; Williams said, adding in reference to four assistants Starr hired last week: &quot;I think these lawyers are going to question fringe witnesses so that 10, 20, even 30 years from now, even the conspiracy nuts will be able to say Ken Starr didn't leave a stone unturned.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LITTLE ROCK, Ark."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
