<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686322" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tennessee Gas ready to make Northeast commitments.</title>
<headline>Tennessee Gas ready to make Northeast commitments.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tennessee Gas Pipeline Co is ready to make commitments to deliver natural gas to the U.S. Northeast, senior vice president Jay Holm said.</p>
<p>The El Paso Energy Corp business unit has closed the Open Season for the Eastern Express Project, ending the period where potential shippers could request service.</p>
<p>The project was proposed in April to provide gas transportation service to Canadian, mid-continent and Gulf Coast shippers to the Ellisburg/Leidy hub which provides access to the large and growing Northeast and mid-Atlantic markets.</p>
<p>In its associated solicitation for capacity turnback, customers with relevant capacity tendered some 90 million cubic feet daily.</p>
<p>Holm said it is significant the tendered volume represents only about 7 percent of Tennessee's total contracts eligible for turnback under the terms of the solicitation, adding &quot;this confirms the value of capacity on Tennessee's system.&quot;</p>
<p>During the open season, the company received requests for service of some 500 million cubic feet daily. Close to 90 percent of this volume is for service from the Chicago hub to various points on the Tennessee and Midwestern Gas pipelines.</p>
<p>The pipeline said it is working with these shippers to provide the requested service in a timely manner and plans to file its application with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission this fall for service to begin November 1, 1999.</p>
<p>Tennessee Gas Pipeline also said a second phase of the Eastern Express Project will meet the additional needs of shippers that expressed interest in alternate delivery points outside the initial scope of the project.</p>
<p>It said this will be called the Eastern Express 2000 Project, adding additional will be announced soon.</p>
<p>This will allow shippers with uncertainty about their capacity upstream of the Eastern Express Project extra time to finalize their strategy and make firm commitments, it said.</p>
<p>Tennessee Gas Pipeline is prepared to work with shippers to meet their needs on a flexible basis with service beginning in 2000 or sooner if possible.</p>
<p>&quot;Our discussions with major shippers in the industry clearly indicate consensus that the Eastern Express Project makes the most sense when compared to other competing projects that transport gas to the northeast,&quot; said Holm.</p>
<p>&quot;Our proposal has a significant advantage compared to other large grass roots projects because it can provide smaller increments of capacity as the market requires. We're ready to make those commitments.&quot;</p>
<p>Tennessee Gas Pipeline's open season solicited binding commitments from shippers rather than the two step process used by other projects, the company pointed out. The other projects initially sought non-binding expressions of interest with the possibility of firm commitments made at a later date.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
