<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686335" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tax plans proliferate on Capitol Hill.</title>
<headline>Tax plans proliferate on Capitol Hill.</headline>
<byline>Tabassum Zakaria</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>As tax legislation headed for a full airing before the Senate and House, yet another tax-cut proposal surfaced Wednesday on Capitol Hill.</p>
<p>Senate Democrats planned to offer their own version of a five-year tax cut plan they said was fairer than the Republican tax bill expected to reach the Senate floor for debate later Wednesday.</p>
<p>Now each party in each chamber of Congress has a tax cut proposal aimed at implementing the requirement in the balanced-budget agreement of an $85 billion net tax cut over five years.</p>
<p>Capitol Hill was riddled with press conferences on taxes as lawmakers tried to solidify support for their particular version.</p>
<p>House Republicans held a meeting that amounted to a pep rally for their tax bill, and the usually closed gathering opened its doors to the press. House Budget Committee Chairman John Kasich, an Ohio Republican, even resorted to Sixties slogans, saying the Republican mantra was &quot;power to the people.&quot;</p>
<p>Democrats accused Republicans of giving a disproportionate amount of tax relief to the wealthy. Republicans said some Democratic provisions amounted to welfare for people who did not pay taxes.</p>
<p>And everyone pulled out charts and numbers that showed their tax relief package would largely help the middle class and families.</p>
<p>The Senate was expected to start debate later Wednesday on its tax bill, which due to changes by the Senate Finance Committee actually amounted to a $77 billion net tax cut, with another $8 billion slated for child health spending.</p>
<p>Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott said changes were being discussed that would raise the tax cut to a net $85 billion over five years by providing tax relief for small businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;We have some other small business provisions that we would like very much to have in our package, and we are looking at those,&quot; the Mississippi Republican said.</p>
<p>Senate Democrats said their plan would take into account not only income taxes but also payroll taxes when providing a child tax credit and that would extend the credit to seven million more families.</p>
<p>The Senate Democrat plan would exclude from taxation 30 percent of gains made on investments such as stocks for people of all income levels. The Republican plan would cut the maximum individual capital gains tax rate to 20 percent from 28 percent.</p>
<p>The Democrat proposal would use identical tax and revenue increases set out in the Republican bill. Senate Democratic Leader Tom Daschle of South Dakota said the new plan had &quot;very broad&quot; support among Senate Democrats.</p>
<p>The House is scheduled to debate and vote on its tax legislation Thursday. Democrats and the White House have strongly objected to provisions in that bill.</p>
<p>&quot;Democrats will oppose it because well over half the benefits go to the richest five percent of taxpayers,&quot; House Democratic Leader Dick Gephardt of Missouri said.</p>
<p>House Ways and Means Committee Chairman Bill Archer, a Texas Republican, said Democratic calculations end up classifying middle-income families as rich and denying tax relief to them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
