<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686508" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.S. under attack at Earth Summit.</title>
<headline>U.S. under attack at Earth Summit.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Once the world's leader on environmental issues, the United States is under attack at the U.N. Earth Summit for refusing to set targets to cut global warming and for reducing funds for ecological projects.</p>
<p>Some Third World countries on Wednesday blocked a text on climate change, hoping that President Bill Clinton, who addresses the summit on Thursday, will give specific targets for curbing carbon emissions from coal, oil and other fossil fuels that cause global warming.</p>
<p>The issue arose during closed-doors negotiations on a document to end this week's conference, follow-up to the landmark 1992 Earth Summit in Rio de Janeiro.</p>
<p>&quot;The big question is whether one should begin negotiations after Clinton has spoken in hopes he will go further than in the Denver Group of Seven summit,&quot; said Michaele Hustedt, a parliamentarian from German's Green Party and a member of Bonn's delegation.</p>
<p>&quot;But the entire German delegation disagrees,&quot; she said, &quot;because he will not go further.&quot;</p>
<p>In Denver Clinton held out firmly against European pressure to set specific targets. The United States is the world's biggest polluter.</p>
<p>The offensive against the United States at the week-long summit began on its first day when British Prime Minister Tony Blair challenged Washington to accept a European Union proposal for reductions in the so-called greenhouse gases.</p>
<p>&quot;We in Europe have put our cards on the table,&quot; he said. &quot;It is time for the special pleading to stop and for others to follow suit.&quot;</p>
<p>The disputes at the meeting go beyond global warming. Some Europeans also want the final summit document to call for a global tax on international aviation fuel, a treaty protecting the world's forests and a world energy strategy to reduce use of oil, coal and other fossil fuels.</p>
<p>All these positions are opposed by Washington.</p>
<p>Evidently annoyed at the European position, State Department spokesman John Dinger said singling out the United States &quot;as a wrongdoer is simply not the case.&quot;</p>
<p>He called the European Union's target of reducing emissions by 15 percent emissions from the 1990 level by 2010 unrealistic, saying he had seen no anaylsis that showed the Europeans would meet their own targets.</p>
<p>A decision has to be made in time for a December climate conference in Kyoto, Japan.</p>
<p>The Clinton administration on Wednesday endorsed strict new proposals to lower the 0.12 parts-per-million standard for smog-forming ozone to 0.08 parts-per-million.</p>
<p>But the White House modified the Environmental Protection Agency's proposals, increasing the number of violations that would be allowed before an area was considered to be out of compliance with the standard.</p>
<p>Coal and oil lobbies have battled any tough restrictions, saying this would cost them billions of dollars a year in pollution controls and would drive industries out of cities and farther into the countryside.</p>
<p>Since power plants, smokestack industries and automobile exhaust are major contributors of these pollutants as well as of greenhouse gases, the new air standards would help the United States in setting future targets on carbon emissions.</p>
<p>The recent environmental barrage against the United States is in contrast to the past. Until the 1990s Washington was trying to make other countries live up to its standards, despite its gas-guzzling automobiles.</p>
<p>During the Cold War, U.S. air and water quality laws were the forerunner of those passed by other nations, according to an analysis by the Washington-based Worldwatch Institute.</p>
<p>The United States in 1972 also helped establish the Nairobi-based U.N. Environment Programme (UNEP) and took a leading role in the 1987 Montreal agreement to protect the ozone lawyer from dangerous chemicals.</p>
<p>Since Rio, Washington has failed to ratity treaties on biodiversity or wildlife conservation and the Law of the Sea that regulates all uses of oceans and their resources.</p>
<p>Funds have been slashed steadily for some of the key U.N. environment projects, such as UNEP.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
