<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686523" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: Police describe fake bomb used on Malta hijack.</title>
<headline>Police describe fake bomb used on Malta hijack.</headline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Empty cigarette packets, two deodorant cans and a switch from an answering machine were used to make a dummy bomb used to hijack an Air Malta aircraft to Cologne on June 9, according to a report issued on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The report was drawn up by a committee appointed by Maltese Prime Minister Alfred Sant to examine Malta airport security.</p>
<p>The committee said security met international standards, but it called for greater alertness by security staff for innocent-looking objects which could by used for other purpose. The report included a letter sent to the Malta police by German investigators after they questioned the hijackers and examined the fake bomb. Turkish hijackers Nosret Akmercan and Ismail Beyazpinar, who hijacked the flight shortly after it left Malta for Istanbul, told the German police they arrived at Malta airport just 10 minutes before the flight and managed to smuggle their equipment in hand luggage past airport security. Once the aircraft was on its way the men waited until the crew were in the rear of the aircraft and then quickly assembled the fake bomb. One of the hijackers bound the bomb to his chest with tape then showed it to one of the aircrew and demanded a change of course to Cologne.</p>
<p>The hijackers surrendered peacefully soon after the plane landed. They called for the release of fellow Turk Mehmet Ali Agca, who is being held in a Rome jail after the failed assassination attempt on Pope John Paul in 1981.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
