<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686548" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FOCUS-Montedison sees stronger 97 after tough 96.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Montedison sees stronger 97 after tough 96.</headline>
<byline>Viviana Vestrucci</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian agri-chemical firm Montedison saw a significant improvement in results in the first five months of this year and intends to press on with streamlining the group, its managing director said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Enrico Bondi told the annual shareholders' meeting that Montedison's gross operating margin rose 13.5 percent to 1.5 trillion lire ($892 million) in the period from January to May this year while sales were up 13 percent to 11.2 trillion lire.</p>
<p>&quot;After a difficult 1996, 1997 is showing signs of recovery with an improvement in the figures,&quot; Bondi said.</p>
<p>Net operating profits rose 16 percent to 951 billion lire in the same period while Bondi said turnover and margin growth for the January-May period had improved on first quarter growth.</p>
<p>Montedison went to the brink of collapse in 1993 along with its sister company Ferruzzi Finanziaria, now called Compart, and has been nursing itself back to health with a long term programme of divestments and restructuring.</p>
<p>Bondi told the meeting the company intended to pursue its policy of streamlining operations and aimed to reduce its holding companies to just seven by 1998 from 51 currently with considerable cuts in structural costs. The group has already pared holding companies drastically from 118 in 1993.</p>
<p>Its sell-off programme will also continue. After divestments already carried out for a total 2.755 trillion lire, Montedison intended selling its 26 percent stake in French financial holding SCI (Societe Centrale d'Investissements) by 1998.</p>
<p>Bondi said the Paris-based company &quot;has no debts but 300 billion lire of liquidity after selling off various activities and we envisage selling our stake by 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>Institutional shareholder Prime criticised Montedison for being &quot;neither a conglomerate nor a real investment holding,&quot; and urged it to get rid of its subholdings European Sugar France (ESF) and Montecatini chemical company.</p>
<p>But Bondi said while he wanted to simplify the structure &quot;it is complicated. For ESF and Montecatini the cost/benefit ratio of their elimination is not favourable at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>He said talks were going on over Montecatini Tecnologie but he ruled out selling an 11 percent stake in energy unit Edison which Montedison holds above and beyond its controlling stake.</p>
<p>He noted that Franco-Italian food group Eridania Beghin-Say posted a good increase in operating profit and turnover in the first five months of this year, with great success in eastern European countries in the edible oils sector.</p>
<p>He also said that the Montell polyolefins joint venture with Royal Dutch/Shell had increased its net operating profit by 11.5 percent thanks to holding down costs.</p>
<p>Bondi ruled out the possibility of any Montedison free capital increase, noting that the capital reduction carried out in 1996 to wipe out previous losses had enabled the group to resume paying a dividend after four years.</p>
<p>The shareholders' meeting approved Montedison's plan to pay a 1996 ordinary dividend of 20 lire and 150 lire per savings share.</p>
<p>In April, Montedison reported a consolidated net profit of 298 billion lire after a 1.07 trillion profit in 1995 which was boosted by a one-off gain from the creation of the Montell venture.</p>
<p>Montedison shares closed 0.52 percent up on the day at 1,152 lire, behind the overall Milan market which showed gains of more than one percent.</p>
<p>$1=1,681 lire</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
