<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68661" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Militant cyclists wage war on streets of Britain.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Militant cyclists wage war on streets of Britain.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's cyclists used to be peaceful creatures, quietly going about their business with wicker baskets attached to the handlebars and bells that were rarely rung in anger.</p>
<p>But no more. The nation's mild-mannered cyclists have evolved into urban warriors, fighting what they see as the evil of the automobile.</p>
<p>Today's militant cyclists wear gaudy Lycra clothing and weave between traffic on aggressive-looking mountain bikes, shouting angrily at motorists who dare to cross their path.</p>
<p>Last month, hundreds of two-wheelers joined forces in their fight against the car and crowded onto the streets of London, aggravating the traffic chaos caused by an underground train-drivers' strike.</p>
<p>The cyclists rode slowly around major road junctions in the heart of the capital, blowing whistles and yelling anti-car slogans at motorists.</p>
<p>The action was organised by Reclaim the Streets, an environmental pressure group fighting to rid cities of the car.</p>
<p>It is a secretive organisation which describes itself as a loose amalgamation of people devoted to green, liberal causes, and often mobilises members via coded telephone messages.</p>
<p>Even a rendezvous with the group's spokesman was held at a clandestine location on a boat moored in one of London's canals.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to be secretive because the police are constantly on our backs,&quot; said the spokesman, who uses the pseudonym Chris Roberts. &quot;If the police are branding you as terrorists, they're likely to arrest you for conspiracy to do this or that.&quot;</p>
<p>The group has staged a series of spectacular protests since its creation in early 1995, some of which have caused considerable damage.</p>
<p>In July, it blocked off the traffic and held a street party on a section of one of the main motorways passing through west London.</p>
<p>Protesters used a pneumatic drill to bore holes in the fast lane of the motorway in which they planted trees. Techno music blared, graffiti were sprayed on the tarmac and thousands of pounds (dollars) worth of damage was caused. And all in the name of the bicycle.</p>
<p>Not long afterwards, police raided the group's offices in north London, confiscating their computer and arresting a member for conspiracy to cause criminal damage.</p>
<p>A heavy price to pay for a bicycle friendly city. But Roberts insists the group still commands considerable support for its campaigning among the public.</p>
<p>&quot;The public has supported us on the narrow issues of urban transport mainly because it's so obvious something needs to be done about it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Britain's Automobile Assocation (AA), which champions the motorist, agrees that more investment is needed in the country's transport system but says it cannot support the activities of groups such as Reclaim the Streets which break the law in their protests.</p>
<p>&quot;Such protests cause chaos for all road users including emergency services, putting lives at risk,&quot; said Rebecca Rees, spokeswoman for the AA.</p>
<p>No doubt the ideal of streets devoid of traffic and pollution is appealing to many. But do the heavy-handed tactics of the militant cyclists do much to further this cause?</p>
<p>&quot;More conventional campaigning groups have been lobbying for a long time and haven't been noticed as much as the issues merit,&quot; says Roberts. &quot;Reclaim the Streets seeks to increase the political and public pressure for change.&quot;</p>
<p>Lynn Sloman, assistant director of one of the more conventional groups, Transport 2000, agrees that Reclaim the Streets had played an important role in raising awareness of transport issues.</p>
<p>&quot;We think Reclaim the Streets has a very important role to play,&quot; she said. &quot;Their direct action follows in a long line of groups that have felt they can't get their voices heard any other way.&quot;</p>
<p>They may already have made their impact. The government announced a National Cycling Strategy earlier this year which aims to quadruple the number of journeys made by cyclists by 2012.</p>
<p>But for Reclaim the Streets the war with motorists is far from over -- they plan to continue fighting for their vision of car-free streets with more protests planned at secret locations across Britain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
