<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686642" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - June 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - June 25.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Bangladesh press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE DAILY STAR</p>
<p>The fire at Magurchhara gas field would die down automatically, said Occidental officials on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Election Commission has suggested that ministers of the ruling Awami League should not participate in campaign in the Manikganj constituency where a parliamentary by-elections is due on June 30.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>The Parbattya Chattagram Janasanghati Samity (PCJSS), the political wing of tribal Shanti Bahini insurgents, is seeking the opinion of its rank and file about a possible peace agreement with the government.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina told the parliament on Tuesday that the amount of default bank loans was coming down because of stern actions by the government.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGLADESH OBSERVER</p>
<p>Main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) will stage countrywide demonstration on Thursday against the 1997/98 budget which it alleged was desinged to protect Indian business interest.</p>
<p>Former Prsident Hussain Muahammad Ershad was released on Tuesday from a heart hospital where he was admitted with severe chest pain last week.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL EXPRESS</p>
<p>Finance Minister S.A.M.S. Kibria on Tuesday told representatives of international donors that the government was committed to carry forward administrative, economic and legal reforms.</p>
<p>German company ABB has won a Taka 2.97 billion deal for installing 151 kilometre power tramission line in Chittagong region. REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
