<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686679" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: No short-term hit to India power cos from rate cut.</title>
<headline>No short-term hit to India power cos from rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The central bank's decision to cut the bank rate by one percentage point to 10 percent per annum effective Wednesday will not impact utility firms in the current fiscal year, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It could impact them negatively but not in the short-term,&quot; said Abhijit Basak, analyst at H.G. Asia Securities.</p>
<p>Some analysts said power sector shares could still react negatively to the news when stock markets reopen on Thursday.</p>
<p>Analysts said India's Electric Supply Act sets returns of utility companies five percent higher than the prevailing bank rate at the beginning of the fiscal year. The current fiscal year runs from April 1, 1997 to March 31, 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;In fiscal 1998 there will be no impact because the Act clearly says that it is going to be based on the rate prevailing in the beginning of the year,&quot; said T.N. Giridhar, analyst at Kotak Securities, the Indian affiliate of Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India had cut the bank rate to 11 percent a few days after the beginning of the current financial year when it announced its credit and monetary policy for the first half of 1997/98.</p>
<p>But analysts said investors were likely to react to the rate cut and could turn sellers in utility stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;There is bound to be slight pressure on utility stocks. The market might use this as a trading opportunity but from a longer-term investment point of view, I would not be very concerned about this,&quot; Giridhar said.</p>
<p>Analysts said power companies were lobbying to delink utility returns from the bank rate.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot have a utility having this kind of volatile return,&quot; Giridhar said.</p>
<p>Jyotsna Subramaniam, analyst at UBS Securities, said the government could modify the Act in the coming months.</p>
<p>&quot;The companies have at least around 14 months to appeal to the government before the next tariff increase some time in October,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said if the provision in the Act remained unchanged until the next tariff hike, the net profit of power companies could be lower by 3.0 to 4.0 percent in 1998/99.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
