<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68665" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IRA's allies say N.Ireland peace process is dead.</title>
<headline>IRA's allies say N.Ireland peace process is dead.</headline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The political wing of the Irish Republican Army (IRA) guerrilla force said on Saturday that Northern Ireland's peace process is dead and a new one should be put in its place.</p>
<p>Martin McGuinness, the chief strategist of the Sinn Fein party, said the current peace talks, from which it is excluded, are going nowhere.</p>
<p>A new process must involve Sinn Fein, he said, and a condition that the IRA must disarm before its political allies can join talks must be dropped.</p>
<p>&quot;These talks are pointless, they are going nowhere,&quot; McGuinness told BBC radio. &quot;I believe they should be wound up,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a need now to reconstruct a new peace process, this time with completely different terms of reference.&quot;</p>
<p>The IRA has waged a 25-year guerrilla struggle against British rule of Northern Ireland, which has a pro-British Protestant majority and an Irish Catholic minority.</p>
<p>Britain and Ireland called all-party talks to give the region a chance to heal wounds, but they have not allowed Sinn Fein to take part until an IRA ceasefire is restored.</p>
<p>In the absence of Sin Fein, the talks have bogged down in wrangling between pro-British Protestant and pro-Irish Catholic nationalists over scrapping guerrilla arms and other issues.</p>
<p>&quot;It is time that people stopped fooling the public (and) recognised that the peace process is dead and that the urgent task now facing us is to establish whether or not we can reconstruct, rebuild a new peace process,&quot; McGuinness added.</p>
<p>He called for unconditional &quot;inclusive negotiations&quot; held within a defined time-frame and said Britain must put in place &quot;confidence-building&quot; measures.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the minimum I believe that Sinn Fein (would need) to go to the IRA to request a second ceasefire. I think that anything less than that is doomed to failure. That is a reality that must be faced,&quot; he said in the radio interview.</p>
<p>He said Britain's early insistence on an IRA arms handover strangled the peace process and kept his party out.</p>
<p>An Irish-American delegation that helped broker the IRA's last ceasefire in September 1994 arrived in Belfast for talks with Sinn Fein leaders.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein has dismissed media speculation that this might point to a possible new truce and said there were no links between the delegation and the reports.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
