<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="686782" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Morgan Stanley Dean Witter earnings hit by charge.</title>
<headline>Morgan Stanley Dean Witter earnings hit by charge.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowksi</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morgan Stanley Dean Witter Discover &amp; Co., reporting results for the first time since the merger of the two brokerage companies, said Wednesday it earned $509 million in its second quarter, down from $551 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>The results included $63 million in one-time costs related to the merger and other acquisitions, resulting in income of 83 cents a share. Excluding the one-time charges, Morgan earned $590 million, or 97 cents a share, up from 92 cents a share earlier.</p>
<p>Sales increased to $3.5 billion from $3.1 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;That's pretty good earnings, considering the $63 million merger charge they took,&quot; said Perrin Long, an independent analyst covering the brokerage industry in Darien, Conn.</p>
<p>The company took the $63 million charge, worth 11 cents a share, to pay for the merger that brought together investment bank Morgan Stanley Group Inc. and retail brokerage and credit card company Dean Witter Discover Inc. on May 28.</p>
<p>Morgan bucked a recent trend in the brokerage industry as its profit increased from the first quarter of this year, when it earned $571 million. However, its trading revenue declined during the period.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, the earnings we've seen so far for the quarter ended May 31 weren't quite as favourable as the quarter before,&quot; Long said. &quot;Part of the reason is that the May quarter includes the less-active markets in April and the Federal Reserve (0.25 percent interest rate) raise.&quot;</p>
<p>Other brokerage firms reported slower second-quarter earnings. Goldman Sachs &amp; Co. said on June that its 18 pre-tax earnings for the second quarter fell to $610 million compared with $905 million in the quarter ended Feb. 28.</p>
<p>A.G. Edwards Inc. said on June 17 that its quarterly earnings fell to 83 cents a share from 87 cents in the first quarter and Quick &amp; Reilley Group Inc. on June 24 reported slower earnings of 49 cents a share.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Dean Witter reported a slowdown in trading revenues to $722 million from $869 million the quarter before and commission income of $484 million, down from $490 million.</p>
<p>Revenues from investment banking, however, rose to $581 million, up $59 million for the quarter, and income from investments rose to $136 million from $56 million.</p>
<p>The company also reported $610 million in administrative and asset management fees, compared with $587 million the year before. Its merchant and card member fees dropped to $424 million from $436 million, and its servicing fees to $187 million from $202 million.</p>
<p>The company increased the provision for consumer loan losses to $611 million, up $202 million over the second quarter last year and $8 million over the quarter ended Feb. 28.</p>
<p>The company said its net charge-off rate for managed consumer loans increased to 7.07 percent, up from 5.22 percent a year ago and 6.91 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>The company added that the deliquency rate on its consumer loans was 6.9 percent for the quarter, up from 5.79 percent a year ago but down from 7.49 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Long added that he was not surprised by Morgan Stanley Dean Witter's $63 million merger charge.</p>
<p>&quot;You got a lot of stuff in there; proxies, lawyers' fees, expenses of terminating staff,&quot; he said. &quot;It's not that big a figure.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
