<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68691" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: FEATURE - Czechs sceptical as Catholics flock to Infant of Prague.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Czechs sceptical as Catholics flock to Infant of Prague.</headline>
<byline>Adriana Rouanet</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Bring me back a miniature of the Infant of Prague,&quot; Hebe Cunha, a 95-year-old Brazilian, told her granddaughter as she set off from Rio de Janeiro for the Czech capital.</p>
<p>The tiny wax statue of the Infant Jesus is a household name across the Roman Catholic world, and its home, a baroque Prague church, is now easily accessible to pilgrims after half a century of restrictions caused by war and communism.</p>
<p>But while foreign Catholics are flooding to see the 45 cm (17.72 inches) statue they believe can perform miracles, many Czechs are sceptical about its powers or oblivious to its very existence.</p>
<p>&quot;The rest of the world already believes in his powers but the local people do not,&quot; said Father Adalbert, a priest at the 17th century Church of Our Lady Victorious, which houses the statue.</p>
<p>Catholics around the world believe that the smiling infant, dressed in a sumptuous robe, has performed countless miracles -- and still does.</p>
<p>Known affectionately in Italian as &quot;bambino di Praga&quot;, the statue is credited with protecting Prague from Swedish invaders in 1639 and helping to eradicate a plague in the same century.</p>
<p>Church records are packed with accounts of how across the centuries it cured people, noble and common, of illnesses when all other remedies had failed.</p>
<p>Solange Grondin, a law student from the Pacific ocean island of Reunion, believes the statue, which is kept in a small glass cabinet, still has those powers.</p>
<p>&quot;As a child I was given a small reproduction of the Holy Infant of Prague with the accompanying prayer without ever knowing where Prague was,&quot; said 27-year-old Grondin.</p>
<p>&quot;Throughout the years it has performed several miracles for me, from helping me to pass difficult exams to curing sick family members.&quot;</p>
<p>Legend has it that the statue was modelled in the 12th century by a dying Spanish monk after he had had a vision of the child Jesus. It is now believed to date from the 16th century.</p>
<p>It is known that Duchess Manriquez de Lara brought the statue to Bohemia in 1556 when she married a Czech noblemen. Her daughter gave it to Carmelite monks at the church in 1628.</p>
<p>Roman Catholicism recognises many pilgrimage sites around the world where miracles are performed. But the Infant of Prague is unusual because it has become open to large numbers of pilgrims only since the 1989 fall of communism.</p>
<p>Hardly had the brutal six-year occupation of Prague by Nazi Germany ended when the communists seized power in 1948 and clamped down on religion, notably the Catholic church.</p>
<p>They never closed the Church of Our Lady Victorious, and masses were held throughout the communist period although records show the number fell dramatically in the Stalinist 1950s.</p>
<p>But foreign pilgrims were deterred from visiting the statue by visa requirements and accompanying red tape.</p>
<p>Father Adalbert recalls how all but regular masses had to be reported in advance to the communist authorities, and secret policemen would keep tabs on who attended.</p>
<p>Many believers and their families suffered discrimination, such as barring their children from universities or good jobs.</p>
<p>But suspicion of the statue and the Czech Catholic church long pre-dates communism.</p>
<p>The word &quot;victorious&quot; refers to the 1620 Battle of the White Mountain, just outside Prague, when the forces of the Catholic Habsburgs defeated the protestant Czech nobility.</p>
<p>This heralded a counter-reformation when Catholicism was reimposed on a predominantly protestant Bohemia. At the same time, Czech sovereignty was snuffed out and the country was ruled by German-speaking Habsburgs until 1918.</p>
<p>These divisions have not been forgotten in what is now a largely secular society. They surfaced last year in a dispute when Pope John Paul canonised Jan Sarkander, a Catholic priest tortured to death by protestant noblemen during the religious wars of the 17th century.</p>
<p>Father Adalbert said even Czech Catholics had a different outlook from other believers.</p>
<p>&quot;They do not believe in adoring a God that is covered in robes, pearls and a jewelled crown,&quot; he said. &quot;In the beginning I didn't believe in the Infant of Prague either but when you work close to him and see him every day, you begin to believe in him.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe that God would give such a small child such incredible powers,&quot; said Jiri Ledvinka, a Czech student who does odd jobs at the church. &quot;In our age we need more belief in philosophy and theology and less faith in miracles.&quot;</p>
<p>Among foreign Catholics, faith in the Infant Jesus seems unshakable. One Brazilian couple, Eduardo Faveret and Juliana Pimenta, had had no plans to visit the statue.</p>
<p>But the couple who live apart -- he studies in Germany while she lives in Rio de Janeiro -- had second thoughts when they heard of the infant's miraculous powers.</p>
<p>As they looked at each other, Pimenta smiled and said: &quot;Maybe we should pay this little holy child a visit.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
