<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68699" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Communists curse ailing Yeltsin, wish him dead.</title>
<headline>Communists curse ailing Yeltsin, wish him dead.</headline>
<byline>Alastair Macdonald</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diehard communists, marking the third anniversary on Saturday of the start of Boris Yeltsin's bloody showdown with Russia's Soviet-era parliament, had no sympathy for the sick president. Some said they wanted him dead.</p>
<p>Few were surprised by a leading doctor's disclosure that the Kremlin apparently hushed up a third heart attack on the eve of Yeltsin's July 3 presidential election victory over communist challenger Gennady Zyuganov.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just what we expect from the current authorities. They have no respect for the law or the constitution,&quot; said Nikolai Argunov, one of the organisers of a rally on Moscow's Smolensk Square to commemorate Yeltsin's constitutionally dubious decree, on September 21, 1993, which dissolved the hostile legislature.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who disappeared from public view days before his reelection, is in a clinic preparing for major heart surgery.</p>
<p>Renat Akchurin, tipped to perform a bypass operation, disclosed on Friday that the president had had an unreported heart attack in late June or early July just before the final runoff vote -- the third the 65-year-old leader had suffered.</p>
<p>&quot;I just want him dead,&quot; said middle-aged Raisa Gorshkova, as she listened to speakers denouncing Yeltsin's order to shell the White House parliament building into submission three years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;He sent so many fine young lads to their deaths, at the White House, in Chechnya,&quot; she added, with a motherly smile.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether he's sick or not sick, we don't care,&quot; said aeronautical engineer Vasily Ryabtsev. &quot;What's important is that he's a criminal. First because he executed our legally elected parliament...And second because he faked the election result.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the red flags waved by many of the thousand or so mainly middle-aged or elderly folk who gathered at Saturday's rally, some banners targeted the president personally.</p>
<p>Under a map of Russia portrayed as a breaking red heart, one urged: &quot;Boris Nikolayevich, for the good of the country and your own health, resign your post of president!&quot;</p>
<p>Like many of the protesters, who represent a hard core of support for Zyuganov, Gorshkova said she had been among thousands of Muscovites who rushed to barricades to defend the communist-dominated Supreme Soviet after Yeltsin dissolved it in frustration at its resistance to reform.</p>
<p>For two weeks they refused to obey the president and, on October 3, crowds of parliament supporters stormed the city council and television centre.</p>
<p>Next day Yeltsin ended the standoff by ordering tanks to shell the building. More than one hundred people died in the clashes.</p>
<p>&quot;We demand justice for those who gave the order to storm the Russian Supreme Soviet building,&quot; read one banner at the rally.</p>
<p>Zyuganov, 52, whose Russian Communist Party rose from the ashes of the assault on parliament to become the main opposition, failed to make a promised appearance at the rally.</p>
<p>But on Friday he made clear he was ready for a comeback if Yeltsin's health problems led to a new election, calling himself the most &quot;legitimate&quot; candidate in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>He accused Yeltsin's Kremlin entourage of &quot;lies and hypocrisy&quot; in working to return an already sick president to power in order to pursue their own presidential ambitions.</p>
<p>&quot;We are on the brink of very serious changes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The speakers who took his place on the podium on Saturday were also in no doubt.</p>
<p>Viktor Morozov, a self-styled cossack leader present at the White House siege, said: &quot;Nothing can stop the new social revolution. We must show the courage we showed three years ago. We will fight to the last drop of blood. Socialism or death!&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
