<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68706" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia's Samper flies to U.S. dogged by scandal.</title>
<headline>Colombia's Samper flies to U.S. dogged by scandal.</headline>
<byline>Tom Brown</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian President Ernesto Samper left for New York on Saturday to address the U.N. General Assembly while caught in a new drug scandal over heroin found stashed on his presidential jet.</p>
<p>The embarassing discovery on board the presidential Boeing 707 was made at the Catam military air base near Bogota during an inspection prompted by an anonymous telephone caller.</p>
<p>Police and military officials said 7.4 pounds (3.4 kg) of heroin were found hidden in 14 small packets stashed in the nose and tail section of the aircraft at the air base where the jet was being readied for the flight to New York.</p>
<p>Conspiracy theories abounded in Bogota as to how the drugs had been planted or smuggled aboard the closely-guarded jet, which is owned and operated by the Colombian Air Force.</p>
<p>Police said no arrests had been made.</p>
<p>Samper, who has defied repeated calls for his resignation because of charges his 1994 election campaign was partly financed by the Cali drug cartel, told reporters before his departure it was the work of someone seeking to hurt him.</p>
<p>He called it an &quot;outrageous and dastardly&quot; act.</p>
<p>&quot;It does harm to everyone ... but a greater harm was averted,&quot; he said, alluding to the scandal that would have erupted if the heroin had been detected by drug or customs agents at New York's JFK international airport.</p>
<p>Samper's U.S. visa was revoked in July because of his alleged ties to drug traffickers and as a sign of Washington's displeasure over a move by Colombia's Congress to clear him of drug corruption charges a month earlier.</p>
<p>The travel restriction does not apply to heads of state visiting the U.N. headquarters, where Samper was due to address the General Assembly on Monday.</p>
<p>Instead of the presidential plane, Samper and an official party that included Foreign Minister Maria Emma Mejia, Finance Minister Jose Antonio Ocampo and about 30 journalists left for New York aboard a jet belonging to Colombia's Avianca airline.</p>
<p>Ironically, a senior government official told Reuters on Friday that Samper's U.N. address would focus on the need for closer cooperation between consumer and producer nations in the war on drugs, which a growing number of critics say is a lost cause.</p>
<p>Washington decertified Colombia as a partner in U.S. counternarcotics efforts in March, arguing that it had not done enough to stem the flow of cocaine and heroin onto U.S. streets.</p>
<p>Some Western diplomats have suggested that Samper might use his U.N. address, and a separate speech as head of the 114-nation Non-Aligned Movement, to &quot;decertify&quot; the United States, since its lack of effective drug treatment and prevention programmes has gone a long way toward creating the world's single largest market for illicit drugs.</p>
<p>The government official, who asked not be identified by name, said Samper would be &quot;quite civilised, given the circumstances,&quot; limiting himself to a message of &quot;either we fix this together or it won't be fixed at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Colombia is the world's leading exporter of cocaine and was identified by the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration earlier this month as the top supplier of heroin to the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
