<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="687239" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSTANT VIEW - U.S. May durable goods fall 0.6 pct.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - U.S. May durable goods fall 0.6 pct.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are comments from U.S. economists after the Commerce Department reported orders for durable goods fell 0.6 percent in May compared to an upwardly revised 1.8-percent increase in April.</p>
<p>Economists in a Reuters survey had expected a 0.6-percent rise in orders for the month.</p>
<p>JOHN LONSKI, CHIEF ECONOMIST AND SENIOR VICE PRESIDENT, MOODY'S INVESTORS SERVICE INC: &quot;This only reinforces the argument that the Federal Resereve will keep monetary policy steady (at its next policy meeting on July 1 and 2).&quot;  </p>
<p>Speaking on Reuters Financial Television, Lonski added that the central bank may also stand pat on rates at its August 19 confab.</p>
<p>GARY THAYER, SENIOR ECONOMIST, A.G. EDWARDS &amp; SONS INC: &quot;It appears that the weakness we have seen in the transportation sector is showing up in this durables number. Part of this could be due to auto strikes. The overall number may not suggest the economy is in trouble. Ex-transportation, we still had a nice advance of 0.2 percent for durable goods in May. This is still a sign of a good, healthy economy.&quot;  </p>
<p>JOSEPH LIRO, CHIEF ECONOMIST, CIBC WOOD GUNDY SECURITIES CORP: &quot;Durables were a little bit below expectations, but April was revised up a little bit. It's probably supportive of the bond market in the early going, but I think the market is looking for any excuse to trade off before the 1300 EDT (five-year note) auction. Any support you get from this number ... will likely dissipate before 1300.</p>
<p>&quot;The Fed is solidly on hold in July and I think the market is pricing in less of a 50/50 chance for a move in August.&quot;  </p>
<p>CHERYL KATZ, SENIOR ECONOMIST, MERRILL LYNCH AND CO INC: &quot;Obviously, a weaker number than expected. Non-defense capital goods orders still continued to rise, which is good in the fact that capital goods, by increasing spending, is inherently disinflationary.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a clear sign there was significant moderation in economic growth in the second quarter, perhaps to about a 2.0 percent pace.&quot;  </p>
<p>ASTRID ADOLFSON, FIRST VICE PRESIDENT AND AN ECONOMIST, MCM MONEYWATCH INC: &quot;It was a mixed report in terms of the industries. You do have an upward revision in the prior month, so they weren't quite as weak as the first glance would have indicated. The (Treasury) market is volatile. I think (it) was affected more by the Japanese Tankan report, but the market bounced a little bit off of the (durable goods) numbers.&quot;</p>
<p>LEE YOUNGDAHL, BOND MARKET ANALYST, AUBREY G. LANSTON &amp; CO INC: &quot;The headline figure is a bit weaker than expected. When you look at the underlying components non-defense capital goods ex-aircraft were up 0.6 percent and the ex-transportation component was near consensus, so really the numbers don't vary too much to what was expected by the marketplace as a whole.</p>
<p>&quot;But it certainly implies a moderate pace of growth in manufacturing and not a substantial pickup in the month of May. It shouldn't shake the Fed tree much at all. The key data (policymakers) would want to look at at this point that might change opinions would be June data which we will only have piecemeal next week.</p>
<p>&quot;We won't have employment data in hand by the time the Fed meets, so this data today will not change the picture much if at all,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
