<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="687486" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain says will not intervene in digital TV market.</title>
<headline>Spain says will not intervene in digital TV market.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's Development Minister Rafael Arias Salgado told the European Commission that the government would not intervene in the Spanish digital TV market apparently reversing its previous position.</p>
<p>The government imposed a law approved at the end of January requiring different digital TV companies to have compatible decoders. Unless otherwise agreed between digital TV companies, this law requires the multicrypt system to be adopted.</p>
<p>However, the only Spanish platform currently in operation, Canal Plus's Canalsatelite Digital, is based on the simulcrypct system.</p>
<p>Canalsatelite complained to the Commission in February about the Spanish legislation on decoders, which effectively bans the pay-television channel from using its technology in Spain.</p>
<p>Canal Plus' decoders are already used in other EU countries.</p>
<p>Telecommunications operators Telefonica de Espana and state-television RTVE are planning to launch a rival digital package Via Digital in September using the multicrypt system prompting allegations that the government is giving them time to get the project ready.</p>
<p>But in a letter published on Wednesday by newspaper El Pais and confirmed by the Development Ministry, Salgado said: &quot;(Spain's digital tv law) ...does not mean that decoders will be withdrawn based on whether they are simulcrypt or multicrypt,&quot;.</p>
<p>He added that: &quot; ...the government is ready, once the initial transition period is over, to allow the market to work without any interference from the Administration.&quot;</p>
<p>However, the European Commission said on Wednesday it would start proceedings against Spain for violating several EU treaty provisions and related legislation which ban obstacles to trade in the bloc's single market.</p>
<p>Justifying its new law, the Spanish government previously said it preferred the multicrypt system because consumers can use the unscrambler for any digital platform, whereas simulcrypt is reportedly not fully interchangeable.</p>
<p>The decoders are devices that consumers rent or buy from the digital television provider to unscramble its programming signals.</p>
<p>Canalsatelite is 15 percent owned by commercial channel Antenna 3 and 85 percent owned by Sogecable, which is in turn 25 percent owned by France's Canal Plus and 25 percent owned by Spanish media group Prisa.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, a Sogecable spokeswoman said until Salgado's proposal was law the group would not withdraw its request.</p>
<p>-- Madrid Newsroom, + 341 585 8340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
