<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="687442" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German call money softer after Buba injects funds.</title>
<headline>German call money softer after Buba injects funds.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>German call money rates eased back slightly on Wednesday after the Bundesbank said it had added 6.6 billion marks in funds to the market in its weekly money market operation.</p>
<p>Traders said that with the injection of funds, rates dipped to around 3.0 percent after trading at around 3.02 to 3.03 percent before the operation. On Tuesday, call maney rates were around 3.05 to 3.07 percent.</p>
<p>They said that if the Bundesbank's addition led to an increase in resverve levels this sesison, rates were likely to ease back further before the month end.  </p>
<p>&quot;No-one can really understand why the Budnesbank allocated funds exactly according to need, but it means that we will have a smooth month end,&quot; said one trader in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, we have excess liquidity,&quot; said another, noting that daily reserve levels had already on Tuesday risen to 41.9 billion marks from 39.7 billion on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;And even if only four billion of the 6.6 billion are left for the reserves, that will be more than enough,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;If liquidity stays at these levels, rates will be pushed down again on towards the end of the week.&quot;  </p>
<p>While daily reserve levels rose to 41.9 billion marks on Tuesday, the monthly average also gained slightly to 40.1 billion marks from 40 billion on Monday.</p>
<p>Borrowings on the Lombard facility were negligible.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt Interbank Overnight Rate was quoted at 3.03600 percent on Wednesday versus 3.08492 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
