<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68758" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai PM in trouble as senior partner pulls support.</title>
<headline>Thai PM in trouble as senior partner pulls support.</headline>
<byline>Sutin Wannabovorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai prime minister Banharn Silpa-archa's future hung in the balance on Saturday after the second largest partner in his six-party coalition demanded he resign ahead of a no-confidence motion set for later in the day.</p>
<p>A parliament official and an opposition politician said Banharn was expected to seek an audience with King Bhumibol Adulyadej later on Saturday, presumably to seek approval to dissolve parliament before the vote.</p>
<p>&quot;The Prime Minister must resign before the vote. Otherwise, the New Aspiration Party (NAP) will abstain from voting,&quot; NAP spokesman Suraporn Danaitangtrakul told Reuters an hour before the voting was due to begin.</p>
<p>The sudden withdrawal of Defence Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh's NAP and smaller coalition partner the Nam Thai party ahead of the scheduled motion appeared to dash hopes Banharn would muster enough votes to survive as premier.</p>
<p>Support from the NAP would be crucial for Banharn, who has led his 14 month-old six-party coalition with 209 seats, to win the opposition-launched censure vote against him.</p>
<p>Suraporn said the NAP, with 57 seats, had been swayed by opposition arguments in parliament and wanted a change in the coalition.</p>
<p>The smaller 18-seat Nam Thai party, also declared it also wanted the premier to quit or it would abstain from voting, a party leader Somchai Pesprasert told reporters.</p>
<p>Few MPs were seen in parliament at the time originally set for the scheduled vote (10.30 a.m. local, 0330 GMT). One said Banharn was instead likely to seek an audience with the king.</p>
<p>&quot;I learned that the prime minister and the president of Parliament are on their way to have an audience with the king. It is almost 100 percent sure that he will seek approval for a dissolution of the house,&quot; Democrat member of parliament Arkhom Engchuan told Reuters.</p>
<p>There was no immediate comment or reaction from Banharn or his Chart Thai party officials on the developments.</p>
<p>Banharn has faced three days of opposition accusations ranging from economic mismanagement and condoning corruption to plagiarising his masters thesis and lying about his nationality.</p>
<p>He has denied all such charges and until Saturday's moves political analysts had expected Banharn to win the vote.</p>
<p>Until Saturday Banharn had showed no sign of conceding defeat and the secretary general of his main Chart Thai party Sanoh Thienthong said earlier all coalition parties had promised to vote for the premier.</p>
<p>The opposition held him responsible for this year's sharp slowdown in the Thai economy, a battered stock market near three year-lows and a baht clouded by devaluation rumours.</p>
<p>Banharn also denied he or his party accepted financial support from a foreign-born former adviser to an ailing bank. Thai political parties are forbidden to take money from foreigners.</p>
<p>Late on Friday he wound up his defence by saying he had answered all the accusations against him.</p>
<p>&quot;I have already answered all the charges,&quot; Banharn said in his final speech. &quot;From now on it depends on the judgement of the members of parliament to make a decision on my fate.&quot;</p>
<p>Opposition leader Chuan Leekpai of the Democrat Party said in his final statement on Friday that Banharn had failed to answer adequately the accusations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
