<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="687683" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's Peters outlines priorities for first budget.</title>
<headline>NZ's Peters outlines priorities for first budget.</headline>
<byline>Vernon Small</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand Treasurer Winston Peters on Wednesday promised his first budget, due on Thursday, would be good for health and education, within the constraints of running a sound economy.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be good for education, I promise you,&quot; Peters told Roseneath Primary School principal John Reynolds during a pre-budget photo opportunity.</p>
<p>Peters broke with the convention of his predecessors by not posing with the first copy of the budget to roll off the printing press. He opted instead to go to the Wellington school.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we should go with tradition. I think we should go with things which indicate where our greatest priorities lie. In this ... budget with key areas like education and health, alongside running a sound economy,&quot; Peters said.</p>
<p>His budget, the first by the centre-right coalition of his nationalist New Zealand First Party and conservative National, will include NZ$950 million ($650 million) in new spending in 1997/98 and a surplus expected to be between $1.5 billion and $1.7 billion -- only half that forecast in March.  </p>
<p>Despite the worsening fiscal position, the coalition has said it will still deliver the NZ$5 billion in extra spending spread over three years agreed by the coalition in December.</p>
<p>The budget is seen as crucial to rebuilding the fortunes of Peters' party and the coalition.</p>
<p>New Zealand First's popularity has fallen from 13 percent on election night to less than five per cent, and a Television One poll on Tuesday showed approval for the government at just 13 percent and disapproval running at 78 percent.  </p>
<p>Spending priorities were well signalled in the coalition agreement, and the budget should show a mix of the open market, fiscally-conservative leanings of National and the push by NZ First for more social spending and for programmes to help Maori.</p>
<p>Peters has said the budget will stress the need for greater self-reliance, while Prime Minister Jim Bolger has talked of the need to improve what he calls &quot;social capital&quot; through encouraging community and volunteer organisation.</p>
<p>But these are seen as political position taking lines rather than a sign of any major initiatives in the budget.  </p>
<p>Peters said on Wednesday it would include an already announced $100 million in tax cuts for low income working families and extra spending on housing.</p>
<p>But the biggest spending areas signalled in the coalition deal were $378 million on health, and $384 million on education in the 1997/98 year as well as a $300 milllion boost to the capital expenditure set to be aimed at those two areas.</p>
<p>It also promised to remove a surtax on pensions from April 1998, although the full impact of around $300 million a year will not be felt until the 1998/99 year.  </p>
<p>Despite pressure from near neighbour Australia, defence spending is not earmarket to increase.</p>
<p>Peters was an outspoken critic of the previous government's asset sales and in particular of sales to foreigners. The coalition has clearly ruled out selling strategic assets including NZ Post, power generators ECNZ and Contact Energy as well as electricity grid operator Transpower.</p>
<p>But National's asset sales programme, stalled by its fragile majority in the House before last October's election, is set to resume with the sale of Government Property Services' $160 million portfolio and other small state-owned trading companies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
