<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="687671" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian dlr finds mixed message in Japan growth.</title>
<headline>Australian dlr finds mixed message in Japan growth.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar slumped against the yen at midday as the market scented a sea change in the Japanese economy which just might lead to the first policy tightening there since August 1990.</p>
<p>Analysts had to radically reappraise the outlook for growth after the Bank of Japan's Tankan survey of business sentiment showed industry was far more upbeat than anyone had imagined.</p>
<p>Japanese bond yields rose sharply as a result and both the local and U.S. dollars lost ground to the yen, although analysts did note that a stronger Japanese economy should be bullish for Australian commodity prices and the A$ in the longer term.  </p>
<p>This prospect, albeit a distant one for the instantaneous world of forex markets, may have helped keep the dollar steady at US$0.7499/04 from an early US$0.7501/06.</p>
<p>That was down on Tuesday's late US$0.7518/23 but well within the US$0.7470/7540 range held since the start of last week.</p>
<p>The rise in Japanese yields was real and immediate, however, and saw the local currency slapped down to 85.00/10 yen from 86.05/15 just before the data hit dealing screens.</p>
<p>In this it mirrored the U.S. dollar which sank to 113.30 yen from 114.80 as the market contemplated an end to the BOJ's ultra-easy policy stance.  </p>
<p>The easing process began officially in July 1991 when the discount rate stood at 6.00 percent and culminated in December 1995 when a 0.50 point cut took it to just 0.50 percent.</p>
<p>The market always knew rates would have to turn higher eventually but had thought the BOJ would hold off until at least the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>The Tankan looked to have changed that with the December 3-month Euroyen futures contract jumping 14 basis points to 99.01, implying a rate of 0.99 percent. The March contract leapt 19 basis points to 98.75 and June 20 basis points to 98.53 -- suggesting scope for a full one point ODR hike in the next year.  </p>
<p>The Tankan's main diffusion index for large manufacturing firms showing a reading of plus 7.0 in June against plus 2.0 in March and expectations of a slight fall.</p>
<p>The shock was all the greater since the market had been lulled by rumours the June survey would be depressed by the economic volatility surrounding a hike in VAT rates in April.</p>
<p>Instead, manufacturing industry seemed to have weathered the disruption remarkably well and were more confident than at any time since 1991.</p>
<p>And the improvement was expected to last with the BOJ forecasting a diffusion index of plus 8.0 for September.  </p>
<p>The improvement was far from universal, however, and indeed owed much to export growth while domestic demand had turned lower after the VAT hike.</p>
<p>The sentiment index for non-manufacturing actually eased to minus 8.0 from minus 7.0 in March and that for small firms improved only marginally to minus 7.0 from minus 8.0.</p>
<p>&quot;The Tankan highlights the continued lop-sided nature of Japan's economic recovery,&quot; said Bankers Trust economist David Bassanese. &quot;The strong showing by manufacturers does incresae the chance of a hike later this year, but the authorities may want to first see if the outlook for other sectors improves.&quot;  </p>
<p>A stronger Japanese economy had positive implications for the A$ which could compensate for narrowing yield differentials.</p>
<p>Japan was the single largest consumer of Australian commodities, which make up over 60 percent of the country's exports, so faster growth there should lead to a greater demand for, and a higher price of, goods like coal and copper.</p>
<p>Analysts said the relationship was so close the main Tankan index had a good correlation with the RBA commodity price index, leading it higher and lower over time. If that held true then the decisive rise in the June Tankan promised to lift commodity prices to the benefit of the A$. --Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
