<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="687731" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai copper ends limit-down on LME losses.</title>
<headline>Shanghai copper ends limit-down on LME losses.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai copper futures ended limit-down across the board on Wednesday on heavy overnight losses on the London Metal Exchange (LME), traders said.</p>
<p>The most actively traded October 1997 contract ended at an intraday low of 22,280 yuan ($2,686) per tonne, losing 710 yuan. It opened at 22,430 and hit a high of 22,490 yuan per tonne.</p>
<p>July fell 640 to 21,890, August 640 to 22,030, September 680 to 22,190, November 710 to 22,340, December 710 to 22,330 yuan.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 111,055 tonnes from 50,380 tonnes.</p>
<p>Copper opened sharply lower and fell further until all contracts closed at the limit-down level.  </p>
<p>On the LME, three months copper last traded at $2,437 a tonne, down $74 from Monday's close, after touching a five-week low of $2,430 a tonne.</p>
<p>LME traders said the failure of the market to convincingly pierce $2,600 earlier in the month, a narrowing in the spread, a few small warehouse stock increases and the approaching summer slow-down all combined to take the heat out of the buy side.</p>
<p>Traders in London said copper looked set to tumble to $2,350 if prices breached $2,400 on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Shanghai traders said these losses destroyed the confidence of local investors who have seen prices fall in the previous two sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;Large amounts of stop-loss selling orders poured into the market on Wednesday, accelerating the downward trend,&quot; a Shanghai trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Market sentiment was extremely pessimistic with long position holders eventually giving up the territory they had dominated for a long period,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The physical price in the Shanghai area plunged to the 22,000/100 yuan level in late Wednesdady, down from 22,600 on Tuesday due to heavy futures losses, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders said technical charts indicated a continued downward trend despite the downside trading of the past three days.</p>
<p>&quot;A mid- and long-term downward trend seems to have taken shape though copper is likely to rebound slightly from time to time in between,&quot; a second traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The next support will be at the 20,000 yuan level.&quot;  </p>
<p>Aluminium futures also ended limit-down.</p>
<p>July fell 390 to 13,510, August 280 to 13,630, September 410 to 13,690, October 460 to 14,020 and November 460 to 14,160 yuan per tonne.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 1,600 tonnes from 1,050 tonnes.</p>
<p>($1=8.2905 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Shanghai Newsroom (8621) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
