<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="687857" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Product Swap - Diesel steady, regrade widens.</title>
<headline>Asia Product Swap - Diesel steady, regrade widens.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore gas oil swaps were steady by midday on Wednesday as players seemed comfortable with present levels following sellers' attempts to move higher last week, brokers and traders said.</p>
<p>Jet fuel values inched higher amid sentiment that demand for the product was better compared to gas oil, with more buyers seen for swaps regrade.</p>
<p>July swaps were indicated at $22.20/$22.40 per barrel, August at $22.70/$22.90 and September at $23.25/$23.50, all barely unchanged from Tuesday's levels.  </p>
<p>On Tuesday, the lowest traded level for July was $22.22 and the highest at $22.40, while August was traded between $22.80 and $22.88 per barrel.</p>
<p>July regrade was bid at $1.60, up 10 cents from Tuesday, while August was at $1.60/$1.75, five to 10 cents over Tuesday. Traders said the physical market still awaited China's third quarter import licenses to help soak up excessive regional demand.  </p>
<p>But there were concerns that the license might not be issued or the quota could be limited as Chinese refiners were worried with their own high stocks which were forcing down domestic retail values.</p>
<p>Because of this, Chinese demand remained scattered.</p>
<p>Nevertheless current low prices were too attractive for Chinese buyers who limited their purchases to 5,000-to-10,000-tonnne parcels, instead of the usual 25,000-to-30,000-tonne cargoes.</p>
<p>The smaller lots were heard sold around $162-$165 per tonne, on a cost-and-freight basis to southern China, traders said.  </p>
<p>Physical buyers re-emerged on Tuesday to buy two cargoes offered by a Malaysian trader at $21.50 and $21.90 per barrel for mid-to-end-July lifting free-on-board (fob) basis.</p>
<p>Buyers took cover when sellers tried to offer at more than $22.00 on Monday, underlining the fact that current values are limited to the $21.50-$21.90 range, traders said.</p>
<p>Naphtha prices slipped along with weaker crudes with July swaps discussed at $20.35/$20.50, down 10 cents from Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Fuel oil remained steady as activities were muted on the physical market on Tuesday. But traders said a local trader would remain as a buyer to support the market this weak to cover its short positions on the physical market.</p>
<p>July swaps were quoted at $99.25/$100.50 per tonne and August at $98.00/$99.50.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
