<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688045" id="root" date="1997-06-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: GREEK DEPO CURVE EASES, BONDS HOLD, ECU/DRS STABLE.</title>
<headline>GREEK DEPO CURVE EASES, BONDS HOLD, ECU/DRS STABLE.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Greek interbank depo curve eased, forex forwards were also easier in calm trading and bonds were holding awaiting the outcome of the central bank's depo tender today, dealers said.</p>
<p>Trading activity in the forex market picked up without affecting the highly visible ecu/drachma rate which was trapped in the 309.10/25 band, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The short-end of the depo yield curve has eased about a tenth of a point and the long-end about five basis points,&quot; said a senior dealer at a foreign bank. &quot;Forex forwards have followed suit on the downside.&quot;</p>
<p>The dealer said the market was awaiting to see whether the Bank of Greece would leave some money into the system today to help Thursday's auction of FRNs.</p>
<p>The central bank offered to drain an unspecified amount of 14-day funds at 11.90 percent today. A pact of about 150 billion drachmas is maturing today.</p>
<p>Greece will auction 150 billion drachmas of seven-year FRNs on June 26. The first coupon is set at 10.40 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;FRN prices are stable but still low and it looks as if the finance ministry will not get the best deal out of tomorrow's auction,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign bank. &quot;Funding remains expensive and the central bank's move to buy a small amount of FRNs on Wednesday will not help much.&quot;</p>
<p>The central bank bought about 1.0 billion drachmas of seven-year FRNs due 2004 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The bond market is quiet and prices are holding,&quot; said a bond dealer. &quot;It will help if the central bank boosts liquidity today via its 14-day, fixed rate depo tender.&quot;</p>
<p>The gross redemption yield of the benchmark 10-year coupon bond due 2007 was at 9.14 percent, the five-year bond due 2002 was yielding 9.77 percent and the three-year bond due 2000 at 10.20 percent.</p>
<p>The mark was quoted at 157.76/86 from Tuesday's 157.715 fix, the dollar at 271.57/67 drachmas from 271.900 and the ecu at 309.12/22 from 309.140 drachmas.</p>
<p>&quot;Ecu/drachma opened at 309.10/15 and hit 309.20/25 before receding to 309.10/15 on light selling from domestic players,&quot; said a forex dealer at a foreign bank. &quot;There is more action on both sides of trade today.&quot;</p>
<p>The National Bank of Greece quoted the following early rates:</p>
<p>** Overnight at 11.70-12.20</p>
<p>** T/N at 11.50-12.00</p>
<p>** S/N at 11.50-12.00</p>
<p>** One week at 11.50-12.00</p>
<p>** Two weeks at 11.50-12.00</p>
<p>** Three weeks at 11.45-11.95</p>
<p>** One month at 11.40-11.90</p>
<p>** Two months at 11.40-11.90</p>
<p>** Three months at 11.30-11.80</p>
<p>** Six months at 10.90-11.40</p>
<p>** Nine months at 10.75-11.25</p>
<p>** Twelve months at 10.60-11.10</p>
<p>--Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
