<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688403" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-ROBSON TO STEP DOWN AS BARCELONA COACH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ROBSON TO STEP DOWN AS BARCELONA COACH.</headline>
<dateline>BARCELONA 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bobby Robson has been told he will not continue as Barcelona first team coach next season although he is expected to stay at the club.</p>
<p>&quot;They told me 10 days ago,&quot; said Robson, in remarks published in the Spanish sport daily 'Marca' on Thursday.</p>
<p>The former England manager, who is expected to stay on at the club in a different capacity, said he would not discuss his future any further until after Saturday's Spanish Cup final.</p>
<p>&quot;I know it's going to be my last game on the bench of the first team, and it is very important for me to say goodbye with a win,&quot; said Robson, in an interview with 'El Mundo Deportivo', also published on Thursday.</p>
<p>Robson joined Barcelona in the close season from Oporto in a move that was rushed through after the sacking of Johan Cruyff.</p>
<p>But Robson struggled to escape from the shadow of Cruyff, who had become the club's most successful coach ever in his eight years at Barcelona.</p>
<p>Despite winning the European Cup Winners' Cup, the Spanish Super Cup and a place in the Cup final, fans have found it difficult to forgive Robson for finishing second in the league to arch-rivals Real Madrid.</p>
<p>He has also been blamed for using unsophisticated tactics with one of Europe's most talented squads.</p>
<p>Ajax coach Louis van Gaal is the man most commentators feel will take over on the bench at the Camp Nou stadium.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BARCELONA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
