<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688594" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CONGO: Brazzaville population flees heaviest fighting.</title>
<headline>Brazzaville population flees heaviest fighting.</headline>
<byline>Emmanuel Braun</byline>
<dateline>BRAZZAVILLE 1996-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of civilians have poured out of Brazzaville, fleeing the heaviest fighting in a three-week-old war believed to have killed more than 1,000.</p>
<p>At least 17,000 people have fled from the inner suburbs since a merciless battle erupted on Wednesday for the airport, an international Red Cross (ICRC) spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The fighting between pro and anti-president factions raged for most of Thursday and subsided only slightly as night fell. It dashed hopes of the swift deployment of a U.N. peacekeeping force.</p>
<p>The remaining foreign Red Cross staff also pulled out by boat from the former French colonial capital to its former Belgian colonial twin city Kinshasa, over the Congo river.</p>
<p>&quot;They have all left,&quot; ICRC spokesman Paolo dell'Oca said.</p>
<p>The city they left behind them was plunged deeper into chaos with an artillery battle for Maya-Maya airport.</p>
<p>Between 1,000 and 3,000 people are estimated to have died in the clashes between the forces of President Pascal Lissouba and his enemy Denis Sassou Nguesso, Congo's Marxist leader for 13 years.</p>
<p>The two had been rivals in presidential elections due to be held in a month's time.</p>
<p>The Bacongo suburb, once a haven of peace held by neutral city mayor Bernard Kolelas, has been hit by dozens of shells.</p>
<p>Several landed in the maternity ward of a hospital on Wednesday, killing a woman who was giving birth.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know how many wounded there are. The staff, the patients, everyone fled,&quot; hospital spokesman Faustin Missakila said, standing amid the shattered buildings.</p>
<p>Despite the shelling, Kolelas hosted fresh mediation talks but without clear progress.</p>
<p>A week-long ceasefire he brokered took some sting out of the battles and let 1,250 French soldiers leave peacefully after evacuating foreigners, but then collapsed.</p>
<p>Losing Maya-Maya, about five km (three miles) from the city centre, would be a big blow to Lissouba. Both sides claimed control of the airport but there was no independent confirmation.</p>
<p>Sassou's aides claimed Lissouba was bringing in Liberian and Angolan UNITA mercenaries to help fight back.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRAZZAVILLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CONGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
