<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688605" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria delay seen hurting First Aluminium.</title>
<headline>Nigeria delay seen hurting First Aluminium.</headline>
<byline>Elu Okolo</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A delay in the startup of Nigeria's aluminium smelter plant would affect the fortunes the country's major user, First Aluminium Plc, dealers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The semi-official Business Times newspaper said on Monday the smelter at Ikot Abasi in southeastern Akwa Ibom state would not be commissioned this month as scheduled because it had not been fully completed.</p>
<p>Traders said First Aluminium was expecting to save large sums on imports of raw materials by buying it locally from smelter company ALSCON.</p>
<p>&quot;Localisation of our raw materials will bring huge benefits in terms of reduction in costs and hence lower market prices of our products,&quot; Gavin Barlas, managing director of First Aluminium said in the annual report, adding that the project was of vital importance to the future of the company.</p>
<p>The plant was originally scheduled to go on stream last October but was postponed till March this year.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the smelter said on Thursday that the commissioning was now postponed to October because of lack of raw materials and adequate working capital.</p>
<p>&quot;Procurement of alumina and other inputs as well as working capital forced the shift in the commissioning date of the plant,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nigeria is seeking to buy the bulk of the 375,000 tonnes of alumina for the plant from Guinea.</p>
<p>A delegation from Guinea was in the country recently for talks on the deal, the ALSCON official said.</p>
<p>The 180,000 tonnes a year project, begun in 1990, is a joint venture between Nigeria, which has a 70 percent stake, Ferrostaal AG of Germany and Reynolds International of the U.S., which share the rest of the equity.</p>
<p>The two technical partners have formed a subsidiary to manage the plant for the next 10 years.</p>
<p>Although the World Bank is critical of the project, saying it is ill-conceived and expensive, Nigeria defended it, arguing it will earn foreign currency from exports and reduce imports of ingots and billets for local aluminium products industry.</p>
<p>First Aluminium closed unchanged at 3.60 naira at the Nigerian stock market on Thursday.</p>
<p>Monte Carlo-based Alucon Holdings S.A. holds 60 percent of the company while the Nigerian public has the remaining 40 percent.</p>
<p>($1=85 naira) -Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
