<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688665" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African short-term money mkt rates continue fall.</title>
<headline>S.African short-term money mkt rates continue fall.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African short-term money market rates fell again on Thursday in line with increasing optimism that economic fundamentals point to an interest rate cut, possibly in the third quarter, dealers said.</p>
<p>Three-month NCD rates were quoted at 15.85 percent offered from overnight levels of between 15.95 and 15.90 percent offered, as the daily shortage dipped to 5.278 billion rand on Wedenesday from 5.492 billion rand on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The BA rate stood at between 15.45 to 15.25 percent from 15.50 and 15.35 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically everything's pointing in the right direction. As long as there are no massive outflows (when forex controls are eased on July 1), rates are going to come off,&quot; said UAL Merchant Bank general treasury manager Chris Doyle.</p>
<p>He said the decline in three to 12 month interest rates reflected the call in the market for an interest rate, assuming there were no massive capital outflows after the July 1 forex easing which will allow individuals to invest offshore.</p>
<p>Comments by Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals on economic fundamentals, specifically the most recent consumer inflation rate, were also turning more positive, dealers noted.</p>
<p>&quot;Stals is now starting to talk positive, saying he is very encouraged by (the latest) CPI number,&quot; Doyle said.</p>
<p>Consumer inflation came in at a 9.5 percent year-on-year rate in May from 9.9 percent in April.</p>
<p>Call rates had not reacted, probably in line with month-end pressures and caution on the part of banks ahead of the exchange control relaxation, dealers added.</p>
<p>Commenting on the recent decline in short-term interest rates on the interbank market, Stals told state radio early on Thursday:</p>
<p>&quot;We think that is right, that is the trend we should expect for the rest of the year...The Reserve Bank is still a little bit reluctant to take any lead in bringing interest rates down. We want to make sure we consolidate the position that the inflation rate will come down.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
