<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688767" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo to invest $80mln by 2000 in copper mine.</title>
<headline>Yugo to invest $80mln by 2000 in copper mine.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslav copper mine Rudnik bakra Majdanpek plans to invest $80 million by the year 2000 in its reconstruction, Belgrade daily Politika reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Majdanpek mine is part of the mining and smelting complex Rudarsko-topionicarski basen Bor (RTB Bor) which groups some 20 enterprises.</p>
<p>The Bor copper complex has invested three million dollars in the reconstruction of the Majdanpek copper mine and will invest another three million by the end of the year, the paper quoted Majdanpek's acting manager Zivorad Stanisavljevic as saying.</p>
<p>Majdanpek excavated in January-May period a total of 11.78 million tonnes of material, up 3.28 million tonnes on the same period in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The thirty percent January-May incease (on the same period last year) is encouraging and indicates the started mine reconstruction will give good results,&quot; Stanisavljevic said.</p>
<p>Results would have been better if the recently bought new machines had arrived on time, he added. Five new trucks are expected to arrive by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The mine soon expects to reach annual production of some eight million tonnes of copper ore, the level to be maintained during its reconstruction.</p>
<p>After reconstruction, the mine expects to produce some ten million tonnes of ore annually, or between 30,000 and 35,000 tonnes of copper in concentrate.</p>
<p>Technology in the flotation has been improved and now it can process 23,000-24,000 tonnes of ore daily.</p>
<p>Geologic exploration determined a reserve of two million tonnes of ore containing an average of 0.5 percent of copper in the southern part of the surface mine.</p>
<p>Additional drilling indicates there is a reserve of 4.5 million tonnes of ore with the same content of copper.</p>
<p>This is a much better percentage of ore than currently exploited which is 0.3 and in some places 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>Exploitation of a 2.1 million tonnes deposit of ore containing copper, zinc, gold and lead is expected to start by the end of next year.</p>
<p>&quot;This is expected to be very profitable because of the rich metal content of the ore,&quot; Stanisavljevic said.</p>
<p>Experts from Majdanpek, Bor and specialised Belgrade institutes have been engaged to determine an adequate ore processing technology.</p>
<p>&quot;Some $5 million are expected to be invested in a flotation equipped with the most advanced technology to process all the ores,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>- Beti Bilandzic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 222 43 05</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
