<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688708" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Japan boats shot at near disputed Russian islands.</title>
<headline>Japan boats shot at near disputed Russian islands.</headline>
<byline>Denis Dyomkin</byline>
<dateline>VLADIVOSTOK, Russia 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian border guards opened fire on four Japanese boats that entered Russia's territorial waters near disputed islands off northern Japan, a border guard spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Border guards fired at the vessels, which then left. I cannot confirm or deny whether anybody was hurt,&quot; Pacific Ocean border guards' spokesman Sergei Kozlyov told Reuters in this Russian Far Eastern port city, which faces Japan.</p>
<p>He said the Japanese vessels had disregarded the border guards' warning signals. Earlier on Thursday, a Japanese coastguard spokesman said an unidentified ship had fired on a Japanese fishing boat, wounding two crew members, one seriously.</p>
<p>He said dense fog had cut visibility in the area at the time of the incident late on Wednesday and added that it was not clear whether the Japanese boat involved, the Eiko-maru, had strayed across the Russian side of the demarcation line.</p>
<p>Moscow has repeatedly accused Japanese fishing boats of poaching in its waters around the Russian-held Southern Kurile Islands, which Tokyo claims as its Northern Territories.</p>
<p>Last August, Russian patrol boats opened fire on two small Japanese fishing boats in the area, seriously injuring two crewmen. Less serious incidents are fairly commonplace.</p>
<p>The Japanese Foreign Ministry has approached the Russian government about Wednesday's incident but Moscow appeared to be taking a firm line, despite a recent warming of traditionally frosty ties between the two former Cold War foes.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Valery Nesterushkin described the behaviour of the Japanese vessels as provocative.</p>
<p>&quot;Attempts to ignore the existing (territorial) status quo are not only fruitless but can harm the postitive atmosphere emerging in the Russian-Japanese relations,&quot; he told a regular ministry news briefing, reading out a prepared statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that the Japanese side will take steps to rule out such incidents in the future,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The commander of the federal marine border guard forces defended the use of force against ships that transgressed Russia's territorial waters.</p>
<p>&quot;The federal border guard service has applied and will continue to apply all measures for the decisive suppression of border violations and the poaching of marine products in Russia's territorial waters,&quot; Admiral Innokenti Nalyotov told Interfax news agency.</p>
<p>He said the border guards had stepped up patrols of the area round the disputed islands, which contains rich fishing grounds.</p>
<p>Japan has refused to sign a World War Two peace treaty with Moscow without the return of the islands, located northeast of Hokkaido, one of Japan's four main islands. The two countries normalised relations in 1956.</p>
<p>Both sides have recently shown a more flexible attitude on the islands issue in a bid to help improve their wider ties.</p>
<p>During a summit meeting of the Group of Seven main industrialised nations in the U.S. city of Denver last week President Boris Yeltsin said Russia would no longer point nuclear missiles at Japan.</p>
<p>Kremlin spokesman Sergei Yastrzhembsky said on Wednesday that Yeltsin and Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto had agreed to begin regular meetings and said the Denver talks had created a &quot;qualitatively new&quot; spirit in bilateral ties.</p>
<p>He said the two countries were due to sign in the next few days a deal granting Japan rights to catch 26,000 tonnes of salmon in Russian coastal waters next year.</p>
<p>Yeltsin and Hashimoto are expected to hold an informal weekend meeting in the Russian Far East or Siberia before the end of the year, Yastrzhembsky said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VLADIVOSTOK, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
