<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688731" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatia says war crimes court treats it unfairly.</title>
<headline>Croatia says war crimes court treats it unfairly.</headline>
<byline>Laura Lui</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Croatian government said on Thursday it remained committed to cooperation with the U.N. war crimes tribunal but was unhappy with what it described as the court's unfair treatment of Croatia, state media said.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite its high level of cooperation Croatia has been exposed to the strongest political pressures to the extent of being accused of alleged non-cooperation,&quot; state news agency HINA quoted Justice Minister Miroslav Separovic as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Problems in (Croatia's) relationship with the Hague tribunal are mostly due to its unbalanced and unequal approach towards the former Yugoslav republics, to the detriment of Croatia,&quot; Separovic said after the weekly cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>The International Criminal Tribunal for former Yugoslavia was set up in 1993 and has so far indicted 75 war crimes suspects -- 54 Serbs, 18 Croats and three Moslems. Only eight are in its custody.</p>
<p>Croatia passed a special law on cooperation with the tribunal in April 1996 which obliges it to hand over war crimes suspects found on its territory.</p>
<p>Following U.S. pressure to comply with the court, it extradited one suspect this April. Last year Bosnian Croat General Tihomir Blaskic handed himself over to The Hague voluntarily and his trial began on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The World Bank this week delayed discussion on a $30 million loan to Croatia after a U.S. request, as Washington judged Croatia had not followed through on commitments to extradite war crimes suspects.</p>
<p>But Zagreb claims it does not know the whereabouts of other Croat suspects despite reports some were seen in the country.</p>
<p>The government said it was &quot;worrisome&quot; that only three men had been accused of war crimes committed against Croatians in 1991 and one for the bombing of Zagreb in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Only three men have been accused for 1991 for 13,000 killed, 40,000 wounded, numerous mass crimes...and nothing is being done about it now,&quot; Foreign Minister Mate Granic told state radio.</p>
<p>&quot;It is simply incredible that no one at all has been accused for crimes against Croats in Bosnia,&quot; echoed Prime Minister Zlatko Matesa on the radio report.</p>
<p>The Croatian government also said it was unhappy with the court's treatment of Blaskic with regard to his detention conditions and a 15-month delay of the beginning of his trial.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the court's duty to secure a speedy and fair trial for the accused,&quot; Separovic said.</p>
<p>Separately, 11 Bosnian Croats indicted by the tribunal for war crimes against Moslems in central Bosnia sent an open letter to the U.N. Security Council, saying they were appalled by the court's &quot;cruel treatment&quot; of Blaskic.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all ready to travel to The Hague and face indictments against us to defend our names and honour, but we have a reason to be worried that we will receive similar cruel and unjust treatment,&quot; they wrote.</p>
<p>They also demanded that the tribunal withdraw an indictment against a Bosnian Croat suspect who they claim lived in the Netherlands during the war and died there in 1995, before he was accused.</p>
<p>The government also said it would propose to the tribunal that Croatia should be allowed to try Croatian suspects captured on its territory, under the tribunal's supervision.</p>
<p>HINA said the government would forward its views to the tribunal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
