<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688887" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: U.S. denies Russian spy plane charges.</title>
<headline>U.S. denies Russian spy plane charges.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Solovyov</byline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. embassy on Thursday denied Russian accusations that an American research plane carrying out geographical surveys of Kazakh territory had spy equipment on board to snoop on neighbouring Russian regions.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very open, scientific mission, and there is nothing secret about it...Everything on board that airplane is open scientific equipment,&quot; U.S. embassy press attache Karen Williams told Reuters. &quot;It is not spy equipment.&quot;</p>
<p>Russia's Foreign Ministry issued an angry statement on Tuesday saying an Orion P-3 scientific plane, which is carrying out geological research over resource-rich Kazakh territory adjoining Russia, has spy equipment on board.</p>
<p>&quot;A dangerous precedent of using the territory of one CIS (Commonwealth of Independent States) state to spy on other states is being created. We expect that the flights of the U.S. Orion P-3 plane over the territory adjoining the Russian Federation will be stopped without delay,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>In Moscow, visiting U.S. Deputy Secretary of Defence John White told reporters: &quot;I know nothing about this specific issue or this statement. We co-ordinate very closely with the Russians on air space and have total transparency. Other than that, I can't comment.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the subject did not come up during his talks on Wednesday with Russian Defence Minister Igor Sergeyev, the first encounter between the new minister and a U.S. government representative.</p>
<p>In the 1950s and early 1960s, U.S. spy planes flew over Soviet territory. On May 1, 1960, a Soviet missile brought down a U.S. U2 spy plane, sparking one of the hottest moments of the Cold War era.</p>
<p>Williams said the Orion scientific flights, which started on June 24, will be carried out until July 11. The geographical surveys were a joint project involving Kazakhstan's Ministry of Science, the U.S. Department of Energy and a number of U.S. reaserch laboratories, she said.</p>
<p>The work includes &quot;photography of geological features, which geologists look at and say whether or not there is a certain mineral in Kazakhstan&quot;, Williams said.</p>
<p>She said besides flights over the Central Asian state's southern Almaty region the plane was also researching areas in the northeastern Semipalatinsk region which borders Russia.</p>
<p>Williams said flights over Semipalatinsk were to study environmental effects of the former Soviet Union's weapons testing areas, including nuclear sites, which sprawl for hundreds of miles.</p>
<p>She said a group of Russian journalists, including a correspondent of the Russian Defence Ministry's Krasnaya Zvezda newspaper, were invited to see the plane when it arrived in the capital Almaty last Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We invited them on purpose, because we wanted to be open about what the mission was and what the plane was,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
