<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688879" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Mir, mission control in intense talks on repairs.</title>
<headline>Mir, mission control in intense talks on repairs.</headline>
<dateline>KOROLYOV, Russia 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Russian-American crew of the damaged Mir space station were engaged in intensive discussions with Mission Control near Moscow on Thursday and officials said repairs would be agreed on within hours.</p>
<p>A 20-minute exchange between Mir and Earth was devoted entirely to urgent technical discussion between the cosmonauts and large numbers of experts who have gathered at Mission Control in Korolyov.  </p>
<p>Poor atmospheric conditions meant there were no clear pictures of the exchange.</p>
<p>Mir's Russian commander Vasily Tsibliyev could be heard by reporters at mission control asking: &quot;Should we switch on button B2?&quot; &quot;Yes, try it,&quot; replied Mission Control. &quot;What's the result?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Not clear,&quot; the cosmonaut replied. &quot;Then try it again,&quot; came the voice of the ground-based expert.</p>
<p>Officials said a commission set up to deal with the damage caused on Wednesday by a collision with a cargo craft would announce the strategy for repairing the solar power supply and punctured Spektr module at 1000 GMT.</p>
<p>Before then a further exchange session with the crew was planned. Communications with Mir are not always possible as the craft passes on its orbit out of Mission Control's radio field. NASA representatives at Korolyov declined to comment until after the repair strategy is announced.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KOROLYOV, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
