<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="688819" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Mir crew to use newest space lifeboat if needed.</title>
<headline>Mir crew to use newest space lifeboat if needed.</headline>
<byline>Andrei Khalip</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>If the crew aboard Moscow's damaged Mir space station have to abandon ship, the two Russian cosmonauts and their British-born American colleague have the latest in a long line of Soyuz &quot;lifeboats&quot; ready and waiting.</p>
<p>Russia and the now-defunct Soviet Union have used more than two dozen Soyuz TM craft to ferry cosmonauts up to Mir and to bring them back down to Earth since the station was first put into orbit 11 years ago.</p>
<p>Officials say the crew are in no immediate danger following Wednesday's collision between an unmanned cargo tug and the intricate orbiting complex.</p>
<p>&quot;In case they need to return they will use the newest (Soyuz) TM-25 capsule,&quot; said a duty officer at Russia's Federal Aviation and Space Search and Rescue Service in Moscow.</p>
<p>The seven-tonne Soyuz TM-25 is the newest model of a well-tested series.</p>
<p>The officer told Reuters by telephone the capsule, capable of taking three cosmonauts up or down, was docked to Mir in February, when it brought crew commander Vasily Tsibliyev, engineer Alexander Lazutkin and German cosmonaut Reinhold Ewald to the Mir station.</p>
<p>Ewald later returned to Earth in Soyuz TM-24 with two Russian cosmonauts who had been in orbit since August 1996. NASA astronaut Michael Foale, a British-born American physicist, flew up to Mir aboard the space shuttle Atlantis in May.</p>
<p>&quot;The (Soyuz) capsule is used as a 'shuttle' for Mir operators. They go up and down in the same Soyuz TM,&quot; the duty officer said, adding that Russia had launched a spare unmanned Soyuz TM-1 in 1986.</p>
<p>It was not clear whether the TM-1 was still docked to the sprawling Mir complex as a reserve lifeboat.</p>
<p>The Soyuz TM craft is a squat bullet-shaped capsule built to withstand the intense heat on re-entry into the Earth's atmosphere.</p>
<p>The capsule floats down under bright orange parachutes and usually lands in the empty steppe of the Central Asian state of Kazakhstan, scorched and scuffed from the descent and dwarfed by the vast open country.</p>
<p>Half a dozen helicopters are quickly on the scene. Experts and medical staff disembark, open the Soyuz hatch, set up tents and chairs and help the cosmonauts out.</p>
<p>Wednesday's incident was described by Russian Mission Control as one of the worst Mir has experienced since it was sent aloft in February 1986.</p>
<p>&quot;At present there is no danger for the cosmonauts,&quot; Russian Space Agency chief Yuri Koptev told reporters at Mission Control near Moscow. &quot;There are no grounds for evacuating the cosmonauts from Mir at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>The ageing station's Spektr module has been sealed off after being holed and losing its air supply during a manual docking with an unmanned Progress supply craft on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Officials said repairs would be agreed on within hours but that it could take nearly two weeks before the work can be carried out.</p>
<p>The launch of a relief craft, originally a routine supply mission planned for Friday, has been delayed by at least 10 days to gather equipment needed for the repairs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
