<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68896" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SNB policy takes SFR rate into account - Gehrig.</title>
<headline>SNB policy takes SFR rate into account - Gehrig.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREUX, Switzerland 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss National Bank (SNB) monetary policy takes the Swiss franc exchange rate into account from time to time, but efforts to steer its market levels can only be temporary, said SNB director Bruno Gehrig.</p>
<p>&quot;Although our policy is mainly directed at long-term stability of price levels, using as an intermediate goal the central bank monetary aggregate, we are anything but indifferent about the franc exchange rate,&quot; Gehrig said.</p>
<p>&quot;But a continual battle against the market, based on all (past) experience, would end in a macro economic fiasco, in increased cyclical instability and all its added the social and economic burdens,&quot; Gehrig said.</p>
<p>His comments were contained in the text of a speech to be delivered to the foreign exchange dealers' club, Forex Suisse.</p>
<p>The Swiss franc level &quot;is far too important for securing the competitive ability, and employment in our country&quot; to be ignored, he said.</p>
<p>Gehrig emphasised that price stability demands a monetary trend, which is directed at growth potential.</p>
<p>The SNB bases its policy on a monetary growth path target, which aims at having money supply grow to accommodate a rising trend in potential output, as opposed to actual output.</p>
<p>But Gehrig said short-term deviations could be tolerated in certain unusual and extreme cases.</p>
<p>Economists have said this could include situations in which inflation is low and actual output is below potential, as is currently the case in Switzerland, or if the exchange rate is much stronger than the SNB would like.</p>
<p>&quot;Price level stability demands a monetary (growth) trend which is directed towards growth potential. In the interim, significant deviations from the trend are possible and can be used as measures against damaging distortions of monetary prerequisites,&quot; Gehrig said.</p>
<p>Even though financial markets were more resilient now than they had been in the past, this did not allow &quot;blind passivity&quot; in cases of extreme temporary phases of over- or under-shooting of currency levels in situations of pronounced uncertainty, Gehrig said.</p>
<p>Regarding foreign exchange business, he said planned European Monetary Union (EMU) would reduce transaction volume in many European centres, given that fewer currencies will be involved in cross trade.</p>
<p>But he said foreign exchange volume was likely to remain respectable in Switzerland, which has declined to join the EMU.</p>
<p>Gehrig said new opportunities were likely to result from heightened awareness of &quot;exotic&quot; currencies and trade in non-traditional emerging market currencies would offer attractive margins and profits, provided that risk is adequately covered.</p>
<p>Derivatives also promise favourable margins, but here too, participants must be aware of potential risks.</p>
<p>Lack of harmonisation in various national payment systems and time zone differences continued to pose settlement risk.</p>
<p>He noted that in Switzerland, over 80 percent of daily total turnover is processed by the Swiss national payment system Swiss Interbank Clearing (SIC).</p>
<p>Regulators, including those in member countries of the Group of 10 major industrial countries, are studying strategies to reduce the risk, such as multi-lateral clearing systems.</p>
<p>&quot;At the collective level of banking, netting agreements and multi-currency settlement systems can bring a significant contribution towards defusing the problem,&quot; Gehrig said.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial, +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREUX, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
