<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68900" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algeria says security in country is improving.</title>
<headline>Algeria says security in country is improving.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algerian President Liamine Zeroual, whose government has been battling Moslem fundamentalist rebels for nearly five years, said on Saturday the security situation in the country was improving.</p>
<p>An estimated 50,000 people have been killed in Algeria's violence since early 1992 when the authorities cancelled a general election which radical Islamists were poised to win.</p>
<p>&quot;The security situation (in Algeria) is improving markedly compared with the years 1993, 1994 and even in early 1995,&quot; Zeroual was quoted by the official Algerian news agency APS as telling a news conference in Algiers.</p>
<p>At the news conference, Zeroual invited opposition parties into his government. He told reporters: &quot;The idea (to broaden government) is not a new initiative...The main point is to associate all political partners in the country's management.&quot;</p>
<p>Diplomats said the invitation did not extend to the Islamic Salvation Front (FIS), barred from government in 1992 despite its electoral successes. Nor did the diplomats expect Algeria's main secular parties to join the government.</p>
<p>Zeroual described Moslem guerrillas fighting his rule as &quot;mercenaries, traitors and criminals&quot; and acknowledged that they still represented a threat.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course, there still remain some problems but the Algerian state has at its disposal all means to wipe out this phenomenon unknown to our society,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Independent analysts say political killings are still a regular occurrence in Algeria.</p>
<p>&quot;The violence still goes on every day,&quot; one senior Western diplomat told Reuters this week. &quot;The situation is still bad, though not as bad as a year ago.&quot;</p>
<p>On Friday a leading singer, 28-year-old Bechir Boudjemaa, was found murdered in the eastern city of Constantine. He had been kidnapped by Moslem guerrillas after leaving a wedding.</p>
<p>Last month the officially appointed rights body, Human Rights National Observatory, said about 1,400 people had been killed by bombs in the past two years.</p>
<p>Diplomats say these figures are conservative.</p>
<p>Security forces reported one person had been killed and 10 wounded by a car bomb parked outside the Hotel Angleterre in central Algiers earlier this month.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the devastation to the building, the figure widely circulating, of nearly 40 deaths, seems more credible,&quot; one diplomat told Reuters. He said that the bomb went off at about 5.45 a.m. when people were sleeping.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
