<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="689021" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - June 27.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>The Peters plan: a balancing act: Treasurer Winston Peters on Thursday delivered a compromise first Budget, balancing NZ First-inspired social policy spending against keeping a tight grip on the purse strings. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Creech sees education's $111m as a down payment: Extra education expenditure of $111 million next year is less than a third of the coalition agreement's $384 million, but Education Minister sees it as a down payment. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Underclass not helped -- Anderton: The Budget did nothing to halt the growth on an alienated, improverished underclass, Alliance leader Jim Anderton told Parliament on Thursday. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Extra funding gets lukewarm response: Extra money for special education was positive, but overdue, Special Education Consumers' Coalition spokesman Cloan Makgill said on Thursday night. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Luxton calls for dairy deregulation: Commerce Minister John Luxton on Thursday mounted his fiercest attack yet on the Dairy Board, calling for the board to be corporatised and lose its export monopoly. Page 13.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Phone billing alternatives to be offered: Telecom is to offer residential customers the choice from August 1 of paying for each local call in return for a lower monthly rental or remain with the present charging system. Page 13.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>Peters bets on growing economy: Package hangs on expectation of 4.2pc rate: The credibility of the coalition government's first budget hangs on a single hook -- the expectation that the economy will grow 4.2 percent in the 1998-99 year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Promised spending on health falls short: The budget has failed to bring the promised spending boosts to health trumpeted in last year's coalition agreement.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Crusade off over state asset sales: The Treasurer, Winston Peters, has dropped his crusade against privatisation by signposting the sale of two state-owned enterprises -- Government Property Services and Vehicle Testing New Zealand.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>$1b payback target: ECNZ has been targeted for a potential $1 billion payback and a raft of state-owned enterprises will be expected to divest non-core businesses as the government moves to boost flagging coffers.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Retailers give thumbs down: Retailers have given Winston Peters' first budget the thumbs down, and say they do not believe his assurance that tax cuts will go ahead as planned enxt year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Tariff cuts cause fear of recession in car industry: New car assemblers and importers are concerned the government will cause a recession in their industry with a harn-fisted approach to announcing changes in tariffs.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE PRESS</p>
<p>A failure -- Labour: The Budget is a failure at all levels and proof that Treasurer Winston Peters is not up to the job, Labour says. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Ruling soon in power-price row: A decision may be made today or tomorrow on the South Island power price differential, Energy Minister Max Bradford says. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Alliance claims Maoris dealth a 'bitter blow': Maoris have been insulted by the Budget, opposition parties say. Page 4.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Lower surpluses surprise markets: Lower-than-expected Budget surpluses caused interest rates to firm on Thursday, while shares and the dollar remained steady. Page 18.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Govt signals readiness to end vehicle tariffs: Zero tariffs on motor vehicles are possible soon after 2000, says Commerce Minister John Luxton. Page 18.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Loophole for funds may be closed: Superannuation funds using index-linked investments to avoid capital gains tax could soon have the loophole closed. Page 18.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
