<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="689036" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ MCI tumbles as RBNZ sanctions monetary easing.</title>
<headline>NZ MCI tumbles as RBNZ sanctions monetary easing.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand monetary conditions eased sharply on Friday morning after the central bank endorsed most of a recent market-led easing.</p>
<p>By 9.30 a.m. (2130 GMT), half an hour after the Reserve Bank's June Monetary Policy Statement, the bank's nominal Monetary Conditions Index tumbled to 784.83 from 824.65 prior to the statement.</p>
<p>The RBNZ said it wanted the MCI to average 825 in the September quarter.  </p>
<p>The 90-day bank bill rate fell to 6.90 from 7.02 percent before the statement and the New Zealand dollar's Trade-Weighted Index dropped to 66.90 from 67.3.</p>
<p>The MCI is a composite of the TWI and the 90-day bank bill rate.</p>
<p>The New Zealand dollar fell to US$0.6832/39 from 0.6875.</p>
<p>In the bond market the 2000 bond yields fell to 6.68 percent percent from 6.77 percent at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>The 11/06 bond was at 7.08 percent from 7.04 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;The kiwi market was trading around 0.6855/60 (to the US dollar) when the statement came out and traded as low as 0.6825,&quot; said a Wellington bank chief foreign exchange dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to be good bids between 25 and 35 it seems to be holding the market at the moment. It was a pretty sharp sell off really.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect it to be pretty well offered now above 68 and a half and I think the pressure will remain on the downside in the next couple of days,&quot; he said, adding that the bank eased a hundred points and the market had only expected 75 at most.  </p>
<p>&quot;They are expecting another 50 point easing in the MCI in December and (the RBNZ) has also said they would tolerate 50 points one way or the other. So what we are saying now is that even though the currency has come off and the MCI is minus 39 now, it is still within the Reserve Bank's comfort range,&quot; the chief dealer said.  </p>
<p>There was no reaction in the equities market.</p>
<p>&quot;From our perspective it seems reasonably neutral,&quot; said Tim Preston at ANZ Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;With some of those growth figures being lower than Treasury's (yesterday) and the easing in conditions the one compensates the other.</p>
<p>I think the market is reacting accordingly. The (NZSE-40) index is up 3.7 (points) and it has been slightly better since the start.&quot;  </p>
<p>A money market dealer said the 100-point easing was &quot;certainly at the extreme end of expectations&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the bill market had bought initially but less than an hour after the statement it had retraced a touch.</p>
<p>&quot;The market seems to have settled a little bit just here while we evaluate things before making the next move.&quot;</p>
<p>He noted that the easing took place more through the currency than through short rates.  </p>
<p>&quot;I was actually thinking it was going to go a lot further than it has, so my view is a little bit biased by that. I think on the day we could see it get down to the low 6.80s (percent) in the 90-days,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dealers expect the yield curve to steepen over the day, with the benefits of the easing seen mainly in the short end.</p>
<p>In the back of traders minds also is the Debt Management Office's announcement on Thursday that it would issue in 1997/98 a new benchmark 10-year bond, maturing in July 2009. The issue will increase supply in the long end of the curve, which is seen lowering prices and lifting yields.  </p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
