<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="689045" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RBNZ endorses 100 b. point easing from Mar level.</title>
<headline>RBNZ endorses 100 b. point easing from Mar level.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Reserve Bank of New Zealand in its six-monthly Monetary Policy Statement on Friday said it wants monetary conditions the equivalent of 100 basis points easier than it set in its March Economic Projections.</p>
<p>The bank projected its nominal Monetary Conditions Index, which was given an arbitrary December quarter base of 1000, to average 825 over the September quarter.</p>
<p>The index is seen moving to 785 in the December quarter and to 808 in the March 1998 quarter.  </p>
<p>The bank expects underlying inflation of 0.3 percent in the June quarter, remaining flat at that level in the September and December 1997 quarters. Core inflation is then picked to drop to 0.1 percent in the March 1998 quarter.</p>
<p>In annual terms, underlying inflation is expected to be 1.0 percent in the March 1998 year, and at 1.1 and 1.7 percent for the succeeding March years.</p>
<p>In its previous forecasts in March, the bank saw inflation falling from 2.2 percent in the March 1997 year to a low of 0.8 percent in most of 1998.  </p>
<p>The MCI is a composite of 90-day bank bills and the New Zealand dollar Trade-Weighted Index. According to the bank's desired conditions of bank bills at 7.5 percent and the TWI at 68.0 set in March, the MCI was at 925.</p>
<p>The bank now sees 90-day bank bills averaging 7.0 percent in the September quarter and the TWI at 67.3.</p>
<p>The following is a table of the bank's quarterly projections: </p>
<p>		    June 1997   Sept 1997   Dec 1997    Mar 1998</p>
<p>Nominal MCI	  897	   825	 785	    808</p>
<p>TWI		     68.0	  67.3	66.9	   66.8</p>
<p>90-day bills	   7.2	   7.0	 6.9	    7.2</p>
<p>Core inflation	 0.3	   0.3	 0.3	    0.1</p>
<p>The following is a table of the bank's annual projections:</p>
<p>			  1997	  1998	  1999	 2000</p>
<p>			  (actual)    (projections) </p>
<p>Nominal MCI	  960	   829	  886	   1029</p>
<p>Real MCI	     970	   885	  905	    902</p>
<p>TWI		     66.4	  67.3	 67.2	   68.0 </p>
<p>90-day bills	   9.0	   7.1	  7.7	    8.5</p>
<p>Core inflation	 2.0	   1.0	  1.1	    1.7</p>
<p>CPI			1.8	   0.4	  1.6	    2.1</p>
<p>--Wellington newsroom (64 4) 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
