<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="689128" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Kelon gets warm welcome.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Kelon gets warm welcome.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese refrigerator-maker Guangdong Kelon Electrical Holdings Co Ltd said its first-ever loan was increased after being oversubscribed.</p>
<p>&quot;This is our first syndicated loan,&quot; said Pan Ning, chairman of the company. &quot;We hope to develop and maintain close relationships with commmercial banks.&quot;</p>
<p>The three-year loan was priced to float at 100 basis points over the London Interbank Offered Rate, and was increased to US$70 million from US$50 million originally.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, the Bank of China's floating-rate certificate of deposit (FRCD) is going the rounds, with banks expected to buy into it, if only for relationship reasons.</p>
<p>&quot;The price is quite tight,&quot; said one manager, primary markets with a Japanese bank.</p>
<p>Previous Bank of China paper was about 41 basis points, while a recent U.S. dollar issue by the Bank of China would yield substantially more if swapped into Hong Kong dollars.</p>
<p>But the deal is expected to be a big success, and a vote of confidence in the territory after the handover, she said, adding that her bank would probably join the deal.</p>
<p>She said the biggest investors in the deal would come from the territory's top group of Hong Kong dollar debt arrangers.</p>
<p>Hong Kong reverts to Chinese sovereignty on July 1 after more than 150 years of British rule.</p>
<p>The Bank of China issue straddles the handover -- it was launched on June 20 and replies are due by July 3, the first trading day after the handover holidays.</p>
<p>By Friday, the bank should have a clear idea of the success of the issue.</p>
<p>One effect of the handover is a virtual closedown of new issues, because of the three-day holiday from June 30 to July 2, and the market will not resume normal levels of activities until the second week of July.</p>
<p>Commercial Bank of Korea was said to be in the market with a US$50 million floating-rate note, but further details were not available.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the region, the Philippines central bank increased some reverse repo rates to deter speculation on the peso, which has come under pressure in baht-related speculation.</p>
<p>&quot;They're pre-empting speculation by foreign funds,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The central bank wants to avoid any widening effect in which other emerging markets' debt or currencies are tarred by the &quot;Thai factor&quot;.</p>
<p>UBS has warned investors in Korea or Thai debt not to be seduced by wide margins.</p>
<p>&quot;Outstanding issues from Korea and Thailand have widened considerably since the beginning of the year,&quot; said Steve Williams, UBS head of fixed income research and new issues.</p>
<p>&quot;At current levels, certain bonds look very cheap. Yet we would highlight the likelihood of continued spread volatility in response to ongoing structural adjustments in either country.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6371</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32840">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
