<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68913" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Prodi says Italy must be in on EU currency launch.</title>
<headline>Prodi says Italy must be in on EU currency launch.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi was quoted on Saturday as saying Italy must be among the countries to launch Europe's single currency in 1999 or risk being left behind.</p>
<p>&quot;I used to think a second group of countries could take part (in monetary union) in a successive phase,&quot; Prodi told La Stampa in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;But I no longer believe that...The countries that will be left out (of the first phase) will remain only farther and farther behind,&quot; Prodi added.</p>
<p>European Union finance ministers were meeting in Dublin on Saturday to drive forward proposals to introduce a single currency, and forge the planned Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) by January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>Top of the agenda is a so-called stability pact which would penalise member states if they ran up excssive budget deficits.</p>
<p>Ministers will also try to iron out the workings of a new Exchange Rate Mechanism (ERM) linking countries which join EMU and those which, for political or economic reasons, do not.</p>
<p>Countries wanting to join the launch face stringent targets on interest and exchange rates, inflation, budget deficits and public debt in 1997, and evaluation of their level of economic integration early in 1998.</p>
<p>Prodi said his centre-left government's 1997 budget, which is designed to achieve 32.4 trillion lire ($21 billion) in deficit cuts and must be presented to parliament by September 30, would be vital to helping Italy meet those targets.</p>
<p>&quot;The budget must be passed all in one piece and straight away,&quot; he said. ($1=1523)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
