<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="689438" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Levitt passing buck on pay-to-play - ABA official.</title>
<headline>Levitt passing buck on pay-to-play - ABA official.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chairman of an American Bar Association panel examining &quot;pay-to-play&quot; by municipal bond lawyers Thursday rejected charges by SEC Chairman Arthur Levitt that ABA is ducking the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not blind to it. We think it's terrible,&quot; Raymond Trombadore, chairman of ABA's standing committee on professional discipline, said following critical remarks by the Securities and Exchange Commission chief in Philadelphia earlier Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not resisting reform, we're calling for reform,&quot; said Trombadore, a partner with Trombadore, Seel &amp; Trombadore.</p>
<p>Trombadore's has circulated a resolution that &quot;decries&quot; lawyers that make or solicit contributions to public officials in return for bond business.</p>
<p>The resolution says ABA should ask state legislatures and regulatory agencies to adopt &quot;appropriate rules to prevent public officials from participating in this practice.&quot;</p>
<p>ABA should urge courts and regulators to enforce ethics rules that bar the practice, adds the resolution, which Trombadore's panel wants ABA delegates meeting in San Francisco in August to adopt.</p>
<p>&quot;Where are the lawyers?&quot; Levitt asked during his address. &quot;I am sorry to have to report to you that, as of today, no meaningful nationwide measure has been put in place by our country's lawyers to stop, or even slow down, 'pay-to-play.' &quot;</p>
<p>After his speech, Levitt said he would not accept a &quot;diluted&quot; alternative being developed by ABA's discipline committee.</p>
<p>But Trombadore said Levitt is passing the buck. &quot;Why doesn't he adopt a regulation as he did for dealers? If he can do it for dealers, why can't he do it for lawyers?&quot;</p>
<p>Trombadore said Levitt in the past has cited constitutional problems with regulating pay-to-play by bond lawyers.</p>
<p>But in today's speech, Levitt noted that a U.S. court has upheld the constitutionality of a Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board rule curbing pay-to-play by bond dealers, Trombadore said.</p>
<p>&quot;My committee is saying this practice ought to be stopped,&quot; Trombadore said. &quot;ABA should enforce our rules and issuers and regulators ought to adopt meausres. He's saying he can't do that.&quot;</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
