<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="689487" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Senators want tobacco execs to admit &quot;lies&quot;.</title>
<headline>Senators want tobacco execs to admit &quot;lies&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senators vilified tobacco companies Thursday for deceit, hypocrisy and hurting children and predicted the proposed tobacco deal would founder in Congress unless cigarette executives admitted their lies.</p>
<p>Members of the Senate Judiciary Committee, the first panel to start preliminary hearings on the proposed $368 billion settlement, critiqued the agreement and outlined parts they would like to change, such as the role of the Food and Drug Administration and the $4 billion yearly limit on liability lawsuit damages.</p>
<p>But none suggested jettisoning the deal, and a tobacco industry lawyer strongly suggested the companies could accept stronger FDA language from Congress, although he was not specific about precisely what would be acceptable.</p>
<p>Several lawmakers recalled the spectacle of tobacco executives at a 1994 congressional hearing swearing under oath that nicotine was not addictive, and saying they were not sure about the connection between smoking and cancer. Led by Sen. Edward Kennedy, a Massachusetts Democrat, they demanded &quot;Big Tobacco&quot; correct the record about the hazards of tobacco.</p>
<p>&quot;Until that gets said,&quot; Sen. Joseph Biden, a Delaware Democrat, warned the industry, &quot;you're not getting very many votes up here.</p>
<p>&quot;Time is not on your side. You're going to go bankrupt,&quot; Biden said, adding that the public finds the industry &quot;repulsive.&quot;</p>
<p>The industry lawyer, Philip Morris Cos. Inc. attorney Meyer Koplow, said he was not in a position to answer questions about nicotine or cancer but that &quot;appropriate people&quot; would face  Congress. Committee Chairman Orrin Hatch, a Utah Republican, said dryly, &quot;I have a feeling that's going to happen.&quot;</p>
<p>Although the harshest language came from Democrats, who used words like &quot;liars&quot; &quot;hypocrites&quot; and &quot;revulsion,&quot; the critique cut across party lines, and Hatch said the Senate would spend several months trying to determine if &quot;this is a good deal.&quot;</p>
<p>Conservative Ohio Republican Sen. Mike DeWine demanded to know why the industry was willing to take steps to reduce youth smoking in the United States but was still selling to children around the globe.</p>
<p>&quot;If it's good enough for the United States, it's good for our kids, why isn't it good enough for Taiwanese children or Chinese children or children in Singapore?&quot; DeWine asked.</p>
<p>Sen. Charles Grassley, an Iowa Republican, questioned why the payments called for by the settlement would be tax-deductible for the cigarette makers, and wanted to know who would help small businesses pay for new anti-smoking regulations.</p>
<p>Behind the scenes, one senator, apparently a Republican, tried to derail the hearings, invoking a procedural rule that allows a single anonymous senator to force a delay. An angry Hatch sought the help of the Senate parliamentarian and countered with a procedural loophole of his own, turning the hearing into a &quot;briefing.&quot;</p>
<p>He told the three witnesses, all of whom helped negotiate the settlement, &quot;You are no longer under oath but you'd better be candid.&quot;</p>
<p>The three witnesses -- Koplow, Mississippi Attorney General Mike Moore and anti-smoking advocate Matt Myers of the National Centre for Tobacco Free Kids -- all defended the general outline of the deal, reached by the major tobacco companies, lawyers handling class actions and 40 state attorneys general last Friday.</p>
<p>The three acknowledged, however, that Congress would make changes. Even industry lawyer Koplow said he realised that Congress would handle the issue of FDA jurisdiction, although he did not make it totally clear how far the industry would go in accepting tougher regulatory language.</p>
<p>He characterised some aspects of the accord as &quot;unacceptable to lose&quot; and said others &quot;may be modified.&quot;</p>
<p>Moore was the most vigorous defender of the negotiated settlement, saying Joe Camel, the Marlboro Man, billboards and cartoons would be &quot;banned, killed, gone forever.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
