<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="68946" id="root" date="1996-09-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistani vegoil prices seen weaker next week.</title>
<headline>Pakistani vegoil prices seen weaker next week.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani vegetable oil prices are expected to dip in the next trading week mainly on an increased cottonseed supply and a good stock position in the country, dealers said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;International vegoil prices are under pressure because of the lack of demand,&quot; dealer Saulat Khan said. &quot;In Pakistan, the stock position is good and arrival of cottonseed has increased, which will further weaken the local prices.&quot;</p>
<p>Vegoil stocks rose to 175,000 tonnes last week from 168,500 tonnes the previous week on arrival of fresh supplies.  </p>
<p>Dealers said RBD palm oil and palm olein stocks rose to 137,000 tonnes compared to 131,000 tonnes last week. Soybean oil and sunflower oil stocks fell to 19,000 from 24,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>The state-run Ghee Corporation of Pakistan (GCP) has a stock of 10,000 tonnes of palm oil and palm olien compared to 13,500 tonnes last week. The GCP has booked import of 9,000 tonnes of RBD palm oil and palm olein for shipment by October 10.</p>
<p>A ship is now discharging 10,800 tonnes of soybean oil at the Karachi Port while two others 19,000 and 12,000 tonnes of palm oil were on the outer anchorage, one dealer said.</p>
<p>One ship with about 13,000 tonnes of palm oil is expected to arrive on September 25 and another with 6,000 tonnes of tallow on September 29, the dealer said. One ship was loading 20,000 tonnes of palm oil at a Malaysian port and another was loading 15,000 tonnes of soyabean oil at a South American port.</p>
<p>Dealers offered the following prices for vegoils:</p>
<p>(price indication C&amp;F Karachi per tonne:</p>
<p>						     Saturday   September 13</p>
<p>    RBD palm oil (September shipment)     $520.00    $542.50</p>
<p>    Soyabean oil (September shipment)     $565.00    $570.00</p>
<p>    Palm fatty acid distillates (Sept)    $360.00    $362.00</p>
<p>Local prices in rupees ($1 = 37.06) per maund (37.32 kg)</p>
<p>						    Saturday   September 13</p>
<p>    Palm oil (Karachi Port)		  1,120	1,125</p>
<p>    Palm oil (Port Qasim)		    1,115	1,120</p>
<p>    Soyabean oil				 1,165	1,150</p>
<p>    Sunflower oil				N/A	  N/A</p>
<p>    Rapeseed oil				 N/A	  N/A</p>
<p>    Cottonseed oil			     1,125	1,145</p>
<p>    Palm fatty acid distillates		935	  945</p>
<p>    Palm olein (per kg)			31.55	 31.55</p>
<p>- Amir Zia 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
