<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="689527" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. rail, carload freight up from yr ago - AAR.</title>
<headline>U.S. rail, carload freight up from yr ago - AAR.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Freight volume on U.S. railroads increased for both intermodal and carload traffic in the week ended June 21 from the year-ago week, Association of American Railroads said Thursday.</p>
<p>AAR reported 105,451 containers, up 9.6 percent from 96,204 reported for the corresponding week last year.</p>
<p>It also reported 68,391 trailers in the week, bringing total intermodal volume to 173,842 trailers and containers, up 8.5 percent from 160,247 in the same 1996 week. Intermodal does not include carloads.  </p>
<p>Carload freight, which does not include intermodal, rose 1.8 percent in the June 21 week to 344,474 carloads from 338,272 a year ago.</p>
<p>Ton-miles in the week rose 2.0 percent to 26.1 billion from 25.6 billion a year ago. The ton-mile, a measure of freight transportation, is one ton of freight hauled one mile.</p>
<p>AAR attributed the 1.8 percent increase in carloads last week to a 20.3 percent increase in crushed stone, gravel and sand, to 21,203 in the June 21 week compared with 17,618 a year ago.  </p>
<p>AAR also reported increases in carloads of lumber and wood products, up 12.7 percent to 5,891 from 5,225 a year ago, and in metals and related products, which rose 7.9 percent in the week to 13,022 carloads from 12,074 last year.</p>
<p>Other categories which had increases were farm products excluding grain which rose 17.8 percent to 1,939 carloads, metallic ores which rose 4.7 percent to 21,450, and motor vehicles and equipment, which were up 4.5 percent to 13,022.</p>
<p>AAR reported declines of 10.2 percent in all &quot;other&quot; carloads to 5,601 in the week ended June 21, followed by a 7.6 percent fall in grain to 20,513 from 22,191.  </p>
<p>AAR said carloads on the two Canadian-based U.S. railroads rose sharply from a year ago, up 8.9 percent to 53,409 carloads in the June 21 week, while intermodal traffic climbed 11.6 percent to 25,429 trailers and containers.</p>
<p>In the first 25 weeks of 1997, AAR said carloads increased 1.5 percent to 8.49 million from 8.37 million in the same 1996 period. Trailers and containers rose 6.7 percent to 4.06 million from 3.80 million, while ton-miles increased 2.0 percent in the period to 661.1 billion from 648.3 billion.</p>
<p>For the same period, AAR reported 1.32 million carloads on the two Canadian-based U.S. railroads, up 2.1 percent from the year-ago period, and 608,414 trailers and containers, up 11.2 percent from last year, AAR said.</p>
<p>Combined total volume in the United States and Canada for the first 25 weeks was 9.82 million carloads, up 1.6 percent from the same 1996 period, while intermodal traffic totaled 4.67 million trailers and containers, up 7.3 percent from last year, AAR said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
