<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="689669" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. high court upholds doctor-assisted suicide ban.</title>
<headline>U.S. high court upholds doctor-assisted suicide ban.</headline>
<byline>James Vicini</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A unanimous U.S. Supreme Court said on Thursday that state governments have the right to outlaw doctor-assisted suicides in a landmark ruling involving the right-to-die controversy.</p>
<p>The nation's highest court refused to create a new constitutional right for mentally competent and terminally ill patients to get medical help to commit suicide.</p>
<p>The two decisions marked the first time the justices have ruled on the existing bans on doctor-assisted suicide, an issue that has sparked a divisive national debate rivaling abortion and capital punishment in emotional intensity.</p>
<p>In one of the most important rulings of its 1996-97 term, the high court upheld laws from New York and Washington states barring doctor-assisted suicide, a decision with far-reaching impact as most states have made the practice a crime.</p>
<p>Chief Justice William Rehnquist said in two opinions for the court, &quot;There is no dispute that dying patients in Washington and New York can obtain palliative care, even when doing so would hasten their deaths.&quot;</p>
<p>He added, &quot;The difficulty in defining terminal illness and the risk that a dying patient's request for assistance in ending his or her life might not be truly voluntary justifies the prohibitions on assisted suicide we uphold here.&quot;</p>
<p>Of the 50 states, only Oregon has allowed physician-assisted suicides, and that law has been put on hold because of a court challenge.</p>
<p>The justices overturned two precedent-setting rulings by U.S. appeals courts in California and New York that struck down as unconstitutional the state laws that make it a crime for physicians to assist in a suicide.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court decision did not involve Dr. Jack Kevorkian, a retired pathologist and the nation's best known advocate of assisted suicide who has publicly acknowledged attending 45 deaths since 1990.</p>
<p>Kevorkian, who was not convicted in three prior cases, had a mistrial declared earlier this month at his fourth trial on assisted-suicide charges in Michigan over the August 1996 death of a 54-year-old woman with multiple sclerosis.</p>
<p>Rehnquist said an examination of the nation's history, legal traditions and practices demonstrate that Anglo-American law has punished or disapproved of assisted suicide for more than 700 years.</p>
<p>He said state laws banning the practice have never contained exceptions for those near death. Rehnquist noted President Bill Clinton recently signed a law barring the use of federal funds to support physician-assisted suicide.</p>
<p>Rehnquist, whose wife died in 1991 after a long battle with cancer, next declared that there was no constitutional right for an individual to commit suicide with another person's assistance.</p>
<p>&quot;Legal physician-assisted suicide could make it more difficult for the state to protect depressed or mentally ill persons or those who are suffering from untreated pain from suicidal impulses,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The state also has an interest in protecting the integrity and ethics of the medical profession,&quot; Rehnquist said in explaining the reasoning behind the ruling.</p>
<p>&quot;Finally, the state may fear that permitting assisted suicide will start it down the path to voluntary and perhaps even involuntary euthanasia,&quot; he concluded.</p>
<p>The right-to-die question presented the high court with one of the most wrenching and difficult dilemmas it has to decide, raising profound legal, moral and ethical questions. Rehnquist said the debate on the issue should continue throughout American society.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court last addressed the issue in 1990, ruling that a person has a constitutional right to refuse unwanted medical treatment in a case involving a comatose woman whose parents wanted to end artifical life support.</p>
<p>Advocates say mentally competent, terminally ill patients should be able to seek help from their doctors when they believe the time has come to end needless pain and agony.</p>
<p>Opponents believe doctors should not be in the business of ending lives and that when a patient's pain and depression are properly treated the desire for death usually fades.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
