<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690171" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU TELLS BELGIUM TO SCRAP VTM'S AD MONOPOLY.</title>
<headline>EU TELLS BELGIUM TO SCRAP VTM'S AD MONOPOLY.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission told Belgium on Thursday to scrap the advertising monopoly granted to Flemish commercial TV channel VTM.</p>
<p>&quot;At the initiative of Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert, the Commission has adopted a decision finding the exclusive advertising licence given to VTM illegal,&quot; the Commission said in a statement.</p>
<p>The Commission rejected an argument by the Flanders government that the monopoly on advertising was intended to safeguard the pluralism of the press.</p>
<p>The government has long resisted abolishing VTM's exclusive rights on the grounds its advertising revenue is distributed among the region's written press, which partly owns VTM.</p>
<p>Speaking on Belgian radio, Van Miert noted however that VTM was currently controlled by three media groups against an initial nine and this weakened the press pluralism argument.</p>
<p>VTM is 44 percent owned by Dutch publishing group VNU. Other shareholders include Belgium's Persgroep NV and Roularta Mediagroep.</p>
<p>Van Miert also said the monopoly could not be justified on 'general good' reasons, such as cultural policy.</p>
<p>VTM's 18-year TV advertising monopoly for Dutch-speaking Flanders, northern Belgium, granted in 1989, has been attacked by rival VT4.</p>
<p>VT4, owned by Nasdaq-listed TV group Scandinavian Broadcasting System , has been broadcasting from London to Flanders to circumvent the monopoly.</p>
<p>VTM threatened on Wednesday to claim 15 to 20 billion francs ($421 to $562 million) in damages from the Flemish government if it lost its advertising monopoly.</p>
<p>Both the Flemish government and the Commission on Thursday poured scorn on the idea.</p>
<p>Regional Economic Affairs and Media Minister Eric Van Rompuy told BRTN radio, &quot;If the European Commission declares us in default today, we'll have to lift the monopoly...and adjust our laws. So I don't really see how there could be a claim for damages.&quot;</p>
<p>Van Miert said, &quot;I don't see how on a solid basis one could ask compensation.&quot; He suggested that VTM be satisfied that it had enjoyed a monopoly for such a long time.</p>
<p>The Belgian authorities have two months to comply with the decision or face legal action.</p>
<p>The Commission's decision could spark a reshuffle in the ownership of VTM. Luxembourg media group CLT-UFA, which is 50/50 owned by Germany's Bertelsmann AG and Luxembourg holding company Audiofina, has said it is interested in the company's operations.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
