<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690172" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Strauss-Kahn &quot;not against&quot; France Telecom sale.</title>
<headline>Strauss-Kahn &quot;not against&quot; France Telecom sale.</headline>
<byline>Penny MacRae</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>New French Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn favours a partial sale of France Telecom but no decision has been taken yet on the controversial issue, a government source said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The source denied media reports that the finance ministry had targeted September as a possible date for the sale of the telecoms giant but added that there was &quot;a potential for a market (flotation) in September ...&quot;</p>
<p>The previous centre-right government decided to privatise France Telecom but it lost power to a Socialist-led administration earlier this month, leaving uncertainty hanging over the float.</p>
<p>A decision to go ahead with the sale would mark a shift away from the Socialists' election programme opposing privatisations and could cause a rift with their Communist coalition partners and left-wingers inside the Socialist party.</p>
<p>The source quoted Strauss-Kahn as telling Socialist parliamentarians this week that: &quot;Personally, I'm not against the opening of the capital on condition that the promises of the prime minister are taken into account.&quot;</p>
<p>Prime Minister Lionel Jospin has said he wanted to consult France Telecom staff before deciding whether to proceed with the privatisation.</p>
<p>The previous conservative government had planned to launch the sale early this month of 30 to 35 percent of France Telecom in preparation for next year's sweeping deregulation of the European telecommunications market.</p>
<p>The sale would have been the biggest ever French stock market operation and was expected to generate between 30 billion francs and 50 billion francs ($5.2-$8.6 billion).</p>
<p>Revenues from sale of France Telecom are urgently needed to shore up balance sheets of ailing state-owned companies without worsening the country's public deficit in the qualifying year for European monetary union, economists say.</p>
<p>Expectations have been building in recent days that the sale may go ahead. Jospin's maiden speech last week to the National Assembly raised market hopes that the party would soften its hostility to privatisations.</p>
<p>Jospin said he opposed privatisation of the telecommunications, electronics and aerospace sectors unless they were &quot;in the national interest&quot; and said &quot;adaptions will be necessary to maintain our rank among the world's most developed nations&quot;.</p>
<p>There were many political considerations attached to the sale of France Telecom, the source said on Thursday. But he noted both Strauss-Kahn and Christian Pierret, secretary of state for industry, favoured the move and their opinions should carry weight in discussions within the party.</p>
<p>The newspaper Liberation quoted Pierret on Thursday as saying at least part of the capital of France Telecom might be opened up.</p>
<p>&quot;With the finance minister, we fixed three aims -- to reinforce France Telecom's strength as a big European telecoms operator, guarantee its independence and allow it to attain critical mass on a world scale&quot;, Pierret said. &quot;All this implies at least a minimum opening to the world of (financial) markets.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;When one sees the finance minister and the secretary of state for industry favouring a very partial opening of the capital, this will mean two (significant) people speaking in support ... in the debate,&quot; the source said. ($ = 5.822 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
