<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690315" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW - ASDA set to outperform.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - ASDA set to outperform.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>British supermarket group ASDA Plc should continue to outperform the market, chief executive Allan Leighton told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Do I believe that we can continue to outperform the industry? Yes I do,&quot; Leighton said.</p>
<p>He said the company expected to refurbish around five stores and open five new ones this year, which will create &quot;about 3,500-4,000 jobs and the distribution centre...we'll be close to 5,000 jobs this year, probably.&quot;  </p>
<p>ASDA's sales from existing stores rose 9.2 percent in the year ending May 3 as pretax profits before exceptionals jumped 16 percent to 353.7 million stg, and it paid out a total dividend of 3.05 pence per share.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be expecting us to outperform not just on sales but operating profit too,&quot; he said, but added that achieving such strong sales growth &quot;becomes more and more difficult&quot;.</p>
<p>Leighton said that last year, ASDA's gross margins were flat and its prices became cheaper as optimising margin mix allowed the company to invest in price.</p>
<p>He said operating margins were &quot;about flat&quot;.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement that industry figures showed it was eight percent cheaper than its major competitors, and Leighton said: &quot;Provided the gap is maintained or increased versus our competitors that's the key measure for me.&quot;  </p>
<p>Leighton said planning permission for new stores was &quot;getting tougher,&quot; but stressed a point of difference for ASDA was the size of its superstores and location in out-of-town sites.</p>
<p>He said he felt ASDA's clothing business, sold under the &quot;George&quot; brand set up with George Davis who worked with Next, could be twice the current size.</p>
<p>Clothing sales at existing stores rose 28 percent. Leighton said there was &quot;still a lot to do...to deliver this kind of performance consistently but I think we will&quot;.</p>
<p>He said volume sales of clothing in the group's best stores were on similar levels to shops in the high street but operating costs were half.</p>
<p>&quot;If I can sort the supply chain out...you can then generate a quality offer...at 20 percent of the price. That is a set of economics that nobody else can emulate,&quot; Leighton said.</p>
<p>He said another area where the company was focusing efforts and had opportunities was in the change towards eating take-away and ready-made meals.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the biggest Indian take-away business in the UK and we have the biggest fish-and-chip take-away business in the UK,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Leighton added that in groceries, &quot;there's still a lot of innovation that you can do&quot;.</p>
<p>ASDA had &quot;lots to do&quot;, particularly in beers, wines and spirits and frozen foods.</p>
<p>&quot;The only way in a very mature marketplace that you can outperform and generate real return is you've got to innovate faster than anybody else,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Jo Winterbottom, London Newsroom +44171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
