<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690430" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs seen steady to off, pork bellies mixed.</title>
<headline>CME hogs seen steady to off, pork bellies mixed.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog futures were expected to open steady to 0.200 cent per lb lower while calls ranged mixed on pork bellies, up 0.300 to off 0.200, livestock analysts said.</p>
<p>Lower cash hog indications on increased hog runs were expected to prompt carryover pressure in hog futures. Hog runs have increased as temperatures dropped, analysts said.</p>
<p>However, higher pork cutout values and reduced hog weights which indicate producers are current could provide underlying support at times. Mixed trade is also likely ahead of USDA's Hogs and Pigs report, they said.</p>
<p>Analyst estimates on Friday's quarterly report put June 1 all hogs and pigs on U.S. farms at an average 102.9 percent of a year ago and ranged from 101.7 to 105 percent. Estimates on hogs kept for breeding averaged 104.3 percent in a range of 103 to 106 percent and hogs kept for market averaged 102.6 percent of a year ago in a range of 101 to 105 percent.  </p>
<p>Nearby pork belly futures were expected to remain supported by firm wholesale pork prices. Fresh product sales were higher and 16 loads of frozen product have gone into users' hands recently. Bacon featuring has also increased, analysts said.</p>
<p>However, next year contracts were again expected to show pressure on expectations of increased product availability. Indications on USDA's hog report, which will be released Friday afternoon, point to increased hog numbers going into next year, they added.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
