<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690479" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Group calls for U.S. sanctions against Italian firm.</title>
<headline>Group calls for U.S. sanctions against Italian firm.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>An influential Cuban American group on Wednesday urged the United States to take action against Italy's Stet SpA, charging that the telecommunications firm was breaking U.S. laws against Cuba.</p>
<p>The Cuban American National Foundation (CANF) said in a letter to Secretary of State Madeleine Albright that Stet was &quot;clearly in violation&quot; of last year's Helms-Burton law, which tightened the U.S. embargo against Cuba.</p>
<p>&quot;The longer we continue to delay sanctions will only embolden the enemies of Cuba's freedom and unscrupulous foreign investors,&quot; said the letter, signed by CANF chairman Jorge Mas Canosa.</p>
<p>&quot;Sanctioning Stet, as the law calls for, will send a signal around the world that the United States remains fully committed to its policy towards the Castro dictatorship,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Cuban President Fidel Castro, the only communist head of state in the Western Hemisphere, confiscated thousands of U.S.-owned properties after taking power in 1959.</p>
<p>Among them were the assets of ITT Corp., which used to operate the Cuban telephone system before the revolution. Stet and Mexican conglomerate Grupo Domos invested in Cuban telecommunications firm ETECSA under a partial privatisation deal starting in 1994.</p>
<p>Invoking the Helms-Burton law, last year the United States imposed penalties on Grupo Domos, which was the larger shareholder of the two foreign investors in ETECSA.</p>
<p>The U.S. government barred key Grupo Domos executives and shareholders from entering the United States, a sanction that extended to their spouses and children.</p>
<p>However, Washington has so far spared Stet, even though the Italian firm raised its stake in ETECSA after the Mexicans pulled out of the Cuban joint venture earlier this year.</p>
<p>The United States has punished only one other firm under Helms-Burton, Canadian mining concern Sherritt.</p>
<p>No European companies have been hit so far, although several are said to be under State Department scrutiny.</p>
<p>The European Union last year challenged the validity of the Helms-Burton law at the World Trade Organisation but this year consented to withdraw its case in order to negotiate a separate agreement with the United States.</p>
<p>CANF is widely seen as one of the most effective interest groups in Washington. It played a key role in pushing for the 1992 Cuban Democracy Act and the Helms-Burton law to increase sanctions against Castro's government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
