<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690577" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Bundestag passes 1998, 1999 tax bills.</title>
<headline>German Bundestag passes 1998, 1999 tax bills.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Bundestag lower house of parliament on Thursday passed the final readings of Finance Minister Theo Waigel's 1998 and 1999 tax reform bills which would cut around 30 billion marks off the national tax burden.</p>
<p>In separate votes, deputies passed the 1999 bill -- which would implement big cuts in income and corporate taxes -- by a majority of 326 to 301. The more modest 1998 tax bill passed by a majority of 326 to 304.  </p>
<p>Separately, deputies of both the Bonn coalition and the SPD voted for Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt's bill to extend state aid to formerly communist eastern Germany into the 21st century, paving the way for passage in the Bundesrat upper house of parliament.</p>
<p>During a debate lasting over five hours, government and opposition rehearsed old arguments for and against Waigel's tax-cutting plan. Waigel said the measures would boost German competitiveness, investment and jobs.</p>
<p>Opposition speakers said the tax reforms would open up a huge hole in state finances which would have to be closed by a hike in value-added tax after next year's general election.</p>
<p>Passage of the package of tax cuts now sends the bills to the Bundesrat, whose SPD majority is expected to vote down the measures on July 4, sending them into parliament's lengthy mediation process.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
