<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690641" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Victory on way in world polio battle, WHO says.</title>
<headline>Victory on way in world polio battle, WHO says.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fight to rid the world of polio by 2000 is on track despite political turmoils and wars, the World Health Organisation said on Thursday.</p>
<p>It said cases of poliomyelitis, a deformer and killer of children, had plummeted by almost 90 percent since 1988 when the U.N. health agency set its goal of eradicating the disease worldwide by 2000 -- and by 43 percent in 1996 alone over 1995.</p>
<p>Polio was eradicated from the western hemisphere in 1991, when the last case was in Peru. Most of the remaining cases in the world are reported in Africa and Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>In 1996, two-thirds of the world's children under five, a record 400 million, were immunised against polio, an infectious viral disease transmitted mainly because of inadequate sewage, compared to only one in 20 in the early 1970s, WHO said.</p>
<p>Thanks to mass immunisation, the number of cases reported in India dropped to 946 in 1996 from more than 24,000 in 1988 and in China, to nil in 1996 from 667 in 1988, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;If progress continues at the present pace, wild polio viruses could be eradicated from the world by 2000,&quot; Dr Harry Hull, head of WHO's global polio campaign, said in a statement.</p>
<p>WHO warned that conflicts in Afghanistan, Albania, Chechnya, former Yugoslavia, Liberia, Somalia, Sudan and central Africa continued to provide fertile ground for new outbreaks.</p>
<p>It singled out former Zaire, now renamed the Democratic Republic of the Congo and reeling from a civil war and a refugee crisis, as the main threat to progress in much of Africa.</p>
<p>Laboratory results from neighbouring countries showed former Zaire to be the origin of imported polio cases, it said.</p>
<p>In Europe, Albania accounted for 167 of the 191 cases reported in 1996, former Yugoslavia 24 and Greece five.</p>
<p>WHO said it estimated funding needs for the worldwide campaign at $600 million until 2000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
