<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69083" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-DODGERS INCREASE WEST LEAD WITH WIN OVER PADRES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-DODGERS INCREASE WEST LEAD WITH WIN OVER PADRES.</headline>
<dateline>SAN DIEGO, California 1996-09-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Los Angeles Dodgers gave themselves a bit of breathing room in their battle with San Diego for the National League West Division pennant by handing the Padres a 9-2 thrashing on Saturday.</p>
<p>Raul Mondesi had four hits, including a bases-load double that keyed a seven-run fifth inning to help the Dodgers increase their lead over San Diego to 1 1/2 games.</p>
<p>Los Angeles has won six of its last eight and closes out the key four-game series with the Padres Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;It wouldn't necessarily make us comfortable, but it would increase our cushion,&quot; Dodgers catcher Mike Piazza said of a possible series-closing win on Sunday.</p>
<p>Ismael Valdes (15-7) won his fourth straight decision, allowing two runs and three hits in seven innings. Scott Sanders (9-5) had his five-game winning streak stopped. He lasted 4-1/3 innings, allowing six runs and seven hits.</p>
<p>The Padres grabbed the lead in the second inning when Jody Reed hit a two-run homer. But Valdes shut San Diego down the rest of the way.</p>
<p>&quot;Jody Reed got us on top, but other than that we didn't have a lot going,&quot; Padres manager Bruce Bochy said. &quot;They certainly had the pitching.&quot;</p>
<p>Eric Karros launched his 33rd homer in the fourth to put Los Angeles on the board and the Dodgers blew the game open in the fifth with the help of Mondesi's three-run double.</p>
<p>In Atlanta, the World Series champion Braves reduced their magic number to two in the East by edging the second-place Montreal Expos 5-4.</p>
<p>Fred McGriff's two-run double in the third put the Braves ahead and Eduardo Perez's two-run homer in the seventh sealed the win for Denny Neagle (16-8), who allowed two runs on eight hits in 7-1/3 innings.</p>
<p>Atlanta can clinch its fifth straight division title with a win over the Expos on Sunday or Monday.</p>
<p>At Florida, Jeff Conine and Devon White led off the ninth inning with back-to-back homers off Billy Wagner to rally the Marlins to a 2-1 victory over the Houston Astros.</p>
<p>The loss pushed Houston 5 1/2 games behind idle St Louis, just about ending the Astros' chances of overtaking the Cardinals for the Central Division title.</p>
<p>Houston's Doug Drabek and Wagner had combined on a five-hit shutout over the first eight innings with Derek Bell's fourth-inning RBI the only run.</p>
<p>Houston nursed its 1-0 lead until the ninth when Conine led off the inning with his 25th homer. White followed with his game-winning 17th homer.</p>
<p>In San Francisco, Kirk Rueter pitched seven scoreless innings and drove in a run and rookie catcher Marcus Jensen had three RBI to pace the Giants to a 6-2 victory over Colorado, eliminating the Rockies from playoff contention.</p>
<p>Colorado won the wild card playoff berth last season but followed an eight-game winning streak by losing five of six to kill its post-season hopes.</p>
<p>Rueter (6-8) gave up five hits and walked one with six strikeouts. Jamey Wright (4-4) allowed six runs and six hits to suffer the loss.</p>
<p>In Pittsburgh, Rich Loiselle got his first major-league win and Jay Bell capped a five-run third inning with a homer as the Pirates extended their winning streak to 10 games with a 8-3 victory over the Chicago Cubs.</p>
<p>Pittsburgh, in last place in the Central Division, ironically is riding the longest winning streak in the majors this season.</p>
<p>Loiselle (1-0) gave up three runs and nine hits in five-plus innings. Dave Swartzbaugh (0-1) was tagged for six runs and five hits for the loss.</p>
<p>Carlos Garcia doubled in two runs in the second and the Pirates blew open the game in the third with Bell's three-run blast making it 7-0.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Curt Schilling allowed five hits in his league-leading eighth complete game as the Phillies edged the New York Mets 2-1.</p>
<p>Schilling (9-9) walked none and struck out 10 in his second straight complete game. Pete Harnisch (8-12) gave up two runs -- one earned -- and five hits for a tough defeat.</p>
<p>The score was tied 1-1 in the sixth when Gregg Jefferies and Benito Santiago singled to put runners on the corners. Ruben Amaro grounded into a double play that plated Jefferies with the winning run.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN DIEGO, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
