<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690851" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>OPPOSITION VOWS TO MAINTAIN PRESSURE ON PROSSER</p>
<p>The Federal Opposition has vowed to continue pursuing Small Business Minister Geoff Prosser over his business dealings, during the winter break.</p>
<p>Labor has been defeated in a bid to force Mr Prosser into Parliament today to explain his conversations with Coles-Myer Director Nick Greiner, and a former councillor at the Bunbury City Council south of Perth.</p>
<p>Shadow Small Business Minister, Stephen Martin, moved the motion after the Government announced this morning there will be no question-time in tomorrow's last day of sittings before the winter recess.</p>
<p>Mr Martin says Mr Prosser's dealings breach ministerial guidelines and he should resign.</p>
<p>He says Mr Prosser is trying to use his ministerial position to advantage his own business interests, has misled the Parliament and has breached the Prime Minister's code of ministerial conduct.</p>
<p>&quot;How many more examples does this Government need,&quot; Mr Martin asked.</p>
<p>&quot;Tim Fischer should do the right thing and say we've driven him to Yarralumla and he's resigned.&quot;</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HILL SAYS WORLD COMMUNITY WRONG ABOUT AUSTRALIA'S STANCE</p>
<p>Federal Environment Minister Robert Hill says the international community has the wrong perception about Australia's stance on Greenhouse gases.</p>
<p>Senator Hill is attending the Earth Summit in New York.</p>
<p>He has acknowledged some countries believe Australia does not want to carry its fair share of the burden to cut Greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p>But he's told ABC Radio, that's incorrect.</p>
<p>Senator Hill says the Government has to convince the international community that what Australia is seeking is fair.</p>
<p>He says Australia is prepared to carry it's share of the burden to reduce Greenhouse emissions, but not an unfair share.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>NSW GOVT RELEASES RESULTS OF STEROID SURVEY</p>
<p>The New South Wales government has released the results of what it says is Australia's first comprehensive study of steroid use.</p>
<p>The National Drug and Alcohol Research Centre surveyed 100 users for the government study, finding almost 90-per cent are injecting veterinary products.</p>
<p>Health minister, Andrew Refshauge says the results are disturbing, particularly the fact that almost half the users are acquiring steroids through doctors.</p>
<p>Dr Refshauge says action is already being taken against the suppliers.</p>
<p>He says the Government is carrying out surveillance of vets and particularly large purchases of products are monitored.</p>
<p>The Minister says so far three vets have been referred to the Veterinary Surgeons Registration Board.</p>
<p>He says the Government is also monitoring the prescribing of anabolic steroids by medical practitioners.</p>
<p>So far, he says, eight complaints have been received by the Healthcare Complaints Commission and all have resulted in disciplinary action.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>NSW INSTITUTIONS FOR INTELLECTUALLY DISABLED &quot;UNSAFE&quot;</p>
<p>An investigation into New South Wales' biggest institutions for the intellectually disabled says they're outmoded and inherently unsafe.</p>
<p>The report, prepared by the Auditor General and the Community Services Commission, says in general, staff don't have proper guidelines to deal with problems like assault.</p>
<p>The report also says medication is being administered illegally, without the consent of residents.</p>
<p>Seven big government facilities and three private centres were investigated, with the report urging the government to act on its own policy to close them down.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CONSTITUTIONAL CONVENTION MAY NOT HAPPEN SAYS CHAIRMAN</p>
<p>The chairman of the Federal Government's planned Constitutional Convention says it may now never happen, unless Labor changes its stance.</p>
<p>The Convention, to debate whether Australia should become a republic, has been delayed until at least next year, after the Senate voted against a voluntary poll to elect half the delegates.</p>
<p>But Chairman and National Party MP Ian Sinclair says the Convention's future is now up to Labor.</p>
<p>And he has dismissed the Opposition's proposal for a plebiscite on the republic as ridiculous.</p>
<p>Mr Sinclair says the process the Government put forward was eminently sensible.</p>
<p>He says it allowed for a mix of delegates who were elected, and for those who were not going to be there as a representative group to be chosen.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FEDERAL GOVT SUSPENDS CONTRACTS WITH REMOVAL FIRM</p>
<p>The Federal Government has suspended all contracts with a Canberra removalist company, until it's determined whether it's paying proper wages to staff.</p>
<p>Unions and the Member for Canberra, Bob McMullan, yesterday claimed the company Atlantis Removals was paying wages which were up to $10.00 below the award rate, for work done after hours and on weekends.</p>
<p>Mr McMullan says the wages are part of a proposed Workplace Agreement which has not yet been approved.</p>
<p>The company has contracts with 10-Federal departments.</p>
<p>The office of Administrative Services Minister David Jull, says the contracts have been suspended until the company confirms in writing that its wages and conditions are above board.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TELSTRA DENIES SETTING UP &quot;DIRTY TRICKS&quot; DEPARTMENT</p>
<p>Telstra has denied setting up a &quot;dirty tricks&quot; department to frustrate a group of complainants.</p>
<p>Two National Party Senators, Ron Boswell and Bill O'Chee, have claimed the telecommunications giant has spent $18 million to discredit a group of complainants.</p>
<p>The Senators say evidence has been presented to a Senate committee that Telstra set up teams to discredit individual compensation claims from the group called Casualties of Telecom. But Telstra's Consumer Affairs Driector, Ted Benjamin, says no group has been set up to conduct improper practices.</p>
<p>He says Telstra participated in an arbitration process run by the Telecommunications Industry Ombudsman to resolve the 16 claims which ran up to $44 million.</p>
<p>Mr Benjamin says 11 of those have been resolved, with settlement awards made of $1.8 million, a fraction of what was originally sought.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
