<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690925" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Peters halves 1997/98 budget surplus forecast.</title>
<headline>Peters halves 1997/98 budget surplus forecast.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand Treasurer Winston Peters on Thursday projected a NZ$1.532 billion budget surplus for the year to June 30, 1998.</p>
<p>He projected the surplus would rise to $1.927 billion in 1998/99, and $2.568 billion in 1999/00.</p>
<p>The 1997/98 surplus compares with the projection of NZ$3.3 billion made in the March Budget Policy Statement (BPS) and against $3.1 billion projected in the December Economic and Fiscal Update (DEFU).  </p>
<p>The BPS projected a NZ$2.6 billion surplus in 1998/99 and a $3.5 billion surplus in 1999/00 while the DEFU projected a $4.4 billion surplus in 1998/99 and a $6.1 billion surplus in 1999/00.</p>
<p>&quot;Though the surplus is reduced, it is still healthy and this confirms the wisdom of aiming for substantial surplus to ensure continued debt reduction throughout the economic cycle,&quot; Peters said, adding there was always a risk forecasts would change.</p>
<p>Peters said tax revenue in 1997/98 had been revised down and demand-driven expenditures such as debt servicing and benefit spending had been revised up.  </p>
<p>&quot;Some of these revisions reflect the fact that economic activity had not accelerated as quickly as the Treasury earlier forecast,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As a result, the operating surplus had been reduced, he added.</p>
<p>Peters said that new spending together with the abolition of a pension tax surcharge would total $900 million in 1997/98.</p>
<p>New spending would total $1.6 billion in 1998/99 and $2.5 billion in keeping with the centre-right coalition government's stated plan to increase spending by NZ$5 billion over the next three years.  </p>
<p>Spending in 1997/98 is forecast at $34.6 billion (35.0 percent of GDP) against the previous forecast of $33.7 billion while revenue is projected at $35.7 billion (36.1 percent of GDP) against the earlier forecast of $36.4 billion.</p>
<p>The operating balance in 1997/98 will be 1.5 percent of GDP against the December forecast of 3.2 percent.</p>
<p>Peters said the government would need to reconsider its long-term fiscal strategy following a referendum in September on a compulsory pension scheme.  </p>
<p>One reason the surplus in 1997/98 is lower is because of the deferral of a Maori settlement claim with the Ngain Tahu tribe from the 1996/97 year.</p>
<p>Treasury said there had been significant unfavourable forecasting changes on the expense side including higher welfare benefits, higher CPI indexation, and pension payments.</p>
<p>Tax revenue was largely unchange from the December forecasts but lower economic growth and revised judgements about the tax base had reduced revenues and offset the effect of deferring the July 1 tax reductions.  </p>
<p>Beyond 1997/98 economic growth was expected to be stronger than projected in December.</p>
<p>As a result of the lower operating balance track, the government net worlth would only be $7.6 billion at June 30, 1998 against the earlier forecast of $9.3 billion.</p>
<p>Net debt to GDP would be $25.23 billion, or 25.5 percent of GDP against the earlier projection of 23.4 percent.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
