<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690953" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>Cambodia: Cambodian PM regrets Albright's no-show.</title>
<headline>Cambodian PM regrets Albright's no-show.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright cancelled a trip to Cambodia because of security concerns, and the country's First Prime Minister said on Thursday he regretted the decision.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very regretful that she is not coming because I wanted to meet her and talk about a number of major issues,&quot; Prince Norodom Ranariddh told reporters.</p>
<p>U.S. State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns told reporters travelling with Albright that Cambodia's security situation was &quot;serious and unpredictable&quot; and would not have permitted the type of visit she wanted.</p>
<p>Ranariddh said Albright had considered stopping off at Phnom Penh airport for talks with him and Second Prime Minister Hun Sen, but the two premiers had agreed that such a visit would not have been appropriate.</p>
<p>&quot;She wanted to come to the airport, but Hun Sen and I agreed that if we just met her at the airport we would be breaking the principles of protocol,&quot; the prince said.</p>
<p>Albright is due to visit the region again in three weeks for an Association of Southeast Asian Nations meeting, and Ranariddh said he hoped she would visit Cambodia at that time.</p>
<p>Ranariddh and Hun Sen share power in a coalition formed after 1993 elections supervised by the United Nations. But relations between the two have been deteriorating since last year when Ranariddh demanded a greater share of power to govern in the provinces.</p>
<p>The political tension resulted in a battle on the streets of Phnom Penh between bodyguards loyal to the two prime ministers last week.</p>
<p>The disintegrating Khmer Rouge guerrilla force has also become a key issue of contention between the two with both men seeking political advantage as the group splits up.</p>
<p>Ranariddh also said on Thursday that there was no fresh news on the fate of Khmer Rouge leader Pol Pot.</p>
<p>He said the guerrilla faction that rebelled against Pol Pot and captured him had to turn him over to authorities if it wanted to make an amnesty deal with the government.</p>
<p>Ranariddh and Hun Sen were due to hold separate talks on Thursday with special envoys from the Group of Seven industrialised countries who were expected to express the group's concern about the political tension in Cambodia.</p>
<p>Claude Martin, the French Foreign Ministry's deputy secretary general, and Yukio Imagawa, a former Japanese ambassador in Phnom Penh, arrived in Cambodia on Wednesday.</p>
<p>G7 leaders and Russian President Boris Yeltsin, meeting in Denver last weekend, called for an end to the political chaos and violence in Cambodia that they said threatened to shatter the relative stability since the 1993 elections.</p>
<p>At the end of their summit, the G7 urged Cambodia's fractious leaders to &quot;demonstrate their commitment to holding free and fair elections by setting a specific date&quot;.</p>
<p>Ranariddh announced on Tuesday that he and Hun Sen had agreed that Cambodia's next general election will be in May 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
