<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690967" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Taiwan-linked China bank opens for business.</title>
<headline>Taiwan-linked China bank opens for business.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first Taiwan-linked bank to be set up in China, First Sino Bank, formally opened for business on Thursday in Shanghai, a bank official said.</p>
<p>The bank is 20 percent owned by Shanghai's Pudong Development Bank and 80 percent by Lotus Worldwide (HK) Ltd., and will largely engage in corporate financing for Taiwan firms on the Chinese mainland, the official said.</p>
<p>The official declined to give details of the backers of Lotus Worldwide, a Hong Kong-registered investment vehicle, but said: &quot;Some of the money is related to Taiwan.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;First Sino Bank will engage in providing financial support for Taiwan-related corporations in China,&quot; a statement from the bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to its role to encourage the development of Taiwanese investment in China, the bank also aims at promoting cross-strait financial exchanges and further facilitating local economic development,&quot; the statement said.  </p>
<p>The statement said that the primary customer base for the bank would be &quot;Taiwanese-linked companies in China and their parent company groups&quot;.</p>
<p>An official said the bank had a paid-in capital of US$50 million and would operate in China under the same terms as a foreign bank.</p>
<p>It has set up office in the Pudong development zone to the east of Shanghai's city centre which the government has decreed will become a financial centre.</p>
<p>Di Weiping, vice-president of the Shanghai branch of the People's Bank of China, said in March that First Sino Bank was a Taiwan-invested bank and welcomed other Taiwan investments in China's banking sector.</p>
<p>Taiwan newspaper reports at the time said Taiwan footwear maker Pou Chen Corp was one of the backers, but the company denied having any involvement in First Sino.</p>
<p>The Taiwan government has warned local firms not to invest in banks on the Chinese mainland.</p>
<p>Beijing has considered Taiwan a renegade province since the Communists won a civil war in 1949 and the losing Nationalists fled to the island across the Taiwan Strait.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
