<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="690947" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Angry and lost, Hong Kong democrats hit out.</title>
<headline>Angry and lost, Hong Kong democrats hit out.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's pro-democracy camp, angry and feeling abandoned, heaped scorn on Thursday on the United States and Britain for dropping a planned boycott of inaugural ceremonies for a new Beijing-picked legislature.</p>
<p>Emily Lau, an outspoken champion of democracy in the territory that reverts to Beijing at midnight on Monday, said the two countries were &quot;disgusting and contemptible&quot;.</p>
<p>But she added: &quot;I am not surprised.&quot;</p>
<p>Newspaper editorials and cartoonists had a field day with the decision by Washington and London to send their Hong Kong envoys to the swearing-in ceremony for the new legislature, which will replace a democratically-elected body.</p>
<p>Visiting British Prime Minister Tony Blair and U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright will stay away.</p>
<p>Lau and other popular politicians, including Democratic Party leader Martin Lee, will be dumped from the new legislature and several figures rejected by voters at the last elections will move in.</p>
<p>An editorial in the South China Morning Post, the territory's main English-language newspaper, said Britain and the United States had lost the moral high ground. It accused them of &quot;shilly-shallying edging towards hypocrisy&quot;.</p>
<p>A cartoon in The Hong Kong Standard depicted the United States, Britain and big business trooping into the swearing-in with Lee outside crying: &quot;They're selling us out.&quot;</p>
<p>Lee said the planned boycott had sent a &quot;very strong message&quot; that Britain and the United States would not accept the legitimacy of the new provisional legislature.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm afraid it is much watered down, if not contradicted,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Even some politicians more attuned to Beijing were startled at the last-minute U-turn before Britain's hands Hong Kong's 6.4 million people over to China after more than 150 years of colonial rule.</p>
<p>&quot;It is baffling to see them blowing, as it were, hot and cold,&quot; said Ronald Arculli, a legislator with the usually pro-China Liberal Party.</p>
<p>A Foreign Office spokesman in London insisted: &quot;This in no way implies approval of the provisional legislature to which we are adamantly opposed.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign Secretary Robin Cook said Britain would strive to ensure that Beijing honours its promises to leave Hong Kong's free-wheeling capitalist way of life unchanged for 50 years under a &quot;one country, two systems&quot; formula.</p>
<p>&quot;We have accepted that our role is to competently carry out the policy commitments already in place,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's last British governor Chris Patten warned China not to use a heavy hand against any protests.</p>
<p>&quot;It's in everybody's interests to ensure that the arrangements for the handover are able to confirm Hong Kong's reputation for moderation and responsibility,&quot; the Financial Times quoted Patten as saying in an interview.</p>
<p>As the swearing-in ceremony gets under way, Lee and his supporters have said they will peacefully invade the colonial-style legislature building and denounce the new assembly from an outside balcony.</p>
<p>Washington and London, proclaiming concern over human rights under Chinese rule, had decided to boycott the investiture, but were unable to persuade their allies to follow.</p>
<p>In backing down, they cited a practical need to work with the new body.</p>
<p>Opinion polls released on Thursday indicated the new legislature lacked significant public support.</p>
<p>If democratic elections were held now, Lee's Democratic Party would beat pro-Beijing forces hands down and Lee himself would become prime minister, the polls in the South China Morning Post showed.</p>
<p>The job of chief executive has gone to Beijing-appointed shipping magnate Tung Chee-hwa, who on Wednesday unveiled a new honours system rewarding those with &quot;a love for the Motherland&quot;.</p>
<p>Among the first to receive the &quot;Grand Bauhinia Medal&quot; -- named after Hong Kong's new floral emblem -- will be Tung's fellow tycoon Henry Fok, who joined a China-backed rescue of his family's troubled shipping empire in the 1980's.</p>
<p>Fok is often described as Hong Kong's new political kingmaker. He made his money running goods into China during a U.N. trade boycott during the Korean war and was labelled a communist sympathiser by British colonial rulers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
