<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="691082" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: INTERVIEW-Vietnam requires greater dynamism - FM.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Vietnam requires greater dynamism - FM.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Edwards</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam is facing its most critical period since reforms were launched in the late 1980s and will need dynamism and creativity to overcome the problems, Foreign Minister Nguyen Manh Cam said in an interview.</p>
<p>The 68-year-old career diplomat, speaking late on Wednesday, said Vietnam had registered significant successes in the decade since Doi Moi (Renovation) policies were introduced, but added it was now faced with new challenges.</p>
<p>&quot;The new stage requires even more creativeness and knowledge and more dynamism,&quot; he said. &quot;We want to develop Vietnam. Every individual and government ministry wants to try their best... (But) no difficulties means no creativeness.&quot;</p>
<p>Cam did not go into detail about what those difficulties were, but said the government recognised the need to accelerate rural development and focus efforts on building the economy through outward-looking trade and other policies aimed at enabling Hanoi to keep up with its regional neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;In the coming time we will need more effort...&quot; he said, repeating in English, &quot;More effort.&quot;</p>
<p>Vietnam has run into problems recently after a decade of spectacular successes resulting from the communist government's launch of free-market reforms in 1986.</p>
<p>Corruption and bureaucracy coupled with a shifting regulatory environment have taken a toll on foreign investment sentiment, while debt problems and a trade deficit that reached $4 billion last year -- or 17 percent of gross domestic product -- have threatened to shake confidence further.</p>
<p>Swedish economists warned last month that the benefits of Vietnam's economic transformation could be close to exhaustion without further trade reforms and a rethink of policies that favour state enterprises.</p>
<p>But Cam brushed aside those concerns and said that while Hanoi would continue to &quot;protect our infant industry appropriately&quot;, Vietnam intended to fulfil its commitments to trade liberalisation policies outlined in the ASEAN Free Trade Agreement (AFTA).</p>
<p>Under this agreement, Vietnam has pledged to lower tariff and other trade barriers by 2006 to bring itself into line with its Association of Southeast Asian Nation (ASEAN) partners.</p>
<p>&quot;We are convinced that...Vietnam will certainly meet its obligations and commitments, positively contributing to the realisation of the AFTA objectives,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cam, who appeared in good health and is considered a candidate for a future leadership post, was Hanoi's former ambassador to the Soviet Union before being appointed as foreign minister in 1991.</p>
<p>Asked about his track-record as Vietnam's most senior diplomat during a period in which it has normalised relations with old enemies China and the United States and joined the ASEAN regional grouping, Cam was modest.</p>
<p>&quot;Still we haven't felt satisfied with what we've achieved,&quot; he said. &quot;Nevertheless, we try our best, but we haven't done things in the most effective way.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Vietnam intended to maintain and broaden its open door policy along guidelines set out at a Communist Party Congress in 1996, while at the same time taking steps to ensure national security and independence.</p>
<p>Asked if the decisions affecting foreign policy made at that meeting might be reviewed in the light of political changes in Vietnam over the past 12 months and in the region, Cam said: &quot;Our foreign policy is consistent and will see no change. The change, if any, is only how to implement this policy more effectively.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
