<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="691278" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Saudis put final touches to marathon barley deal.</title>
<headline>Saudis put final touches to marathon barley deal.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabia was putting the final pieces in place on Thursday morning for a $140 million grain deal to buy a million tonnes of barley for its animal herds this autumn, European grain traders said.</p>
<p>Negotiations to supply the world's largest barley importer, now in their third day, have dragged on longer than usual because of the heavy response to an international tender.</p>
<p>One trader estimated the total amount of barley offered at four million tonnes, of which the kingdom's buyers must sift through the best offers to match volume, dates and price.</p>
<p>&quot;That's why it is taking so long, but I would say it is being done this morning,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Traders said on Wednesday that the best offers to supply the barley were at $142 per tonne including the $20-22 cost of freight as well as colouring necessary for Saudi barley imports.</p>
<p>A small proportion of imported barley must by dyed red to meet Saudi rules for distinguishing it from the local crop.</p>
<p>Traders said the final deal was likely to emerge in a range between $142 and $146 or $148 per tonne, worth $120-122 and upwards as an fob departure price for grain exporters.</p>
<p>That is considered cheap by several traders -- one of whom called the tender a &quot;bloodbath&quot; on prices -- but others point to the sharp recent fall in world wheat and corn values.</p>
<p>U.S. soft red winter wheat was pegged overnight at $130 per tonne and U.S. no.2 yellow corn at $109, both for September.</p>
<p>Fob export barley has recently been quoted around $130 per tonne fob and Iran on Wednesday bought a far smaller quantity of 50,000 tonnes of barley for October shipment at $127-128, fob.</p>
<p>The Saudi purchase tender is for one million tonnes of barley from any export origin to be delivered in September and October.</p>
<p>The European Union, Canada, the U.S. and Australia are among the leading exporters likely to supply the barley.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
