<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="691319" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Wars decline in '96 but not through peace-SIPRI.</title>
<headline>Wars decline in '96 but not through peace-SIPRI.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of major armed conflicts around the world fell to 27 in 1996 but only thanks to inactivity rather than peace treaties, the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI) said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Swedish defence research organisation said in its annual survey that there were 27 major conflicts waged in 24 locations worldwide in 1996 compared to 30 in 25 places in 1995.</p>
<p>All but one were internal. The first interstate conflict since 1992 broke out when troubles between India and Pakistan over the Kashmir issue flared up again.</p>
<p>SIPRI said the 1996 figures showed the downward trend in conflicts had continued for the seventh year running, falling since 1989 when there were 36 conflicts in 32 locations.</p>
<p>But SIPRI said few comprehensive peace agreements were reached last year and those in place were often in trouble.</p>
<p>&quot;The decline in the number of conflicts was mainly because they were inactive rather than because the incompatibility was resolved,&quot; said SIPRI's yearbook, which is considered the standard reference work on world conflicts and disarmament.</p>
<p>&quot;This also explains why conflicts have reappeared in the statistics after a time of absence.&quot;</p>
<p>Of the 27 major armed conflicts recorded for 1996, the origins of 22 can be dated back to before 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;(This) suggests that the longer a war or the more intense a war, the more difficult is its peace process,&quot; SIPRI said.</p>
<p>However, 1996 did see the end of the post-Cold War period.</p>
<p>Conflicts where Cold War superpower involvement was the greatest appeared to have ended and most of the fighting emerging from the breakup of the Soviet Union and Yugoslavia was at least contained by the end of 1996, SIPRI said.</p>
<p>But SIPRI noted that not only were armed conflicts spreading over larger areas now, but so was general social and political instability, which pointed to a lack of state legitimacy.</p>
<p>&quot;The causal links obviously go both ways -- armed conflict leads to instability and instability leads to armed conflict,&quot; SIPRI said.</p>
<p>&quot;Thus a region becomes locked into a vicious spiral, in some cases towards complete state failure, as in Somalia and Zaire.&quot;</p>
<p>Three major armed conflicts were listed in 1996 but not in 1995 of which two were old conflicts reignited, including the fighting between India and Pakistan.</p>
<p>In Northern Ireland the ceasefire with the Irish Republican Army (IRA) broke down.</p>
<p>The new conflict on the list was in northern Uganda, where fighting between the government and the guerrilla Lord's Resistance Army surged last year, although it began in 1993.</p>
<p>Six wars recorded in 1995 did not reappear in 1996.</p>
<p>These were the last remaining conflicts in the former Yugoslavia, Angola and Liberia.</p>
<p>Two others were removed from the list after what appeared to be a victory by one side -- the Indian government in Punjab and the Burmese government over the Mong Tai Army which has been fighting for independence of the Shan state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
