<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="691398" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's TV Azteca sees 33 pct ad market share '97.</title>
<headline>Mexico's TV Azteca sees 33 pct ad market share '97.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-06-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's private television network TV Azteca on Wednesday estimated it would capture about a third of the country's total TV advertising market this year.</p>
<p>Mexico's total television ad market this year will be about $1.2 billion, company officials said at a television industry conference in Mexico City. They did not give comparative figures for the ad market last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate that TV Azteca will sell about $400 million in ad sales, about a third of the potential market,&quot; said Gustavo Guzman, vice-president of sales at Azteca.</p>
<p>Mexico's television market is dominated by Azteca and its more powerful rival, Grupo Televisa SA. However, since its privatization a few years ago, Azteca has steadily gained audience and ad market share.</p>
<p>Guzman said Azteca is considering making further moves in Central America, where it recently paid $15 million for a network in El Salvador.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to buy networks in other countries there in the same way we did in El Salvador,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Azteca is already bidding for channels up for grabs in Guatemala, he said.</p>
<p>Azteca will present its ad plan for clients for 1998 on July 15, he added.</p>
<p>((--Cyntia Barrera Diaz, Mexico City newsroom +525 728 9549))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
