<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="691372" id="root" date="1997-06-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: OPEC freezes output, vows quota compliance.</title>
<headline>OPEC freezes output, vows quota compliance.</headline>
<byline>Rosalind Russell</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>OPEC talks in Vienna resulted in an agreement to try to rescue weak oil prices by extending a freeze on the cartel's production quotas until the end of the year.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia and Iran also extracted renewed vows from those of the 11 members - a majority - who flout the mandatory limits that they will now stop their cheating.</p>
<p>Prices ticked briskly up on the news from the Vienna conference of the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries on Wednesday. North Sea Brent crude settled 35 cents firmer at $18.21 per barrel.</p>
<p>But sceptical analysts said that, longer term, the market would demand proof of actual production cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;People will not believe that anything has changed until they see it,&quot; said Leo Drollas, economist at the London-based Centre for Global Energy Studies.</p>
<p>The accord that is being extended sets a ceiling on total OPEC volume at 25.03 million barrels daily, including exports by Iraq under its food-for-oil deal with the United Nations.</p>
<p>But violations by exporters like Venezuela and Nigeria have taken actual supply to 27 million.</p>
<p>Prices have sagged, down to around $18 per barrel from $25 in January, vexing Iran in particular, and apparently also irritating OPEC linchpin Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>Ministers said there were no threats this time by the Saudis to turn up the taps on their huge unused capacity as a retaliatory measure.</p>
<p>But delegates believed that Oil Minister Erwin Arrieta of Venezuela got a tongue lashing at private talks with the Saudis' Ali Naimi and Iran's Gholamreza Aghazadeh.</p>
<p>Later, said a Gulf source, Venezuela confessed to excess of 800,000 barrels or 30 percent above its quota - something it has always stoutly denied.</p>
<p>&quot;All of the cheaters made confessions,&quot; said this source.</p>
<p>The source said that all except three big Gulf producers -- Saudi Arabia, Kuwait and the United Arab Emirates -- plus Libya and Indonesia were guilty to some degree.</p>
<p>Naimi meanwhile told lobby reporters that what followed was a &quot;100 percent&quot; commitment to quotas.</p>
<p>Some seasoned OPEC-watchers were sceptical.</p>
<p>John Lichtblau, head of Petroleum Industry Research Associates, deemed it &quot;unthinkable&quot; that populous, cash-pinched sellers like Venezuela and Nigeria could cut to quota.</p>
<p>U.S. oilman Oscar Wyatt questioned whether fuel demand would be strong enough to lift prices if OPEC produces as much as it is likely to do.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing to lift this market...it would have to be some external event other than consumption,&quot; said Wyatt, retiring chairman of Coastal Corp.</p>
<p>OPEC's problem is that is lacks a mechanism to compel a sovereign state to honour its quotas, although Iraq was briefly an effective &quot;policeman&quot; in 1990 just before it invaded Kuwait and when its tanks stood on Gulf frontiers.</p>
<p>Its oil minister, Amir Rasheed, told reporters in Vienna on Wednesday, however, that promises to keep to quota would suffice now.</p>
<p>&quot;We got their assurances and that is more efficient than any mechanism,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OPEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
