<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="691499" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CORPORATE BONDS - Junk bonds quiet but steady.</title>
<headline>US CORPORATE BONDS - Junk bonds quiet but steady.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. high-yield corporate bonds were little changed in a typically quiet summer Friday session, while some big investment grade issuers capitalized on lower rates, dealers said.</p>
<p>High-yield issuance was limited to Archibald Candy Corp's $100 million 10.25 percent B2/single-B seven-year senior secured note deal, priced at par to yield 385 basis points over U.S. Treasuries via Jefferies &amp; Co.</p>
<p>The issue was well bid in the aftermarket, traders said, quoted at 101-1/4 at mid-afternoon.  </p>
<p>Despite the apparent success of that deal, several traders said the market was extremely quiet on Friday and a true read of investor sentiment was difficult to gauge. But opinions were mixed, as were prices, regarding any recovery of the tone from the sloppy session endured on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a few spotty things happening with some things up and some down,&quot; one trader at a New York shop said. &quot;But there's a lot of apathy today and on the whole things are unchanged.&quot;  </p>
<p>Closely watched high-yield bond fund cash flows from AMG Data provided little solace on Friday. Weekly inflows slowed to $128.3 million in the week ended June 25, compared to $457.7 million and $627.4 million in the prior two weeks.</p>
<p>Some issues slated for pricing on Friday were yet to be seen by late afternoon. Among the issues are: Boyd Gaming Corp's $250 million 10-year 144a senior subordinated notes from Salomon Brothers; Glasstech Inc's $70 million 10-year 144a senior notes from CIBC Wood Gundy Securities; and West Coast Entertainment Corp's $110 million 144a seven-year senior notes from Credit Suisse First Boston.  </p>
<p>Salomon Brothers and CIBC Wood Gundy did not return phone calls late in the session. West Coast Entertainment's pricing timeframe was still uncertain at that time, said a source close to that deal.</p>
<p>Secondary high-yield trades were limited. Grand Union's 12 percent debt due 2004 dropped about one point, but one trader discounted the weakness as all trades were small.  </p>
<p>In the investment grade arena, Bear Stearns Cos Inc sold $400 million 6-1/2 percent three-year notes to yield 40 basis points over Treasuries and First Maryland Bancorp issued $200 million 7.20 percent 10-year notes to yield 76 basis points over the curve.</p>
<p>Bear Stearns &amp; Co led the former deal and Goldman Sachs &amp; Co managed the latter.</p>
<p>Investment grade issuance totaled about $7.5 billion on the week. Junk bond supply was more than $2.5 billion.</p>
<p>In the Treasury market, a Federal Reserve coupon pass and short-covering helped break prices out of a week-long slump, analysts there said. The benchmark 30-year bond closed up 14/32 to yield 6.78 percent and the 10-year T-note rose 8/32 to yield 6.46 percent.</p>
<p>((--Al Yoon, 212-859-1672))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
