<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="691408" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP Legal Affairs Committee agenda - June 30-July 1.</title>
<headline>EP Legal Affairs Committee agenda - June 30-July 1.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Legal Affairs and Citizens' Rights</p>
<p>[[ Monday 30 June 1997 ]]</p>
<p>===] Monday, 30 June 1997</p>
<p>===] afternoon</p>
<p>1.1 In the presence of the Council and Commission</p>
<p>2. Industrial designs and models: legal protection (directive) (T02083) (93/114) (T02083) COD0464 COM(96)0066 C4-0296/97 + JURI Fond R MEDINA ORTEGA M. (PSE) (PE217.342/CM ) - Exchange of views</p>
<p>3. Services of general interest in Europe (Commission communication) (T04993) (96/110) (T04993) COS0459 COM(96)0443 C4-0507/96 + JURI Avis A COT Jean-Pierre. (PSE) (PE220.569 ) F ECON Fond R BILLINGHAM Angela T. (PSE) - Consideration of draft opinion - Decision on procedure</p>
<p>4. United Nations Convention of 10 December 1982 on the Law of the Sea (T05419) (97/024) AVC97038 COM(97)0037 + JURI Fond R COT Jean-Pierre. (PSE) (PE221.629 ) - Exchange of views</p>
<p>5. Coordinators' meeting (PE222.476/AN1 )</p>
<p>===] Tuesday, 1 July 1997</p>
<p>===] morning</p>
<p>6. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure</p>
<p>7. Admission to the occupation of road haulage and passenger transport operator and mutual recognition of diplomas (T05401) (97/008) **I (T05401) SYN97029 COM(97)0025 C4-0087/97 + JURI Fond R BERGER Maria. (PSE) (PE221.449 ) - Adoption of draft report</p>
<p>8. Final phase of the EC/Turkey Customs Union - Community position in the Joint Committee (T04739) (97/022) (T04739) CNS96020 COM(96)0018 C4-0126/96 + JURI Avis L GEBHARDT Evelyne. (PSE) (PE222.272/CM ) F POLI Fond R KITTELMANN Peter. (PPE) - Examination of the legal basis</p>
<p>9. Community system for fisheries and aquaculture - amendment of Regulation (EEC) No 3760/92 (T04991) (97/043) (T04991) CNS96183 COM(96)0350 C4-0538/96 + JURI Avis L GEBHARDT Evelyne. (PSE) F PECH Fond R SOUCHET Dominique. (EDN) (PE220.890/DEF) - Examination of the legal basis</p>
<p>===] afternoon</p>
<p>10.1 Budget 1998 - Section III (T05367) (97/017A) (T05367) BUD0083 + JURI Avis A ROTHLEY Willi. (PSE) (PE221.445/AM1) F BUDG Fond R TILLICH Stanislaw. (PPE) (PE222.006 ) - Exchange of views with the participation of Mr EMRINGER, Director General of the Office for Official Publications on - the question of access to legal documents</p>
<p>10.2 Budget 1998 - other sections (T05368) (97/017B) (T05368) BUD0084 + JURI Avis A ROTHLEY Willi. (PSE) (PE221.445/AM1) F BUDG Fond R TOMLINSON John E. (PSE) (PE222.907 ) - Exchange of views</p>
<p>===] Wednesday, 2 July 1997</p>
<p>===] morning</p>
<p>11. Exchange of views with Mr GARZON CLARIANA, Jurisconsult, on: - the opportunity to intervene in a case pending before the Court on Justice (97/012) - cases pending before the Court ot Justice on which Parliament has an interest - the contents of some of the news provisions of the Amsterdam Treaty</p>
<p>11.1 This item will be held in camera.</p>
<p>12. Any other business</p>
<p>13. Date of next meeting (PE/VII/OJ/16-97 )</p>
<p>13.5 Deadline for texts for translation before the next meeting (reminder): - Wednesday, 18 June 1997 A N N E X I</p>
<p>===] APPOINTMENT OF RAPPORTEUR ON:</p>
<p>1. 14th annual report on monitoring application of Community law (1996) (T05552) (97/058) ATT1538 + JURI Fond - Rapporteur - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - Group - - - - - - Points - - - - - - by rotation: ELDR</p>
<p>1.1 * * *</p>
<p>===] APPOINTMENT of DRAFTSMAN on:</p>
<p>2. A Union policy against corruption (communication) (T05530) (97/056) (T05530) COS0571 COM(97)0192 C4-0273/97 + JURI Avis F LIBE Fond R BONTEMPI Rinaldo. (PSE) - Draftsman - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - Group - - - - - Points - - - - - no provision yet for adoption</p>
<p>3. Further development of mobile and wireless communications - Challenges and choices for the European Union (T05525) (97/055) (T05525) COS0569 COM(97)0217 C4-0271/97 + JURI Avis F ECON Fond R (PPE) - Draftsman - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - Group - - - - - Points - - - - - no provision yet for adoption</p>
<p>4. Consumer health and food safety (T05513) (97/051) (T05513) COS0563 COM(97)0183 C4-0238/97 + JURI Avis F ENVI Fond R PAPAYANNAKIS Mihail. (GUE) - Draftsman - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - Group - - - - - Points - - - - - no provision yet for adoption A D D E N D U M</p>
<p>0.</p>
<p>1. (97/059) Implementation of Community law in the Kingdom of the Netherlands (97/059) Question de l'application du droit communautaire au Royaume des Pays-Bas - Exchange of views - FIN - i END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
