<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="691718" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: CLOUDS MAY FORM OVER ZLOTY NEXT WEEK TRADERS SAY.</title>
<headline>CLOUDS MAY FORM OVER ZLOTY NEXT WEEK TRADERS SAY.</headline>
<byline>Wojciech Moskwa</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish markets could be headed into rough waters next week as unsettled foreign investors ponder whether to slim zloty positions amid a ballooning current account deficit, dealers said on Friday.</p>
<p>This week dealers received mixed signals from foreigners, some of whom had sold short-term Polish papers over the last few days, worried that the zloty would weaken over time.</p>
<p>&quot;Some foreigners have been slowly closing positions over the week, while others are asking about (buying) T-bills, to take advantage of the zloty's recent fall,&quot; said Piotr Bednarek, senior dealer at ING Bank in Warsaw.</p>
<p>As a result of the withdrawal, which has so far been confined to short-term instruments and spared longer-term bonds, the zloty fell about half a percentage point against the basket of currencies this week.</p>
<p>Some said foreigners were discouraged by a statement made by deputy central banker Witold Kozinski this week, who signalled that a Czech-style financial crisis may be further down the road for Poland if it failed to balance its budget in 1998, which the government later said was impossible.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a signal that the ice may still be thin underneath Poland's macro reforms and the market should pay attention to these extreme statements as they don't come from an extreme man,&quot; David Mars, head of Emerging Europe and Africa Economic Research at SBC Warburg in London, said earlier this week.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) backed up Kozinski with a strong worded statement of its own, which called for a balanced budget by 1999 and an immediate tightening of the country's already restricitive monetary policy.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Marek Belka tried to soothe investors reassuring monetary tightening and planned 1998 deficit reduction were sufficient to prevent the external deficit from reaching critical levels next year.</p>
<p>Dealers said however the zloty, which on Friday found balance at about one percent above the parity rate, could be in for a rough ride if further waves of foreign withdrawal hit the foreign exchange market next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Buyers and sellers are at equal strength now and the zloty is range bound...but its seems that the zloty's downside could be more vulnerable in days to come,&quot; said Mateusz Bienek, forex dealer at Societe Generale in Warsaw.</p>
<p>On Friday the zloty was fixed at an average of one percent from the weighted dollar and mark parity rates, weaker than last Friday's 1.49 percent fix.</p>
<p>Dealers said the zloty would probably not be under downward pressure from the start of next week, but said that a rise above one percent from parity could set off more foreign sales of Polish paper.</p>
<p>Dealers said Polish T-bill yields would continue to rise at next Monday's 1.1 billion zloty primary auction amid small interest from both domestic players and foreigners.</p>
<p>They expected the 52-week T-bill yield to rise to 21.70 percent from Wednesday's 21.67 and the maximum to about 21.73.</p>
<p>&quot;This week's statements were definitely not optimistic about Poland's longer term outlook, which should be reflected in higher yields on Monday,&quot; said Wojciech Labryga, dealer at Bank Slaski SA.</p>
<p>Dealers said the 13-week and 26-week yields would also rise by about five basis points from 21.00 and 21.49 percent respectively at the last primary tender.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
