<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="691892" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Short-covering by local banks after a hefty institutional order earlier hauled bond yields to their lowest levels in 16 months on Friday.</p>
<p>After drifting between 14.46 and 14.37 percent for much of the trading day, yields suddenly gapped to an intraday low of 14.30 percent -- its lowest level since February 20 last year -- shortly before 1400 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;During lunch a local institution took out a few banks. Then when the banks tried to cover this afternoon, there seemed to be a bit of a tight squeeze...the guys were caught short,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the demand from institutions in general over the last few days appeared to stem from a shift in sentiment away from the money market, where short-term rates have been falling steadily, towards bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;Institutions are piling in at the moment after thinking that the money market was a good place to be all year,&quot; one said, adding that chart signals on the long-end were extremely bullish and that there was a general dearth of stock in the market.</p>
<p>A broker also noted that there were positive expectations in the market of bullish money supply and private sector credit extension data -- due for release at 1500 GMT.</p>
<p>Economists have called for a 15.19 percent increase in May money supply growth from a preliminary 15.44 percent in April, while growth in credit extended to the private sector was expected to rise 16.56 percent year-on-year from 16.95 percent before.</p>
<p>Dealers said barring any negative surprises from the Reserve Bank data, the market was likely to extend its gains further on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
