<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="692013" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Rally leads Romania OTC market higher.</title>
<headline>Rally leads Romania OTC market higher.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong buying of high-cap stocks pushed Romania's over-the-counter (OTC) market forward on Friday, helping it to extend previous gains.</p>
<p>Traders expected prices to touch new highs early next week, with foreign investors putting pressure on the heavyweights. They said high-caps were seen growing stable by mid-week.</p>
<p>On Friday, leaders outnumbered decliners by 143 to 86, with the prices of 329 stocks remaining flat.</p>
<p>Three independent indices, computed by brokerage houses on the basis of average prices and market capitalisation, soared from Wednesday's session. The VAB-RA all-share index went up by 3.4 percent to 4,654.3 points, BIG-OTC rose by 3.86 percent to 3,652.52 and CAS-RQ jumped 3.7 percent to 835 points.</p>
<p>Traders said refineries, as well as steel mills had been in high demand.</p>
<p>Oil refinery Petromidia closed 1,000 lei stronger at 37,500, while another refinery, Arpechim, firmed 1,000 lei to 34,000.</p>
<p>Steel mill Sidex closed 1,000 lei up at 20,000. The company was expected to reach 25,000 lei by the end of next week.</p>
<p>Otelinox steel mill ended 2,500 lei up at 38,000. Its forthcoming move to the Bucharest exchange was expected to help its prices higher on Monday. Otelinox won approval for bourse listing and will join trading next month. A local broker said it would be suspended from OTC trading on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Turnover inched down to 25.14 billion lei from 25.23 on Thursday.</p>
<p>($=7,027 lei)</p>
<p>-- Andrei Iva, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
