<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69215" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnian factions pursue war aims through other means.</title>
<headline>Bosnian factions pursue war aims through other means.</headline>
<byline>Dan de Luce</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnia's factions are jockeying for position in the country's peacetime presidency and analysts say the main Moslem party may soon find itself squeezed by Croat and Serb leaders who oppose a unitary state.</p>
<p>Disagreements between the Serb and Moslem members of the newly-elected collective presidency came to the surface only hours after preliminary election results were announced last week.</p>
<p>The Croat member, Kresimir Zubak, avoided any public comment on the disputes but he chose to meet his Serb counterpart, Momcilo Krajisnik, first before holding talks with the top vote- getter, Moslem president Alija Izetbegovic.</p>
<p>&quot;That was not a coincidence,&quot; said Ivo Komsic, a moderate Croat opposition leader and member of the former collective presidency.</p>
<p>Serb and Croat nationalist leaders may have toned down their rhetoric in the aftermath of the September 14 election, but they remain committed to building separate states in Bosnia, analysts said.</p>
<p>Unlike the main Moslem nationalist party, Serb and Croat nationalists were careful not to run candidates in each other's territory. Komsic said that too was no coincidence.</p>
<p>&quot;They had an agreement on this election. There was a deal,&quot; Komsic told Reuters.</p>
<p>The post-election manoeuvering illustrates how Bosnia has been caught between its powerful neighbours, Croatia and Serbia, throughout the Yugoslav conflict.</p>
<p>Factions founded and sponsored by Croatia and Serbia wield heavy influence over Bosnian politics and effectively control the country's borders.</p>
<p>The Moslem-led Bosnian government enjoys diplomatic recognition but after 3-1/2 years of war its flag flies only along a small stretch of border in the northwest, a symbol of Sarajevo's impotence.</p>
<p>When asked about Serb-Croat relations, Krajisnik said last week his side would form no coalition against another party.</p>
<p>Western diplomats say the Bosnian Serbs have at last grasped the importance of expressing public support for the wishes of the international community.</p>
<p>&quot;They have learned how to say &quot;Yes'. That's a step forward,&quot; said one diplomat. &quot;Whether they will follow through is another matter.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department has dismissed speculation about alliances forming in the collective presidency and says all three parties have committed themselves to making the joint bodies work.</p>
<p>U.S. and European diplomats say they expect Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic to ensure compliance from the Bosnian Serb leadership as he is anxious to win the permanent lifting of economic sanctions against his country.</p>
<p>Washington, which brokered the Dayton agreement, may have more difficulty forcing Croatian President Franjo Tudjman to deliver his Bosnian Croat proteges, diplomats said.</p>
<p>Unlike Serbia, analysts say the United States lacks real leverage over the Croats.</p>
<p>Since the Dayton treaty was signed in December, Tudjman has twice been called to the White House for brow beatings.</p>
<p>U.S. officials reprimanded Tudjman for allowing the Bosnian Croats to retain their self-declared mini-state, &quot;Herceg-Bosna&quot;.</p>
<p>Although he pays lip service to the peace pact, diplomats say Tudjman remains committed to a &quot;Greater Croatia&quot;.</p>
<p>As for the Moslem nationalist Party of Democratic Action (SDA), analysts say the party has become increasingly strident and ran a campaign appealing almost exclusively to Bosnian Moslems.</p>
<p>Critics say the SDA leadership is incapable of guiding the country to post-war reconciliation among Roman Catholic Croats, Orthodox Christian Serbs and Moslems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
