<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="692150" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks seen buoyant, peso slightly weak.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks seen buoyant, peso slightly weak.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>-Mexico stocks viewed slightly up at open</p>
<p>-Peso expected weak on month-end dollar demand</p>
<p>-Cetes overnight rate seen nervous on seasonal pressures</p>
<p>The Mexican bourse was expected to open lightly up on Friday because of left-over buy orders from Thursday's close, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market should open up, we expect less activity (during the day),&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>He added that the upcoming Federal Reserve Open Market Committee on July 2 and the U.S. July 4 holiday were keeping many players out of the market.  </p>
<p>Technical analysts situated support at 4,400 points on the IPC index, compared to Thursday's close of 4,464.98 points.</p>
<p>The peso was seen opening on the weak side, because of end of the month and end of the week demand for dollars.</p>
<p>The spot, or 48-hour peso, was expected to trade between 7.95 and 7.97 pesos per dollar. Pre-open bids stood at 7.9540/7.9580 per dollar, compared to Thursday's close of 7.9500/7.9555.  </p>
<p>The overnight Cetes rate was expected to rise as big buyers held back from the market.</p>
<p>The overnight interest rate could close at between 21 and 22 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>((--Timna Tanners, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7903))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
