<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="692259" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China's troop movements send shudder through HK.</title>
<headline>China's troop movements send shudder through HK.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Communist China sent a shudder through Hong Kong on Friday, announcing its plans to send 4,000 troops streaming into the territory by land, sea and air just hours after taking over the British colony next week.</p>
<p>Word of the looming arrival of the People's Liberation Army (PLA) troops, along with 21 armoured cars and six helicopters, brought back memories of the 1989 massacre of pro-democracy demonstrators centred in Tiananmen Square in Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Beijing leaders)... should have more sensitivity towards Hong Kong people's feelings. Hong Kong people are not very enamoured of the PLA,&quot; pro-democracy campaigner Emily Lau said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't need so many, and we don't need them coming in such a fashion by air, land and sea. Come on -- the people of Hong Kong are worried about the PLA,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Chris Patten, the last of Britain's governors after more than 150 years of colonial rule, was also quick to condemn the decision to send in such a large force along with the ominous armoured cars.</p>
<p>&quot;It doesn't sound to me the right sort of signal to send to the international community and above all I think it is a most appalling signal to send to the people of Hong Kong,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>The 1989 Tiananmen events provoked a dramatic flight of people and capital from Hong Kong and galvanised the local pro-democracy movement.</p>
<p>The arrival of the PLA has been one of the greatest concerns for Hong Kong residents in their return to Chinese rule.</p>
<p>&quot;Without a show like this, they probably wouldn't feel like they were really here. It just shows how different the two systems are,&quot; said pro-democracy legislator Christine Loh.</p>
<p>About 700 PLA troops will already be in Hong Kong before the handover at midnight on June 30 but Beijing had previously kept details of later deployments secret.</p>
<p>When Beijing did announce details, it was through the office of Tung Chee-hwa, its handpicked chief executive-designate for the new Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (SAR).</p>
<p>The statement said 4,000 troops along with helicopters, ships and the armoured cars, would cross the border at three points at 6 a.m. (2200 GMT) on July 1.</p>
<p>That will be just six hours after Prince Charles, heir to the British throne, formally gives up the fiercely capitalist colony of 6.4 million people to China.</p>
<p>The PLA troops in Hong Kong will be answerable not to Tung but to the central Chinese government, and will not be bound by SAR laws. They will be stationed in former British barracks, where up to 10,000 troops were once stationed to guard against the threat from China. In recent months the number of British troops has dwindled to fewer than 1,000.</p>
<p>Governor Patten said he would try to stop China from making such a show of military force but there was, in fact, little he can do in the final days of British rule.</p>
<p>&quot;I do think that it is most unfortunate that this decision has been made. We will continue to make representation and hope that this decision is reversed.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I'm right in saying the arrival of the armoured personnel carriers will more or less coincide with the evening network news in the United States of America,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
