<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="692348" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China's B share markets split on HK handover.</title>
<headline>China's B share markets split on HK handover.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's foreign currency B share markets on Friday offered different views on the return of Hong Kong to Chinese rule with Shanghai bracing for negative news and Shenzhen optimistic, brokers said.</p>
<p>The split reflected investor uncertainty over the direction of China's stock markets after the handover, which fed a frenzy of share buying earlier this year, they said.</p>
<p>Domestic currency A share markets in both Shanghai and Shenzhen fell sharply on expectations that Beijing will take further steps to crack down on speculation, brokers said.</p>
<p>Shanghai's B index was dragged down by speculation that negative news on market regulation will emerge after the return of Hong Kong to Chinese rule, which takes place at midnight on Monday.</p>
<p>But Shenzhen B shares ended up on a rebound ahead of the holiday for the Hong Kong handover, due to institutional buying of companies expected to post good 1997 interim results.</p>
<p>China's markets will be closed on Monday and Tuesday for a holiday to mark the Hong Kong handover.</p>
<p>The Shanghai B index was dragged down by a sharp decline in the A share market as well as uncertainty over the market's direction after the handover.</p>
<p>The B index fell 0.651 points or 0.79 percent to 81.478 points on volume of 19.669 million shares worth $10.845 million, compared with around $16.4 million on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The major positive factor (the Hong Kong handover) which boosted the market for half a year has faded, and technical charts showed a weak short-term outlook, resulting in today's falls,&quot; a local broker said.</p>
<p>Of 45 B shares, 42 traded with 25 down, 14 up and three flat.</p>
<p>B share companies expected to report poor interim results for the first half of 1997 in July and August rounded out the list of biggest losers on Friday, brokers said.</p>
<p>Shanghai's A share market was hit by rumours Beijing plans to allow part of China's government and institutional shares, which are not traded, to list on the stock market, they said.</p>
<p>The China Securities Regulatory Commission, the market watchdog, denied knowledge of an announcement on the matter.</p>
<p>Shanghai's A share index plunged 36.421 points or 2.71 percent to 1,306.778 points on volume of 530.587 million shares worth 8.3 billion yuan.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Shenzhen's B index rose 0.91 points or 0.63 percent to end at 144.72 after losses for four straight sessions. Turnover expanded to HK$106 million from Thursday's HK$67 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying was focused on counters expected to post strong 1997 interim earnings, which boosted the B share index,&quot; said Cheng Li, an analyst at China Guotai Securities.</p>
<p>Analysts said they expected most listed firms to report slightly better first-half results this year with the effect of last year's two interest rate cuts flowing through to the 1997 interim results. The Shenzhen A share market dipped 10.66 points or 2.32 percent to 449.42 on turnover of 11.5 billion yuan as investors pulled out amid concerns that Beijing may introduce fresh anti-speculative measures in July, brokers said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
