<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="692477" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASA asteroid probe views Mathilde on way to Eros.</title>
<headline>NASA asteroid probe views Mathilde on way to Eros.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Zabarenko</byline>
<dateline>LAUREL, Md 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A NASA space probe waltzed by the asteroid Mathilde on Friday in a fortuitous peek at this large, dark, slow-turning rock on its way to another asteroid, Eros.</p>
<p>The first images made by the Near Earth Asteroid Rendezvous (NEAR) satellite showed the skull-like face of Mathilde, an irregularly shaped &quot;stealth asteroid&quot; with a diameter of roughly 38 miles (61 km).</p>
<p>NEAR will get no nearer to Mathilde than 750 miles (1,200 km), but that should be close enough to glimpse features as small as a football field, according to scientists at Johns Hopkins University's Applied Physics Laboratory outside Washington, which built the space probe for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</p>
<p>The unmanned craft was expected to snap about 780 pictures of Mathilde's dark surface as it sped by at 22,000 mph (35,000 kpm) this weekend.</p>
<p>The first image, which reached Earth on Friday morning, showed a pockmarked lump that looked eerily like a human skull, complete with eye sockets and a gaping mouth.</p>
<p>The mouth was a crater as deep as Mount Everest is high, researchers said as the images were beamed down to Earth. A second image showed a deep gash.</p>
<p>Researchers know little about Mathilde except that it is extremely dark and probably loaded with carbon. Less than 4 percent of the light that hits Mathilde is reflected back, making it one of the blackest objects in our solar system, and NEAR scientist Donald Yeomans dubbed it the &quot;stealth asteroid&quot; because much of it remains dark.</p>
<p>Mathilde is currently about 205 million miles (330 million km) away from Earth in a wide band of asteroids between the orbits of Mars and Jupiter.</p>
<p>Mathilde's slow rotation -- it makes only about one revolution in 17 days at &quot;roughly the velocity of an overweight ant,&quot; according to Yeomans -- has researchers puzzled, and the NEAR images may help resolve that mystery.</p>
<p>Discovered in 1885 in Vienna and named for the wife of the vice director of the Paris observatory, Mathilde is a C-type asteroid, one of the most common types of asteroids and also one of the most primitive.</p>
<p>Astronomers believe Mathilde and other asteroids could be the material left over from the formation of the planets, including Earth, around 4.6 billion years ago.</p>
<p>But the flyby of Mathilde was not part of NEAR's main mission; the rock just happened to be on the way to Eros, another, slightly smaller asteroid that NEAR will encounter in early 1999 and spend a year examining.</p>
<p>To get there, the solar-powered NEAR will get a boost from Earth's gravitational pull in a &quot;slingshot&quot; pass around our planet. NEAR will orbit the potato-shaped Eros as close as nine miles (14 km) from its surface.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAUREL, Md"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
