<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="692441" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks soar as quarter ends, rate outlook steadies.</title>
<headline>Stocks soar as quarter ends, rate outlook steadies.</headline>
<byline>Mary Kelleher</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average soared more than 100 points on Friday, in a strong rebound from recent bouts of profit-taking as the quarter closed and investors were optimistic that U.S. interest rates would remain steady.</p>
<p>Shortly after 1 p.m. EDT/1700 GMT, the blue-chip Dow index was up 107.66 points or 1.40 percent at 7,761.91, following a volatile morning that saw the New York Stock Exchange set, lift, and then replace its curbs on programme trading.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues outpaced losers by a 17-8 margin on volume of 256.2 million shares on the NYSE.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite index rose 5.53 points to 1,441.91.</p>
<p>The stock market was optimistic about prospects for corporate earnings, inflation and interest rates, analysts said. Porfolio managers said they were also still buying stock before the quarter ended.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is moving higher on the conviction the Federal Reserve will not act to raise interest rates when it meets next week,&quot; said Sam Stovall, an analyst at S&amp;P Industry reports. &quot;And the talk around town is that the Fed won't raise rates at its August meeting either.&quot;</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve's policy-making Federal Open Market Committee is set to meet on July 2, with most market-watchers looking for it to leave U.S. interest rates alone.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond partly reflected the outlook for steady interest rates, rising 14/32 points and sending its yield down to 6.75 percent, below 6.78 percent at Thursday's close. The price and yield move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>&quot;There's so much good news around,&quot; said Frank Calta, managing director of institutional trading at Dain Bosworth said. &quot;Earnings reports seem to be bullish, rumours about Japan selling Treasuries look meaningless the Fed doesn't look like it will raise rates, and bonds are up.&quot;</p>
<p>The Commerce Department said a final revised estimate of gross domestic product -- the broadest measure of national economic activity -- showed it expanded at a 5.9 percent annual rate in the first quarter, instead of 5.8 percent.</p>
<p>Even though economic growth was even more robust than previously thought during the first quarter, it has slowed enough since then that the Fed likely can avoid avoid raising interest rates next week to restrain it, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Economics are driving the market this morning,&quot; said Phil Orlando, chief investment officer of Value Line's Asset Management unit.</p>
<p>Earlier in the week, comments by Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto triggered a sell-off in bonds and equities amid fears Japan planned to sell its U.S. government bonds.</p>
<p>The stock market overcame its jitters, rising as money managers bought shares to include in their second-quarter portfolios, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Portfolio managers are still in the market,&quot; said Thomas O'Brien, head trader for domestic equities at Guzman &amp; Co.</p>
<p>But analysts have said that with prices trading at high valuations, the stock market could still see volatile swings.</p>
<p>Among specific issues, PacifiCare Health Systems Inc. fell 8-1/4 to 57-5/8. The company said it expected to report second-quarter earnings per share of 30 cents to 45 cents, below the $1.15 earned before pre-tax charges in the year-ago quarter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
