<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="692543" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USDA comments on quarterly hog inventory report.</title>
<headline>USDA comments on quarterly hog inventory report.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Agriculture Department issued the following comments on its quarterly hog inventory report:</p>
<p>U.S. inventory of all hogs and pigs on June 1, 1997, was 58.2 million head. This was 2 percent above June 1996 and 4 percent above the March 1, 1997 inventory.</p>
<p>Breeding inventory, at 6.95 million head is up 1 percent from June 1, 1996 and up 2 percent from March 1, 1997.  Market hog inventory, at 51.2 million head was 2 percent above last year and 4 percent above last quarter.</p>
<p>The 1997 U.S. pig crop at 25.5 million head was 2 percent more than 1996 but 3 percent less than 1995.  Sows farrowing during this period totaled 2.95 million head, slightly below last year.</p>
<p>Litter rate increases continue at a record level, with an average of 8.65 pigs saved per litter for the March-May period.  Last year the litter rate averaged 8.47 pigs per litter.  Pigs saved per litter by size of operation ranged from 7.60 for operations with 1-99 hogs to 8.80 for operations with more than 2,000 hogs and pigs.</p>
<p>U.S. hog producers intend to have 2.91 million sows farrow during the June-August 1997 quarter, 5 percent above the actual farrowings during the same period last year, but 2 percent lower than 1995.  Intended farrowings for September-November 1997, at 2.89 million sows are 6 percent above 1996 and 3 percent above the 1995 period.</p>
<p>The total number of hogs under contract, owned by operations with over 5,000 head total inventory, but raised by contractees, accounted for 26 percent of the total U.S. hog inventory.</p>
<p>All inventory and pig crop estimates for 1996 were reviewed using final pig crop, official slaughter,  import, and export data in U.S. level balance sheets.  Based on the findings of this review, slight revisions were made to the market hog weight group inventories for March 1997.</p>
<p>((Washington commodities desk 202 898 8467))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100119">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
