<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="692699" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: INSTANT VIEW - Italy cuts discount rate 50 bps.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Italy cuts discount rate 50 bps.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are economists' immediate views on the Bank of Italy's 50 basis point cut in its key discount rate to 6.25 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>The Bank of Italy also cut its fixed term advances or Lombard rate to 7.75 percent from a previous 8.25 percent.</p>
<p>Riccardo Barbieri, economist at Morgan Stanley in London, said: &quot;It's a positive move for the market. Some will argue 75 basis points would have been more bullish for the market.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;(Bank of Italy governor Antonio) Fazio has struck a balance between his caution (on inflation and wages policy) and the approach the Bank of Italy had taken and the need to provide some encouragement to the government in its efforts to cut the budget deficit,&quot; Barbieri said.  </p>
<p>The Bank of Italy last reduced interest rates on January 21 when it cut both the discount and Lombard rate 75 basis points.</p>
<p>Ken Wattret, economist at Paribas in London, said: &quot;The economic rationale (for a cut) has been there for a long long time. Inflation is non existent and increasingly important has been the strength of the currency.&quot;</p>
<p>The lira is currently trading at 976 per mark, much stronger than its central parity of 990 in the European currency grid.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing as ever with the Bank of Italy has turned into a guessing game. Over the three previous cuts the move has come hot on the heels of the CPI figures but this time around there's been a bigger delay, and I think that's basically caught the market out,&quot; Wattret said.  </p>
<p>Preliminary inflation data for June indicates Italian consumer prices are running at 1.4-1.5 percent year on year compared with 1.6 percent in May, the lowest level for 28 years.</p>
<p>The discount rate is now at its lowest level since September 1975.</p>
<p>Wattret said 50 basis points was not very generous but &quot;I think there may be some mileage in expecting another cut in the next quarter. What really matters now is what happens on the budget, this is the key issue for monetary policy in Italy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If the government delivers a tough budget for 1998 including structural cuts in expenditure then the Bank of Italy will reciprocate by lowering rates further. Real short rates are still very high even taking into account of this 50 bps cut. There's still scope for rates to come down but the timing will remain as opaque as ever,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Marcello Esposito of Banca Commerciale Italiana said, &quot;I'm surprised at the cut because no one was expecting one anymore, but 50 basis points is hardly sufficient.</p>
<p>&quot;There's still room for a further cut, the problem is deciding when,&quot; he said, adding that the Bank's caution was clearly linked to the government's budgetary measures. &quot;We could see a further half point reduction in autumn, after the 1998 budget has been revealed.&quot;</p>
<p>Mario Noera of Deutsche Bank in Milan said the market would be asking what data the central bank was monitoring and what specifically had led to this cut.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not know what this cut is linked to,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On the macroeconomic front, all the conditions had for some time seemed in place for a cut, especially after Italy's EMU convergence plan had been approved, but there were still the problems of France, Germany and the single currency to be resolved.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was looking for more than a half point cut, I think we'll have to wait until autumn for another similar one,&quot; Noera said.</p>
<p>Roberto Fumagalli of JP Morgan in Milan said, &quot;A cut of 50 basis points doesn't change life much but it's better than nothing and will certainly help. Market reaction will not be negative.&quot;</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +39 2 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
