<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="692611" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton says tobacco deal must not cripple FDA.</title>
<headline>Clinton says tobacco deal must not cripple FDA.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton on Friday said the tobacco settlement proposal was a &quot;terrific achievement&quot; but must not be allowed to paralyze the Food and Drug Administration.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a terrific achievement,&quot; Clinton said of the negotiated settlement reached a week ago between the tobacco industry and state attorneys general. &quot;But my preliminary take is that we do not want to paralyze the capacity of the FDA to protect the American people.&quot;  </p>
<p>Under the accord, cigarette makers agreed to recognise the authority of the FDA to regulate tobacco and nicotine.</p>
<p>But critics, including leading U.S. public health groups, said the actual legal language in the accord would severely hamper FDA authority over tobacco. They demanded revisions.</p>
<p>Clinton's comments about the FDA appeared to be his most critical so far about the proposal, which a White House task force will study and which Congress would have to enact.</p>
<p>Clinton also lauded the pact as a historic achievement and said: &quot;Even in Washington, $368 billion is a lot of money.&quot; Much of that money, to be paid by the tobacco industry under the accord, would go to public health and anti-smoking initiatives.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
