<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69272" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: BHP CEO says not bullish on copper price.</title>
<headline>BHP CEO says not bullish on copper price.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chief executive of the Australian resources group The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd has said he wouldn't describe himself as bullish on the price of copper.</p>
<p>John Prescott has also said in a television interview that BHP had to learn to live with the lower price and manage their business accordingly.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't describe myself as bullish about the copper price,&quot; Prescott said on the Business Sunday program, adding he recognised it was cyclical.</p>
<p>BHP became the world's second largest copper producer when it bought U.S. copper producer Magma Copper Co for US$2.4 billion earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's fallen a bit further than it would have had it not been for (the) Sumitomo incident but we have to learn in these circumstances to live with lower copper prices some time and I'd regard any short term spikes as just that,&quot; he said of the copper price.</p>
<p>BHP announced a 23 percent drop in first quarter net profit on Friday. Net profit for the three months to August 31 was A$287 million, down from A$372 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>A stronger Australian dollar exacerbating the weak copper and steel markets was cited by BHP as a factor behind the fall.</p>
<p>Prescott expected the copper price to remain weak for some time, and said BHP would have to manage its business accordingly.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll hunker down and assume that we're in for a rough time on the copper price and we'll manage our business accordingly, which means there'll be clear focus on costs, there'll be clear focus on efficiency and every effort will be made to improve further the performance of our best mines and operations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prescott also said that BHP's boost in copper production was a scheduled boost that was well known in the market, and that copper had been placed in the market before the reduction in price occurred.</p>
<p>BHP shares closed five cents lower at A$16.04 on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
