<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69297" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stages anti-Japan protest over islands.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stages anti-Japan protest over islands.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chanting &quot;Down with Japanese militarism&quot;, thousands of Taiwan protesters marched through the streets of Taipei on Sunday, denouncing Japan's assertion of sovereignty over a chain of uninhabited East China Sea islands.</p>
<p>Between 5,000 and 10,000 demonstrators, accompanied by a band of drummers, waved flags of Taiwan's exiled Republic of China government and shouted &quot;Protect the Diaoyus&quot; as the march wound its way through the capital.</p>
<p>Dozens of activists from Hong Kong and Macau also took part in the rally, sparked by Japan's claim to the islands, known in Chinese as the Diaoyus and in Japanese as the Senkakus.</p>
<p>An effigy of Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto was tied to the front of a car and flogged.</p>
<p>&quot;The Diaoyu islands belong to the Chinese,&quot; protester Wei Tsu-chun told Reuters. &quot;We Chinese people cannot be bullied by any country. We cannot tolerate any country invading our territory.&quot;</p>
<p>The dispute erupted in July after Japanese ultra-rightists erected a lighthouse on one of the islands, angering rival claimants Taiwan and China.</p>
<p>Taiwanese anger has swelled in recent days since Tokyo sent patrol ships to repel private Taiwan vessels that tried to approach the islands.</p>
<p>&quot;Every Chinese person is furious when we hear Japan occupies our Diaoyu islands,&quot; protester Chang Shu-fan said. &quot;I wish they would leave immediately.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan and Hong Kong activists said they would leave from Taiwan late on Sunday to sail to the islands northeast of Taiwan and southeast of Japan's Okinawa to hoist the rival flags of the People's Republic of China and Taiwan's Republic of China.</p>
<p>Taiwan and China have been bitter rivals since a civil war split them in 1949 when the Republic of China government, defeated by the communists, took refuge on the island.</p>
<p>The activists, organised by Taipei county assemblyman Chin Chieh-shou, said they planned to avoid confrontation with Japanese patrol vessels in the area.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, protesters were preparing to board a rusty tanker bound for the islands to play cat-and-mouse with Japanese warships and try to assert China's sovereignty over the isles.</p>
<p>Hong Kong, a British colony on the south coast of China, reverts to Chinese rule next year.</p>
<p>Taiwan said on Saturday it was prepared to defend the Diaoyus, but only as a last resort. Taiwan's foreign ministry is expected to hold a second round of talks with Japan next month on rival claims to fishing waters around the islands.</p>
<p>Japan took the islands as war booty after defeating imperial China in 1895.</p>
<p>Beijing and Taipei say Chinese claims go back centuries but both have resisted mounting calls to expel Japan by force.</p>
<p>Many Taiwan people have criticised their government for taking too conciliatory a stance towards Tokyo and some even suggested that Taipei enlist mainland China's help.</p>
<p>Hong Kong activists have been even more vocal, urging China to respond with force to Japan's territorial assertion.</p>
<p>A group of paroled Taiwan criminals have announced a &quot;dare-to-die&quot; mission to bomb the Japanese lighthouse.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
