<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69299" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai markets seen up, cautious on PM resignation.</title>
<headline>Thai markets seen up, cautious on PM resignation.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Charles</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's financial markets should react positively to news of premier Banharn Silpa-archa's resignation, but the mood will be cautious as investors await a clearer political picture, analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;At least initially the (stock) market will react positively. But then it will probably be stuck in a narrow band as people wait to see what happens,&quot; said Somjai Phagaphasvivat, professor at Thammasat University.</p>
<p>Investment analysts agreed, noting that the bourse rose last week every time a rumour surfaced that Banharn might step down or lose a no-confidence vote.</p>
<p>After a bruising three-day no-confidence debate, where he was blasted with opposition attacks of corruption and mismanaging the economy, Banharn on Saturday announced he would step down in seven days.</p>
<p>He resigned in exchange for support from the five other parties in his coalition during the no-confidence vote. He later won the vote 207-180.</p>
<p>&quot;I must admit that there are things that can still be improved,&quot; Banharn said in his resignation announcement.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore, in order to make it possible (for the government) to solve economic and other problems, I will resign as prime minister within seven days.&quot;</p>
<p>Banharn and his government have been blamed for many of Thailand's financial woes in recent months.</p>
<p>Thailand's battered stock market has tumbled to near three-year lows in the past few weeks, on political uncertainty and investor fears that the government was unable to handle the slowing economy and sagging exports.</p>
<p>Two support funds were set up to shore up the bourse, and although they helped sentiment slightly, most analysts said underlying political and fundamental economic problems needed to be resolved for a sustained rebound.</p>
<p>Thai stocks closed flat on Friday ahead of the outcome of last year's censure debate, with the index ending 2.48 points lower at 1,045.38 after moving in a right range.</p>
<p>Thailand's economic growth is now projected at its slowest level in a decade. Some private economists see gross domestic product growth slowing sharply in 1996 to about 6.2 percent from 8.5 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>The baht has also been clouded by repeated rumours of a devaluation to solve economic problems. Although the central bank denied the rumours, over the past few months it was forced to inject billions of baht through bond repurchase markets and intervene in offshore swap markets to support the baht.</p>
<p>The six parties in the coalition government are currently negotiating to find a successor to Banharn.</p>
<p>But analysts said the cabinet makeup, especially ministers with economic portfolios, is as important to investors as knowing who the new prime minister will be.</p>
<p>&quot;They need to put in credible professionals to be responsible for the economy,&quot; said Somjai.</p>
<p>Banharn's poor choice of economic ministers was part of his downfall, analysts said.</p>
<p>Konkiat Opaswongkarn, president of Asset Plus Securities, said a new prime minister must restore people's confidence and said his most important job will be to name the right people to handle the economy.</p>
<p>Some leading Thai businessmen said they preferred a dissolution of parliament and a total change of government to a new prime minister and a reshuffled cabinet.</p>
<p>The Board of Trade called on Banharn last week to dissolve the house in order to solve economic problems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
