<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693037" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Top court says lap dancing too indecent for Canada.</title>
<headline>Top court says lap dancing too indecent for Canada.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Supreme Court ruled on Thursday that the erotic practice of lap dancing was too indecent for Canadian standards of tolerance.</p>
<p>&quot;In effect, men, along with drinks, could pay for a public, sexual experience for their own gratification and those of others,&quot; Justice John Sopinka wrote in a 7-0 decision. &quot;In my view, such activities gave rise to a social harm that indicates that the performances were indecent.&quot;</p>
<p>Lap dancing, where bare-bottomed women gyrate on customers' laps, became popular in strip joints across Canada after an Ontario judge ruled in 1994 that it was not indecent by the standards previously set by the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>The government appealed that case and won in 1996, prompting the present to the Supreme Court. The case involved Cheaters Tavern in Toronto, managed at the time by Allan East and owned by Patrick Mara, both of whom were charged with allowing indecent performances.</p>
<p>&quot;Patrons of Cheaters could, for a fee, fondle and touch women and be fondled in an intimately sexual manner, including mutual masturbation and apparent cunnilingus, in a public tavern,&quot; Sopinka said.</p>
<p>He said the appropriate test to determine indecency was whatever society was comfortable with at the time -- &quot;the community standard of tolerance.&quot; He agreed with the appeals court that the activities at Cheaters degraded and dehumanized women, dehumanized sexuality and caused people to act in a way &quot;as if we live in a society without any moral values.&quot;</p>
<p>The Supreme Court announced in March that it was upholding the appeals court's conviction of East but it gave its reasoning only on Thursday. It also restored Mara's original acquittal on the grounds that as owner he did not necessarily know what was happening in his strip club.</p>
<p>Sopinka pointed to how the lap dancing was done for all to see and declared that the activities were &quot;indecent insofar as they involved sexual touching between dancer and patron.&quot; He gave little guidance on whether dancers remained free to strip in front of customers as long as they kept their distance.</p>
<p>Sgt. Chris Hobson of the Toronto police morality squad said the brief verdict in March had curbed lap dancing somewhat but everybody had been awaiting Thursday's reasoning.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been a decrease but it's still there. I think this written text, this final decision, will be extremely helpful,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
