<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693029" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PacifiCare warns of shortfall, stock tumbles.</title>
<headline>PacifiCare warns of shortfall, stock tumbles.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Orr</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>PacifiCare Health Systems Inc. warned Friday that its second-quarter profits would be sharply below expectations, sending the managed health care company's stock tumbling for the second time in a week.</p>
<p>In a statement, the company, based in Cypress Calif., said earnings are likely to fall to between 30 cents and 45 cents a share in the quarter, well below the year ago's operating profit of $1.15 a share and below Wall Street's estimates.</p>
<p>PacifiCare also said it expected to report a substantial drop in earnings for the fiscal year ended in December.</p>
<p>The warning triggered a sell-off in its Class A and Class B stock, which both tumbled $4.94 to $60.94 after earlier falling as low as $55.50 on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>The Class B stock tumbled more than 20 percent earlier this week after company warned of a substantial earnings shortfall in the second quarter. However, Friday's specifics were worse than many analysts had expected.</p>
<p>Prior to the company's warning earlier this week, analysts expected PacifiCare to post second-quarter profits of about $1.16 a share. After the statement, analysts cut their estimates by 10 cents to 20 cents a share.</p>
<p>The company attributed the shortfall to substantially higher health care costs in a number of markets, mainly those acquired in the $2.2 billion purchase of FHP International Co.</p>
<p>Weakness in PacifiCare operations in California and Oregon and one-time expenses for reserve increases and other adjustments were also cited.</p>
<p>PacifiCare said the FHP California operations it acquired in February were performing below expectations, due mainly to a decline in commercial prices in 1996, and are responsible for about 25 percent of the total earnings shortfall expected.</p>
<p>The company also said its own operations in California are being hurt by higher-than-expected prescription drug costs and higher health care costs in its Medicare programme.</p>
<p>PacifiCare also forecast a significantly lower membership growth rate this year in its commercial and Medicare product lines, and said medical loss ratios are expected to increase this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We are obviously disappointed by the performance of a number of these newly acquired assets,&quot; President Alan Hoops said in a statement. He added that the integration of FHP operations is proceeding on schedule and according to plan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
