<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693013" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NationsBank near deal to buy Montgomery - report.</title>
<headline>NationsBank near deal to buy Montgomery - report.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>NationsBank Corp. is close to announcing it will buy investment bank Montgomery Securities Inc. for around $1 billion, financial cable television channel CNBC reported Thursday.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for San Francisco-based Montgomery declined to comment on the report or whether an agreement had been reached. But she said the company has made no secret of its plans to find a buyer over the past two months.</p>
<p>She said Montgomery Chairman Thom Weisel has expressed an interest in selling a stake and added the closely held company has held negotiations with several banks.</p>
<p>&quot;He's basically said the business is moving towards one-stop shopping and we need a partner to give us the financial resources to grow the business and one who can strategically help the business,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Officials at Charlotte, N.C.-based NationsBank declined to comment on the report.</p>
<p>A merger between the companies would be the latest in a trend of combinations between commercial banks and brokerage houses.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, BankAmerica Corp. announced it would buy investment bank Robertson Stephens &amp; Co., another San Francisco investment bank, for about $540 million.</p>
<p>In April, Bankers Trust New York Corp. agreed to buy Alex Brown &amp; Sons Inc. for $1.7 billion. A month later, Swiss Bank Corp. agreed to buy Dillon Read &amp; Co. for $600 million.</p>
<p>The wave of mergers was sparked by a recent easing of Federal Reserve restrictions on commercial banks' ability to engage in brokerage activities.</p>
<p>Montgomery specializes in high-technology firms. The brokerage had 1996 revenues of $705 million.</p>
<p>NationsBank stock fell $1 to $66.625 in consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
