<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69310" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Feisty Hong Kong fund puts wind up Hambros.</title>
<headline>Feisty Hong Kong fund puts wind up Hambros.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Davison</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Like a piranha circling a whale, the small but tenacious Regent Pacific Group Ltd is relentlessly pursuing Hambros Plc</p>
<p>&quot;If a company puts itself into the public arena and is owned by shareholders, then it has to be accountable to shareholders for its performance,&quot; Regent Pacific managing director James Mellon told Reuters in an interview this past week.</p>
<p>The venerable investment bank is just the latest prey for Regent, often called a &quot;vulture fund&quot;, reflecting its predatory nature.</p>
<p>Rather than buying up distressed debt at discount prices as most vulture funds do, Regent tries to rip apart under- performing investment funds to return value to unit holders.</p>
<p>&quot;The only reason it (Regent) gets aggressive is because an undervalued situation (is) like an oyster. You have to prise it open to get to the pearl,&quot; Mellon said.</p>
<p>Often, this means having to battle past unwilling management, he said.</p>
<p>Founded in 1990, Regent Pacific is a mid-sized Asian investment fund company with US$2 billion under management.</p>
<p>In addition to managing a variety of its own retail funds and Asian-dedicated portolios for larger institutions, a total of US$1.3 billion of Regent Pacific's assets are held in &quot;under-valued asset&quot; funds dedicated to closed-end funds and Australian property trusts.</p>
<p>Run by a group of tough-minded executives, Regent Pacific usually generates more headlines than the rest of Hong Kong's investment community put together.</p>
<p>&quot;This company is not out to pick fights, even though it might look like that at the moment,&quot; Mellon said.</p>
<p>&quot;This company is out to make as much money as possible on our equity and that is what every company should be doing.&quot;</p>
<p>Following a couple of small successes, Regent Pacific has recently became embroiled in high-profile battles with Pioneer Industries International (Holdings) Ltd and now with Hambros.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Hong Kong-listed Pioneer managed to fend off Regent's attempts to force a sale of its primary holding, a 3.77 percent stake in Bangkok Bank, Thailand's biggest bank.</p>
<p>Accusations by Regent, including an allegation Pioneer's shares were trading at a 60 percent discount to net asset value, has seen them fall to 5.30 from 5.90 when the tussle started. Pioneer's stake has now dropped in value to about HK$2.2 billion.</p>
<p>Now, Regent, with a three percent stake, is threatening to agitate shareholder support for a restructuring of Hambros involving the spinning off of non-core assets.</p>
<p>&quot;Frankly speaking, the thing is better broken up than left as it is,&quot; Mellon said.</p>
<p>Hambros, whose chief executive accused Regent of being &quot;gratuitously rude&quot; after he met a Regent representative last month, has failed to respond publicly to many of Regent's accusations.</p>
<p>Hambros in Hongkong referred calls to its London office, from where there was no immediate comment available.</p>
<p>London-based analysts, who also said Hambros was worth more broken up, cautioned that a buyer was unlikely to surface given the company's poor market performance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
