<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693143" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: ACT change may hit UK investment - tax advisers.</title>
<headline>ACT change may hit UK investment - tax advisers.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Changing the current system of Advance Corporation Tax (ACT) could cost British industry 200 million stg a year more tax on the profits of their U.S. subsidiaries, tax experts at accountants KPMG Tax say.</p>
<p>And getting rid of the ACT tax credit could also reduce the attraction of the UK to international investors as well as substantially increasing the tax burden of foreign multinationals with UK interests, it said in a press release.</p>
<p>There is widespread speculation that the July 2 budget will reduce the 20 percent ACT tax credit on share dividends or even scrap it altogether, to save the government money.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be advisable for the government to issue a consultative document so that all relevant issues could be taken into account,&quot; KPMG warned.</p>
<p>Careless wording of the legislation or scrapping of the tax credit for individuals as well as for tax-exempt entities such as pension funds could triple the rate of withholding tax charged by the U.S. on dividends paid to UK parent companies.</p>
<p>At present, the U.S. levies a reduced withholding tax rate of five percent on dividends paid to UK companies which own at least 10 percent of the voting shares in the relevant U.S. company.</p>
<p>But this reduced rate is dependent on the ACT tax credit. If that is abolished, then a higher rate of 15 percent will apply.</p>
<p>The British/American Chamber of Commerce put the value of total investment by UK companies in the US at the end of 1995 at around 71 billion stg, KPMG said, estimating this means a dividend flow of 2.8 billion stg per year, assuming yields of 4.0 percent.</p>
<p>So an increase in withholding tax to 15 percent from five percent could cost British industry as much as 280 million stg.</p>
<p>&quot;While this is an estimate, it seems unlikely that the total cost to UK industry would be less than 200 million per year and could be considerably more than that,&quot; KPMG said.</p>
<p>The true position is complicated by the fact that some U.S. subsidiaries are held via non-UK international holding companies, with the withholding tax rate dependent on the relevant U.S. treaty.</p>
<p>In terms of inward investment in the UK, there would be an impact on investors from countries such as the U.S., the Netherlands, Italy and Sweden, KPMG said.</p>
<p>--Cheryl Juckes +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
