<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693295" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Muni credit spreads widen in past week -- Delphis.</title>
<headline>Muni credit spreads widen in past week -- Delphis.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>After tightening for several weeks, credit spreads among long-term municipal bonds widened 10 basis points in the week ended Thursday, Delphis Hanover Corp. said Friday.</p>
<p>The credit spread between Aaa-rated and Baa-rated 30-year bonds widened 10 basis points to 70 basis points.</p>
<p>The credit spreads for one-year and 10-year maturities, however, remained unchanged at 65 basis points each.</p>
<p>The high-grade municipal yield curve held mostly steady for the week.</p>
<p>The spread between one-year and 30-year bonds in the triple-A category was unchanged for the second week in a row at 175 basis points. The Baa yield curve steepened 10 basis points to 180.</p>
<p>Average yields on one-year, Aaa-rated municipal bonds rose five basis points for the second consecutive week to 3.70 percent. Baa-rated one-year bonds also rose five, to 4.35 percent.</p>
<p>In the intermediate sector, yields on Aaa-rated 10-year bonds rose five basis points to 4.75 percent, and Baa-rated ten-years rose five to 5.40 percent.</p>
<p>Munis outperformed the Treasury market over the week.</p>
<p>The yield on the government long bond rose 10 basis points to 6.78 percent, after falling 10 in each of the three prior weeks. Thirty-year Aaa-rated municipal yields, meanwhile, rose just five basis points over the same period to 5.45 percent.</p>
<p>Thirty-year, Aaa-rated munis yielded 80.4 percent of the Treasury long bond at the close Thursday, compared to 80.8 percent the week before.</p>
<p>Yields were up 15 basis points on 30-year, Baa-rated bonds, moving to 6.15 percent.</p>
<p>--Steven Dickson, 212-859-1652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
