<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693416" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares seek to shrug off modest slump.</title>
<headline>German shares seek to shrug off modest slump.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were lower in late dealings on Friday but traders said the slump would not deter the market's ongoing rally and prospects for the DAX index to register new record highs in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>But some traders said the DAX index will likely take a breather next week and trade in a range ahead of the Federal Reserve's policy meeting on Tuesday and Wednesday even though no U.S. interest rate change is expected.</p>
<p>&quot;People are playing the market cautiously because of the Fed meeting and also because it's hard to predict these days what Wall Street is going to do,&quot; said one Frankfurt trader.  </p>
<p>&quot;Few people expect much movement ahead of the Fed meeting and there's not many new buy orders in the market,&quot; he said. &quot;We're due for a bit of consolidation.&quot;</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX, which reflects all-day computer trade, was down 8.43 points at 3,811.73 points in post-bourse dealings and about 15 points above the bourse close at 3,795.41 points when the DAX registered a loss of 9.88 points for the session.</p>
<p>Some traders remained optimistic that the DAX index would soon resume its uptrend and test 4,000 points, with the index underpinned by prospects for Germany's economic recovery, a firmer dollar and higher German debt prices.  </p>
<p>&quot;The losses look like a small bout of profit-taking,&quot; said one trader. &quot;The institutional buyers will be back next week.&quot;</p>
<p>Rotating interest in all the main blue chip sectors had supported the market through the week, with banks, chemicals and carmakers all coming in for attention and helping offset factors like Monday's 2.5 percent slide in the Dow Jones index.</p>
<p>On Friday, eight DAX shares rose and twenty two fell during the bourse session.</p>
<p>Dealers noted that Deutsche Telekom AG, trading ex-dividend, was unusually firm amid positive sentiment generated by its shareholder meeting Thursday.  </p>
<p>Telekom shares ended bourse trade up 50 pfennigs at 43 marks but slipped to 42.83 marks in IBIS dealings.</p>
<p>Dealers noted that the market was keen on carmaker shares. Volkswagen AG, boosted by a restatement on Thursday by Merrill Lynch of a strong buy recommendation, advanced 28 marks to 1,305 marks in bourse trade and surged to 1,321 marks in post-bourse computer dealings.</p>
<p>Luxury carmaker BMW AG was also higher on the day, rising five marks to 1,432 marks. BMW shares remained at that level in IBIS trade.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
