<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693550" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kohl tones down Euro-rhetoric but still wants EMU.</title>
<headline>Kohl tones down Euro-rhetoric but still wants EMU.</headline>
<byline>Tom Heneghan</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany, boxed in by its struggle to launch Europe's single currency amid rising voter scepticism about European integration, is cutting back its once-ambitious EU goals to a package of modest and popular measures.</p>
<p>Still determined to see the euro currency start in 1999, Chancellor Helmut Kohl has dropped far-reaching plans for to harmonise policies on such sensitive topics as immigration with his less enthusiastic European partners.</p>
<p>The defensive, new tone, marked by frequent references to German national interests that would not have been expressed before, came across in a speech Kohl delivered to parliament on Friday about the EU's Amsterdam summit.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't become tired of Europe,&quot; he said before critics could make that charge. &quot;But we have to stand up for our own interests as we see them.&quot;</p>
<p>The irony, for Bonn insiders, was that Kohl's original Maastricht strategy foresaw a political union he should have been defending in this speech.</p>
<p>Kohl failed to win that long-standing German goal at the Maastricht summit in 1991 and came home saying the inter-governmental conference on EU reform that has just finished would take that decisive step forward.</p>
<p>But Germany, which now has difficulty meeting the stiff budget deficit criterion for the monetary union that Kohl once again defended, emerged at this month's Amsterdam summit as a foot-dragger on harmonised immigration policies.</p>
<p>Euro-enthusiasm in other countries has waned so much, especially after the departure of Kohl's former ally French President Francois Mitterrand, that talk of a real political union was all but non-existent.</p>
<p>Parallel to public scepticism about a single currency, German voters have become wary about community-wide immigration laws that would let refugees enter the EU through another country but gravitate towards rich Germany.</p>
<p>As Kohl put it: &quot;On the issue of residence requirements for third country citizens living legally in the EU, we were able to agree on clear rules that block uncontrolled access to the German welfare system or the German labour market.&quot;</p>
<p>On other issues as well, Kohl was keen to show he was just as good at blocking integration on policies where German interests were at risk as he has been in the past in pushing his EU partners towards his dream of European unity.</p>
<p>&quot;We opposed majority voting for several issues with good reason, because that was the only way we could protect our own national interests,&quot; he said. &quot;I would name as examples industrial policy, rules for craftsmen and the free movement of seasonal workers.&quot;</p>
<p>The chancellor said seasonal workers sometimes left Germany after a short contract here but continued to draw benefits from its welfare system like unemployment support.</p>
<p>&quot;People in Germany would not understand this, so we have to make sure we are not outvoted on these issues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Officials in Kohl's Christian Democratic Union said the new tone suited the mood in Germany, where the pro-European enthusiasm that post-war West Germans like Kohl share is increasingly challenged by scepticism and concern about all the changes his unity dream would entail.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to meet people on their own ground,&quot; one party strategist said. &quot;There is a lot of scepticism out there.&quot;</p>
<p>This more sober approach was also a signal to other EU partners that Germany, which long pursued a highly pro-European line in part as reconciliation with its former adversaries, was now approaching European issues as a normal country with national interests just like the other members.</p>
<p>&quot;This is what the British and the French do, and we can and should do it too,&quot; the strategist added.</p>
<p>But this did not mean Germany was losing interest in monetary union, a goal which Kohl once again supported in his speech as a key factor in securing Europe's competitiveness on world markets.</p>
<p>Calls for a delay, including those from the increasingly vociferous Bavarian state premier Edmund Stoiber, would only undermine the domestic political foundation on which Kohl's 14-year centre-right coalition stands, the strategist said.</p>
<p>&quot;A delay would give smaller right-wing parties the chance to say to voters 'vote for us, it's your last opportunity to save the Deutschemark',&quot; he said. &quot;A delay would only help these Eurosceptics.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
