<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693624" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Ireland police escape suspected IRA ambush.</title>
<headline>N.Ireland police escape suspected IRA ambush.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-06-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Suspected IRA guerrillas launched a rocket attack on a police patrol in north Belfast on Thursday night but the officers escaped injury, Northern Ireland security sources said on Friday.</p>
<p>A hijacked car believed to have been used by the attackers was found on fire in the nearby republican New Lodge district minutes afterwards, the sources said.</p>
<p>Police said an armoured police Land Rover van had slowed down near a school when the missile was fired at it just before midnight.</p>
<p>&quot;The projectile missed the Land Rover and struck a corner wall of the school. No member of the Land Rover crew was injured and there are no reports at this stage of anyone else having been hurt,&quot; a Royal Ulster Constabulary spokesman said.</p>
<p>No group claimed responsibility, but security sources said the weapon was a type often used by Irish Republican Army guerrillas who have waged a long war against British rule.</p>
<p>British security forces had been on alert for IRA attacks after two police officers were shot dead in Lurgan town on June 16. On Wednesday police foiled a guerrilla plan for a gun attack on a security patrol in south Belfast.</p>
<p>The rocket was fired in a flashpoint zone where tension has been high for months between Catholic nationalists and Protestant loyalists.</p>
<p>Just 36 hours earlier, British Prime Minister Tony Blair launched an initiative to bring peace to the province where the IRA and their pro-British Protestant foes have stepped up hostilities in recent months.</p>
<p>Later on Friday British-sponsored &quot;proximity talks&quot; were due to be held near Belfast to try and broker an agreement between Protestant marchers and Catholic objectors about a contentious parade due on July 6 in the town of Portadown.</p>
<p>Controversy about the annual pro-British &quot;marching season&quot; has fuelled fears of sectarian clashes across the province.</p>
<p>David Brown, a Belfast councillor for the Protestant Ulster Unionist Party, told BBC radio: &quot;That (attack) doesn't send a great message...The IRA have no interest in peace, they are only interested in murdering people.&quot;</p>
<p>Ken Maginnis, a member of parliament for the biggest Protestant party, the Ulster Unionists, said his party had no wish to torpedo Blair's initiative.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;If the initiative is as shallow and as hollow as it appears it is going to be made by Sinn Fein/IRA then how on earth can you expect us to be serious about it.&quot;</p>
<p>In a statement to parliament on Wednesday, Blair detailed Anglo-Irish proposals for defusing a long-running wrangle about how IRA armaments will be scrapped if the guerrillas call a cessation of violence.</p>
<p>He also said full-scale talks on the province's future would start in mid-September regardless of whether Sinn Fein, the IRA's political wing, was at them.</p>
<p>Blair disclosed that three days before the Lurgan murders, Britain told Sinn Fein that it could get into talks six weeks after the IRA called an unequivocal ceasefire.</p>
<p>London and Dublin say that the IRA must abandon violece before Sinn Fein can be given a seat at talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
