<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693984" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta stocks higher at lunchbreak.</title>
<headline>Jakarta stocks higher at lunchbreak.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta stocks made further gains in the midsession on Friday on active buying of secondaries coupled with modest investor interest in selected blue chips, brokers said.</p>
<p>At the lunchbreak, the Jakarta Composite Index was up 4.62 points, or 0.65 percent, to 714.02 points. Gainers led losers by 60 to 40, with 55 counters unchanged. Total turnover was about 306 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;The rebound in the share price of Telkom helped the index gain further in the late morning, but the focus is still on secondaries,&quot; one local broker said.  </p>
<p>Blue chips telecommunications firm Telkom, the heaviest weighted stock on the index, cigarette firm Gudang Garam and cement maker Indocement all made gains in modest buying, brokers said.</p>
<p>But they said the market focus remained on secondaries such as property firm Bakrieland, Surya Semesta Internusa, ceramics manufacturer Intikeramik Alam and engineering firm Bukaka Teknik Utama.  </p>
<p>Bakrieland topped the active list with around 28 million shares traded, rising 125 rupiah to 2,075 rupiah. Brokers said positive sentiment in the stock was boosted by plans for a rights issue and acquisitions.</p>
<p>Brokers said the potential for further gains in the index was small, however, with profit-taking expected in the afternoon session.</p>
<p>--Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
