<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="693994" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Funds overweight Hong Kong but see short-term woes.</title>
<headline>Funds overweight Hong Kong but see short-term woes.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Davison</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Institutional money is largely overweight Hong Kong and views the market positively in the medium to long term, although it expects some volatility in the next few weeks, a Reuters poll showed on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It'll go down and then come back up again,&quot; said Marshall Mays, chief strategist at Nikko Research Center. &quot;I'm underweight now and then I'll go back to overweight.&quot;</p>
<p>Six of nine international and regional fund managers, polled by Reuters this week, revealed an overweight position compared to the benchmark Morgan Stanley Capital Index Asia ex-Japan Free index. Two were underweight and one was neutral.</p>
<p>&quot;Money is already starting to come in, with people saying we are quite happy with the way things are going and are becoming quite happy with the way Hong Kong has begun to prosper under the new arrangements,&quot; said Christopher Ryan, managing director of HSBC Asset Management.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the money that has been coming into the market has been coming from offshore, and that is something we really haven't seen in the past couple of years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong stocks have been on a roller-coaster ride in the past few weeks, lurching into record territory as the colony prepares for its return to Chinese rule at midnight on Monday.</p>
<p>But the emergence of red chips, Hong Kong-based companies with mainland parents, have made fund managers nervous.</p>
<p>&quot;We anticipate changing our (Hong Kong) weighting,&quot; said David Semple, regional strategist at Peregrine Asset Management.</p>
<p>&quot;We are long-term believers and certainly we don't like to categorise ourselves as traders, but the fact is, this is a very strange happening.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still happy to be well overweight at the moment but if things move too quickly - and we can anticipate some volatility - we might change our heavily overweight allocation.&quot;</p>
<p>Red chips started to soar in February as investors anticipated future asset injections of unknown value by Chinese parents.</p>
<p>By contrast, the Hang Seng index backed away from a breach of the 15,000 level in early June, sagging while red chips attained stellar average price to earnings ratios of at least 30 times -- far higher than the Hang Seng average of 15.</p>
<p>But, after a two week slide that took the Hang Seng back below 14,000, investors piled back in pushing Hong Kong blue chips above the key 15,000 barrier and confirming investor enthusiasm for Hong Kong's future after July 1.</p>
<p>The index closed Friday's morning session 6.88 points higher at 15,134.90 points.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain more confident rather than less of the Hong Kong market in the next few months,&quot; said Stewart Aldcroft, director of marketing for Templeton Franklin Investment Services.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe China will be a great supporter of the Hong Kong market, particularly in the handover period. We were forecasting a pre-handover rally and we are forecasting a post-handover rally. We do have positive sentiment towards this market.&quot;</p>
<p>But Templeton, a bottom-up investor with a stock-picking strategy based on strict valuation criteria, maintains an underweight position with a 14-percent allocation against the MSCI benchmark of 38 percent, partly because it owns no red chips.</p>
<p>Valuation of these companies is impossible, Aldcroft said, and other institutional investors agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;Red chips are going to do worse, much worse,&quot; said Nikko's Mays. &quot;They are just dream paper, nonsense. I think the idea of asset injection is legalised robbery.&quot;</p>
<p>Jardine Fleming Unit Trusts, which holds about 14 percent of its Greater China trust in red chips, advocated selectivity to avoid short-term disappointment.</p>
<p>Below are the fund managers positions on Hong Kong, some with targets for the Hang Seng Index:</p>
<p>TEMPLETON FRANKLIN INVESTMENT - underweight, positive</p>
<p>Hang Seng end-1999: 20,000 points</p>
<p>JARDINE FLEMING UNIT TRUSTS - overweight, positive</p>
<p>Hang Seng end-1997: 15,500 points</p>
<p>PEREGRINE ASSET MANAGEMENT - overweight, short-term negative, long-term positive</p>
<p>Hang Seng end-1997: 16,000 points</p>
<p>MORGAN STANLEY ASSET MGT - significantly overweight, positive</p>
<p>Hang Seng end-1997: 16,500 points</p>
<p>Hang Seng end-1998: 21,000 points</p>
<p>NIKKO RESEARCH CENTER - underweight, short-term negative, long-term positive</p>
<p>Hang Seng end-1997: 14,300 points</p>
<p>LGT ASSET MANAGEMENT - overweight, positive</p>
<p>HSBC ASSET MANAGEMENT - overweight, positive</p>
<p>NOMURA ASSET MANAGEMENT (ASIA) LTD- overweight, positive</p>
<p>SBC WARBURG - neutral, negative</p>
<p>Hang Seng end-1997: 14,300 points</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6470</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
