<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694065" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Patten defends Britain's HK inauguration plans.</title>
<headline>Patten defends Britain's HK inauguration plans.</headline>
<byline>Brian Williams</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Governor Chris Patten on Friday defended Britain's late decision to send officials to the swearing-in of a Beijing-picked legislature for Hong Kong and made clear he supported the action.</p>
<p>Responding to complaints by democracy activists that the decision was a climbdown, Patten said Britain needed, and had a &quot;moral responsibility&quot;, to maintain links with the government that would run Hong Kong on its return to China next Monday.</p>
<p>The provisional legislature, to be sworn in shortly after the midnight Monday handover, replaces a democratically elected body.</p>
<p>After vowing to have nothing to do with the provisional legislature and announcing British Prime Minister Tony Blair would not attend, London switched course and decided to send its top diplomats in Hong Kong to the swearing-in.</p>
<p>Patten, the last governor in 156 years of British colonial rule, did not directly answer when asked why Britain initially took a strong stand against attending the legislature ceremony, then followed a U.S. decision to send a representative.</p>
<p>Patten, In a radio call-in programme, said a distinction needed to be made between the presence of a political leader like Blair and the need for British diplomats to maintain their links with the colony.</p>
<p>Apparently anxious to ensure there was no perception of a split between him and Blair's new Labour Party government, Patten stressed: &quot;Just in in case anyone has any doubt about what has happened, the course of action which British ministers are following is one which I wholly support and wholly endorse.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there was no way a British government could justify to its parliament &quot;publicly elected officials (like Blair) going to the inauguration of a provisional legislature which is not elected.&quot;</p>
<p>However, British diplomats were going to be in close contact with the new Chinese leaders and &quot;it is in Hong Kong's interests that that relationship isn't affected in any way&quot;, Patten said</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a question of a boycott, it's a question of what is right and seemly and what is not right.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
