<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694049" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Intria plans 1-for-4 rights,acquisitions.</title>
<headline>Intria plans 1-for-4 rights,acquisitions.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian infrastructure developer Intria Bhd said on Friday it was proposing a one-for-four rights issue and the issue of 40.8 million new shares to help pay for acquisitions worth a total of 129.6 million ringgit.</p>
<p>The rights will be priced at 1.15 ringgit a share, Intria said in a statement issued by its merchant bankers.</p>
<p>Intria proposed to pay 65.3 million ringgit for the entire issued and paid-up capital of Merdeka Park Holdings Sdn Bhd to be paid by the issue of 40.8 million new shares at 1.60 ringgit each.  </p>
<p>Merdeka Park is an investment holding firm with a 70 percent interest in Puncak Vista Sdn Bhd which owns 32.3 acres of land in Kuala Lumpur including two stadiums and the surrounding areas.</p>
<p>Puncak Vista's land is valued at 553 million ringgit. It intends to develop the land within the next seven years into office blocks, a shopping and entertainment centre, hotel and service apartments, condominiums and an amphitheatre. The entire project will be named Plaza Merdeka.</p>
<p>Intria stock was suspended on Friday, being last traded on Thursday at 4.10 ringgit.  </p>
<p>In the second proposition, Intria will buy the entire issued and paid-up capital of Pelangi Enterprise Sdn Bhd for 15.3 million ringgit which will be paid in cash.</p>
<p>Pelangi owns 10 units of 3-storey shop offices which have been renovated into a modern hospital.</p>
<p>Under the third proposal, Intria will pay 49 million ringgit for the entire issued and paid-up capital of Peninsula Hospital Sdn Bhd in cash. The company owns a 10-acre plot of land in Kuala Lumpur valued at 48 million ringgit.</p>
<p>Intria said 100 million ringgit of the gross proceeds of about 223.75 million ringgit from the rights issue would be used to repay existing borowings.</p>
<p>Another 100 million ringgit will be used to partially finance the Plaza Merdeka project, and most of the remaining cash to provide additional working capital for the company, said Intria.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
