<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69411" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Helms, Gantt seek center in '96 rematch.</title>
<headline>Helms, Gantt seek center in '96 rematch.</headline>
<byline>Lorrie Grant</byline>
<dateline>CHARLOTTE, N.C 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A wave of new independent voters was expected to make the swing decision on whether North Carolina's next senator will be Republican incumbent Jesse Helms or Democratic challenger Harvey Gantt.</p>
<p>The candidates, however, are not new, as their bid for the Senate is a rematch of the heated 1990 contest Helms won after a racially charged television ad. Gantt is black.</p>
<p>But this time, according to political analysts, Helms, 74, the conservative, and Gantt, 53, the more liberal candidate, were tempering their messages in hopes of winning the unaffiliated voters.</p>
<p>&quot;They truly are up for grabs. They are more reform minded and looking for more policy discussion,&quot; Katy Harriger, a Wake Forest University associate professor who specialises in national elections, said of the independent voters.</p>
<p>&quot;The left and right are going to the middle to portray themselves as pragmatic (and) at the same time caring,&quot; added Bob Billinger, professor of history and government at Wingate University in Wingate, North Carolina.</p>
<p>He said unaffiliated voters did not like the tax-and-spend-liberals portrayal by conservatives who said they were going to slash government after the 1994 election. &quot;Americans didn't want want government slashed and on the other hand didn't want tax-and-spend,&quot; he said. &quot;They wanted caring but sensible politicians who spend money wisely.&quot;</p>
<p>There are 686,598 new registered voters in the state since the last Helms-Gantt race, and the fastest-growing number of them are unaffiliated with any party, officials said.</p>
<p>The North Carolina Board of Elections said 431,920 North Carolinians have registered as unaffiliated, or independent, over the past six years.</p>
<p>Harriger said most voters who call themselves independents lean more one way than the other and that the number of truly independent voters is a much smaller percentage.</p>
<p>They also tend to be highly educated, earn high incomes, and have a great dislike for negative campaigns, she added.</p>
<p>Both the Helms and Gantt campaigns have run fairly positive television advertisements this election season.</p>
<p>&quot;Independent voters will have the least tolerance for the negative attacks on the other side, and both candidates are spending a lot of time to build a positive image of themselves,&quot; Harriger said.</p>
<p>To counter the &quot;too liberal&quot; tag that Helms has started to use in his ads, the ads run by Gantt, an architect who twice served as mayor of Charlotte from 1983-1987, describe him as a traditionalist emphasising values and discipline.</p>
<p>But Dalit Toledano, communications director for the Gantt campaign, said the candidate was concentrating on such proposals as eliminating parole for violent criminals, tax deductions for working families and alternative schools for kids who get in trouble rather than labels or name tags.</p>
<p>Early Helms ads show the senator with his granddaughters who tell what a good guy he is while others have focused on policy as compared to the traditional hot-button issues of pornography and gays that he has opposed strongly in the past.</p>
<p>A Helms campaign spokesman did not return calls.</p>
<p>In their last bout, Helms won by a 53-47 percent margin after running a commercial that charged Gantt favoured quotas that cost white workers their jobs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARLOTTE, N.C"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
