<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69429" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek socialists take election lead in exit polls.</title>
<headline>Greek socialists take election lead in exit polls.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's ruling socialists took a strong early lead in national elections on Sunday, according to exit polls by three Greek television channels.</p>
<p>The socialists led by Prime Minister Costas Simitis, running his first national campaign, had 41.5 to 42 percent. The opposition conservatives led by Miltiades Evert had 38 to 38.7 percent, the exit polls showed.</p>
<p>Antenna channel said the figures, if confirmed, would give Simitis's Panhellenic Socialist Movement (PASOK) more than 159 deputies in the 300-seat parliament. That would be down from the present 170 seats but still a clear absolute majority.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first time PASOK has won a national victory without Andreas Papandreou. I am very touched,&quot; said George Papandreou, son of the late socialist party founder.</p>
<p>Simitis's socialist supporters went wild on the exit polls, racing through the streets of Athens with their car horns sounding and green and white PASOK flags flying from their windows.</p>
<p>Papandreou, who forged PASOK from an array of left-wing parties after the fall of a brutal seven-year military junta in 1974, died in June after a heart-attack.</p>
<p>Four smaller parties -- three on the left and one on the right -- would also enter parliament with scores ranging from 3.3 to 5.3 percent, according to the exit polls.</p>
<p>Simitis, 60, called early elections confident of an easy win over the feuding conservatives. But Evert rallied his forces and staged a vigorous campaign, closing the gap in opinion polls.</p>
<p>The socialists, running without Papandreou's guiding hand for the first time, initially appeared confused and without any clear programme.</p>
<p>Simitis himself seemed torn between the old radical populist party of Papandreou and the new, progressive socialist movement he had vowed to create.</p>
<p>A staunch pro-European technocrat, Simitis took over as prime minister from an ailing Papandreou in January and was elected leader of PASOK after Papandreou's death in June.</p>
<p>An election win would clinch his grip on power within PASOK and within the country, and give him a four-year mandate to carry out a reform programme which he says will make Greece an equal and respected European Union partner.</p>
<p>Based on the exit polls, a string of socialist ministers leapt forward to claim victory in television interviews although the interior ministry has yet to issue any official figures.</p>
<p>&quot;The people voted for political stability and renewal,&quot; said Development Minister Vasso Papandreou, no relation to Andreas.</p>
<p>Simitis campaigned on pledges to make the necessary economic sacrifices to meet Greece's EU convergence targets. He said the country knew it could no longer live on handouts and wanted the dignity and respect that came with hard work.</p>
<p>His austerity message shocked many leftist voters after years of Papandreou's free-wheeling spending and dealt him a hard blow in early opinion polls.</p>
<p>It was also clear Simitis was struggling with the challenge of his first national campaign but in the closing days he found his stride and returned to Papandreou's brand of populism.</p>
<p>A Simitis win would also ensure the survival of PASOK in the post-Papandreou era. Many political commentators felt PASOK was a one-man phenomenon and when Papandreou died the party would break up.</p>
<p>He became Greece's first socialist prime minister in 1981 and was reelected in 1985. He was voted out of office in 1989, sunk by seamy scandals but was eventually acquitted of corruption charges. He came back in October 1993 with a landside victory.</p>
<p>Simitis is a German and British trained economist and lawyer who served in every Papandreou cabinet. But he often disagreed publicly with Papandreou and twice resigned ministries, most resently in 1995 as industry minister.</p>
<p>His open feuds created an image of being his own man. He was well organised when Papandreou fell ill and quit. Simitis was first elected premier by the socialist parliamentary group and then, in another close vote, he took control of PASOK.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
