<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694245" id="root" date="1997-06-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Publicis boss unhappy with Bozell report.</title>
<headline>Publicis boss unhappy with Bozell report.</headline>
<dateline>CANNES, France 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Publicis chairman Maurice Levy said on Friday he was unhappy to learn of talks between U.S. advertising groups Bozell and True North Communications Inc from press reports.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be noted that the main shareholder in True North is simply informed about these negotiations by the press,&quot; Levy said in answer to Reuters questions.</p>
<p>Publicis owns 20 percent of True North, the parent of U.S. advertising group Foote, Cone &amp; Belding (FCB).</p>
<p>Banking and advertising sources attending the International Advertising festival here this week told Reuters that Bozell was close to announcing a link with an advertising group of similar size.</p>
<p>Possible partners are True North, France's Havas Advertising or Britain's Leo Burnett, several sources here say.  </p>
<p>Didier Stora, chairman of Bozell France, contacted by Reuters by telephone on Wednesday, declined to confirm or deny the talk.</p>
<p>But he said his company interested plenty of people because it was in excellent health, and was &quot;very coveted&quot;.</p>
<p>Bozell, the 14th advertising group worldwide, had a gross margin of $473 million in 1996, a rise of 17 percent over its 1995 figure.</p>
<p>It comes between Publicis and Franco-British BDDP on the world league table of advertising companies.</p>
<p>It has only two major clients in Europe, American car maker Chrysler and South Korean conglomerate Samsung.</p>
<p>Publicis and True North have just finalised their divorce after a long cooperation, leaving both free to seek other partners.</p>
<p>True North has gross margin of some $490 million following its split with Publicis. In Europe it bought Publicis out of FCB agencies in Paris, London, Lisbon and Paris but sold its share of Publicis FCB Europe to the French group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANNES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
