<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69457" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German union to protest against cuts in sick pay.</title>
<headline>German union to protest against cuts in sick pay.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of IG Metall, Germany's largest union, said on Sunday they would conduct limited work stoppages next month as part of a campaign to maintain full pay for sick days.</p>
<p>Ludwig Kemeth, Stuttgart representative of the engineering union, said workers in the Stuttgart area would demonstrate on October 10 against employers' plans to reduce sick pay in line with the government's Programme for More Jobs and Growth.</p>
<p>Government and opposition officials warned employers that the new law passed by parliament earlier this month, which provides for a 20 percent cut in pay on sick days, applied to future contracts, not existing ones.</p>
<p>Labour Minister Norbert Bluem said the government had been careful not to undermine the validity of current contracts.</p>
<p>Social Democrat leader Oskar Lafontaine said his party would oppose administration efforts to reduce sick pay for civil servants.</p>
<p>The government sought the sick-pay reductions to help reduce companies' costs and encourage manufacturing investment in Germany.</p>
<p>IG Metall chairman Klaus Zwickel said about 60 labour representatives from the automobile and electronics industry would hold a strategy session on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;If employers intend to break contracts, there will be appropriate action,&quot; Zwickel said.</p>
<p>Employers' recent statements that they will seek reductions in bonuses for vacations and Christmas show that difficult negotiations lie ahead, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not looking to strike, but we will strike if forced to,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some employers have already said they would cancel old contracts to negotiate new ones with the reduced sick pay, while others asserted they could simply cut sick pay without new labour agreements.</p>
<p>The retail sector in North Rhine-Westphalia reached an agreement with its workers that includes full pay for sick days, at least through the end of 1997, and raised wages 1.85 percent, retroactive to April.</p>
<p>The retail agreement also provides for premiums of 20 to 40 percent for working the newly extended shop hours.</p>
<p>Employers in the retail sector claimed they had to make concessions to employees so that they could stay open the additional hours provided for under another new law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
