<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69469" id="root" date="1996-09-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French freemasons hail Republic as Pope hails king.</title>
<headline>French freemasons hail Republic as Pope hails king.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>As Pope John Paul celebrated a long-dead French king on Sunday, freemasons visited the battlefield of Valmy to mark the downfall of the monarchy in 1792 and the proclamation of the Republic.</p>
<p>Hundreds of other protesters, most of them leftists and anarchists, gathered in Paris to protest against the Pope's conservative moral teachings and the use of public funds to help with his four-day visit.</p>
<p>Freemasons believe the pope's attendance at the 1,500th anniversary of the baptism of Frankish king Clovis tramples the ideals of the 1789 Revolution, violates a 1905 law separating the state from the Church and plays into the hands of far-right nationalists.</p>
<p>&quot;We had believed that separating churches and state in 1905 had achieved secularisation of the Republic's institutions,&quot; Yves Lapouge, head of the French freemasons, told supporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Today, these churches are trying under various forms to impose fundamentalism...oppose women's rights, impose the (Moslem) veil, to let themselves be recognised as a component of Europe,&quot; he said in an attack on both Roman Catholicism and Islam.</p>
<p>&quot;We must revive both the dreams of 1792 and today's battles,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Valmy, 30 kms (20 miles) from Reims where the Pope was saying mass to 20,000 faithful, marked the victory of the Revolution over its foreign foes.</p>
<p>There, on September 20 1792, ill-equipped, ragtag troops fired by revolutionary fervour defeated invading Prussian and Austrian armies intent on crushing the Revolution.</p>
<p>The French monarchy was abolished and the Republic proclaimed the following day.</p>
<p>&quot;We deemed it important to recall the anniversary of the Republic when others, in Reims, are extolling France's religious identity and make a baprtism the origin of the nation,&quot; said freemason leader Stephane Fillet.</p>
<p>Nationalists say the baptism of Clovis marked the birth of France. Opponents say he was a brutal warlord whose baptism was aimed at wining over the Church's support for more conquests.</p>
<p>Freemasons were among some 70 groups who called the Paris protest.</p>
<p>The demonstrators gathered at Bastille square to prepare for a march, carrying banners proclaiming &quot;Religion oppresses&quot; and showing the Pope making a rude arms gesture.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to protest against the Right and the government hijacking the baptism of Clovis. The Pope let himself be manoeuvred, Clovis was a thug,&quot; said protester Renee Lemignot of the Movement against Racism.</p>
<p>&quot;We are here to demonstrate against the money spent by the state on the Pope's visit,&quot; said another protester, Hughes Lenoir.</p>
<p>Protesters estimated the state and local authorities spent some 30 million francs ($6 million) on facilities for the visit.</p>
<p>Atheists also held a protest rally in a sports hall in Reims, where Clovis was baptised and where French kings were traditionally crowned. Police said some 700 people attended.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
