<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694750" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SASOL'S NEW ACID PLANT COMMISSIONED.</title>
<headline>SASOL'S NEW ACID PLANT COMMISSIONED.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sasol Solvents, a division of Sasol Chemical Industries Ltd, has commissioned a plant to extract and purify acetic acid and propionic acid, the company said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The plant, which will have the capacity to produce about 16,000 tonnes of acetic acid and 7,000 tonnes of propionic acid annually, represents a capital investment of 167 million rand ($37 million).</p>
<p>Most of the acid production will be exported offshore.</p>
<p>The aqueous stream emanating from the Synthol process of Sasol Synthetic Fuels at Secunda contains commercially viable amounts of acetic acid and propionic acid, the company said.</p>
<p>Until recently these acids were treated in a biological plant. They are now being extracted, purified and marketed by Sasol Solvents.</p>
<p>Acetic acid is used mainly to manufacture solvent acetates, as well as for the production of cellulose acetate, vinyl acetate, monochlor acetic acid and food additives. </p>
<p>Propionic acid is used for producing calcium propionate -- a new-generation mould-inhibitor in bread -- and as a preservative for stored wheat and animal feeds. It is also a feedstock for producing some polymers, herbicides and pharmaceuticals.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +2711 4821003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
