<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694776" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NatWest faces new flurry of merger rumours.</title>
<headline>NatWest faces new flurry of merger rumours.</headline>
<byline>Joe Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>National Westminster Bank faced a further flurry of merger rumours on Sunday, hampering its wish to get back to normal after it last week revealed details of derivatives losses at its investment banking arm.</p>
<p>Sources close to the bank said NatWest had hoped it could return to trying to re-build confidence after it admitted that 90 million pounds ($150 million) of losses had been covered up at NatWest Markets over a period of two years.</p>
<p>But Sunday's newspapers, almost inevitably, featured further stories in what has been a torrent of speculation since it emerged, almost one month ago, that NatWest had approached fellow British Bank Abbey National to talk about a merger.</p>
<p>Those talks never got off the ground but the market now firmly believes that NatWest is in play.</p>
<p>On Sunday, NatWest was linked In the Sunday Times with insurance and financial services giant Prudential Corporation.</p>
<p>Such a merger would work in terms of synergies - Prudential's products allied to NatWest's distribution capabilities - but NatWest Markets is unlikely to appeal to Prudential chief Peter Davis who is still working to integrate Scottish Amicable, the life company the Pru bought earlier this year.</p>
<p>A deal with the Pru might also mean the breaking off of NatWest Markets, though the investment bank's Treasury business would have to be retained by the parent making it difficult to sell as a separate entity.</p>
<p>The Pru is Britain's biggest fund manager with over 90 billion pounds under management.</p>
<p>No Prudential sokesman was immediately available for comment on Sunday.</p>
<p>The break-up of NatWest is also discussed in the Sunday Telegraph which speculates that Andrew Large, outgoing head of the Securities and Investments Board, will be approached to take the job at the head of NatWest Markets left vacant after Martin Owen resigned two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Market analysts are known to be keen that NatWest end the uncertainty at the investment bank which group chief executive Derek Wanless is running on a temporary basis.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't like it that they did not announce a successor to Martin Owen,&quot; one banking analyst said. &quot;It gives the impression that things are continuing to drift at NatWest Markets and that will hurt the business.&quot;</p>
<p>Large is a friend of NatWest Group chairman Lord Alexander and worked in the City, as well as for BP, before he went to the SIB.</p>
<p>The Sunday Telegraph also continued its consideration of a possible merger between NatWest and Barclays which most analysts were dismissing last week as impossible on competition grounds because the combined bank would have over 50 percent of Britain's small and medium corporate business.</p>
<p>A NatWest spokesman called on the Takeover Panel, which polices the City's takeover rules, to make Barclays clarify its position and end the speculation which he said was damaging to NatWest's business.</p>
<p>The NatWest spokesman declined to comment on the link with the Pru or whether Large would be approached.</p>
<p>Barclays has consistently refused to comment on the speculation and did so again on Sunday. Analysts said Barclays is avoiding making a public statement because it does not wish to be held to be &quot;offside&quot; in the jargon of takeovers.</p>
<p>If any company makes a statement, for example, denying interest in another, then the Takeover Panel will deem that they are unable to then make a bid for a period of between three and 12 months depending on the circumstances.</p>
<p>But analysts said that the panel can also say a company is &quot;offside&quot; if it decides it has had anything to do with fomenting City rumours while at the same time declining official comment.</p>
<p>City sources said it was unlikely that the Takeover Panel had intervened at this stage. ($ = 0.601 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
