<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694774" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rain stops horse show for UK queen's anniversary.</title>
<headline>Rain stops horse show for UK queen's anniversary.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Torrential rain has forced the cancellation of a major horse show planned as a tribute to Queen Elizabeth's golden wedding aniversary, the organisers said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Two years of planning had gone into the Royal Pageant of the Horse, which had been due to feature more than 1,000 horses and 4,000 participants in an extravaganza in Windsor Great Park, west of London, on July 5.</p>
<p>But the organisers said heavy rainfall over the past month had turned the park to mud, making it unsafe to construct a large stage, seating tribunes and lighting towers for the show.</p>
<p>&quot;Following a detailed inspection of the site in the Great Park, it was decided that it was unsafe for both the public and the participants, riders and horses, to continue,&quot; the organisers said. The pageant will not be rescheduled.</p>
<p>The average June rainfall in the park, which is close to the queen's castle at Windsor, is 25.59 millimetres.</p>
<p>But as of Saturday the total this June was 84.6 millimetres, with more heavy rain forecast next week.</p>
<p>Louisa Radcliffe, a spokeswoman for the show, said it would have been too risky to go ahead even if the weather forecast had been promising.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all down to the great British weather, and we can't do anything about it,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The heavy rain has taken its toll of other outdoor events, notably the Wimbledon tennis championships.</p>
<p>The queen, a keen horsewoman, was said to be very upset by the cancellation of the show, which was meant to be one of the highlights of the celebrations for her 50th wedding anniversary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
