<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694784" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - UK to keep eye on Hong Kong from sidelines.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - UK to keep eye on Hong Kong from sidelines.</headline>
<byline>David Ljunggren</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's delegates at the ceremony to hand Hong Kong back to China on June 30 are unlikely to be paying much attention to the fireworks display, the marching bands and the ranks of distinguished guests.</p>
<p>Instead, they will be chewing over two crucial questions -- will China keep its word on preserving Hong Kong's freedoms and what can be done if Beijing reneges on the deal?</p>
<p>&quot;We can't pretend we're going to bomb China,&quot; said one senior British official. &quot;We can't send in a gunboat.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain has vowed many times to keep a close eye on China to ensure it sticks to the terms of the 1984 Sino-British Joint Declaration, under which Beijing promised to maintain Hong Kong's democratic system for at least 50 years.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed to report to parliament every six months on Hong Kong, at least until the turn of the century,&quot; Foreign Secretary Robin Cook wrote in the Times newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;I have also put Hong Kong at the top of the agenda for my meetings with other foreign ministers...a successful, stable and free Hong Kong matters to the whole international community,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts agree that Britain's sole chance of bringing pressure to bear on China if things went wrong would be to mobilise international support in an attempt to bring Beijing back into line.</p>
<p>&quot;Britain can't achieve a great deal apart from publicity, but the importance of publicity cannot be overestimated,&quot; said Peter Ferdinand, China expert at the Royal Institute for International Affairs think-tank.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese don't like bad forms of publicity and wouldn't like to lose too much face if things go badly,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The idea of Chinese tanks crushing street protests in Hong Kong was hardly top of the agenda in 1984 but came into sharp focus after the 1989 Tiananmen Square crackdown in which hundreds, and possibly thousands, died.</p>
<p>Last year China enraged Britain and fuelled the nightmares of Hong Kong's democrats by announcing it would scrap the colony's legally-elected parliament and replace it with a hand-picked provisional legislature.</p>
<p>Officials in London say the next crucial test will be to see whether China sticks to its obligation to hold free elections to a permanent legislature next year.</p>
<p>&quot;If there were to be a crackdown, Britain couldn't do much more than shout and wave a big stick,&quot; said Damon Bristow, expert in Anglo-Sino relations at the Royal United Services Institute think-tank.</p>
<p>&quot;The most Britain could hope for is that the United States would do something and we could back them up...Washington can do more than we can because after the handover Britain will no longer be an Asian-Pacific power,&quot; he said in an interview.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary for State Madeleine Albright has struck a hard line on human rights but suspicions remain that Britain's European Union partners with significant trading interests in China might be less keen to upset Beijing by raising their voices in protest.</p>
<p>All Britain can do for the time being is keep its fingers crossed that Beijing sticks to the 1984 agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not see the issue of Hong Kong as a festering sore in bilateral relations. We prefer the metaphor of a bridge rather than a barrier. Our attitude is one of cautious optimism,&quot; said the British official.</p>
<p>But much depends on fate.</p>
<p>&quot;Relations between Britain and China are more fraught than both countries would wish because they can always be blown off course by events,&quot; said Ferdinand.</p>
<p>&quot;What happens if criminals flee to Hong Kong and seek to stay there when the crime they committed carries the death penalty on the mainland?&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>&quot;What happens if a Hong Kong businessman is accused of a crime on the mainland where the death penalty applies? This could put the cat among the pigeons. If that happens, there would be an immediate crisis.&quot;</p>
<p>Officials declined to comment on what would happen if Hong Kong citizens decided to flee en masse from any future crackdown and ask for asylum in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is a flood of refugees after a crackdown Britain would be morally obliged to take those who came here,&quot; said Bristow. &quot;Especially a government which has made a commitment to human rights.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
