<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694831" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia cenbank eases rules for 7-year investors.</title>
<headline>Slovenia cenbank eases rules for 7-year investors.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-06-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Slovenia, bowing to widespread criticism of its controversial rules for foreign investors, said on Friday it would ease the rules for those who buy securities for a minimum period of seven years.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to attract strategic investors we decided to change the rules in the case of securities which are purchased for at least seven years,&quot; Janko Tratnik, director of the Bank of Slovenia foreign business department, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the money paid into the accounts for a seven- year purchase would not be considered as foreign liability which must be balanced against foreign assets, and this should significantly reduce the costs of the accounts.</p>
<p>Banks said that expenses involved in the balancing procedures were the reason for the high costs of the fiduciary accounts, which averaged about 12 percent of the amount handled.</p>
<p>International investors have stayed away from the Slovenian market since February when the central bank ruled that foreigners must open fiduciary accounts at one of 14 fully licensed banks in order to trade in securities.</p>
<p>Since then the Ljubljana bourse turnover has dropped to a tenth of its previous level, while the blue chip SBI stock index fell by over 23 percent.</p>
<p>Banks said the new decree would enable them to reduce costs of the accounts significantly in cases of long-term purchases but gave no estimate of the new costs.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first step in softening the conditions for foreign investors and I believe that is positive,&quot; said Drasko Veselinovic, head of the Ljubljana Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the conditions for foreign investors will be gradually eased until the year 2,000 or until Slovenia's association agreement with the European Union is fully enforced,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The association agreement that was signed in June last year yet needs to be ratified by Slovenia's parliament and by most EU parliaments before being enforced.</p>
<p>Analysts said the decree would have a positive effect on the market, but added foreign capital inflow would remain limited as seven years was seen as a very long period to be holding a share.</p>
<p>&quot;In spite of that the decree will, at least over a short-term period, raise domestic investors' hopes of fresh foreign capital inflow which will improve liquidity on the bourse,&quot; one said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
