<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694830" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Official dies in Albania election violence.</title>
<headline>Official dies in Albania election violence.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A local election official in southern Albania was shot and killed during voting in his district on Sunday, the first person to die in violence on election day, the interior ministry said.</p>
<p>A ministry spokesman in Tirana identified the man as Burhan Misiri, the chief electoral official in a village near the town of Fier.</p>
<p>&quot;The crime was politically motivated,&quot; the spokesman said by telephone, adding a policeman was injured by gunfire during the melee. He said the victim was a member of President Sali Berisha's ruling Democratic Party while the chief suspect had links to the Socialist Party challenging it for power.</p>
<p>Voting in Albania's general election, viewed as the sole means of stopping months of unrest, had been proceeding with only minor incidents.</p>
<p>Both the Democrats and the Socialists denounced the shooting in the village of Mberrc.</p>
<p>The head of the Central Election Commission, Kristaq Kume, issued an appeal for Albanians to vote in peace. He said the shooting was &quot;an event which must be denounced and amounts to an attack not only on him and his family but on all of us&quot;.</p>
<p>Both sides have complained of irregularities, mainly of voters left off registration lists.</p>
<p>There have also been instances of armed gangs stealing ballot papers or tampering with ballot boxes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
