<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694847" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia rebel rejects Samper peace plan - TV.</title>
<headline>Colombia rebel rejects Samper peace plan - TV.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of Colombia's second largest guerrilla army ordered his regional commanders not to negotiate a peace deal with President Ernesto Samper's government, local media reported Sunday.</p>
<p>The NTC TV news programme quoted parts of an alleged phone conversation between Manuel Perez, head of the National Liberation Army (ELN), and a local guerrilla chief, said to have been intercepted by military intelligence.</p>
<p>&quot;Corruption makes him (Samper) an illegitimate authority ... he constantly says one thing and then breaks his word,&quot; Perez said on the recording.</p>
<p>Perez, a radical Roman Catholic priest originally from Spain's northern Basque region, said, however, that he would talk to members of the Church-led National Conciliation Commission to study possible peace proposals.</p>
<p>The Perez recording came a week after two of the ELN's jailed leaders described Samper's calls for peace talks, backed by a group of Colombia's top industrialists, as a &quot;significant development.&quot;</p>
<p>Samper floated the idea of a new peace process after the largest of the country's three rebel forces, the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC), released 70 troops on June 15.</p>
<p>The rebels had been holding 60 of the soldiers prisoner for more than nine months. At a handover ceremony in a temporarily demilitarized region of southern Colombia, the FARC's supreme leader Manuel &quot;Sureshot&quot; Marulanda said he would be ready to sit down and hammer out a plan for &quot;peace with social justice&quot;.</p>
<p>But he set a series of tough pre-conditions, including the demilitarization of other areas and the break-up of right-wing paramilitary groups, that the government seems unlikely or unwilling to be able to meet.</p>
<p>Some political analysts suggested the Cuban-inspired ELN, set up by radical Roman Catholic priests in 1966, may agree to peace talks more readily than the FARC.</p>
<p>But the Perez recording appears to torpedo any real hopes of starting a new process to end Latin America's longest-running guerrilla war before Samper leaves office next August.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
