<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694943" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japanese glad over arrest in case but fears remain.</title>
<headline>Japanese glad over arrest in case but fears remain.</headline>
<byline>Yuka Obayashi</byline>
<dateline>KOBE, Japan 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Residents in this western Japanese city are relieved that the grisly murder of an 11-year-old schoolboy seems to have been solved, but shock and fear remain.</p>
<p>In a country renowned for its low crime rate, the beheading of the schoolboy and subsequent news that a 14-year-old has been charged with the crime has sent shock waves through the city and all of Japan.</p>
<p>The 14-year-old confessed on Saturday to strangling then beheading Jun Hase. The two youths were believed to have been acquainted, police said.</p>
<p>&quot;The killer is a really cruel man. I am really scared,&quot; said Yuki Hatanaka, an eight-year-old girl who lives in the same neighbourhood as the victim and the suspected killer.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't go out and play outside,&quot; she said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Parents and education officials in Kobe were equally shocked. The senseless violence among youths in the United States and some other industrialised countries is rare in Japan.</p>
<p>They also expressed worries about whether there are any lessons for one of the pillars of Japan's post-war success, its education system.</p>
<p>After the murder, the killer sent a letter to a local newspaper saying that he was fed up with the strict education system which he said had made him an invisible entity.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not just the problem with the boy himself but also with the entire society, including parents and schools,&quot; said Yoshihiro Kubota, a father of three schoolchildren in Kobe.</p>
<p>&quot;I realised that it is very difficult to raise children. If I were the parents of the murderer, I would be very shocked,&quot; said Kazuko Kajiura, a 32-year-old mother of two children.</p>
<p>She said that despite the arrest, her daughter, an elementary school student, would continue to carry the noise-emitting alarm given to students following the May 24 killing.</p>
<p>As people looked for what could turn a teenager into such a brutal killer, they blamed the education system but saw wider problems as well.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an insult against the education system. But his parents also carried the responsibility for not caring enough,&quot; said Masahiko Mano, an 87-year-old retiree.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this is the problem of Japan's entire society,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Those worries were echoed in official Japan. The nation's education minister said in Tokyo that he would dispatch a senior government official to Kobe to investigate the case.</p>
<p>Takashi Kurihara, head of the education department in Hyogo Prefecture which includes Kobe, said he was &quot;alarmed and confused&quot; at the news.</p>
<p>He said that emphasis must be put on teaching children the preciousness of life.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto had been moved to ordering a special commitment to solving the case and hundreds of police officers were mobilised in the investigation.</p>
<p>At the same time, some of the cynicism that has become standard in other countries in the face of increasing brutality by young people was also apparent.</p>
<p>&quot;I was not that surprised. It reflects an increasing number of younger criminals in Japan,&quot; said Nobuaki Yamagiwa, a 48-year-old businessman.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KOBE, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
