<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="694963" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan pro-China march draws scant following.</title>
<headline>Taiwan pro-China march draws scant following.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>On Saturday, 70,000 Taiwanese braved downpours to stage a rally asserting their island's independence from China prior to Beijing's reabsorption of Hong Kong.</p>
<p>On Sunday, supporters of Taiwan-China reunification held a rally intending to counterbalance Saturday's throng.</p>
<p>About 100 people turned up.</p>
<p>In a scant show contrasting with the fervour and sheer size of Saturday's anti-Beijing march, a drum-beating Chinese nationalist group took to the streets of Taipei to celebrate Hong Kong's July 1 handover to Beijing sovereignty.</p>
<p>Rebuffing the call by Saturday's protesters to prevent Taiwan from being gobbled up by China, Sunday's demonstrators hailed Hong Kong's impending handover and urged eventual reunification for China and Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;Hong Kong's handover is something that all Chinese people should celebrate,&quot; Lee Chih-jen, organiser of Taiwan's Chinese Nation United Front which staged the march, said to a scattering of supporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are here to counterbalance the rally from Saturday, because otherwise the international world would believe that all the people in Taiwan support Taiwan independence,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>While Saturday's march included prominent members of opposition parties and a U.S. ex-congressman, Sunday's march was shunned even by leaders of Taiwan's largest pro-unification party, the New Party.</p>
<p>Whatever their stand on independence, Taiwan political groups universally reject what Beijing regards as a generous offer -- reunion under the &quot;one country, two systems&quot; model of local autonomy that underlies Hong Kong's handback.</p>
<p>Beijing, which has seen Nationalist-ruled Taiwan as a rebel province since a 1949 civil war split, vows to attack if Taipei stops advocating reunion and pursues independence.</p>
<p>Sunday's protesters branded independence supporters as &quot;rejects of the Chinese people&quot; who jeopardised Taiwan's prosperity and peace.</p>
<p>&quot;The independence people are risking peace across the Taiwan strait in order to get attention,&quot; a protester said.</p>
<p>Taiwan's ruling Nationalist Party says it wants to unite with China, but only after Beijing's Communist Party agrees to adopt political reforms like those that have transformed Taiwan from an iron-fisted autocracy into a lively democracy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
