<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="695070" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Floridian may be UFO believers' nefarious redhead.</title>
<headline>Floridian may be UFO believers' nefarious redhead.</headline>
<dateline>ORLANDO, Fla 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Joe Kittinger retired to Florida, took up hobbies and until a year ago never suspected he was a key figure in a far-reaching conspiracy theory.</p>
<p>Then a U.S. Air Force captain called and asked Kittinger if he had ever dropped crash-test dummies from high-altitude balloons near Roswell, New Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;About 50 times,&quot; Kittinger said.</p>
<p>With that, the Air Force was one step closer to closing its books on reports of flying saucers, alien autopsies and government coverups at Roswell.</p>
<p>The 68-year-old Kittinger, when he was stationed there, sported a thick head of red hair, wore captain's bars on his uniform and recovered lifeless, anthropomorphic figures from the desert.</p>
<p>That made him a good fit for the mysterious Red-Headed Captain, a nefarious figure in the annals of UFOlogy, the man who believers allege spirited away the alien victims of a downed flying saucer in 1947.</p>
<p>If you search the many Internet sites devoted to Roswell, you'll find dozens of references to the Red-Headed Captain. He also figures prominently in many books and film and television reenactments. It was he, according to believers, who first drew a curtain of secrecy on those alien bodies that has not been parted in 50 years.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all a crock,&quot; Kittinger said. &quot;We needed the data (from the dummies) and we went to a lot of trouble to recover them. If that meant searching a wheat field in the middle of the night, that's what happened.&quot;</p>
<p>Roswell this week celebrates the 50th anniversary of an event the Air Force insists never happened. By naming Kittinger in its own recently published investigation -- &quot;The Roswell Report: Case Closed&quot; -- the Air Force hopes to drive the point home.</p>
<p>Although Kittinger fits the description of the Red-Headed Captain -- his telephone answering machine now greets callers with the words &quot;Hello, you've reached the home of the UFO mystery man&quot; -- he was nowhere near Roswell when the events of 1947 did or did not take place.</p>
<p>But he was there in the 1950s, an expert in high-altitude balloons and parachuting, conducting experiments on whether astronauts could one day survive parachute drops from the edge of space.</p>
<p>He supports the Air Force conclusions that when UFO phenomena re-emerged as a popular subject in the 1970s, the residents of Roswell confused memories of events separated by years and tied them all to a 1947 newspaper headline about a &quot;flying disk&quot; recovered in the desert.</p>
<p>The Air Force, which originally said it had captured a flying saucer, quickly reversed itself to say the disk was actually a high-altitude balloon.</p>
<p>After exhaustive research, that is still what it says. UFO enthusiasts accuse the Air Force of a massive coverup.</p>
<p>&quot;People are going to believe what they want to,&quot; Kittinger said. &quot;Too many people have made too much money spinning Roswell conspiracy theories to simply accept the Air Force's conclusions.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORLANDO, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
