<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="695094" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Chechens parade economic plans at Swiss ski resort.</title>
<headline>Chechens parade economic plans at Swiss ski resort.</headline>
<byline>Elif Kaban</byline>
<dateline>CRANS MONTANA, Switzerland 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>At an international forum in a Swiss ski resort, rebels-turned businessmen from Russia's breakaway Chechnya region paraded ambitious plans at the weekend for an economic resurrection and a common Caucasus market.</p>
<p>&quot;We studied the European common market and we are launching our own Caucasus single market,&quot; Khoz-Akhmed Noukhayev, the Chechen head of the newly-formed U.S.-Caucasus International Chamber of Commerce, told Reuters at the annual forum.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the friendship of the peoples of the Caucasus is strong enough to overcome any obstacles on our path,&quot; said Noukhayev, who two years ago was a commander on the frontline in the breakaway Russian region's war against Moscow's forces.</p>
<p>Sporting a limp he said was caused by a Russian gun and accompanied by an aide wearing Chechnya's trademark sheepskin hat, Noukhayev said now it was time for business with Russia. &quot;We need to live together side by side.&quot;</p>
<p>Russia withdrew its last troops this year after it failed to crush the rebels in 21 months of war, leaving the region with de facto control over its own affairs. Chechnya and Moscow have agreed to postpone a settlement of its final status for five years.</p>
<p>In a region ridden with ethnic conflicts, wars and banditry, the Caucasus initiative may need a long time before it bears fruit, although Western interest continues to focus on securing pipelines to take out huge amounts of oil from Azerbaijan.</p>
<p>One of the oil pipeline routes passes through Chechnya, where oil refining was the only major industry before the war left the economy in ruins.</p>
<p>Investors may be put off not only by the presence of big amount of weapons but also by Chechnya's reputation for kidnappings and mafia deals.</p>
<p>Security was tighter than usual at this year's forum, where Saudi tycoon Adnan Khashoggi said he and Saudi partners would set up an investment bank to finance the Caucasus common market project.</p>
<p>The bank would finance oil, transport and telecommunications deals in the &quot;Eurasian Common Market&quot; of the Transcaucasus republics of Azerbaijan and Armenia as well as Georgia and south Russia, which envisages harmonised taxes and a unified payments system.</p>
<p>Countries of the former Soviet region are keen to end their its economic dependence on Russia in oil, trade and transport.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm looking at trade and oil financing deals in this region,&quot; said Khashoggi.</p>
<p>The Caucasus initiative, first conceived by the late Chechen president Dzhokhar Dudayev who spearheaded Chechnya's independence drive from 1991 until he was killed in a Russian rocket attack last year, also won the blessing of Georgia.</p>
<p>&quot;This project is essential for the region and for the reinforcement of political and economic ties,&quot; Georgia's minister of state Niko Lekishvili told the forum. &quot;Georgia is actively supporting the Eurasia-Caucasus common market project.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CRANS MONTANA, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
