<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="695173" id="root" date="1997-06-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japanese banker linked to scandal attempts suicide.</title>
<headline>Japanese banker linked to scandal attempts suicide.</headline>
<byline>Teruaki Ueno</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-06-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former chairman of Dai-Ichi Kangyo Bank attempted suicide on Sunday, police said, two days after he was questioned by prosecutors over his role in a payoff scandal involving &quot;sokaiya&quot; racketeers.</p>
<p>They said that Kuniji Miyazaki, 67, was taken to hospital after trying to hang himself at his Tokyo home. A spokesman said police later found a suicide note in the house.</p>
<p>Miyazaki stepped down as a senior adviser to DKB in mid-June after admitting contacts with a racketeer who is at the centre of the scandal involving DKB as well as Nomura Securities.</p>
<p>Miyazaki served as DKB president from 1988 to 1992 and as chairman from 1992 to April 1996.</p>
<p>His tenure included the period from 1994 to 1996 when 11.78 billion yen ($103 million) in dubious loans were made to the racketeer, Ryuichi Koike.</p>
<p>On Thursday, four former executives of DKB were indicted on charges of making the payments to Koike. They were the first Dai-Ichi Kangyo executives to be indicted in the case.</p>
<p>The sokaiya extort money from companies by threatening to disclose management incompetence. Some have strong financial backgrounds and threaten to raise embarrassing questions at annual shareholder meetings.</p>
<p>Disruptions by sokaiya at the meetings became so widespread in the 1980s that Japan outlawed making payments to the racketeers in 1983.</p>
<p>At its annual meeting on Friday, which was free of any disruptions, DKB management said it would ensure that the bank would sever all ties with racketeers.</p>
<p>&quot;No matter what else changes, the foundation of a bank is its credibility. We are quite ashamed of having hurt the credibility of our bank,&quot; departing Dai-Ichi Kangyo president Katsuhiko Kondo told the stockholders.</p>
<p>He apologised for the scandal, but acknowledged that the bank still had 7.5 billion yen ($65.7 million) of loans outstanding to racketeers.</p>
<p>Katsuyuki Sugita, incoming DKB president said at the meeting that: &quot;The new management will completely reject any request from racketeers.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite its illegality, major corporations have found it difficult to end their ties to the sokaiya.</p>
<p>While DKB, the third-largest bank in the world in terms of assets, and Nomura have been the only two companies linked to the latest scandal, legal experts say other big companies have very likely made similar payments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
