<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="695394" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-ATLETICO AND TOTTENHAM BATTLE FOR JUNINHO.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ATLETICO AND TOTTENHAM BATTLE FOR JUNINHO.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Atletico of Spain and and Tottenham of England were locked in a battle on Monday to sign Brazilian midfielder Juninho.</p>
<p>Tottenham had looked the favourites when Middlesbrough said they had agreed to sell the player to the English premier league side for 11 million pounds ($18.3 million).</p>
<p>But later Atletico Madrid director general Miguel Angel Gil said he expected to sign the Brazilian. He gave no price but Spanish media put it at $20 million.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing signed,&quot; said Gil, son of club owner Jesus Gil. &quot;Just a verbal agreement with the player. This morning I have spoken with his club ... and it is normal that the words should be resepected.&quot;</p>
<p>Only hours earlier Dave Allen, public relations officer for English first division Middlesbrough, said: &quot;We have accepted the bid from Tottenham and we have informed Juninho. It is now subject to him agreeing personal terms.&quot;</p>
<p>However, the London club would not comment on how far negotiations with the Brazilian had reached.</p>
<p>&quot;All I can say is that the play is in play,&quot; said Tottenham's chief executive Claude Littner. &quot;Who he goes to is up to him.&quot;</p>
<p>Juninho, who is leaving Middlesbrough after they were relegated from the premier league, is understood to favour a move to Spain where he feels greater exposure on television in Brazil would increase his chances of making the national squad for the 1998 World Cup finals.</p>
<p>But both Allen and Littner dismissed reports in Spanish newspapers on Monday that the Brazilian had signed for Atletico Madrid at the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;That is not true. At the moment Juninho is still a Middlesbrough player,&quot; said Allen. &quot;Atletico made an offer some weeks ago but it was derisory.</p>
<p>&quot;Tottenham are the only club we have accepted an offer from and the way is clear for them to discuss terms with Juninho.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
