<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="695408" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SOCCER-FIFA TO RULE ON DISPUTE OVER RONALDO.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FIFA TO RULE ON DISPUTE OVER RONALDO.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>FIFA, world soccer's governing body, said on Monday it would decide if Brazilian striker Ronaldo was free to move from Barcelona to Internazionale.</p>
<p>FIFA received an official request from Internazionale to investigate the transfer, along with 40 pages of documentation, on Monday, supporting their claim to the world footballer of the year.</p>
<p>Now it will be up to FIFA's players' status committee to decide whether the 20-year-old Brazilian is free to move to the Italian club after paying $27.6 million to free himself from his contract with Barcelona.</p>
<p>FIFA rules, however, state that a player cannot buy out his contract for the purposes of obtaining an international transfer.</p>
<p>The Spanish Football Federation has refused to issue a transfer certificate for Ronaldo on the grounds that such &quot;buyouts&quot; or withdrawal clauses found in Spanish league contracts are valid for domestic transfers only. Moves abroad must be negotiated by the two clubs.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is that the Ronaldo case is now in FIFA hands,&quot; said FIFA spokesman Andreas Herren.</p>
<p>No date has been set for the next meeting of the players' status committee but, because of the intense interest in the dispute between the two clubs, Herren indicated that it was probable an extraordinary meeting would be called &quot;because of the need for a quick decision&quot;.</p>
<p>Before a meeting can be convened, FIFA said it would first have to receive documentation from the Spanish F.A. explaining its position.</p>
<p>&quot;The Spanish F.A. has never recognised the transfer,&quot; said Herren. &quot;They have said they would not comply with the transfer and have basically told the Italians to take it to FIFA if you want to challenge this.&quot;</p>
<p>If Inter are forced to negotiate directly with Barcelona, who recently signed Ronaldo until 2004, they are bound to face a massive transfer fee.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
