<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="695421" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TENNIS-SPOTLIGHT-POWER OF LOVE TURNS GAME FOR TESTUD.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SPOTLIGHT-POWER OF LOVE TURNS GAME FOR TESTUD.</headline>
<byline>John Mehaffey</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>One point short of a famous victory, Sandrine Testud rolled her eyes to the leaden skies then across the net to Monica Seles, shifting nervously from foot to foot.</p>
<p>Finally she turned to her Italian boyfriend Vittorio, huddled among the spectators overlooking the number three court.</p>
<p>On his signal she served straight, deep and fast for her sixth ace and an astonishing 0-6 6-4 8-6 win over the Wimbledon second seed.</p>
<p>Nothing had looked less likely half an hour into Monday's third round match.</p>
<p>On a court of low and uncertain bounce after the heavy rain which ravaged the opening week, Seles breezed through the first set in exactly 30 minutes.</p>
<p>&quot;I was just trying to start playing,&quot; said the unseeded Testud. &quot;I was just so slow and nothing was going right for me.&quot;</p>
<p>The 25-year-old Frenchwoman, who lives and trains in Rome, finally won a game, holding serve in the second game of the second set after dropping the first two points.</p>
<p>She broke Seles in the next game with the American showing the first signs of uncertainty by double-faulting on the final point.</p>
<p>Hitting longer and with more power as she gained in confidence, Testud held service to win the second set in 42 minutes.</p>
<p>&quot;I got a little bit tight, missed a couple of shots and the set was gone,&quot; Seles reflected.</p>
<p>The American, who looked overweight and cumbersome around the court, lifted her game in the deciding set, hitting some ferocious back-hand winners but proving fallible on the forehand.</p>
<p>Up 5-2 with a break, she seemed poised for victory only to falter against an opponent hitting just as hard and looking far fleeter around the court.</p>
<p>Seles dropped service twice, squandering a match point while leading 6-5, and letting Testud serve for the match.</p>
<p>Which Testud did in some style, with aces on the first and last points, hitting a ball in triumph in the general direction of Vittorio.</p>
<p>&quot;It was beautiful,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Vittorio's contribution apparently goes further than his court-side advice.</p>
<p>How have you got so fit?, Testud was asked.</p>
<p>&quot;Love,&quot; was the instant reply, followed by a more considered response.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been training pretty hard the last winter in Rome&quot; she added. &quot;It has paid off today, the whole year I have been playing pretty well.&quot;</p>
<p>Seles was left to ponder a day of missed opportunities, during a difficult period in her life when she is consumed with worry about her father Karolji who has cancer. She has also to contend with some tasteless tabloid headlines about her weight.</p>
<p>&quot;All the matches that I lost this year, I've been up 5-2, so it seems like a magic number for me to lose,&quot; she concluded. &quot;I just love the game, I think that's the reason why I started, that's the reason I came back.&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
