<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="695649" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria opponents demand papers for London trip.</title>
<headline>Nigeria opponents demand papers for London trip.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's umbrella opposition coalition called on Monday on military rulers to hand back the passport of their member who is to lead a delegation to address Commonwealth ministers in London.</p>
<p>Abraham Adesanya, who plans to lead the delegation of the National Democratic Coalition (NADECO), told reporters in Lagos that he had asked for his passport from Nigeria's second in command and from the internal security service.</p>
<p>&quot;If they really want to help then it's not difficult for them to forward my passport ... it wouldn't take one hour,&quot; Adesanya said.</p>
<p>His passport was confiscated in September 1994, as Nigeria went through a wave of protests and strikes after the arrest of Moshood Abiola, who is believed to have won a 1993 annulled presidential election and is backed by NADECO.</p>
<p>Adesanya said that he would be happy with replacement travel documents if they allowed him to leave Nigeria on July 6 to attend the July 10 meeting with the Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group (CMAG).</p>
<p>&quot;If we have no documents it would mean I would not be able to go and at that stage we would officially inform the CMAG,&quot; Adesanya said.</p>
<p>Africa's most populous nation was suspended from the club of Britain and its former colonies in 1995 after the hanging of nine activists. A meeting in October this year is to discuss whether the military have made enough moves towards democracy and better human rights to let Nigeria back in.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
