<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="695802" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: OSCE says Albania vote &quot;adequate and acceptable&quot;.</title>
<headline>OSCE says Albania vote &quot;adequate and acceptable&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The pan-European body overseeing Albania's general election said on Monday the vote could be considered &quot;adequate and acceptable at this stage&quot;.</p>
<p>A preliminary statement issued by Catherine Lalumiere, the top official observing the election under the auspices of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe, said the vote had showed Albanians' desire for a democratic future &quot;despite minor flaws in many areas and some very serious problems in a few areas&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;We believe therefore that we can say that the elections can be considered as adequate and acceptable,&quot; said the statement, read out by Lalumiere at a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;The result of these elections can be the foundation for a stable, democractic system, which Albanians want and deserve,&quot; it added, citing large voter turnout, relatively few incidents of intimidation and non-partisan conduct of most electoral commissions.</p>
<p>The OSCE had sent more than 450 observers throughout the rugged country to help ensure a free vote 13 months after the last general elections were found to have been unfair. Top OSCE officials had admitted before the election that it was unlikely to meet fully all Western criteria for fair elections.</p>
<p>President Sali Berisha has admitted the defeat of his Democratic Party in the election and the opposition Socialists say that along with allied parties they should have a two-thirds majority in the 155-seat assembly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
