<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696036" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China begins Hong Kong handover countdown.</title>
<headline>China begins Hong Kong handover countdown.</headline>
<byline>Benjamin Kang Lim</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>China on Monday began the final countdown to the return of Hong Kong by clearing Beijing's Tiananmen Square of tens of thousands of revellers and sending troops to the border with hours to go before the handover.</p>
<p>Troops of China's People's Liberation Army (PLA) left amid cheering crowds in the southern boomtown of Shenzhen on the first leg of their march into Hong Kong to assert Chinese sovereignty over the British colony at midnight (1600 GMT).</p>
<p>The first 509 soldiers, due to march into Hong Kong at 9.00 p.m. (1300 GMT), streamed out of the barracks in a cavalcade of 39 army-green trucks towards the border after a solemn departure ceremony and a speech by China's top military officer.</p>
<p>China's ruling Communist Party moved to allay fears over the stationing of PLA soldiers in Hong Kong, telling the garrison to love the people of Hong Kong and protect their prosperity.</p>
<p>&quot;With your actual deeds (you must) win the support and love of the Hong Kong people,&quot; General Liu Huaqing, vice-chairman of the Central Military Commission, told a departure ceremony.</p>
<p>Many people in Hong Kong view the arrival of the PLA with alarm, recalling the army's June, 1989, crushing of student-led demonstrations in Tiananmen Square. Hundreds were killed.</p>
<p>&quot;The return of Hong Kong to the motherland... has been a dream for more than 100 years but became reality step by step only under the leadership of the Communist Party,&quot; the official People's Daily said in a front-page editorial.</p>
<p>Late paramount leader and communist veteran Deng Xiaoping negotiated the return of capitalist Hong Kong, reaching accord with London in 1984 to recover the territory, seized after Britain defeated a weak imperial China in the 19th-century Opium Wars.</p>
<p>The editorial was the latest installment in a propaganda blitz that has billed the handover as one of the most important events of the year, if not the decade, and as a moment that will wash away a century and a half of national disgrace.</p>
<p>In Beijing's Tiananmen Square where Chairman Mao Zedong declared communist rule, hundreds of police, backed by paramilitary People's Armed Police, advanced in tight-knit ranks on crowds, pushing reluctant and curious onlookers to the sides of the vast square.</p>
<p>Sanitary workers, garbage trucks and sweepers moved in to clean up debris left by tens of thousands of city residents and tourists from all over China who had flocked to the square over the weekend and braved a downpour on Monday to see the red lanterns, flowers and decorations for the handover celebration.</p>
<p>The square was sealed off to allow 100,000 people to join an official party and watch the countdown clock tick away the final seconds to the moment of the handover at midnight on Monday. Most of Beijing's 11 million residents have been advised to stay at home and watch television.</p>
<p>China has rarely allowed large crowds on Tiananmen Square since the army crushed the student protests in 1989.</p>
<p>High above China's capital, a blimp proclaims the impending recovery of the territory, bearing the message &quot;Celebrate the Return of Hong Kong&quot;.</p>
<p>Down below, Chinese flags flutter across the city while banners stream across pedestrian bridges and on street corners, shouting: &quot;Wash away 100 years of national shame&quot; and &quot;A better tomorrow for Hong Kong&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
