<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696030" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: New Hong Kong takes shape as legislature sworn in.</title>
<headline>New Hong Kong takes shape as legislature sworn in.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Davison</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG, China 1996-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's new leaders took centre stage in the early hours of Tuesday with the swearing-in of its new chief executive and the inauguration of a provisional legislature appointed by Beijing.</p>
<p>As dawn approached and the British departed by air and sea, the formalities for Chinese rule over the former British colony speeded up and the new Special Administrative Region took shape.</p>
<p>Billionaire shipping magnate Tung Chee-hwa took the oath of office as chief executive, effectively replacing last colonial governor Chris Patten, at a solemn ceremony in the glittering harbourfront Convention Centre attended by Chinese President Jiang Zemin and Premier Li Peng.</p>
<p>Immediately afterwards, his new government -- 24 departmental secretaries led by Chief Secretary Anson Chan -- also took the oath, followed by the new 60-member provisional assembly.</p>
<p>The ceremony was attended by many foreign dignitaries but boycotted by U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright and British Prime Minister Tony Blair.</p>
<p>The pair left ceremonies marking the end of British rule early to avoid the investiture, in protest at China's decision to scrap the democratically elected assembly that existed under British rule and replace it with an appointed body.</p>
<p>As the new legislature was being sworn in at the Convention Centre, Hong Kong democrats protested from the balcony of the nearby legislative council building, where the China-backed deputies will shortly take up residence.</p>
<p>The defiant democrats pledged to continue speaking out on behalf of Hong Kong people and to fight for democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;We pledge to continue to be the voice of Hong Kong People -- in or out of office -- and to fight to get democracy back,&quot; Democratic Party leader Martin Lee told a crowd of thousands gathered below in Statue Square.</p>
<p>The democrats insist that they were elected in 1995 to represent the people of Hong Kong for a four-year term, until 1999.</p>
<p>But the protesters and the absence of the British and Americans went unnoticed by most other nations, who avoided the Anglo-U.S. boycott to observe and recognise the new Hong Kong as China stamped its mark indelibly upon it.</p>
<p>Alongside Tung and the new legislators stood Hong Kong's new tier of top judges and the 24 departmental secretaries or &quot;ministers&quot;, all but one of whom also served under Patten.</p>
<p>The inauguration ceremony took place under Beijing's red flag, ending more than 150 years of national shame for China as Patten and Prince Charles steamed out of Hong Kong aboard the royal yacht Britannia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG, China"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
