<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696109" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK Democrat speaks freedom as British rule fades.</title>
<headline>HK Democrat speaks freedom as British rule fades.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Davison</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Martin Lee, Hong Kong's leading democrat, spent the last few hours under British rule stressing a message of freedom and urging Hong Kong journalists to keep telling the truth as they saw it.</p>
<p>Lee also told a packed news conference at the Foreign Correspondents Club he planned to press on with a protest at the legislative building against a Beijing-appointed legislature soon after the handover at midnight (1600 GMT) on Monday.</p>
<p>He said he would use a ladder to climb to the balcony to read a speech if he was blocked from getting there through the building.</p>
<p>Lee said freedom was what had made Hong Kong the pearl of the Orient. &quot;The lustre of the pearl is our freedom. If we lose our freedom, that pearl loses its lustre,&quot; Lee said just hours before Hong Kong's handover to China at midnight on Monday.</p>
<p>He also encouraged Hong Kong's press community to continue reporting truthfully.</p>
<p>&quot;Why should courage be required to do the job of a reporter?&quot; he asked. &quot;There has been too much fear already generated.&quot;</p>
<p>Journalists must put into practice the press freedoms that China's president Jiang Zemin and foreign minister Qian Qichen have pledged would remain in force in Hong Kong after Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Remember, lots of people are watching you. Chances are if you don't write it (a sensitive story), others will follow. If you do, they will follow you,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lee said he and nine other legislators were going ahead with their protest against replacement of the democratically-elected Legislative Council with the China-appointed provisional body.</p>
<p>While the new legislature was being inaugurated in the early hours of Tuesday, Lee and his group were determined to go to the legislative council chamber in central Hong Kong and read speeches from the balcony.</p>
<p>Should their path be blocked, Lee, a member of the outgoing legsilative but not the provisional body, said he would use a 30-ft (10-metre) ladder to climb up to the balcony.</p>
<p>&quot;I will climb up to the balcony and make my speech first in Chinese and then in English,&quot; he said. &quot;After that we intend to leave the building in a dignified way.&quot;</p>
<p>The democrats already have permission to enter the chamber, but it was not known if they would be allowed to get to the balcony.</p>
<p>Lee said he hoped he would not have to use the ladder.</p>
<p>&quot;Our intention is not to create a scene,&quot; he said. &quot;It is not very interesting to see a thin guy climbing up a ladder. It is much more interesting to see a fat gu falling down a ladder.&quot;  </p>
<p>China is replacing the elected Legislative Council with an unelected chamber. Lee's Democrats face a year in the wilderness until new elections are held, possibly next May.</p>
<p>China has taken action to reverse democratic reforms introduced in the twilight of British rule.</p>
<p>&quot;We are prepared to defend the freedoms we cherish. We are prepared to work with China to build a better future for Hong Kong and for China,&quot; Lee said to cheers and applause from a crowd of pro-democracy demonstrators waving banners.</p>
<p>&quot;As we stand here this early morning in democratic solidarity, we declare Hong Kong people want democracy... The flame of democracy has been ignited and is burning in the hearts of our people. It may not be extinguished. Nay. It will only grow stronger.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
