<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696236" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Compaq unveils new Presario consumer line.</title>
<headline>Compaq unveils new Presario consumer line.</headline>
<byline>Therese Poletti</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Compaq Computer Corp. Monday unveiled a new line of Presario home computers, including a couple of units priced under $1,000 with several features aimed at turning the PC into a consumer appliance.</p>
<p>Compaq, the world's largest supplier of personal computers, also said it formed alliances with four software companies to sell PCs in schools.</p>
<p>In addition, the Houston-based company said it formed a new product group to concentrate on its lines of networking and communications products in Europe.</p>
<p>The new product line -- which includes eight Presario systems and two notebooks -- is Compaq's latest move to become the preferred brand in the &quot;digital&quot; home, the company said at a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Isn't it amazing how the PC has blossomed into the essential digital appliance for the home?&quot; said Mike Heil, senior vice president and general manager of Compaq's consumer group. Heil said Compaq's easy-to-use products and its strong service and support have helped the company grow in the home market.</p>
<p>Heil and other Compaq executives touted the company's growing market share in the consumer retail sector, saying that Compaq has about 21 percent of the U.S. retail market. Compaq is also the world's leading personal computer maker.</p>
<p>Some of the new features of the new Presarios include an &quot;Easy Access&quot; button start-up for fast Internet access. In more expensive models, a &quot;Creativity Imaging Center&quot; captures video and still images from a camcorder, a VCR or a digital camera, which can be transmitted to the PC and edited.</p>
<p>&quot;The focus is on creativity, with digital cameras and other features,&quot; said Richard Zwetchkenbaum,an analyst with International Data Corp. in Framingham, Mass. &quot;This is a big trend in the consumer marketplace.&quot;</p>
<p>Zwetchkenbaum added that new consumer PCs from Hewlett-Packard Co. and Sony Corp. also include features to make PCs more consumer friendly.</p>
<p>Compaq's less expensive products include the new Presario 2200, which starts at a price of $799 with a 180 MHz Media GX processor developed by Cyrix Corp., without a monitor. When purchased with a 14-inch Compaq colour monitor, consumers can buy the total system for about $999.</p>
<p>The new Presario 4504, with a minitower design that takes up less desk space and an Intel Corp. Pentium 200 MHz processor, starts at $999 without a monitor, the company said.</p>
<p>The Presario 4504, 4508 and 4528 range in price from $999 to $1,899 and are expected to be available at nationwide retail stores in July.</p>
<p>The Presario 4808, 4814 and 4824 range in price from $1,999 to $2,699 and also will be available in July. These computers include a creativity imaging centre, home theatre surround sound, DVD players, Pentium II processors, and backlit easy access buttons, Compaq said.</p>
<p>The features of the notebooks, the 1200 and 1600 series, include Intel pentium chips with MMX multimedia technology and an eight-hour &quot;DisqPlay&quot; for music CDs, which can play CDs even when the computer is not turned on, the company said.</p>
<p>The Presario 1200 and 1600 Notebook Series are priced between $2,299 and $2,999.</p>
<p>Compaq said it formed software alliances with Apple Computer Inc.'s Claris Corp., CUC International Inc.'s Davidson &amp; Associates, Citadel Technology Inc. and McAfee Associates, as well as continuing its agreement with Roger Wagner Publishing Inc.</p>
<p>Compaq said in a statement that it will integrate the companies' software into a Presario ES personal computer aimed at schools with a price starting at $1,799.</p>
<p>It said it will add a number of PC models for sale to schools, starting with the Presario 1090ES notebook, the first portable computer to be offered through its education programme.</p>
<p>Compaq said its new European product group allows the company to focus on a fast-growing and strategic business, and fully align Europe with the company's corporate structure.</p>
<p>Compaq's stock rose $1.25 to $99.75 in consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange in late afternoon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
