<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696291" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Craving for yield raises U.S. interest in LDC debt.</title>
<headline>Craving for yield raises U.S. interest in LDC debt.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The world is growing smaller, at least judging by what U.S. bond investors have been adding to their portfolios.</p>
<p>Over the past few weeks, developing nations have turned to U.S. institutions for massive amounts of financing, as low interest rates in the industrialised world sent money managers scrambling to find higher returns.</p>
<p>&quot;We see increasing interest from a wide array of traditional fixed-income investors,&quot; said Nathan Sandler, managing director at Trust Company of the West.</p>
<p>&quot;Their motivation for wanting to explore this asset class is really a function of all the different opportunities that this asset class offers -- pure return,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As of June 27, JP Morgan's Emerging Market Bond Index-plus rose 10.28 percent this year, a growth that lags its 39.3-percent return in 1996, but well above the 2.8-percent 1997 year-to-date return in the Lehman Brothers Government Bonds Index.</p>
<p>U.S. investors began trickling back into emerging markets assets after the rebound from Mexico's 1994 financial crisis, but the trend has turned into a flood.</p>
<p>Developing countries issued close to $10 billion in new debt in June. Most notably, Russia floated $2.0 billion Eurobonds, Poland sold $400 million Yankee bond, and Mexico prepaid $6.0 billion notes with cheaper, longer-term paper.</p>
<p>To capture tempting yields, many U.S. high grade fund managers now dedicate about 5 percent of their assets to the emerging markets, and these levels may rise to 10 percent, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The area of greatest growth to emerging market demand won't come from the dedicated emerging market portfolios,&quot; said Hock Lau, portfolio manager at GT Global's High Income and Strategic Income Funds. &quot;It will come from opportunistic investors, what some people call the cross-over place of traditional U.S. high-grade bond investors to the emerging markets was sped up when developing nations improved their macro-economic profiles, trimmed budget deficits and extended the duration of their debt profiles.</p>
<p>These reforms, particularly in Latin America and Eastern Europe, led to a remarkable number of credit upgrades to investment-grade status that allowed U.S. institutions, insurance companies and endowments to invest there.</p>
<p>&quot;The march of countries toward investment grade and improving credit is real,&quot; said Tim Kearney, managing director of institutional fixed income at Prudential Investments.</p>
<p>He pointed to Russia and Venezuela as countries whose bonds should gain as the reforms begin to pay off.</p>
<p>Lau said he felt very positive over prospects in Russia and Bulgaria.</p>
<p>As always, there could be danger ahead, and U.S. investors said their optimism would hinge on the Federal Reserve maintaining its current steady approach to U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>In 1994, the rapid rise of U.S. rates diminished the attractiveness of the emerging markets, as U.S. investors captured higher yields at home.</p>
<p>Investors said they felt sanguine that financial markets could now better distinguish among individual nations, unlike three years ago when Mexico's crisis spread havoc across the emerging markets in a process dubbed the &quot;tequila effect.&quot;</p>
<p>As evidence of the changing times, investors said that recent instability in the Czech Republic and Thailand did not present sustained challenges to their neighbours or the wider emerging markets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
