<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696393" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton says tax plan aimed at broad middle class.</title>
<headline>Clinton says tax plan aimed at broad middle class.</headline>
<byline>Jackie Frank</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton unveiled a proposed tax cut compromise with congressional Republicans on Monday that concedes a modest reduction in capital gains taxes and insists that child tax credits benefit working poor families.</p>
<p>The president said he is willing to work with Republican leaders in the House and Senate to reach agreement on a net $85 billion five-year tax cut that he can sign into law.</p>
<p>The House of Representatives and Senate each passed versions of the tax bill, and conference committees will meet to work out a unified proposal when they return from the July Fourth holiday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are committed to work with the Republicans and this is a good-faith effort to do that, incorporating both their ideas for capital gains and some other things as well,&quot; Clinton said in a brief statement from the White House lawn as he departed for Boston.</p>
<p>Clinton's plan lowers the tax on investments, provides a phased-in $500-per-child tax credit calculated in such a way as to permit low-income parents to benefit, and includes $35 billion worth of tax breaks for higher education. He also offered a new, separate plan to increase the cigarette tax by 20 cents per pack with the proceeds to help children's health programmes. The Senate had passed a similar version.</p>
<p>While the House and Senate bills contain elements of these, Clinton criticised them as skewed toward providing a larger share of benefits for higher-income people.</p>
<p>&quot;They do an inadequate job of opening the doors to college ... They direct far too little relief to the middle class. They include time-bomb tax cuts that threaten to explode the deficit. They do not do enough to keep our economy going,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our plan gives the vast majority of aid to the middle class, the 60 percent in the middle, and much, much more than either the plan that passed the Senate or the plan that passed the House,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The tax cut is a politically important part of the budget agreement worked out with Congress that aims to reduce the government's budget deficit to zero by 2002. Cutting taxes takes revenue from the government, but both sides have called it a &quot;dividend&quot; for the public.</p>
<p>On a cut in the capital gains tax rate paid on investment profits, the cornerstone of the Republican tax plans, Clinton offered an alternative that would allow exclusion from tax of 30 percent of the profits on investments from assets such as stocks, bonds and real estate held a year or more.</p>
<p>He refused to take one step sought by Republicans by not offering to index the tax rate to allow investors to avoid tax on the portion of capital gains accrued due to inflation. Administration officials said this would explode the deficit.</p>
<p>Clinton's method would drop the top tax rate by only a fraction, to 27.7 percent from the current maximum 28 percent, but would show up as a greater benefit for those with moderate incomes. The Republican bills cut the top capital gains rate to 20 percent from 28 percent.</p>
<p>Central to his plan is nearly $35 billion in tax cuts designed to encourage higher education. It was modified to give a maximum $1,500 tax credit in 1998 and a 20 percent tuition tax credit for the third and fourth years of college. Clinton dropped the requirement that students maintain a &quot;B&quot; grade average. The tax break would not be available for the wealthy.</p>
<p>His plan would give lower- and middle-income families with children under age 17 a $400-per-child credit next year. The tax credit would rise to $500 per child in 1999 and in 2003 children up to age 19 would be eligible.</p>
<p>Clinton's original tax plan offered in his budget called for a net $22 billion tax cut. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin told reporters that once a larger tax cut was agreed upon with Congress, the administration was able to expand its plan for such purposes as covering teenagers with a tax credit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
