<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696342" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - U.S. T-bond options vols slightly bid.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - U.S. T-bond options vols slightly bid.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for U.S. Treasury bond futures-options were very slightly firmer by late Monday, but brokers said activity stayed subdued mainly ahead of Thursday's U.S. June employment report.</p>
<p>&quot;Into tommorow's (NAPM) data it's slightly firmer, but it's not even firm enough to comment on,&quot; said a broker at the Chicago Board of Trade. &quot;It's pretty unchanged on the day.&quot;</p>
<p>She quoted August at-the-money futures-options at 7.7/7.85 percent, September at 8.10/8.17 percent, and December at 8.26/8.40 percent, all up a couple of tenths &quot;but nothing to talk about before FOMC.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Volatility has been a little bit bid over the course of the day,&quot; added another floor broker, who said some shorts will probably cover before the long weekend and after reaping so much profit already.</p>
<p>&quot;The (likelihood) at this point for a continued selloff in volatility is limited,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He quoted the August 111 straddle and the September 110/112 strangle each at just under 8.0 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>The first floor broker expected some players who have been profitably short volatility to cash in before Thursday's jobs data, but she doubted all would flock toward the exits.  </p>
<p>&quot;Over the last several weeks and with today's quiet markets, players have done really well being short volatility, and they've got so much in it now I can't see what the risk-reward of staying short at this point is,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>&quot;But net/net people still want to be short because of the long (holiday) weekend,&quot; she said. &quot;(So) you'll see them covering in...mostly in short-dated stuff like August.&quot;</p>
<p>Featured activity Monday included one commission house that bought 5,000 deep out-of-the-money August 115 calls at 1/64, possibly for another firm, said the second broker.  </p>
<p>The first broker said she saw intraday spec buying of August 110 puts, which she said were mainly covered by Monday's close. She also noted firm position-maintenance, with one dealer seen doing August 110-113 combos by selling calls and buying puts with a 0.65 percentage point skew.</p>
<p>((Derivatives Desk(312)408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
