<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696541" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan using donated mlns to repay foreign debt.</title>
<headline>Pakistan using donated mlns to repay foreign debt.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The State (central) Bank of Pakistan (SBP) said on Monday it was using $210 million, collected from the public after an appeal by Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif, to repay foreign debt.</p>
<p>Sharif launched his National Debt Retirement Programme (NDRP) to raise money in the form of donations and deposits after winning power in February elections.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign currency deposits amounting to about $210 million received up to June 26, 1997 under the NDRP are being used in the repayment of foreign debt,&quot; the SBP said in a statement.</p>
<p>On Friday, the SBP said it had used 1.5 billion rupees from privatisation of a state-owned bank to retire domestic debt.</p>
<p>The proceeds from this month's sale of a 70 percent stake in Habib Credit and Exchange Bank Ltd were used to retire debt totalling 1.5 billion rupees which carried an interest rate of 17.29 percent a year.</p>
<p>The SBP also said it had used a donation of 1.7 billion rupees it had received from an undisclosed source to retire domestic debt carrying the same interest rate.</p>
<p>&quot;Accordingly, since June 27, 1997, a total of 3.2 billion rupees of the most expensive debt has been retired,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Pakistan's domestic debt will total one trillion (1,000 billion) rupees at the end of fiscal 1996/97 (July-June) according to budget estimates.</p>
<p>($1 = 40.56 rupees)</p>
<p>-- Karachi Newsroom 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
