<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696889" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bosnia expected to reach debt deal with creditors.</title>
<headline>Bosnia expected to reach debt deal with creditors.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnia is expected to reach an agreement with its commercial bank creditors later today to restructure debt it inherited as one of the former Yugoslav republics, emerging market specialists said on Monday.</p>
<p>Bosnia is said to have asked for forgiveness on 90 percent of its commercial bank debt, but emerging market experts said the figure was likely to be closer to 65 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;They are finishing off talks right now. We think there is going to be a 65 percent discount in terms of face reduction amount,&quot; said one banking source who requested anonymity. &quot;They are looking at nine percent of $4.3 billion (principal).&quot;</p>
<p>Bosnia, which began debt talks with the London Club of commercial bank creditors last Wednesday, is also expected to issue bonds with a possible 25-year maturity as part of the debt restructuring, the source added.</p>
<p>Another emerging market source, who has been following Bosnia's debt talks, said he did not believe the country would receive the 90 percent debt forgiveness they were said to have asked for from the banks.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't think they will get that much,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>--Diane Craft, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5110</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
