<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="696995" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar, South Korea sign deal to double gas supply.</title>
<headline>Qatar, South Korea sign deal to double gas supply.</headline>
<byline>Kedar Sharma</byline>
<dateline>DOHA 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar and South Korea on Monday signed a final sales-and-purchase agreement to double the volume of liquefied natural gas supplies from Qatar to 4.8 million tonnes a year by the turn of the century, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The first ship carrying the gas will leave the Qatari shores in July 1999 and by 2001 the supply will be lifted to 4.8 million tonnes a year,&quot; said Youssef Hussein Kamal, under-secretary at the ministry of finance, economy and trade and chairman of Ras Laffan LNG Company (Rasgas).</p>
<p>&quot;The deal will run for 25 years,&quot; he told reporters after signing the deal with Han Kap-Soo, chairman of South Korea's Korea Gas Corporation (Kogas).</p>
<p>Rasgas is Qatar's second LNG venture designed to tap its mammoth gas reserves -- the third largest in the world, after Russia's and Iran's.</p>
<p>Rasgas is 66.5 percent owned by Qatar General Petroleum Corp, 26.5 percent by Mobil Corp, four percent by Japan's Nissho Iwai and three percent by Itochu Corp. Kogas is expected to join the project with five percent equity.</p>
<p>Kogas had originally signed an SPA in 1995 to take 2.4 million tonnes of liquefied natural gas annually from Rasgas from mid-1999 with an option to increase the volume by a further 2.4 to three million tonnes a year from 2000.</p>
<p>But it only exercised the option in February, after Rasgas dropped a &quot;minimum take-or-pay price clause&quot; in the SPA and offered Kogas a five percent stake in the project, and signed a memorandum of understanding with Rasgas.</p>
<p>The doubling of the volume has now enabled Rasgas, struggling for customers against fierce competition from other Gulf, Asian and Australian LNG producers, to &quot;benefit from the economies of scale and build two LNG trains,&quot; a Rasgas executive said.</p>
<p>&quot;The major construction contracts and financing arrangements for building the second train to supply the additional volume have already been put in place,&quot; Rasgas' Kamal said.</p>
<p>Both Kamal and Han said the price of gas supplied would be determined periodically, taking into account the rate of inflation and the prices of other sources of energy, particularly crude oil, during the supply period.</p>
<p>Han said that by 2000 his country would need 18 million tonnes of gas annually, of which 5.3 million tonnes would come from Indonesia, 4.8 million tonnes from Qatar, 4.1 million from Oman and two million tonnes from Malaysia. The rest would be bought on the spot market or met through short-term contracts.</p>
<p>Kamal said Rasgas was now able to sell half of its targeted production of 10 million tonnes a year. &quot;For the rest we are scouting the global market to find customers. Talks with Lebanon, China, Turkey and Taiwan are underway,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
