<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697242" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish bonds slip back amid currency speculation.</title>
<headline>Irish bonds slip back amid currency speculation.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish bonds slipped back in thin trade on Monday as speculation about a revaluation of the Irish pound continued to preoccupy the market, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is increasingly talking about the new finance minister revaluing the punt within the next couple of months,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;The argument runs that if the currency isn't revalued and goes into EMU at the central parity rate of 2.41 marks, it will be an inappropriate level for the booming Irish economy.&quot;</p>
<p>The pressure to revalue was keeping the punt firm and well bid at the short end, the dealer said.</p>
<p>Dealers say that currency concerns and high money market rates have been keeping both non-residents and domestic investors out of the Irish bond market.</p>
<p>By 1510 GMT, the 6.5 percent bond due 2001 was down seven pence at 102.15 to yield 5.90 percent, while the eight percent bond due 2006 was down 22 pence at 109.75 to yield 6.54 percent.</p>
<p>Yields against German Bunds were broadly unchanged from Friday's close at 159 basis points over in the five-year bond, and 94 over in the 10-year.</p>
<p>Views among economists are mixed on whether the new government will adjust the punt's exchange rate in the ERM to discourage recent speculative selling of the Irish unit, fuelled by the view that currencies will enter the euro at their ERM central parity.</p>
<p>The Irish pound is currently trading well above that level.</p>
<p>The weak punt has been causing Irish bonds to underperform against Spain and Italy over recent weeks, dealers said.</p>
<p>Elsewhere on Monday, U.S. NAPM data from Chicago and New York suggesting the economy is growing at full steam, and raising the odds in favour of a rates rise after this week's FOMC meeting, weighed on bond markets.</p>
<p>At home EBR figures on Wednesday and credit data on Thursday will be a focus, particularly EBR which is likely to show a large budget surplus at mid-year and emphasise that there will be limited issuance of fresh stock over the balance of the year.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected the National Treasury Management Agency (NTMA) to issue a statement about supply later in the week.</p>
<p>International focus will be on U.S. payrolls on Friday, an important indicator of Q2 growth.</p>
<p>--Kevin Smith, Dublin Newsroom +353 1 661 3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
