<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697360" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Period of consolidation of benefit to HMR - Hoechst.</title>
<headline>Period of consolidation of benefit to HMR - Hoechst.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hoechst Marion Roussel (HMR), the drugs unit of German chemicals and drugs group Hoechst AG, may be eyeing a period of consolidation even as the global drugs industry engages in massive restructurings, the group's chairman said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless something really attractive comes up as an acquisition, then two years of breathing space would do us (HMR) good,&quot; Hoechst AG chairman Juergen Dormann told the German newspaper Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung.</p>
<p>Dormann's comments come as the industry remains in flux with new partnerships, such as French group Rhone-Poulenc Rorer's bid for its U.S. drugs unit and Swiss group Roche AG's bid for Germany's Boehringer Mannheim.</p>
<p>Dormann spoke to the newspaper on the eve of Hoechst's biggest change to date on July 1 when Hoechst AG will officially become a strategic management holding company with no responsibility for operational business.</p>
<p>Hoechst's units, including the HMR drugs unit, will be separate legal entities and be responsible for their business.</p>
<p>Hoechst earlier announced plans to exit the generic drugs business and Dormann on Monday said the group would try &quot;to anticipate developments.&quot; It is attempting to sell its U.S. generics unit Copley.</p>
<p>But sources close to the company have said there has been no real interest yet.</p>
<p>For the group's diagnostics business Behring Dade, Dormann said no date has yet been set for a bourse listing and that Behring was investigating whether or not it might consider taking a majority in the joint-venture between Behring and U.S. group Dade International.</p>
<p>Similarly, Hoechst is still considering the option of listing the industrial gases unit Messer Griesheim on the bourse next year.</p>
<p>Dormann repeated comments made at the company's annual festival that he expected a slightly improved operating profit in 1997.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
