<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697375" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Repsol shares gain on LPG price freeze removal.</title>
<headline>Repsol shares gain on LPG price freeze removal.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Spain's Repsol outpaced the indices on Monday after the Industry Ministry confirmed it would cancel a price freeze imposed on liquid petroleum gas (LPG), a factor which has weighed on the energy firm's results.</p>
<p>At 0930 GMT Repsol was up 80 pesetas, 1.12 percent, to 6,330 while the Ibex-35 blue chip index gained 0.48 percent to 6,972.42.</p>
<p>&quot;This is very important news which could add around 10 percent to Repsol's annual operating profit. We'll be revising up our year-end profits forecasts,&quot; said a dealer at a Spanish bank who requested anonymity.</p>
<p>He set a medium-term target price for the shares of 6,700 pesetas.</p>
<p>Repsol's operating profit in 1996 was 198.6 billion pesetas.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first quarter, the effect of LPG on the operating results from the gas division was 12 billion pesetas, although the effect in that quarter, because of seasonal factors, is much greater than in the rest of the year. But the overall impact on its profit and loss account is substantial,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
