<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697462" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - ITALY - MONDAY JUNE 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - ITALY - MONDAY JUNE 30.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>* Italy's bicameral commission aimed at carrying out constitutional reforms ended its talks and is expected to vote today its final programmatic document about electoral reform and a new semi-presidential system (all).</p>
<p>* In an interview, hard left Communist Refoundation party leader Fausto Bertinotti said prime minister Romano Prodi's optimism about an agreement of social parties on welfare state reforms was not so understandable. Prodi had been earlier quoted as saying he was confident the hard left Communist Refoundation would eventually support welfare reform (Corriere della Sera).</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>* Financial markets are expected to rise after Bank of Italy announced on Friday it would reduce the discount rate to 6.25 percent from 6.75 percent. The fourth rate cut in less than 12 months was welcomed by politicians, unions and businessman, who had been urging Bank of Italy governor Antonio Fazio for weeks to ease the cost of borrowing and thus help stimulate the country's sluggish economy (Repubblica).</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +39266129450</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
