<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697596" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: BHP says has no plans to sell Hartley mine.</title>
<headline>BHP says has no plans to sell Hartley mine.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd (BHP) on Monday said it had no plans to sell out of its majority-owned Hartley platinum project in Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>BHP has had development problems with its 67-percent-owned project, which has estimated reserves of 50.9 million tonnes of platinum group metals at a grade of 5.3 grams per tonne.  </p>
<p>BHP Minerals chief executive Dick Carter told a briefing seminar that despite sale speculation, the company remained committed to the project.</p>
<p>The project is expected to reach full production at the end of calendar 1998, he said.</p>
<p>Some problems have been encountered, but the project's underground performance has improved significantly, he added.</p>
<p>The mine, a joint venture between BHP and Delta Gold NL, was originally forecast to start production at the end of 1996 but heavy rains, problems in breaking ground and training workers delayed the startup.  </p>
<p>The project is currently mining 27,000 tonnes of ore per month and aims to reach full production of 180,000 tonnes of ore by September 1998 when it is expected to have platinum output of 150,000 ounces, 110,000 ounces of palladium, 11,500 ounces of rhodium and 23,000 ounces of gold.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-3 9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
