<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697510" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain seen eyeing simple 5 bln stg utility tax.</title>
<headline>Britain seen eyeing simple 5 bln stg utility tax.</headline>
<byline>Jo Winterbottom</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A levy on privatised utilities planned by Britain's new Labour government for its July 2 budget will be aimed at raising around five billion pounds ($8.3 billion) with a straightforward formula based on profits, tax experts said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Picking something simple, that's going to be the over-riding force..it will remove uncertainty swiftly and is easier to get onto the statute books, harder to challenge,&quot; said Lucy Chennells of the Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS).</p>
<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer (finance minister) Gordon Brown, who will present the budget to parliament, has said it will include a one-off tax on privatised utilities which have seen &quot;excess profits&quot; since they were sold off by the previous Conservative government.</p>
<p>Five billion pounds was the median figure given in a Reuters survey of economists carried out on June 19/20 and many analysts consider share prices have this amount already factored in.</p>
<p>The tax, aimed at covering a three-billion-pound programme to cut youth unemployment, was a central plank of Labour's manifesto on which it swept to victory two months ago.</p>
<p>Brown has so far given no details of the amount to be raised, the companies which will pay or the formula to be used for calculation.</p>
<p>&quot;He'll be working backwards from an answer. He will have to define which companies will be liable and then the basis of calculation,&quot; said one tax expert who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Five billion pounds would provide the government with some extra revenue after funding its unemployment programme while not stretching companies enough to prompt them to mount a legal challenge, observers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Five billion is about the upper limit of what they can achieve without a legal challenge. The bigger it is the more likely it is to be challenged,&quot; said David Smith, chief economist at Williams de Broe.</p>
<p>Brown is widely expected to give a definition of companies liable for the tax without listing them by name, tax experts said, in order to avoid being challenged for discrimination.</p>
<p>&quot;He could define it as all the companies which had regulators, or all those which had a golden share (protective government stake) or a government licence, but the most likely seems a combination of tests,&quot; said another tax expert.</p>
<p>The definition is expected to include privatised water and electricity companies and could be broad enough to cover British Telecom, the former British Gas utility Centrica and even Railtrack and airports agency BAA.</p>
<p>The budget is also expected to outline the formula to be used to calculate &quot;excess profits&quot; and the amount to which companies are liable.</p>
<p>Analysts have largely considered two main avenues for this formula, one based on shareholder returns and one on profits.</p>
<p>The latter is gaining favour, partly because the target has been outlined as &quot;excess profits&quot;, partly because it would avoid lengthy legal wrangling over definitions and partly because it would remove uncertainty more quickly, tax experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The windfall levy is not a tax on capital gains that individuals have actually made, but rather it is a tax on the companies themselves. As such, it would be more conventional to base the tax on an objective measure of company profits,&quot; Chennells wrote in the IFS &quot;Green Budget&quot; published in May.</p>
<p>A further advantage of basing the tax on profits is that the information to be used in calculations is already published, either in company accounts or figures submitted to regulators.</p>
<p>In addition, there are seven of the original 12 regional electricity companies (RECS) which are now owned by American companies which would be able to offset a tax on profits in their U.S. taxation, while other methods could mean they faced double taxation.</p>
<p>But there are problems over using profits as a base which Brown will have to address, including defining &quot;excess&quot; and the parameters of a timescale.</p>
<p>Analysts suggest that &quot;excess&quot; could be determined against a benchmark such as an index of the leading 100 stocks while time parameters would have varying impacts on individual firms.</p>
<p>&quot;The choice of timeframe has a fairly marked impact on the amount individual companies would have to pay. Where the government draws the line might depend on where it wants the levy to fall,&quot; said one tax expert.</p>
<p>The government might also consider payment in instalments, tax experts said, as it does not need the total funding for its welfare-to-work programme in one go and staggered payments might soften the blow for companies.</p>
<p>&quot;It only takes one company to go to court to put the budget under uncertainty. Brown will be making it easy to work out, ensuring no one company suffers more than others and it would help if payments are spread,&quot; said one economist who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;Brown is going to pick the base and timeframe that raises what he needs or what he feels he could obtain without making the industry squeal,&quot; the tax expert said.</p>
<p>($ = 0.600 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
