<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697593" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Timing seen a mystery for next Australian rate cut.</title>
<headline>Timing seen a mystery for next Australian rate cut.</headline>
<byline>John Mair</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economists see another cut in official Australian interest rates as likely during July, but no one is quite sure when the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) will make the announcement.</p>
<p>Sluggish consumer demand, a stalled labour market and a weak manufacturing sector coupled with only moderate price and wages pressures are seen justifying a rate cut.</p>
<p>&quot;Several of the conditions necessary for another cash rate cut after (Tuesday's) RBA board meeting are in place,&quot; UBS Australia chief economist Stephen Roberts said.  </p>
<p>Official rates were cut to 5.50 percent on May 23, in a move that caught markets by surprise. It was the fourth cut in rates since July 31 last year, when the cash rate was 7.50 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason why we're leaning towards another easing is that conditions really haven't improved significantly from the last easing...the sort of conditions that triggered the easing in May are still in place,&quot; National Australia bank senior economist David Lansley said.</p>
<p>Economists surveyed by Reuters put the odds of a rate cut being delivered in July at just over 50 percent, but no one was confident of the exact timing.  </p>
<p>The RBA can change interest rates on any day it chooses, with the first opportunity to do so coming at 9.30 a.m. (2330 GMT) on Wednesday, but some feel that the Bank may wait until it has seen June quarter inflation and wages data due on July 23 and 24 respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;There is little reason why the Reserve Bank should not move this week, but equally there are several important data releases later in July that the Reserve Bank might want to wait for,&quot; Roberts said.  </p>
<p>As well, while the RBA meets to consider a cut, its U.S. counterpart, the Federal Open Markets Committee (FOMC) will be meeting on Tuesday and Wednesday.</p>
<p>U.S. rates are seen on a tightening cycle, and although analysts do not expect a move to be made after the FOMC meeting concludes on Wednesday, they said the RBA is likely wait until Thursday just to be sure.</p>
<p>&quot;The outcome of the FOMC meeting, through its effects on interest rate differentials, will be the key to an additional easing by the RBA,&quot; Societe Generale economist Glenn Magurie said.  </p>
<p>Australian and U.S. official rates are level at 5.50 percent, and it is uncharted territory for local rates to be below those of the U.S.</p>
<p>This factor which has weighed heavily on the Australia dollar, currently trading at its lowest levels since February 1996, and is seen as one reason arguing against a cut.</p>
<p>A sustained fall in the currency could lead to inflationary pressures, just as the current low levels of inflation in part reflect the Australian dollar's appreciation last year.  </p>
<p>&quot;Whilst the activity and price data is broadly supportive of a fifth easing, the question mark is the Australian dollar,&quot; Maguire said, although others did not see the RBA as being overly concerned about the currency if the domestic economy remained soft.</p>
<p>&quot;Any sort of continued weakness in the labour market is going to cause them to ease, and I don't think that they're going to be to concerned about the currency,&quot; Axiom Funds Management economist Matthew Drennan said.  </p>
<p>&quot;One of the sectors that needs the biggest boost is probably manufacturers, and those manufacturers competing with imports particularly, and they're going to benefit from a weaker currency so I think the Reserve Bank would be quite happy to see the currency a bit softer,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
