<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697625" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taipei cautiously welcomes HK office.</title>
<headline>Taipei cautiously welcomes HK office.</headline>
<byline>Lawrence Chung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan said on Monday it would allow Hong Kong to set up a Taipei office after it reverts to rule by communist China, the island's arch rival.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no problem at all for the Special Administrative Region government to set up a representative office here after the handover,&quot; Kao Koong-lian, vice chairman and spokesman of the cabinet-level Mainland Affairs Council, told reporters.</p>
<p>Britain hands over Hong Kong to China at midnight (1600 GMT) on Monday, ending 156 years of British colonial rule.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the principle of reciprocity, we will allow Hong Kong to open the office here since we have already set up ours there,&quot; Kao said.</p>
<p>Taiwan has a visa office, an information centre and an economic office in Hong Kong, all using informal titles that do not bear the name of Taiwan's Republic of China government due to absence of formal relations.</p>
<p>Kao said his council would inaugurate the recently established Hong Kong Affairs Bureau on Tuesday to coordinate the services of its three major offices in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Kao said economic and cultural exchanges between Taiwan and Hong Kong should be able to continue after the July 1 handover.</p>
<p>&quot;Nor will there be any changes in future travel and shipping between the sides,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Taiwan and Hong Kong recently signed an agreement to allow ships to sail into each other's harbours, avoiding a sovereignty problem by agreeing vessels would enter port flying no flags.</p>
<p>Kao said it was hard to predict whether Hong Kong would be able to maintain high levels of autonomy under Chinese rule.</p>
<p>&quot;It needs further observation. But there is a popular saying about the future condition of Hong Kong -- politically pessimistic and economically optimistic,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Beijing has said it would allow Hong Kong to largely run itself under a system of local autonomy.</p>
<p>Taiwan, however, cautioned that Chinese control of Hong Kong, main conduit for the island's huge &quot;indirect&quot; investments in China, would increase Beijing's power to squeeze Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;After July 1 communist China will have more chips to play against Taiwan. If we do not have some sense of forewarning, then we are being too optimistic,&quot; William Li, who oversees Hong Kong affairs at the council, was quoted as saying by the local United Daily News.</p>
<p>Analysts have warned Beijing's strategy was to lure Taiwan into economic dependency on the mainland as part of its bid to rein in the island, considered a renegade province by China since they split in 1949 after a civil war.</p>
<p>Hong Kong is the main transit point for some US$30 billion worth of investment projects that Taiwan businesses have poured into the mainland since cross-strait political tensions began to thaw in the 1980s. The sides still have no official ties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
