<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697670" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: U.S. anti-abortionists in row at HK handover.</title>
<headline>U.S. anti-abortionists in row at HK handover.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Sprague</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. anti-abortion activists on Monday denounced Beijing's draconian family planning policy and got into a shouting match with China supporters in protests ahead of Hong Kong's midnight handover to Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a day of celebration, this is a day or grieving,&quot; shouted Randall Terry, founder of the Operation Rescue group in the United States.</p>
<p>The anti-abortionists demonstrated on Monday outside the venue where Britain will give the colony back to Beijing.</p>
<p>He decried Hong Kong's handover to what he described as history's &quot;bloodiest regime&quot;.</p>
<p>Terry plans to demonstrate on Tuesday outside Hong Kong's Legislative Council where he says he will pray for the collapse of the Chinese communist government.</p>
<p>Holding up outside the Hong Kong Convention Centre a two metre (six foot) photograph of the decapitated head of an aborted female foetus, Terry and his group of 11 U.S. Christian ministers blasted Beijing's one-child policy.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the fruit of Deng Xiaoping,&quot; he said, criticising the late Chinese leader who is credited with China's economic revival. &quot;He is the one who initiated the one-child policy. He is a murderer who is rotting in hell.&quot;</p>
<p>Terry's claims enraged Bernard Wijedoru, a Hong Kong District Affairs Adviser to Beijing and a 20-year-long resident of the territory, who said he was walking by after picking up his invitation to one of the day's many festivities.</p>
<p>&quot;Why do you come here? What right do you have? This is an important event for Hong Kong, the day colonialism is ending,&quot; Wijedoru shouted back at Terry. &quot;You are a bloody coolie who wants to break up China.&quot;</p>
<p>Terry in turn accused Wijedoru of taking blood money and predicted that God would bring down China's communist rule.</p>
<p>Wijedoru's words also enraged a passing Hong Kong Chinese who accused the Sri Lankan-born man of having no right to talk about Chinese.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
