<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697644" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Headlines - June 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Headlines - June 30.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Hong Kong press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Front page coverage in all papers was dominated by the Hong Kong handover preparations.</p>
<p>-- APPLE DAILY -- Research showed a sudden drop in confidence towards the &quot;one country, two systems&quot; policy, because some people were worried about Hong Kong's economic future and suspected that freedom would be restricted. The daily said many people were getting depressed and nervous as the handover became a reality.</p>
<p>-- SING TAO -- More than 10,000 people in the New Territories had signed up to take part in activities welcoming the People's Liberation Army soldiers tomorrow morning. On top of that, thousands of villagers have spontaneously organised &quot;welcome teams&quot; to meet the Hong Kong garrison.</p>
<p>-- MING PO -- When rehearsing their swearing-in yesterday, many government officials' poor Mandarin made people laugh. Executive Councillors S.Y. Chung was the worst, while Chief Secretary Anson Chan was most fluent despite a Shanghai accent.</p>
<p>-- APPLE DAILY -- Shenzhen Public Security Bureau received information that two Xinjiang separatist had entered Shenzhen, planning to place bombs, possibly at the railway station during the handover. British military intelligence sources had also reported that the IRA was planning to create trouble in Hong Kong to get the world's attention.</p>
<p>-- TA KUNG PAO -- The pro-Beijing daily said about 10,000 people in China's northeastern city of Harbin participated in a marathon race, led by Olympic champion Wang Junxia, on Sunday to celebrate the Hong Kong handover.</p>
<p>-- ECONOMIC JOURNAL -- After operating Renminbi business for three months, most foreign Banks in Shanghai think Renminbi business will have a bright prospect and plan to invest more in Renminbi transactions. But the head of Hongkong Bank's Shanghai branch says Chinese banks will continue to play dominant roles in Renminbi business.</p>
<p>-- ECONOMIC JOURNAL -- Beijing has decided to carry out a large-scale reorganisation of its publishing business. All the internally distributed publications will be closed down. The registration for new newspapers has stopped since early last year. Up to now, there are 2,202 registered newspapers, plus more than 6,400 internally distributed ones.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- The Hong Kong stock exchange has been the scene of some of the most frenetic privatisation of state-owned assets seen anywhere in the past few months. But brokers said the handover rally had not quite played inself out.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG STANDARD -- Despite a spate of anti-China protests, including an overnight &quot;silent sit in&quot; launched on Sunday to denounce the provisional legislature, police expected a peaceful day in Hong Kong on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
