<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697976" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Socialists claim Albania win, but few results in.</title>
<headline>Socialists claim Albania win, but few results in.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's Socialist Party claimed victory over President Sali Berisha's Democrats in a general election seen as key to ending months of violence, but with few results declared it was too early to call the outcome.</p>
<p>Socialist leader Fatos Nano, released from jail in March three years after what was widely considered a suspect trial, told reporters his party's data showed it had won 60 of 115 seats contested under majority voting.</p>
<p>With expectations of gaining at least half the remaining 40 seats shared out under a proportional system, Nano said the Socialists and allied leftist parties would hold a two-thirds majority in parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;A centre-left coalition will control two-thirds of the new parliament for sure,&quot; Nano said amid jubilation at his party's headquarters in central Tirana.</p>
<p>Officials of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) and the Council of Europe, who assisted Albanian authorities in organising the election, appeared happy with the way polling had been conducted.</p>
<p>It was impossible to gauge quickly how the Balkan nation of 3.4 million had voted. The country has primitive communications, few computers and no tradition of exit polling.</p>
<p>But the looks on the faces of party supporters may have given a hint. Democrats at their party's offices in Tirana appeared glum while their Socialist rivals hugged each other and beamed widely.</p>
<p>Democrat secretary-general Genc Pollo said it was far too early for Nano to claim a victory, but acknowledged that the Democrats might not have won as many seats as they had hoped.</p>
<p>&quot;We are doing less well than we thought but we are still waiting for the results,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Whatever the outcome, any new government has an uphill task to restore order in swathes of southern Albania which remain in the grip of gangs, criminal cliques and local mafia warlords.</p>
<p>Senior OSCE representative Catherine Lalumiere and OSCE and Council of Europe officials toured Tirana and flew by helicopter to four regions to hear accounts of the voting from some of the 500 international observers and Albanian electoral officials.</p>
<p>Observers were escorted by some of the 7,000 soldiers of a multinational protection force deployed in Albania in April after weeks of violence, looting and killings sparked by the collapse of pyramid investment schemes. Some 1,500 people have been killed in the violence in the Balkan state.</p>
<p>&quot;The procedures, from what we have seen and heard, were satisfactory and the turnout very good, up to 80 percent in some areas,&quot; said Lalumiere.</p>
<p>Isolated incidents across the country claimed at least one life, an electoral official killed near the southern town of Fier.</p>
<p>Problems were also reported with electoral registers and delivery of ballot papers in outlying areas, but the election had none of the voter intimidation and ballot stuffing which marred last year's election.</p>
<p>Lalumiere was due to give an early idea of observers' findings at a news conference at 3 p.m. (1300 GMT) on Monday.</p>
<p>The OSCE's special envoy to Albania, Franz Vranitzky, who helped broker a deal among the country's political parties in March that led to the elections, was due back in Tirana on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The head of the Central Electoral Commission, Kristaq Kume, said it appeared more than 60 percent of the electorate had voted, which he considered an acceptable showing.</p>
<p>The election was held 13 months after Albania's third multi-party polls since communism was toppled in 1990. Those polls were judged by the international community to be seriously flawed. The Democrats won almost all the seats in parliament.</p>
<p>Berisha has held power since 1992 and was re-elected by parliament to a new five-year term the day after a state of emergency was declared on March 2. He insists he will respect the results of the election but has said he would be unable to &quot;cohabit&quot; with a leftist administration.</p>
<p>Nano said he would find it difficult to work with Berisha and suggested on Sunday night that with the result he expected the president should quit.</p>
<p>If a leftist alliance wins a two-thirds majority, it would have the power to bring in a new constitution and could effectively remove the head of state by parliamentary vote.</p>
<p>Albanians were also asked on Sunday to vote in a referendum on whether to restore a monarchy which ruled from 1928 to 1939. Rumours abounded that exiled King Leka had done better than expected. If Albanians reject the republic, arguments over changing the head of state become academic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
