<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="697917" id="root" date="1997-06-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Tax changes to cost German 13.7 bln DM in 98 - BDI.</title>
<headline>Tax changes to cost German 13.7 bln DM in 98 - BDI.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Last-minute changes made to German tax reforms would cost companies an extra 13.7 billion marks next year, the head of the country's powerful industry lobby said in an interview published on Monday.</p>
<p>Hans-Olaf Henkel, head of the Federation of German Industry (BDI), told the Handelsblatt daily that amendments adopted by the lower house of parliament last week meant that businesses could no longer support government tax policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The tax reform in its current form is not acceptable to German industry,&quot; Henkel told the financial daily.</p>
<p>Henkel said businesses had supported Finance Minister Theo Waigel's original plan to cut income and corporate taxes by around 30 billion marks by 1999 -- even though most of the net cuts would have benefit wage earners and not companies.</p>
<p>But new limits on tax writeoffs against losses would hit the ability of companies to ride out recession, and also deter investment.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors would think twice about investing in Germany if they could not fully offset startup losses,&quot; Henkel said.</p>
<p>Waigel's tax reform bills face certain defeat next week in the upper house of parliament, which is controlled by the opposition Social Democrats (SPD).</p>
<p>Henkel urged the Bonn coalition and the SPD to strike a compromise deal in subsequent parliamentary mediation. &quot;More important than any ideological debate is a reform signal to deal with the pressing jobless situation in Germany,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097 150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-06-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
