<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69804" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kmart bonds poised for recovery - Salomon.</title>
<headline>Kmart bonds poised for recovery - Salomon.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kmart Corp debt should tighten by 40 or 50 basis points in the short-term as a result of improvements in sales and profit margins, according to Salomon Brothers analysts David Markus and Robert Rahman.</p>
<p>A recovery should occur based on a combination of new-found strengths, including the &quot;dramatic&quot; cost reduction of $238 million for the first half of 1996, the analysts said in a recent research report.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that (Kmart) should easily achieve its target of reducing selling, general and administrative expense by $450 million to $500 million,&quot; the analysts said.</p>
<p>The debt is poised to tighten beyond the forecast 40 to 50 basis points as sales and margins improve, they said.</p>
<p>Savings are being achieved through Kmart's elimination of underperforming stores, the sale of its auto service department, increased labor efficiency, better use of advertising and cuts in overhead expenses, they said.</p>
<p>Other positives include increased marketing of frequently purchased consumables and a strong new management team led by Chairman/Chief Executive Officer Floyd Hall and Chief Operating Officer Warren Flick, they said.</p>
<p>For all their confidence, however, Markus and Rahman said Kmart's failure to successfully grow sales are reduce SG&amp;A expenses will limit potential improvement. They also noted the company's Builders Square stores continue to depress margins.</p>
<p>--U.S. corporate bond unit, 212-859-1672</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
