<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698036" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco trade groups win ruling in Florida's suit.</title>
<headline>Tobacco trade groups win ruling in Florida's suit.</headline>
<dateline>WEST PALM BEACH, Florida 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The trial judge in Florida's Medicaid lawsuit against the tobacco industry on Tuesday narrowed the counts against two tobacco trade organizations in the $1 billion case.</p>
<p>Palm Beach County Circuit Court Judge Harold Cohen ruled that neither the Council for Tobacco Research-USA Inc nor the Tobacco Institute Inc would be liable for paying any part of the health-care costs claimed by the state of Florida.</p>
<p>He said neither was liable because they did not manufacture or distribute cigarettes.  </p>
<p>But Cohen refused to dismiss the trade groups from other counts alleging the industry conspired to hide the dangers of smoking through false advertising and false statements to journalists and Congress.</p>
<p>Both trade groups were formed in the 1950s.</p>
<p>The Tobacco Institute spoke on behalf of the tobacco industry in the decades-long debate over smoking, while the research body funded medical and scientific investigations of tobacco use. Florida claims both deceived the public.</p>
<p>Cohen also retained the right to break up the organizations if they should be found to have participated in the conspiracy alleged by the state of Florida.</p>
<p>Michael Klugman, an attorney for the tobacco research group, said not a single document had been produced to show the trade organizations had conspired with the tobacco companies.</p>
<p>Another tobacco lawyer said the conspiracy charges against the trade groups may be dismissed before the scheduled start of the trial on August 4.</p>
<p>The state is seeking to recover public funds spent on treating ailments linked to tobacco use.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WEST PALM BEACH, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
