<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698069" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US blue chips end higher, boosted by bond rally.</title>
<headline>US blue chips end higher, boosted by bond rally.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dow industrials finished higher on Tuesday, powered by a strong performance in the bond market after fresh evidence the U.S. economy continues to grow at a moderate pace.</p>
<p>The Dow rose 50 points to close unofficially at 7722, paced by financial stocks J.P. Morgan &amp; Co Inc, which rose 3-1/8 to 107-1/2, and Travelers Group Inc, which gained 1-5/8 to 64-11/16.</p>
<p>Early in the session, stocks and bonds got a boost from a key monthly report on U.S. manufacturing activity.  </p>
<p>The new information came from the National Association of Purchasing Management's (NAPM) monthly survey, which showed an increase in U.S. manufacturing activity in June, though at a slower pace than economists had expected.</p>
<p>The report was soothing after Monday's stronger- than-expected regional manufacturing surveys, which prompted last-minute jitters over the Federal Reserve's interest rate policy meeting, which began Tuesday and ends on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think anybody's scared at this point,&quot; said Arnie Owen, managing director of capital markets at Cruttenden Roth. &quot;I certainly don't think anyone sees any inflation out there.&quot;  </p>
<p>Bonds shot higher after the report, sending the yield on the benchmark 30-year U.S. Treasury down five basis points to 6.74 percent, and stocks quickly followed, led by interest rate-sensitive sectors such as finance and transportation.</p>
<p>Airlines were among the strongest performers, with Delta Air Lines Inc rising 1-13/16 to 84-7/16 and Southwest Airlines Co leaping 1-5/8 to 27-1/2.</p>
<p>Early in the day, Southwest was cited on Lehman Brothers' annual list of 10 &quot;uncommon values,&quot; a portfolio of stocks the firm believes will outperform the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index over the next 12 months.  </p>
<p>While Wall Street is nearly unanimous in expecting the Fed will leave interest rates steady, it still faces a critical test in the monthly data on U.S. payrolls and wages. The report is due out Thursday, instead of its traditional Friday release, because of the Independence Day-shortened work week.</p>
<p>Between the employment figures and the Fed meeting, analysts said market action could be quite contained over the next session.</p>
<p>&quot;In the past we've hesitated before employment reports and before Fed meetings and this week we have both,&quot; said Gregory Nie, technical analyst at EVEREN Securities.  </p>
<p>Among individual issues, Office Depot Inc tumbled 3-13/16 to 15-5/8 in the first trading since Monday's court ruling blocking the company's planned merger with Staples Inc.</p>
<p>Shares in Staples, generally considered to be the stronger of the two office-supply retailers by analysts, rose 1-1/16 to 24-5/16.</p>
<p>Boeing Co gained one point to 54-1/16 after the company won unconditional approval from U.S. regulators for its merger with McDonnell Douglas Corp. McDonnell Douglas rose 1-3/16 to 69-11/16.  </p>
<p>Pierce Leahy Corp jumped 5-9/16 to 23-9/16 in its New York Stock Exchange debut. Pierce Leahy, based in King of Prussia, Pennsylvania, manages archived records including paper records, microfilm and video tapes.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 rose 5.89 ponts to 891.03.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite fell 3.82 points to 1438.25.</p>
<p>((-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
