<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698104" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMM currency futures close mixed.</title>
<headline>IMM currency futures close mixed.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMM currency futures closed mixed, as the summer doldrums set into the forex market amid continued comments on European monetary union from European officials, traders said.</p>
<p>A senior associate of German Chancellor Helmut Kohl said France and Germany must meet soon to clear up differences on the planned single European currency and economic policy.</p>
<p>His comments underscored recent debates within Kohl's ruling alliance and kept mark buyers from becoming too enthusiastic, they said. September marks rose to $0.5782 in reaction to weaker than expected U.S. economic data.  </p>
<p>The U.S. June National Association of Purchasing Management index and U.S. May construction spending numbers were lower than expected.</p>
<p>The data solidified expectations that the Federal Open Market Committee will leave interest rates unchanged at its two-day meeting this week.</p>
<p>U.S. Deputy Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers said there was no inflation in sight despite a strong U.S. economy.</p>
<p>Summers also said the dollar was &quot;in a very strong position&quot; and that financial markets would be fine if the United States maintained solid fundamentals.  </p>
<p>September marks dipped to $0.5753, but held above the contract low set overnight at $0.5750.</p>
<p>September sterling held losses on liquidation ahead of the U.K. budget announcement on July 2, while September Swiss francs edged near the four-month low of $0.6868.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Mexican peso futures continued to rally, contrary to most trade expectations for declines ahead of Mexico's July 6 mid-term elections. However, profit-taking was nowhere to be found as September pesos rose to $0.122525.  </p>
<p>At the end of pit trade, September yen was off $0.000027 at $0.008799, marks were down $0.0009 at $0.5756, Swiss francs fell $0.0023 to $0.6885, sterling lost $0.0050 at $1.6556, Canadian dollars were up $0.0008 at $0.7284, Australian dollars were $0.0020 lower at $0.7522 and Mexican pesos were up $0.000475 at $0.122475. ((Chicago Derivatives desk 312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
