<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698252" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: CYCLING-TOUR DE FRANCE CURIOSITIES.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-TOUR DE FRANCE CURIOSITIES.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A few curious facts and figures from the Tour de France cycle race which starts in Rouen on Saturday:</p>
<p>Eugene Christophe of France was the first rider to wear the race leader's yellow jersey when it was introduced in 1919. He rode his first Tour in 1906 and his eighth and last in 1925.</p>
<p>Christophe rode into Tour folklore in 1913 when he walked 14 kilometres from the summit of the Tourmalet mountain in the Pyrenees after breaking the front forks of his bike.</p>
<p>At the smithy of St Marie de Campan he repaired his machine, watched by a Tour official who penalised him three minutes for allowing outside help -- a young boy pumped the forge bellows.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Only four men have won the Tour de France five times. Spain's Miguel Indurain was the first to achieve it in consecutive years, winning in 1991, 92, 93, 94 and 95.</p>
<p>The others were Bernard Hinault of France in 1978, 79, 81, 82 and 85, Eddy Merckx of Belgium in 1969, 70, 71, 72 and 74, and the late Jacques Anquetil of France in 1957, 61, 62, 63 and 64.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Only four men have worn the yellow jersey from start to finish. Ottavio Bottechia (Italy) in 1924, Nicolas Frantz (Luxembourg) in 1928, Romain Maes (Belgium) in 1936 and Anquetil in 1961.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>France's Pelissier brothers, Henri (1923), Francis (1927) and Charles (1930) all wore the yellow jersey, but only Henri finished the Tour as winner.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Biggest winning margin -- two hours and 49 minutes by Maurice Garin of France in 1903. Smallest margin -- eight seconds by Greg LeMond of the United States in 1989.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Most stage wins: Eddy Merckx (Belgium) 34.</p>
<p>Most stage wins in one Tour: 8 by Charles Pelissier in 1930, Merckx in 1970 and 74 and Freddy Maertens (Belgium) in 1976.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Longest Tour de France: 5,745 kms (1926). The Belgian winner, Lucien Buysse, completed it in 238 hours and 44 minutes, an hour and 22 minutes clear of the runner-up.</p>
<p>Longest stage: 482 kms from Les Sables d'Olonne to Bayonne. The first winner of this stage was Jean Alavoine in 1919.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Most Tours completed: Joop Zoetemelk of the Netherlands finished 16 times, winning the Tour once and placing second a further six times.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>In 1914 the last rider, Henri Leclerc, finished more than 99 hours behind the winner, Philippe Thys of Belgium, after 15 stages covering 5,287 kms.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>More than 3,500 people accompany the Tour each year. Riders and back-up crews total 500. There are 400 organisation workers and 800 in the publicity caravan.</p>
<p>The media accounts for a further 1,800 including representatives of some 50 television channels from around the globe.</p>
<p>The Tour's 1,500 vehicles range from motor cycles to articulated mobile offices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
