<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698371" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY UNION-Injuries cloud teams for Bledisloe Cup.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-Injuries cloud teams for Bledisloe Cup.</headline>
<text>
<p>CHRISTCHURCH, July 2 - The composition of the starting sides for Saturday's Bledisloe Cup rugby test between the All Blacks and the Wallabies at Lancaster Park was still clouded by injury problems on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Canterbury's Andrew Mehrtens was withdrawn from the All Black training session at the half-way mark yesterday. Coach John Hart said it was to avoid aggravating his hamstring injury.</p>
<p>Mehrtens, who missed the two tests against Argentina, limped as the backs practised, and was pulled off by the All Blacks' medical team for the fear of fatigue worsening the damage.  </p>
<p>Aucklander Carlos Spencer took Mehrtens' place at first five-eighth for the remainder of the practice session.</p>
<p>Meanwhile in Brisbane, Wallaby coach Greg Smith kept quiet about who would be in his starting 15.</p>
<p>He wouldn't say when he would name his team though it appeared at training he had made his choice.</p>
<p>At least one change will be made from the team that beat France in the second test last Saturday. ACT lock David Giffen broke his foot and has been replaced in the squad by Queensland's Garrick Morgan.  </p>
<p>Smith maintained his expanded squad of 24 to provide expected cover for some injuries, but yesterday's training session suggested he may effect two further changes to his starting side.</p>
<p>Former Auckland lock/flanker Daniel Manu could be fitted into blindside flanker in place of ACT captain Brett Robinson to add beef and power to the pack.</p>
<p>Centre Jason Little was still being touted to play by Smith, though the player gave himself just 30 percent chance of pulling on his boots at Christchurch's Lancaster Park for the Bledisloe Cup.  </p>
<p>&quot;Not good,&quot; he said of his chances of playing with a serious hip injury after skipping yesterday's training.</p>
<p>The talented midfield back will travel with the team to Christchurch today, though Daniel Herbert is strongly tipped to wear the No 13 jersey opposite Frank Bunce on Saturday.</p>
<p>Another player under the cloud since the weekend was openside flanker David Wilson, whose hip and rib injury had mended enough by yesterday to allow him some pack-down time with his forwards.</p>
<p>&quot;They're a bit like the All Blacks,&quot; Hart said of the Australians having adequate cover for all positions.  </p>
<p>Manu sat out the two tests against France with a shoulder problem but he showed little sign of that yesterday, team manager John McKay said.</p>
<p>&quot;He is an option at this stage, we were just looking at combinations,&quot; McKay said.</p>
<p>Manu, with New Zealand experience, has always performed strongly against New Zealand teams and that hasn't escaped Smith's attention.</p>
<p>He was the best Wallaby forward despite their 43-6 defeat in last year's corresponding match at Athletic Park.  </p>
<p>Mehrtens, forced out of the two tests against Argentina by the hamstring that cut short his test against Fiji three weeks ago, said he felt a slight twinge at training yesterday.</p>
<p>&quot;They (All Blacks medical team) thought I shouldn't force it too much right now, I've still got a couple of days,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hart had said he would not risk injuries as the season was long and hard.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not overly confident,&quot; he replied when asked if Mehrtens would have recovered fully by Saturday.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think we have to be realistic that he might not come right. I have to wait and get the view of the medical staff as to what is the most appropriate thing to do.</p>
<p>&quot;But Carlos has been told quite clearly right from last Sunday that there was a possibility the injury might not come right. He's in test mode anyway.&quot;</p>
<p>Hart said his major concern was the Wallabies ideal buildup for the match in their two tests against France whereas his team were untested by Argentina and Fiji.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Australians will be at a different level than we've been in this year, so that's a bit of a risk for us. We thought Argentina were a lot better than they were. I've been bitterly disappointed with what they offered.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
