<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698419" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African farmers, miners complain about rain.</title>
<headline>S.African farmers, miners complain about rain.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Abnormal weather in South Africa has flooded a desert, blocked roads with snow and delayed harvesting of maize crops, government and agriculture officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Japie Grobler, chairman of the National Association of Maize Producers (NAMPO), told reporters rain and snow in the eastern Free State in recent days would further delay harvesting of maize by up to two weeks and would force farmers to postpone planting winter wheat.</p>
<p>&quot;The maize crop doesn't dry in this weather. The sun is shining today, but we need wind to dry the crop. We're hoping for some dry air,&quot; Grobler said.</p>
<p>He said artificial drying facilities were running at 100 percent capacity but could not meet demand and some exporters were getting anxious at the delay in getting the crop out of the fields.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a big problem. In Reitz and Bethlehem, wheat farmers say it will be three to four weeks before they can get into their fields to plant.&quot;</p>
<p>Maize farmers in North West province also reported excessive moisture in their crop, Grobler said.</p>
<p>Piet Grobler, marketing manager at agricultural co-operative Sentraal Oos based in the Bethlehem area, told Reuters that more snowfalls and wet weather were forecast for later this week.</p>
<p>&quot;This will delay the harvest more,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Namakwaland semi-desert region of Northern Cape province had some of its heaviest rains since 1925, with one area recording in one week the amount of rain it received in an average year.</p>
<p>Floods washed away roads near the town of Springbok, isolating the 600 people of a hamlet called Kommagas, local government officials said. Air force helicopters ferried food to the town.</p>
<p>The Kleinzee diamond mine on the Namakwaland Atlantic coast, owned by De Beers Consolidated, has lost two days of production because of the floods, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The areas affected treat an average of 375,000 tonnes of ore a month.</p>
<p>In KwaZulu-Natal province, snow blocked some roads in mountainous areas, police said. --Cape Town newsroom +2721 252238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
