<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698469" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Damaged Mir stable, spacewalk outside considered.</title>
<headline>Damaged Mir stable, spacewalk outside considered.</headline>
<byline>Viktor Anoshkin</byline>
<dateline>KOROLYOV, Russia 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's space station Mir, damaged last week in a docking accident, is in stable condition and may undergo an external inspection as well as one inside the vessel, Mission Control said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We can draw only one conclusion as of today -- the situation on Mir is stable,&quot; deputy flight director Viktor Blagov told a news briefing in the control centre outside Moscow.</p>
<p>He said the crew had fully recovered from the stress that followed the June 25 collision. &quot;They are working as planned, or even more. They are sleeping normally,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A control centre official in charge of medical issues, Igor Goncharov, said the crew of two Russians and one American had been recommended to drink no less than two litres of water a day and to eat dairy products as much as possible.</p>
<p>The Spektr scientific module, which was docked with Mir, was holed during a collision with an unmanned cargo craft. Mission control on Monday gave the Mir crew instructions for a daring spacewalk inside the station to restore power supply from the damaged module.</p>
<p>Blagov said tests had shown that the Progress craft had been overloaded at the time of the collision but added that this would not have caused the accident.</p>
<p>&quot;The real reasons (for the collision) are not known yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Blagov singled out American Michael Foale for praise, saying the British-born cosmonaut had played an active part in closing the hatch after the collision in dangerous circumstances.</p>
<p>&quot;We are beginning crew training for entering the Spektr module,&quot; Blagov said, adding that the provisional date for entering Spektr was set at July 11. &quot;We have a reserve date as well -- July 14.&quot;</p>
<p>Blagov said the possibility of the crew leaving the station to conduct an external inspection was also under consideration. He said Mission Control was unsure about the exact location of the hole, which could be concealed by equipment.</p>
<p>&quot;Moving equipment in a narrow module wearing spacesuits is pretty dangerous. On the other hand we may find the place of de-hermetisation from the outside. Cosmonauts could do that during their scheduled spacewalks.&quot;</p>
<p>It was not clear whether he meant the current Mir crew or a fresh one, due to replace it in August. Blagov also said the crew would receive special hoses for cooling their spacesuits while in the Spektr.</p>
<p>The cargo, including electric cables, connections and a &quot;hermoplate&quot;, has been loaded onto a new Progress freighter, which is due to be launched on July 5. Blagov said the time of the launch was set at 8.11 Moscow time (0411 GMT).</p>
<p>Progress will reach Mir two days later.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KOROLYOV, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
