<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698584" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania's king says robbed of referendum win.</title>
<headline>Albania's king says robbed of referendum win.</headline>
<byline>Ron Popeski</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's self-proclaimed king said on Tuesday his compatriots had voted to restore the monarchy in a referendum held alongside general elections but that their will had been denied by mass fraud.</p>
<p>Leka I told a boisterous news conference that data compiled by monarchists showed that between 54 to 66 percent of Albanian voters had favoured restoring the monarchy in Sunday's vote. He said the Socialist Party, apparently headed for victory in the election, was behind widespread intimidation and cheating.</p>
<p>&quot;We needed 50 percent and that achievement is in danger of being destroyed. This is the free will of the nation I am concerned about, not myself,&quot; Leka said.</p>
<p>&quot;This situation was everywhere...We have sufficient evidence to prove that the monarchy has won the referendum. And believe me, (electoral officials) will accept our evidence. It's not our evidence, it's theirs. We didn't manufacture it.&quot;</p>
<p>Official results have yet to be published, but Socialist Party tallies give the monarchists 20 to 30 percent. The king said that, regardless of irregularities, as a democrat he would &quot;accept the result and the verdict of the people&quot;.</p>
<p>Leka, who stands 2.04 metres (six feet 10 inches), fled Albania in 1939 ahead of an invasion by Italian Fascist troops when he was less than a week old. He has since lived in Spain, Britain and most recently in South Africa.</p>
<p>He returned to Albania in April after nearly 60 years in exile and campaigned extensively, but drew only small crowds, including 3,000 at a closing rally last week in Tirana.</p>
<p>He was shown frequently on television addressing informal meetings seated on the ground. Slick publicity spots suggested Albania's dilapidated capital might one day look like other European cities with royal palaces, like London or Madrid.</p>
<p>The king pledged to be a force above politics and restore order within three months of reclaiming his crown.</p>
<p>He is also committed, at least publicly, to restoring &quot;ethnic Albania&quot; -- including Kosovo in former Yugoslavia, where ethnic Albanians outnumber Serbs nine to one, and parts of northern Greece.</p>
<p>His remarks to journalists were repeatedly interrupted by cheering supporters denouncing the Socialists and accusing their leader Fatos Nano of being a Greek spy.</p>
<p>He said 200,000 ballots for the referendum had gone missing and others were burned. Armed gangs had terrorised officials at polling stations and voting had been disrupted by gunbattles.</p>
<p>He said President Sali Berisha's tacit acceptance of the election outcome, by admitting the defeat for his Democratic Party, was irrelevant.</p>
<p>Equally irrelevant were assurances by the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) that the vote had been &quot;adequate and acceptable&quot; as more than 500 international observers had paid little attention to the referendum.</p>
<p>&quot;The OSCE took no account of the referendum,&quot; he said. &quot;They told me they were here only to look after the election.&quot;</p>
<p>Berisha agreed to the referendum in March under an accord with 10 parties to form a unity government and hold early elections to end unrest which killed more than 1,500 people.</p>
<p>Monarchists began proclaiming victory soon after polls closed and said they had scored particularly well in the north, home to most of Albania's Roman Catholics. A 'yes' vote, they said, would immediately restore the 1928 royalist constitution.</p>
<p>Nano denounced Berisha as a dictator during the campaign and said it was up to Albanians to choose their form of government, including an &quot;Anglo-Saxon&quot; model if they wished. But he believed voters would reject the monarchy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
