<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698651" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: FEATURE - Yeltsin has vast constitutional powers in Russia.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Yeltsin has vast constitutional powers in Russia.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-06-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin, who marks the first anniversary of his re-election on Thursday, has a tailor-made constitution which gives him much more authority than the other branches of power.</p>
<p>The president is the formal head of state and commander-in-chief of the armed forces, controls the government, names most top officials and has the last word in most state affairs. He can be legally ousted only with great difficulty.</p>
<p>The consitution was approved in a national referendum in December 1993, just two months after Yeltsin sent tanks and troops to quell a hardline revolt in Moscow which ended a two-year power struggle with the Soviet-era parliament.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who inspired the concept of the new constitution, deliberately made it hard for the president's powers to be challenged by parliament or any other branch of power.</p>
<p>Under the constitution, the president must be at least 35 and a resident of Russia for at least 10 years. He can occupy the post for two four-year terms at the most.</p>
<p>The president names the prime minister, who must then be confirmed by the State Duma lower house of parliament, and also names all other ministers. He can chair government meetings, which in effect gives him control of the cabinet.</p>
<p>The president also has the right to dismiss the prime minister and the government.</p>
<p>The president has the right to issue decrees which do not contradict the constitution. With many vital laws still not adopted, these powers enable him to bypass parliament on some important decisions.</p>
<p>The president signs into law all legislation passed by the Duma and the Federation Council upper house. He can veto laws and the veto can be overrun only by a two-thirds majority in each chamber.</p>
<p>Under the constitution, the president heads the armed forces and names all top military officials. He has the power to declare a state of emergency in all or part of the country.</p>
<p>He also names all top judicial officials and the prosecutor general, who must later be approved by parliament.</p>
<p>The president can dissolve the Duma if it refuses three times to back his candidate for prime minister or if it votes no-confidence in the government. A parliamentary election must then be held within three months.</p>
<p>The president cannot dissolve the Duma in the first 12 months after it has been elected.</p>
<p>The parliament has little means of exerting real influence on the president apart from impeaching him. This can be done if parliament proves in court that he has committed high treason or another serious crime.</p>
<p>But the complicated impeachment procedure makes it extremely difficult to carry out.</p>
<p>The president can also be replaced if he resigns of his own accord or if his health prevents him carrying out his duties. But the latter clause is not spelled out in the constitution.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's aides have said a provision stating that the president is the guarantor of the constitution gives the Kremlin leader even stronger powers to bypass the law if he believes the country's stability is under threat.</p>
<p>Yeltsin violated the letter of the law when he dissolved the Soviet-era parliament in September 1993. But he later argued that the supreme interests of democracy and his duties as the guarantor of the constitution made such a step unavoidable.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
