<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698789" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>Australia: INSIGHT-Aussie on a knife edge for rate verdict.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT-Aussie on a knife edge for rate verdict.</headline>
<text>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>AUS$ S/Term range  *Support *Restnce *RSI-14 *MA-10  *MA-20</p>
<p>US$ *0.7400/0.7580 *0.7500  *0.7540  *43.16  *0.7505 *0.7527</p>
<p>--------------VIEWS FROM THE MARKET - July 2 -------------------</p>
<p>*Offshore range roughly US$0.7505/7540</p>
<p>*AUD lost more of its rally offshore to lapse to $0.7505 as repeated upside attempts were frustrated by offers at $0.7540 *Finely balanced as market waits to see if the RBA will ease this morning, first opportuntiy after Tuesday's board meeting</p>
<p>*Some think RBA will hold until Thursday others see no cut at all. Retail trade data today may help clarify the outlook  </p>
<p>By 0815 am (2215 GMT) the local dollar had inched back to US$0.7510/15 from US$0.7525/30 late here Tuesday but remained well up on Monday's late US$0.7453/58.</p>
<p>Traders said the currency had made a stab at the upside overnight but was smothered by fresh offers at US$0.7540, which looked to be solidifying as good resistance now. Support had been found at US$0.7505 with the key bulwark put at Monday's US$0.7440 low.</p>
<p>The latter will surely be seen again if the RBA does decide to ease at its 9.30 am (2330 GMT) money market operation, the usual window for a policy move.  </p>
<p>A half point cut would take official cash rates below their U.S. equivalent for the first time since financial makrets here were liberalised in 1983.</p>
<p>Short term money rates began to enter this unfamiliar territory more than a month ago after the RBA surprised with its May 23 cut and dire employment and retail sales data suggested the economy was far more vulnerable than anyone had thought.</p>
<p>The dollar had fallen all the way from 78 cents as a result and analysts saw a risk of reaching 73 cents, last year's trough, should it ease for a fifth time, although much depended on whether the market perceived this as the last of the cycle.  </p>
<p>If the market was confident the year-long easing cycle had truly ended the dollar could actually rally over the next few months. However, dealers had been burned by false dawns before, particularly in February and March when the dollar rallied 4-1/2 cents to an 80 cent peak only to turn tail when economic reality fell short of bullish expectations.</p>
<p>Equally, retail sales data for May should show if the market was right to have been so bearish in recent weeks. Analysts look for a bounce of around 2.0 percent after April's shock 1.7 percent fall and anything less than 1.0 percent would be considered soft. -- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
