<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698886" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Pacific Can sees construction profits down.</title>
<headline>Pacific Can sees construction profits down.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pacific Can Investment Holdings Ltd said on Tuesday it expected profits from its construction division to fall further.</p>
<p>&quot;Although sales of ready-mix concrete is expected to increase, the profit of this division is expected to decline because of lower margins and higher depreciation charges,&quot; Pacific Can said in a note with its first-half financial results.</p>
<p>Construction revenues grew 27.8 percent year on year to Singapore $20.9 million in the six months to March 31, 1997 against S$16.3 million previously.  </p>
<p>The division's pre-tax loss in the period narrowed to S$1.1 million against S$2.3 million previously.</p>
<p>The outlook was similarly pessimistic for can operations the note added, with a joint venture operation in Malaysia not expected to contribute positively in the current business year and the outlook for can making in China remaining poor.</p>
<p>&quot;The group does not expect positive contributions from its joint venture in Malaysia in the current financial year,&quot; it said, attributing the weakness to start up costs and low market penetration.  </p>
<p>Pacific Can earlier reported an interim net loss of S$5.7 million, a slight improvement on the previous period's S$6.9 million deficit.</p>
<p>It said lower revenues and provisions for anticipated losses on certain contracts and doubtful debts were responsible for the interim loss.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703011)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
