<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698869" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korea's metals trade surge reasons queried.</title>
<headline>South Korea's metals trade surge reasons queried.</headline>
<byline>Jae Hur</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A surge in South Korea's base metal futures and options trade this year was due to brokers transferring positions and synthetic hedging strategies by major traders, the finance ministry said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But domestic traders and brokers cast doubts on the official explanation for the explosion in futures and options volume and said a more plausible explanation was heavy trading by a single company, most probably LG Metals Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;The position give-up between brokers could be a reason for the rise, but overtrade by one major company, probably LG Metals, is the main reason,&quot; said a dealer with a major trading house, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>South Korea's base metal futures and options trade soared to 485,558 lots in the first four months of this year from 43,293 lots in the same period a year ago, according to data from the Korea Futures Association.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we understand, transferring positions among brokers by major local traders and more complicated hedging strategies which combine futures and options were the main reasons behind the rising metal futures turnover,&quot; said Lee Jong-gap, a director in the finance market division of the finance ministry.</p>
<p>Asked whether the ministry had been investigating LG Metals, which has been rumoured to be facing huge losses after a rally in copper, Lee said &quot;the government does not investigate an individual company's futures operations and activities.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If one company has losses from its futures trade, the company has to assume all responsibility,&quot; Lee added.</p>
<p>On Monday, June 23, the ministry summoned several Korean metal brokers to probe overseas futures trading by domestic companies following the sharp increase in base metal futures and options trade through the London Metal Exchange (LME).</p>
<p>On June 24, the day following the news, the daily trading volume in LG Metals stock jumped to 310,000 shares, closing up 100 won at 16,200.</p>
<p>This compares with a trading volume of 73,370 shares on Tuesday when LG Metals closed up 400 won at 16,300.</p>
<p>Normal daily trading volume in the stock is between 50,000 to 60,000 shares.</p>
<p>LG Metals spokesman Lee In-soo told Reuters on Tuesday the company had a &quot;tight management system&quot; for its futures operations and was closely monitoring its positions.</p>
<p>&quot;The rumours that we are facing huge options-related losses on the LME are groundless,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Lee said the metals market had &quot;no need to worry&quot; about LG Metals open LME metal options positions, but he declined to comment on the rumours.</p>
<p>Trade sources in Seoul said the ministry seemed to have reduced the scale of its investigation following the report on June 23 and had focused on LG Futures Co Ltd, the major broker for LG Metals.</p>
<p>They said they believed LG Futures had last week submitted an explanation to the finance ministry of LG Metals' increasing turnover, but LG Futures could not be reached for comment on the market talk.</p>
<p>Some traders said a heavy copper sell-off on the LME last week may have wiped out the rumoured options-related losses of LG Metals, but others warned of possible new problems caused by price volatility as the company is believed to have traded short straddles and short strangles.</p>
<p>A short strangle is an option strategy combining the sale of a call and a put with the same expiry date but different strike prices and a short straddle is a strategy combining the sale of a call and a put with the same expiry date and strike price, both in anticipation of very little movement in futures prices.</p>
<p>On Monday, Japanese traders said they were carefully watching any developments related to LG Metals as a key to copper price movements ahead of the LME options expiry on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very nervous (about South Korea),&quot; said a trader at one of Japan's major trading houses. &quot;It might flare up into a big scandal, like Sumitomo, and lead to a price collapse.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier this month an analyst with Samsung Securities said LG Metals' ordinary profit is expected to surge 491.3 percent to 45 billion won this year from 7.6 billion won in 1996.</p>
<p>The forecast was based on comparatively strong copper prices, treatment and refining charges and a stable currency market, the analyst said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
