<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698816" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-C&amp;W to buy BellSouth Optus stake.</title>
<headline>RTRS-C&amp;W to buy BellSouth Optus stake.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Cable &amp; Wireless Plc will acquire BellSouth Corp Inc's 24.5 percent stake in Australian telecommunication group Optus Communications Pty Ltd, taking its stake to 49 percent, Optus said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>C&amp;W will acquire BellSouth's 490 million shares in Optus for A$980 million, plus an interest in a cellular property in Latin America, Optus said.  </p>
<p>In addition, C&amp;W will receive from Optus the right to buy a further 289.9 million ordinary shares at A$1.75 a share exercisable over the next three years, Optus's acting chairman Bob Dalziel said.</p>
<p>&quot;Mayne Nickless Ltd and the Australian institutional investors retain their respective holdings of 25 percent and 26 percent,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Should Cable &amp; Wireless exercise all its options, its stake in Optus would increase beyond 50 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The initial transaction is subject to Australian government and Foreign Investment Review Board (FIRB) approval, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This new shareholding structure creates a focus and clear commitment to Optus's integrated communications strategy, which draws on the combined strength of broadband, wireline, wireless and satellite technologies,&quot; Dalziel said.</p>
<p>Dalziel, who is managing director of Mayne Nickless, said he was speaking on behalf of the shareholders.</p>
<p>Optus's recently appointed chief executive officer, Peter Howell-Davies, will hold a media conference at 0100 GMT (11 a.m.) in Sydney on Wednesday to outline his plans for the group, Optus added.</p>
<p>He had been CEO of a C&amp;W unit.  </p>
<p>In a separate statement, Dalziel said as Mayne Nickless's managing director that Mayne Nickless welcomed the agreement.</p>
<p>He noted that the the C&amp;W call options are only exercisable if the mooted float of Optus proceeds.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Mayne Nickless will no longer be required to underwrite the A$100 million incentive offered by Optus to the US West Inc group to assist in the rollout of local telephony services, he said in a statement.</p>
<p>As part of the same arrangement, Mayne Nickless will also not take up an additional 30 million shares at A$1 each in Optus, he said.  </p>
<p>These arrangements were part of the March settlement which allowed Optus to take full ownership of the Optus Vision pay television group, Dalziel said.</p>
<p>The US West incentive payments will continue to be borne by Optus.</p>
<p>&quot;Optus is looking forward to actively participating in the rationalisation of the Australian pay TV industry and associated cable infrastructure issues which will pave the way for a float of Optus as soon as possible,&quot; Dalziel said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
