<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="698951" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Key West, Myrtle Beach get green group thumbs down.</title>
<headline>Key West, Myrtle Beach get green group thumbs down.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>To the summer crowds heading to Key West, Myrtle Beach, the Outer Banks, and Florida's Panama City, environmentalists on Tuesday warned: beware of dirty water.</p>
<p>The Natural Resources Defense Council said those four areas and Puerto Rico were the most popular U.S. beaches without pollution tests for swimmer safety last year or no notices to keep swimmers out of unhealthy water.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd be careful about swimming in those waters, particularly after a heavy rain,&quot; said Sarah Chassis, director of NRDC's coastal project, which annually tracks more than 30 coastal and Great Lakes areas around the United States.</p>
<p>NRDC warned that swimming in water tainted with sewage could lead to fever, diarrhea, vomiting and muscular problems. Toxic algal blooms were also a threat, killing fish and potentially harming fishermen, swimmers and others in beach and river waters.</p>
<p>Florida's Key West and Panama City, South Carolina's Myrtle Beach, North Carolina's Outer Banks, and Puerto Rico were singled out because they were known to have storm drains nearby and septic pollution but had no warning systems.</p>
<p>&quot;We picked areas that weren't pristine,&quot; Chassis said in an interview.</p>
<p>Although Myrtle Beach and North Carolina recently started testing programs, they were on the list because Myrtle Beach had no plans to alert the public about pollution, and North Carolina had not yet set a health standard nor designed a public notice system, she said.</p>
<p>North Carolina officials disputed the report, saying they had statewide, health-based water quality standards in place. Dare County, which covers most of the Outer Banks, had a water testing and warning program which in fact resulted in a 100-foot patch of beach being closed for a short time two months ago in Kill Devil Hills, a county spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was closed because we detected a problem,&quot; said county spokeswoman Dorothy Holt.</p>
<p>While keeping North Carolina on its list, NRDC took Santa Barbara in California and Miami Beach in Florida off the list of &quot;beach bums&quot; from last year because they had adopted new monitoring systems.</p>
<p>In areas where there were public alerts, almost 85 percent of beach closings and warnings nationwide last year were triggered when bacteria levels rose above water quality standards, according to NRDC. But those standards varied from state to state and even county to county.</p>
<p>Among the nation's beaches with more than one million visitors each year, NRDC approved New Jersey's Cape May, New York's Jones Beach, California's Venice Beach and Windansea Beach in San Diego.</p>
<p>Fort Lauderdale in Florida, Ocean City in Maryland, Virginia Beach in Virginia, and Oahu in Hawaii were considered reasonably safe for swimmers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PURI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
