<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699123" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Viacom's Blockbuster still in rough seas.</title>
<headline>Viacom's Blockbuster still in rough seas.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Benkoe</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Viacom Inc. on Tuesday announced a $300 million charge for Blockbuster Video -- clearing the decks for Blockbuster's new chief executive, analysts said.</p>
<p>But the video rental unit still has rough seas to navigate, the analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;No question, the company is looking to provide a clean slate for the new management to go forth and conquer,&quot; said Chris Dixon, an analyst at PaineWebber.</p>
<p>Viacom named John Antioco, a former head of PepsiCo Inc.'s Taco Bell unit, as head of Blockbuster last month.</p>
<p>Still, despite the new leadership and the financial cleansing, some analysts were unconvinced that Blockbuster is a proper corporate fit for Viacom, which also owns MTV Networks, Paramount Pictures, Showtime Networks, and publisher Simon &amp; Schuster, among other media entities.</p>
<p>Viacom said Tuesday that Blockbuster's second-quarter results will be below Wall Street estimates, and it will take a $300 million charge to reduce inventory and close underperforming stores outside the United States.</p>
<p>One big thorn in Blockbuster's side is distribution, analysts said. It is switching from an outside contractor to doing its own distribution and is in the midst of completing a new distribution centre in Dallas.</p>
<p>&quot;It's taking longer and costing more than anticipated,&quot; Dixon said of the distribution transition.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly, there are problems in the interim, and it's hurting them,&quot; said David Doft at Furman Selz.</p>
<p>However, in the long run the new distribution system could be a boon, analysts said. &quot;By bringing distribution inside, they can get better controls and perhaps get some incremental margin improvements,&quot; Dixon said.</p>
<p>Analysts said Blockbuster's move of its headquarters to Dallas from Fort Lauderdale, Fla., in March also hurt results. With a lot of staff members choosing not to relocate, the unit has had to cope with new personnel.</p>
<p>Analysts concurred with Viacom management that a weak lineup of movies in the first half also hurt.</p>
<p>&quot;The video rental market continues to be difficult,&quot; Doft said. &quot;It's been a tough quarter and a tough year.&quot;</p>
<p>However, the analysts foresaw movies with greater potential video revenue coming out later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;If they can get their house in order, then in the second half you can see a marked turnaround,&quot; Dixon said.  He cited the whole crop of summer movies out now that will hit video stores later this year.</p>
<p>Some analysts, however, still see Blockbuster as an incompatible drain on Viacom and its stock.</p>
<p>&quot;They should get rid of it,&quot; said Hal Vogel, an analyst at Cowen &amp; Co. &quot;It's not compatible with the other businesses they are in. It's a major distraction.&quot;</p>
<p>Viacom said in April it plans a public offering next year of a new class of Viacom stock for Blockbuster.</p>
<p>If Blockbuster was spun off or sold, the remaining company would be solid, Vogel said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's a strong company,&quot; he said. &quot;MTV and Nickelodeon are doing well. Paramount will do fine with (its new movie) 'Face/Off.' It's a good collection of assets.&quot;</p>
<p>Trading in Viacom's stock on the American Stock Exchange was halted for almost two hours, was virtually unchanged. Its A shares rose 31 cents to $29.75, while B shares climbed 37.5 cents to $30.375.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
