<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699170" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Merger to reunite Red Adair firefighting veterans.</title>
<headline>Merger to reunite Red Adair firefighting veterans.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two rival Houston-based international oil well firefighting firms Tuesday announced plans to merge by late July in a deal that reunites veterans of the legendary Red Adair's former company.</p>
<p>In the deal, International Well Control will acquire the assets of Boots &amp; Coots LP to form a new company, Boots &amp; Coots/IWC. Financial terms were not disclosed.</p>
<p>The Houston-based company will be headed by Brian Krause, who formed International Well Control in 1994 along with a group of senior firefighters after Adair retired and sold his business to Global Industries Ltd. in late 1993.</p>
<p>Asger &quot;Boots&quot; Hansen and Edward Owen &quot;Coots&quot; Matthews, who left Adair's company to form Boots &amp; Coots in 1978, will be consultants to the new company.</p>
<p>Adair began his career with well firefighting pioneer Myron Kinley, and found fame on the cover of Life magazine after extinguishing the &quot;Devil's cigarette lighter,&quot; a massive Middle East oil well fire in the late 1950s.</p>
<p>His legendary status grew with the 1968 release of the John Wayne movie &quot;Hellfighters,&quot; a film based loosely on Adair's career which glamorized the gritty life of the international well firefighter.</p>
<p>Crews from the two companies extinguished 245 of the 700 well fires set by Iraqi troops as they retreated from Kuwait at the end of the Gulf War.</p>
<p>In the past month, the companies joined forces to battle a well explosion and fire that killed four rig workers in Louisiana, and separate blowouts in West Texas and Bangladesh.</p>
<p>&quot;We've started to see quite an increase in the last year here,&quot; said Krause, who said stepped-up drilling and ageing wells were contributing to more frequent blowouts. &quot;You also don't have the experienced personnel that you used to have.&quot;</p>
<p>The deal continues a steady consolidation in the well firefighting industry, which has shrunk to three active companies from 10 since the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>The acquisition is expected to close by July 31, and Boots &amp; Coots/IWC is considering a public stock offering to expand its international operations, Krause said.</p>
<p>The company will continue IWC's WellCall venture with Halliburton Energy Services, and plans to expand operations to battle tanker and refinery fires, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
