<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699110" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME feeder cattle end mostly up, live cattle mixed.</title>
<headline>CME feeder cattle end mostly up, live cattle mixed.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME feeder cattle futures remained supported from lower corn futures and tight feeder supplies while live cattle closed mixed in active nearby months, traders said.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle closed 0.575 cent per lb higher to 0.025 lower with August up most at 81.450 cents. Live cattle ended up 0.175 to off 0.175 with only August up at 64.625 cents.</p>
<p>Although profit taking continued to weigh on feeder cattle at times, prices again moved up following the falling feed costs and tight feeder supplies. Buy stops were hit on the rally around midsession, they said.</p>
<p>The profit taking came as the market looked overbought after posting its highest price level since August 1994. But support was still evident as cash markets held firm and the CME index headed higher, they said.</p>
<p>The latest CME feeder cattle index was up $1.22 to $80.30 per cwt, the highest level since April 21, 1994.</p>
<p>ADM Investor Services, Iowa Grain in ABN Chicogo Corp bought on the early rally while E.D.&amp;F. Man and Rosenthal Collins bought late, pit sources said.  </p>
<p>Live cattle also showed profit taking pressure early but rallied late when buy stops were hit in August above the 50-day average of 64.650 cents. Both fed cattle and boxed beef markets were holding better than expected which provided underlying support, traders said.</p>
<p>Activity at $63 per cwt increased in cash cattle during the day which encouraged ideas cash cattle markets could hold stronger than expected through the holiday period, they said.</p>
<p>Cargill Investor Services bought August late while RBH bought October. Cargill also spread long June and December live cattle/short January and August feeders, pit sources said.</p>
<p>In live cattle options, commission houses bought December 70 puts and sold 66 puts early, pit sources added.</p>
<p>Trading was light in boneless beef and trimings with reports of frozen trimmings being offered below futures weighing on the market. Rosenthal sold August and October trimmings while commission houses sold boneless beef and locals bought, traders said.</p>
<p>Trimmings ended 0.50 cent lower to 0.80 higher with nearbys down, paced by August at 43.00 cents per lb. Boneless beef ended unchanged with August at 94.00 cents.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
