<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699126" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US archeologists wait for agency move on skeleton.</title>
<headline>US archeologists wait for agency move on skeleton.</headline>
<dateline>PORTLAND, Ore. 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of prominent archaeologists seeking to study a 9,000-year-old human skeleton has put a lawsuit on hold pending a decision by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, a lawyer for the scientists said Tuesday.</p>
<p>A federal court ruling Friday criticised the Corps' decision to hand the bones of the &quot;Kennewick Man&quot; to Indian tribes for burial.</p>
<p>Paula Barran, an attorney for the scientists, said the ruling requires the Corps to &quot;go back to square one&quot; in its review process and come up with an initial determination by October as to what the agency will do with the skeleton. She said if her clients are denied access to the bones they will pursue further legal action.</p>
<p>The nearly intact skeleton, considered one of the most significant discoveries of human remains in the New World, was found nearly a year ago along the banks of the Columbia river in Kennewick, Wash. Carbon dating has determined that it is more than 9,000 years old and initial study by anthropologists revealed Caucasoid features unlike native Americans or any other present-day population group.</p>
<p>But the bones have been held in limbo by the Corps since the agency agreed to transfer them to area tribes for reburial in accordance with the Native American Graves Protection Act.</p>
<p>Dutch Meier, a spokesman for the Corps in Walla Walla, Wash., said the agency had not yet completed its review of last week's ruling by U.S. District Judge John Jelderks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORTLAND, Ore."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
