<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699227" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: E.A. Moos cuts back muni effort, 15-17 jobs lost.</title>
<headline>E.A. Moos cuts back muni effort, 15-17 jobs lost.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>E.A. Moos &amp; Co scaled back its municipal operation, cutting 15 to 17 jobs as of Tuesday, Edward Moos, managing partner of the Summit, N.J.-based firm, said.</p>
<p>While the firm has exited public finance completely, it will continue to engage in sales and trading selectively, Moos said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;What we really are doing is exiting the day-to-day municipal bond business,&quot; he said. &quot;The municipal bond business day-to-day has become an extremely tough business, and what we are going to do is get down to a hardcore five-to-seven people (operation), and work on special situations.&quot;</p>
<p>Municipal new issue underwriting spreads have contracted to &quot;razor&quot; thin levels, while volume has remained light, Moos said, adding that the same is true in public finance.</p>
<p>&quot;In public finance you work months and months on a deal, (and) you find out they want you to do the deal for $3.75,&quot; he said, explaining that the firm recently handled a new issue at that price per bond. &quot;It's not worth the risk.&quot;</p>
<p>The firm's municipal professionals once numbered 30, he said, but that figure was pared back to 22 a year or so ago.</p>
<p>The remaining five to seven professionals will continue to trade municipals, focusing on &quot;junk&quot; municipals and some similarly rated corporates, as well as other debt, Moos said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will trade the market wherever opportunity arises, whether it's municipal bonds, whether it's government bonds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>E A Moos has always considered itself a trading firm that is unafraid of taking positions, Moos said.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, what's interesting is one of the biggest customers in the muni bond business -- we are talking one about one of the mega funds -- said to somebody that he was sad to see us dropping out of the business because we provided liquidity,&quot; he said, adding that his firm takes more risk than some of its larger competitors.</p>
<p>((--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
