<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69922" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: European veg oils end quiet day little changed.</title>
<headline>European veg oils end quiet day little changed.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Closing European vegetable oil prices were little changed on Monday at the end of a quiet day.</p>
<p>Malaysian private forecaster Ivan Wong's latest report on local palm oil output, stocks and exports had little impact on the market.</p>
<p>Prices tried to dip following the release of what traders saw as a bearish report, but rose again as short covering emerged in Malaysia.</p>
<p>Wong's report put local palm oil output during September at 860,000 tonnes, an increase of six percent over August.</p>
<p>Wong estimated end-September palm oil stocks at 910,000 tonnes, compared with the Palm Oil Registration and Licensing Authority's (PORLA) 800,893 tonnes at end-August.</p>
<p>He said palm oil exports in September were projected to be 655,000 tonnes versus PORLA's 638,601 tonnes.</p>
<p>There was also talk of Indonesian buying but traders in Europe said they were unaware of this.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I know there was no Indonesian buying today, just some short covering towards the close,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Crude palm oil cif Europe closed unchanged to $2.50 up while refined palm oils were $2.50 lower with no further business reported during the afternoon.</p>
<p>Lauric oils finished a tradeless session with coconut oil unchanged and palmkernel oil unchanged to $5.00 up.</p>
<p>Soft oil sellers back-tracked during the afternoon trimming Monday morning's gains to up to 0.50 guilders for soy and rape oil with no business reported.</p>
<p>-- Jim Ballantyne, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8062</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
