<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699214" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mississippi, tobacco industry negotiate ahead of trial.</title>
<headline>Mississippi, tobacco industry negotiate ahead of trial.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>Tobacco industry lawyers and the Mississippi attorney general's office were fervently negotiating on Tuesday to try to head off the first state Medicaid trial, scheduled to begin next week.</p>
<p>If the Mississippi trial proceeds July 9, the verdict could signal the outcome of some of the lawsuits pending in 39 other states. It could also have a political impact on the broader $368.5 billion settlement proposed by the industry and top state legal officials on June 20.</p>
<p>Although Mississippi Attorney General Mike Moore had hoped to reach a settlement of his lawsuit with the industry quickly, negotiations were continuing Tuesday in Washington. Sources close to the talks said the industry was balking over money and regulatory issues.</p>
<p>Florida Attorney General Robert Butterworth, whose trial against the industry is scheduled to begin Aug. 4, also had talks with cigarette makers Friday. But he left because the offer was insufficient.</p>
<p>Butterworth  told Reuters the state is determined to go ahead with its lawsuit.</p>
<p>&quot;The two sides are simply too far apart for there to be any negotiated settlement,&quot; he said. &quot;We want what's in the complaint or there is no settlement.&quot;</p>
<p>Florida is seeking $1 billion in actual damages, which could be tripled if the state can prove the tobacco companies engaged in criminal conduct in the sale and marketing of cigarettes.</p>
<p>Although the nation's top legal officers and the tobacco industry reached a landmark $368.5 billion pact last month that included some health care concessions from cigarette makers, the accord has been criticised as too lenient by a number of members of Congress who must approve it.</p>
<p>In addition, President Clinton said the tobacco settlement must not be allowed to paralyse the federal Food and Drug Administration.</p>
<p>With the agreement's fate uncertain, the states must settle their lawsuits individually or go to trial. Forty state attorneys general have sued the industry to recoup Medicaid costs of sick smokers.</p>
<p>The Mississippi case is being widely watched because it is the first of the lawsuits to go to trial and because it is considered a particularly strong case. The trial will be decided by a judge, not a jury, and Mississippi law is favourable to the plaintiffs, legal experts say.</p>
<p>But going to trial is very risky to both the states and the tobacco industry. If Mississippi wins, it will signal the strength of these innovative lawsuits and help support the demand for both a greater amount of money and health care concessions from the industry.</p>
<p>If cigarette makers should win, however, it would boost the industry's resolve to fight the other lawsuits and to resist efforts to obtain a harsher overall settlement through legislation.</p>
<p>Mississippi's Moore said Monday that tobacco companies had only a few days to settle his state's $940 million Medicaid lawsuit or the trial would proceed.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm optimistic. I can't imagine why they wouldn't want to settle with us because I think their chances are not good in Mississippi,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
