<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699567" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee called to open 2.00 cents higher.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee called to open 2.00 cents higher.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures were called to open 2.00 cents per lb higher on Tuesday, in line with gains overnight in London, traders said.</p>
<p>London robusta futures were higher early Tuesday, as forecasts for cooler weather in Brazil this weekend underpinned the market. At midday break, benchmark LIFFE September was up $28, to the session high of $1,825, while spot July rose $33, to $1,798.</p>
<p>Monday, New York arabica futures ended higher on weather-related buying, but dealings were extremely thin. September rose 3.10 cents, to 172.40, after ranging from 175.00 to 166.50. Spot July finished 2.50 cents firmer, at 192.40 cents, while the outer months closed up 1.90 to 3.50.</p>
<p>The July/September switch narrowed to 20.00 cents, from 20.60 cents at the close on Friday, while September/December widened to 21.50 cents compared with 20.30 cents.</p>
<p>Brazilian meterologists Somar said on Monday that a polar air mass may pass through Brazil's coffee-growing regions from the evening of July 5, representing the greatest threat of frost seen so far this year.</p>
<p>But U.S.-based forecaster Weather Services Corp said on Tuesday that there was no damaging cold indicated through the weekend in Brazil's coffee belt, with temperatures expected to be near to above normal.</p>
<p>Technically, traders said 175.00 cents basis September would provide nearby resistance, followed by 181.00. Support was pegged at 165.00 cents, they said.</p>
<p>After Monday's close, CSCE reported certified coffee stocks rose by 2,224 60-kg bags as of June 27, to 45,893 bags. However, there were 12,130 bags pending grading, the exchange said.</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
