<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699668" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE futures steady with NYMEX help.</title>
<headline>IPE futures steady with NYMEX help.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent and gas oil futures steadied on Tuesday with short-covering by fund buyers and stronger NYMEX values helping it hold high, traders said.</p>
<p>But they said New York and fund activity was by itself an insufficient explanation for the strength in the IPE and some confessed they were at a loss.</p>
<p>By 1440 GMT August Brent futures were up 15 cents at $18.66 a barrel, gas oil was $1.75 higher at $167 a tonne and front month WTI was up 20 cents at $20 a barrel.</p>
<p>WTI's $20 was called the pivot figure for a rise or fall.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's somewhat of a mystery as to why we are so strong,&quot; said one broker. &quot;But to make it a definitive rise I think that psychologically WTI has to hold above $20 a barrel.&quot;</p>
<p>The effect of weekend news that Iraq would not be exporting crude until August, which buoyed markets on Monday, has now died away. Technicals were also nearly uniformly negative, leaving a variety of accounts in the market for the day's rise.</p>
<p>&quot;Its an absolute mystery and I don't like it at all,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>Early buying on the IPE saw the August Brent contract bounce off resistance at $18.77 and then trade in a narrow range  </p>
<p>Some spread trade was reported, with funds rolling forward their positions into following months, but most brokers said the IPE had been largely shadowing New York. Volume was high considering U.S. stock data was due out later tonight.</p>
<p>&quot;Last night we saw Wall Street buying the spread, but it seems a bit forced here now and a bit strong,&quot; said one broker. &quot;We're watching WTI around $20 and unless that breaks downwards we are going to stay up.&quot;</p>
<p>August Brent closed 33 cents higher on Monday after a late rush of buying pushed figures through resistance and into the new territory where they were trading on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
