<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69977" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Tennis-Newcombe says Australia can win Davis Cup next year.</title>
<headline>Tennis-Newcombe says Australia can win Davis Cup next year.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia captain John Newcombe on Monday claimed his team could win the Davis Cup next year after they defeated Croatia 4-1 in Split at the weekend to qualify for the competition's elite world group.</p>
<p>&quot;I really believe Australia can do it, which is why this tie was just so important for us,&quot; Newcombe said in a statement released by Tennis Australia on Monday.</p>
<p>Australia, winners of the Davis Cup 26 times, were relegated from the world group last year for the first time in the country's history. They then had to play through Asian region qualifiers before the tie against Croatia.</p>
<p>Having successfully returned to the 16-nation world group, Newcombe said he hoped his team would be among the eight top seeds for next year's competition. Seedings for next year will be announced when the draw is made in England on October 8.</p>
<p>&quot;Winning this tie (against Croatia) was just so important for Australian tennis. I think we are capable of anything next year. The tide has turned,&quot; Newcombe said.</p>
<p>Newcombe had hinted he and coach Tony Roche would stand down from their positions if Australia lost to Croatia.</p>
<p>Jason Stoltenberg set up the win when he defeated world number four Goran Ivanisevic in five sets on Friday. Mark Philippoussis also won his opening singles rubber before Mark Woodforde and Pat Rafter secured the tie with an easy win in Saturday's doubles.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
