<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="69978" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ SPORT - Rowing investigates Olympic failures.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT - Rowing investigates Olympic failures.</headline>
<text>
<p>CHRISTCHURCH, Sept 23 - Rowing New Zealand (RNZ) boss Mike Stanley has called for an investigation into the failure of two crews at the Olympic Games in Atlanta last month, NZPA reported on Monday.</p>
<p>The men's coxless four and the lightweight double sculls were eliminated in the repechages at Atlanta after being rated possible medal chances.</p>
<p>&quot;Few could have picked that both crews would have been so conspicuously off the pace,&quot; chief executive Stanley said in RNZ's annual report released today.  </p>
<p>Stanley said the disappointment among the crews was tangible and equalled their dismay at performing so poorly.</p>
<p>&quot;Their performance requires thorough examination,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>RNZ will discuss the unsatisfactory performance of some of the Olympic crews at the 109th annual meeting in Christchurch on Saturday.</p>
<p>Stanley also criticised television stations for exploiting the disappointment of scullers Brenda Lawson and Philippa Baker after they finished last in their Olympic final at Lake Lanier.</p>
<p>Television found a way to tarnish their image as truly great champions, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;They (Baker and Lawson) knew it was their last shot at an Olympic title and probably their last row together. It hurt.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite comprehensive funding and extensive preparation for the Olympics, New Zealand's best effort on the water was a fifth in the coxless pair.</p>
<p>David Schaper and Toni Dunlop had only six weeks together to pull off a major surprise of the Olympics by coming from nowhere to finish fifth in the final.</p>
<p>Saturday's meeting will outline where New Zealand rowing is heading in the next four years to the Sydney Olympics.  </p>
<p>Questions have been be asked whether New Zealand might have fared better in Atlanta by sending fewer crews with more funding and resources.</p>
<p>Of the five Kiwi boats entered in the Olympic regatta, only two made the medal finals.</p>
<p>The Sports Foundation granted rowing $186,000 this year but the sport is on notice that the present level of funding is dependent on world championship and Olympic gold medals being won.</p>
<p>RNZ will further review its operations and future plans at a special meeting on November 2.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
