<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699799" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco moves to tighten anti-drug penalties.</title>
<headline>Morocco moves to tighten anti-drug penalties.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morocco's justice minister said on Tuesday his country was preparing a law to raise penalties for people convicted of money laundering as part of the war against drug smugglers.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to the new law extending jail terms of drug traffickers, a law against money laundering is under way,&quot; Abderrahman Amalu said in a statement carried by the official news agency MAP.</p>
<p>Last month, Morocco's interior ministry announced it had drafted a law increasing the maximum jail term for drug traffickers to 30 years from 10 years, with a maximum fine of 800,000 dirhams ($85,000).</p>
<p>Amalu's statement follows his meeting with visiting British International Drugs Coordinator Derek Plumbly who told Reuters on Monday: &quot;I believe 1,500 to 3,000 tonnes (of cannabis resin) are produced in Morocco annually.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have very good cooperation police-to-police and customs- to-customs, but you have a very large area of cultivation,&quot; he said, adding that production figures were a very rough estimate.</p>
<p>Amalu said he told Plumbly that &quot;Morocco does not stop deploying its efforts...to contribute efficiently to the international campaign led with the aim of totally eradicating this scourge and reducing the culture, consumption and illicit traffic of drugs in general and of cannabis in particular.&quot;</p>
<p>Moroccan Prime Minister Abdellatif Filali has announced a government plan to invest 1.5 billion dirhams ($160 million) in 1997/98 to upgrade the infrastructure of its northern regions where much of the cannabis is grown.</p>
<p>Amalu said however that Morocco's efforts would not have the desired results unless Europe could help financially.</p>
<p>Morocco launched a crackdown on drug smuggling last year, and Interior Minister Driss Basri said recently it had seized 103 tonnes of cannabis bound for Europe in 1996. It had also arrested more than 18,000 drug traffickers, including 342 foreigners.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
