<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699983" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electricity seen higher after Monday's rise.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electricity seen higher after Monday's rise.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures were called to open higher Tuesday after rising Monday on news the 1,070 megawatt (MW) San Onofre 2 nuclear unit would shut for a two week repair outage.</p>
<p>&quot;It'll test the upside again today. I think it's just a trade play,&quot; said a New York futures brokers.</p>
<p>In over-the-counter business, August Palo Verde (PV) futures were quoted at $35.40-35.75 a megawatt hour (MWh) against Monday's settlement at $34.90, while August California-Oregon Border (COB) were discussed at $23.25-23.85 versus yesterday's close at $23.40.</p>
<p>On ACCESS, August PV traded at $35.20, up 30 cents Monday's regular settlement, while August COB finished with an offer at $25.00.</p>
<p>On the upside, analysts and brokers expect August PV to test chart resistance at $36.25 and August COB at $24.00.</p>
<p>Southern California Edison Co said it expects the San Onofre 2 nuclear unit in San Clemente, Calif., to remain off line until July 15 to to replace its charge line check valves.</p>
<p>The adjacent 1,080 MW San Onofre unit 3 is still out of service, and scheduled to resume operation around July 10.</p>
<p>Also, the 560 megawatt (MW) Agua Fria natural gas-fired power plant was shut late Monday, market sources said.</p>
<p>The status of the station, operated by Salt River Project, could not be confirmed at this time.</p>
<p>The WNP-2 nuclear plant in Washington state is expected to stay down as it continued to await clearance from the Nuclear Regulatory Commission before beginning start-up operations.</p>
<p>A 550 MW unit at the coal-fired Laramie River Station in Wyoming was said to have tripped off line Sunday, with no restart date available.</p>
<p>The six to 10 day forecast called for temperatures in the Pacific Northwest to average below normal, while those in the Southwest would run above normal.</p>
<p>Late last week the Western Systems Coordinating Council board approved a derating of the Pacific Intertie transmission sytem to 6,300 MW from the current 7,200 MW, which was to be effective today.</p>
<p>((--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
