<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="699956" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Purchasing managers say manufacturing slowed in June.</title>
<headline>Purchasing managers say manufacturing slowed in June.</headline>
<dateline>TEMPE, Ariz. 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Growth in the manufacturing sector slowed slightly in June from the previous month, with an accompanying decline in prices, the nation's purchasing managers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>At the same time, the overall economy continued to grow in June for the 74th consecutive month, according to the National Association of Purchasing Management.</p>
<p>&quot;The manufacturing sector grew at a slower pace in June than in May with production and new orders growing at slower rates,&quot; said Norbert Ore, chair of the group's Business Survey Committee and director of purchasing at Sonoco Products Co.</p>
<p>Analysts said a sharp rise might have signalled manufacturing strength, raising fears about an interest rate hike by the Federal Reserve, whose rate-setting Federal Open Market Committee was meeting on Tuesday and Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ore said that the views of purchasing executives, who are responsible for buying everything from paper to steel for the nation's factories, remained optimistic on future business conditions. However, a few expressed concerns on continuing softness in European markets, interest rates and manpower shortages.</p>
<p>The Purchasing Managers' Index declined to 55.7 percent in June from 57.1 percent in May. Its Production Index decreased from 57.0 percent to 56.0 percent, and its New Orders Index declined from 64.2 percent to 62.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall picture in June as indicated by growth in production, new orders, backlog of orders, and a continued reduction in prices is one of continued growth in manufacturing activity,&quot; said Ore.</p>
<p>&quot;The rate of growth of new orders is strong while prices are receding, with only three industries reporting that they are paying higher prices.&quot;</p>
<p>The industries that reported paying higher prices in June were printing and publishing, chemicals, and industrial and commercial equipment and computers.</p>
<p>The decline in the purchasing managers' index sparked gains on Wall Street. The Dow Jones industrial average shot up more than 60 points to 7,733.</p>
<p>The inflation-sensitive 30-year Treasury bond gained 13/32, or $4.06 per $1,000 face value, and its yield slipped to 6.75 percent from 6.79 percent Monday.</p>
<p>The decline in the NAPM index assuaged financial markets' fears about excessive growth in the manufacturing sector, which might fuel inflation, analysts said.</p>
<p>Both markets were susceptible to inflation and interest rate jitters as the Federal Reserve's FOMC began its two-day meeting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEMPE, Ariz."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
