<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700065" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France Telecom awaits IPO decision with US loss.</title>
<headline>France Telecom awaits IPO decision with US loss.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>France Telecom confirmed on Tuesday it posted a 1996 loss under U.S. accounting rules and said it awaits a decision by the government on whether its suspended Initial Public Offering (IPO) will go ahead.</p>
<p>The decision on the sale of a minority stake in France Telecom lies in the hands of Prime Minister Lionel Jospin who will have to weigh his Socialist Party's opposition to a sale against the financing needs of the state and the company's competitiveness.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the company, saying he had no knowledge when a decision on the sale was due, confirmed a report in the Financial Times newspaper that under U.S. Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP) the company would have made a 1996 loss of some 33.9 billion francs instead of a profit of 2.1 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes it is correct, but it is nothing new,&quot; a spokesman said, adding the difference was due to the treatment in the accounts of a one-off 37.5 billion franc payment to the government in exchange for the state assuming the pension liabilities for civil servants employed by France Telecom.</p>
<p>The company filed its accounts according to GAAP rules with the Securities and Exchange Commission as part of preparations of its planned, but now suspended, IPO.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we are concerned those documents are not public,&quot; the spokesman said. The loss would have been larger than the biggest French corporate loss on record, a 1995 deficit of 25.6 billion francs at Alcatel Alsthom .</p>
<p>&quot;For us 1996 is a year of transition and the loss under U.S. accounting rules does not reflect our underlying earnings situation,&quot; the spokesman said. The government's assumption of pension liabilities was a key deal struck by the former centre-right government of Prime Minister Alain Juppe to gain employee support for the partial privatisation.</p>
<p>France Telecom staff are keeping their civil service status, including job guarantees and pension packages, while the state will carry the cost of the relatively old age structure of its payroll.</p>
<p>Otherwise the company would have been burdened with much higher pension charges than its competitors.</p>
<p>The previous government planned to sell a stake of some 35 percent in order to raise some 30 to 50 billion francs -- the biggest French stock market flotation ever. At the time France Telecom was valued at between 160 and 210 billion francs.</p>
<p>The operation, scheduled for late May, was first postponed after French President Jacques Chirac called an early parliamentary election and then suspended when the left gained office.</p>
<p>Both the Socialist and the Communist parties said during their campaigns that they were against the privatisation of France Telecom.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn recently told Socialist members of parliament that he is open to a partial sale of the telecoms operator on condition the staff of the company is consulted.</p>
<p>Strauss-Kahn will be quizzed on his policy intentions by the influential finance commissions of parliament, on Wednesday, and the senate on Thursday. These meetings are behind closed doors.</p>
<p>Receipts from a France Telecom sale cannot be used to reduce the country's deficit to qualify for the single currency, but they can serve to finance other expenses that would otherwise weigh on the budget.</p>
<p>Junior industry minister Christian Pierret met France Telecom chairman Michel Bon last month and talked with union representatives last week in preparation for a decision.</p>
<p>Analysts do not expect a decision until after the results of an audit of public finances due to be completed by July 21. If Jospin gives the go-ahead, and financial analysts believe he will, the sale could resume in September at the earliest.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
