<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700160" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Renault June sales down but orders flat.</title>
<headline>Renault June sales down but orders flat.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>French carmaker Renault SA, whose car sales in France plunged 48.1 percent in June, said the drop was due to low inventories in the run-up tox the new model year.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman said orders, year-over-year, were unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of orders for cars for the new model year, last month was flat relative to June 1996,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Renault did not raise prices at the start of the new model year begun on Tuesday, she said.</p>
<p>Asked why the company fared worse than the French car market, which was down 30.7 percent in June, the spokeswoman said, &quot;Our performance was atypical relative to the other car companies. We had less in stock ... after managing inventories to arrive at the end of the model year at very low levels.&quot;</p>
<p>Although Renault's market share fell in June to 19.8 percent, it was 26.1 percent for the January-June period, compared with 28.9 percent for the PSA Peugeot Citroen group.</p>
<p>The French carmakers' association CCFA, which released the monthly sales figures, did not have data on monthly orders.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
