<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700155" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria's ATX index surges to record closing high.</title>
<headline>Austria's ATX index surges to record closing high.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austria's ATX index of 21 blue chips chalked up its biggest point gain in three years when it powered to an all-time closing high on Tuesday, the Vienna bourse said.</p>
<p>And analysts forecast the index has further room on the upside after it closed 30.17 points, or 2.3 percent, higher at 1,339.87.</p>
<p>Traders said buying was triggered after the index broke through resistance at 1,310 points soon after opening.</p>
<p>Investmentbank Austria sees the ATX's short-term target at 1,400 points on the condition that the schedule for the introduction of Europe's single currency is adhered to.</p>
<p>Winners overwhelmed decliners with 18 ATX shares advancing and three declining.</p>
<p>The day's best performer was luxury hosiery and lingerie maker Wolford, up 80 schillings at 1,270.</p>
<p>Creditanstalt preferred shares were the worst performers, losing 1.25 percent to 486.85 schillings.</p>
<p>Regional utility EVN the most actively traded, up 30 schillings at 1,610 on turnover of 104,097.</p>
<p>The broad-based Vienna bourse index advanced 8.07 points or 1.69 percent to 485.78 points.</p>
<p>The July ATX future gained 40 points to 1,347 on turnover of 1,915 contracts. -- Vienna newsroom, +431 531 12256</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
