<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700158" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares seek to reach all-time record highs.</title>
<headline>German shares seek to reach all-time record highs.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were seeking fresh strength for a run at all-time record highs after ending bourse trade at a new closing high on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The export-dependent chemical sector stole the spotlight, drawing strength from the dollar trading above 1.74 marks.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index ended bourse trade up 34.08 points at 3,819.85 points, surpassing the old record closing high set last Thursday at 3,805 points.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected the DAX index to stabilise above the crucial 3,800-point level in the coming days and would seek to break the all-time record DAX high at 3,827.52 points.  </p>
<p>One factor driving the market up was Hoechst AG suring nearly six percent to end up 4.32 marks at 78.30 marks.</p>
<p>Banking group CSFB said it had raised its rating on Hoechst to buy from hold and also said it had set a price target of 90 marks per share, which sparked the buying interest.</p>
<p>Rival Bayer AG rose 3.28 marks to 70.30 marks and BASF AG rose 1.61 marks to 66.06 marks.</p>
<p>Chemical shares were indeed back in vogue, recovering from losses tied to Hoechst dampening investor interest at the beginning of March with a weaker-than-expected outlook for 1997 and had generally outperformed the DAX index.  </p>
<p>Traders looked for the chemical sector to lead the market in the near-term, fuelled by Hoechst chairman Juergen Dormann giving a positive outlook in recent public presentations.</p>
<p>Carmakers also benefited from the stronger dollar as luxury carmaker Porsche AG surged 210 marks to 2,530 marks after Lehman Brothers raised its price estimate for Porsche to 3,600 marks from 3,000 marks.</p>
<p>But rival carmaker BMW AG slumped 24 marks to 1,419 marks and Volkswagen fell 6.50 marks to 1,330.50 marks as investors shifted their weighting within the sector.  </p>
<p>One top loser among DAX shares was airline Lufthansa AG, which fell 1.05 marks to 32.40 marks on profit-taking after recent sharp gains.</p>
<p>Market attention also focussed on software group Beta Systems AG, the share price of which more than doubled on Monday from its initial public offering price of 100 marks to end the session at 206 marks.</p>
<p>Beta Systems shares ended down 21 marks at 185 marks.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
