<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700156" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU launches high-tech venture capital scheme.</title>
<headline>EU launches high-tech venture capital scheme.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union launched a scheme on Tuesday to help make venture capital available to innovative small companies, saying Europe should take a cue from the United States in its effort to create jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe can't just sit back and concentrate on classical technologies and classical industries,&quot; EU Research Commissioner Edith Cresson told a news conference.</p>
<p>The pilot plan, an initiative of the European Commission and European Investment Fund (EIF), aims to encourage investments in start-up high-technology projects by offering money to help cover administrative costs.</p>
<p>The Commission said in a statement it had contributed 7.5 million ecus ($8.5 million) to the project, known as I-TEC, which was endorsed by EU leaders at their summit in Amsterdam earlier this month as a way to tackle high unemployment.</p>
<p>That money will complement 75 million Ecus ($84.8 million) in venture capital that the EIF -- a partnership between the EU and 77 financial institutions -- has already targeted for small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) through 1998.</p>
<p>Cresson said European investors needed to overcome their traditional resistance to investing in new and smaller companies in sectors such as information technology and biotechnology, saying the United States had led Europe in creating jobs by taking that approach.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not talking about any old jobs being created in fast food stores,&quot; she said. &quot;Most of the jobs created in the United States are in markets for the future.&quot;</p>
<p>The new money will be offered to qualified venture capital operators to cover up to 50 percent of the costs of appraising and managing investments. The maximum contribution will be five percent of the investments made, with a ceiling of 500,000 ecus ($565,000).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150203">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
