<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700399" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK manufacturing expands for 13th month in June.</title>
<headline>UK manufacturing expands for 13th month in June.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>British manufacturing expanded for the 13th month in a row in June, the Chartered Institute of Purchasing and Supply (CIPS) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Its seasonally adjusted purchasing managers' index (PMI) dipped to 53.4 from 54.4 in May, but any reading above 50 signals an expansion in manufacturing.</p>
<p>&quot;The main source of new business was the domestic market, with the strength of the pound again reported to have significantly subdued foreign demand,&quot; the CIPS said.</p>
<p>Export orders rose modestly due to the continued strengthening of economic growth in overseas markets and total order levels showed significant growth as a result.</p>
<p>The report, which is sponsored by Reuters, is considered to be a reliable barometer of the performance of manufacturing industry.</p>
<p>Purchasing managers reported further growth in output to meet the rise in order books. However, although more than a quarter of all firms raised production during the month, growth slowed compared to the level recorded in May and was the lowest level seen so far this year.</p>
<p>The deceleration was in part attributable to an increased incidence of firms deliberately reducing stocks of finished goods in order to cut costs.</p>
<p>The CIPS said companies had yet to experience significant capacity constraints or the potential inflationary impact on prices that tends to accompany supply shortages.</p>
<p>&quot;Suppliers were reported to have had little difficulty in meeting existing levels of demand and one in five firms recorded a fall in prices compared with May,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Manufacturers reported a further significant fall in input prices in June and average prices have now fallen for 20 consecutive months.</p>
<p>The strength of the pound was again the principal factor behind falling input prices.</p>
<p>Manufacturing firms remained reluctant to take on new staff in June and employment showed only modest growth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
