<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700318" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed expected to hold interest rates steady.</title>
<headline>Fed expected to hold interest rates steady.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve is expected to decide to hold interest rates steady at a two-day meeting that begins on Tuesday as it tries to gauge the future course of the U.S. economy, analysts said.</p>
<p>With economic growth slowing from its pell-mell first-quarter pace and inflation low, central bank Chairman Alan Greenspan should have little trouble persuading fellow policy-makers to hold off from raising rates, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is performing admirably,&quot; said Robert Dederick at Northern Trust Co. in Chicago. &quot;There isn't any reason for them to change rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Economic data released on Tuesday buttressed that view, painting a picture of an economy that is growing solidly without any worrisome signs of inflation.</p>
<p>A key gauge of the health of the manufacturing industry dipped in June, and construction spending eased. But an index of leading indicators pointed to continued growth ahead.</p>
<p>The central bank's policy-setting Federal Open Market Committee is expected to announce its rate decision at about 2:15 p.m. EDT/1815 GMT on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Fed increased short-term rates in March for the first time in more than two years in a bid to brake the economy's growth and keep inflation from rising. The federal funds rate -- the rate banks charge each other for overnight loans -- was raised a quarter percentage point to 5-1/2 percent.</p>
<p>But the central bank held off from tightening credit further at its last meeting in May, largely at the behest of Greenspan, who argued the economy would slow on its own without another rate rise by the Fed.</p>
<p>That is indeed what has happened. Growth appears to have slowed to a 1-1/2 percent to 2 percent annualized pace in the second quarter from a sizzling 5.9 percent rate in the first, the fastest clip in more than nine years, analysts said.</p>
<p>Politics also would seem to argue against a rate rise now, they said. Greenspan is slated to present the Fed's semi-annual assessment of the economy to Congress on July 22 and would find it hard to defend a rate hike to lawmakers when growth is slowing and inflation is low.</p>
<p>&quot;With the second-quarter slowdown, for the Fed to tighten now would really draw the wrath of Congress,&quot; said economist David Seiders of the National Association of Home Builders.</p>
<p>Anti-inflation hawks at the Fed recognise it would be difficult for the central bank to raise rates at a time of slowing growth. But they believe higher rates will be needed eventually to keep inflation in check because the economy is already running above capacity.</p>
<p>At 4.8 percent, the unemployment rate is at its lowest point in nearly 24 years and is well below levels that in the past have led to stepped-up wage demands and higher inflation.</p>
<p>However, Fed officials said Greenspan is sceptical of claims that low unemployment causes inflation and believes policy-makers should instead look for signs of stresses and strains in the economy in setting interest rates.</p>
<p>So far, there are not many such signs. By some measures, inflation appears to be decelerating, not accelerating. Wages are rising, thanks to the tight labour market, but not yet at a pace that portends faster inflation.</p>
<p>Fed officials said Greenspan welcomes higher wages as long as they are matched by increased worker productivity, and thus are not inflationary.</p>
<p>Some analysts believe one sign of possible strain in the economy is the ebullient stock market.</p>
<p>If the market's heady rise -- blue chips advanced by more than 16 percent in the second quarter alone -- prompts wealthy consumers to go on a spending spree, that could fuel inflation. But so far that is not happening.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
