<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700477" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: FOCUS-C-C Amatil finalises San Miguel deal.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-C-C Amatil finalises San Miguel deal.</headline>
<byline>Richard Pullin</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shareholders in Australian soft-drink bottler Coca-Cola Amatil Ltd gave final approval on Tuesday to an agreement with San Miguel Corp to create the largest Coca-Cola bottler outside the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;With good sales margins and relatively high per capita consumption the Philippines offers C-C Amatil shareholders substantial and immediate bottom-line benefits,&quot; chairman Dean Wills told an extraordinary general meeting.  </p>
<p>Under the share-swap deal, C-C Amatil will acquire the giant Philippine group's soft-drink subsidiary, while San Miguel will receive 192.5 million shares, a 25 percent stake, in C-C Amatil.</p>
<p>The Coca-Cola Co, which owned 30 percent of the San Miguel subsidiary, Coca-Cola Bottler Philippines Inc (CCBPI), will also be issued with new shares in C-C Amatil, but its total holding will be diluted to 33 percent from 36 percent.</p>
<p>The deal was valued at A$3.4 billion, based on C-C Amatil's average share price in March, but is worth considerably more at present.  </p>
<p>While some San Miguel shareholders felt they should have received a greater stake in C-C Amatil, the merger has kickstarted the Australian group's shares off their lows following a profit warning late last year.</p>
<p>Since the April 3 announcement, C-C Amatil's share price has soared to past the A$17 mark from below A$12, a 43 percent gain in just three months.</p>
<p>Analysts have said C-C Amatil would receive an immediate boost from the acquisition, given that CCBPI generated almost identical profits to C-C Amatil in 1996, but on half the sales.  </p>
<p>Wills told reporters after the meeting he believed the share price rise was also driven by the market's assessment of the company's future potential.</p>
<p>Based on 1996 figures, the expanded group would service a consumer population of 450 milion people, generate sales revenue of A$4.87 billion and a net profit of about A$286 million.</p>
<p>&quot;This is of great strategic importance to us,&quot; said Wills. (It) gives us a very strong foundation in Asia.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts have speculated that C-C Amatil may continue its rapid expansion, seeking franchises in other Asian countries, in particular the vast Indian market.  </p>
<p>Wills said C-C Amatil was aiming to increase total consumption in its Asian markets, and would look to replicate the success of marketing in the Philippines in other Asia countries.</p>
<p>Some cost savings could also be expected through strategies such as combining sugar purchases, although the CCBPI was very well run.</p>
<p>&quot;Our number one objective (in the Philippines) is to keep that management team in place,&quot; added chief executive Norb Cole.  </p>
<p>San Miguel will take four places on an expanded C-C Amatil board as part of the deal, and has nominated its chairman and chief executive Andres Soriano and chief finance officer-treasurer Delfin Gonzalez.</p>
<p>Rafael Alunan, a former secretary of the department of the interior and local government, is the third nominee, while a fourth, independent director -- who will also be an Austraian citizen -- has yet to be named.</p>
<p>C-C Amatil shares were trading 22 cents lower at A$16.98 at 3.55 p.m. (0540 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
