<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70056" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Sept 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Sept 23.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Kenyan press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY NATION</p>
<p>- Major plan for pension schemes: a bill is drafted proposing establishment of an authority empowered to run all pension revenue schemes in the government and private sectors, including the state National Social Security Fund.</p>
<p>- Supreme Council of Moslems of Kenya add their voice to a call for constitutional reforms.</p>
<p>- A convicted rapist is arrested in connection with the rape and murder of a five-year-old girl in the Rift Valley town of Nakuru after girl's naked body found dumped in maize plantation.</p>
<p>EAST AFRICAN STANDARD</p>
<p>- Controversial corned beef consignment impounded in Kenyan port of Mombasa by authorities is unlikely to be British, the British agriculture ministry says.</p>
<p>- Farmers are opposed to any plan to sell the giant Kenya Planters' Cooperative Union, two directors of the farm agency and main Kenyan coffee miller say.</p>
<p>KENYA TIMES</p>
<p>- The Law Society of Kenya has admitted that some of its unscrupulous members were using the society as a conduit to con unsuspecting donors of millions of shillings on purported campaigns to press for constitutional reforms in Kenya.</p>
<p>- Fate of 400 pupils in a 30-year-old primary school in Bomet district of the Rift Valley region in the balance after a land grabber threatens to kick them out.</p>
<p>EAST AFRICAN</p>
<p>- Burundi leader Major Pierre Buyoya says he may cut short his planned three years of military rule if the internal situation is brought under control but warns that if regional sanctions continue much longer, the country will explode.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
