<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70075" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Sept 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Sept 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's national carrier Balkan Airlines' two leased Boeing 767 aircraft cuased some 67 percent of the company's losses, the company balance sheet shows.</p>
<p>-- Managers and other staff of Bulgaria's tobacco holding Bulgartabak are expected to buy some 51 percent of the firms in the holding, the company's chief Spas Gelemerov said. @</p>
<p>-- Depositors in bankrupt banks should be compensated only after the court declares the financial institutions' insolvent, trade minister Atanas Paparizov told the national television.</p>
<p>Under the current deposit guarantee law the state covers individual deposits in full as soon as the central bank opens bankruptcy procedure against debt-ridden banks.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet decided on Sunday that six banks would be closed and the most attractive state firms would be offered for sale, the newspaper said without quoting sources. @</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria may use part of privatisation proceeds to guarantee deposits in bankrupt banks and to cover foreign debt principal payments, deputy prime minister Roumen Gechev said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's transport ministry is expected to discuss today a new financial plan for Sofia airport's reconstruction.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria will seek an increase in its ferrous metal exports to the European Union from current 50,000 to 75,000 tonnes during a meeting on September 25 in Sofia, industry ministry officials said.</p>
<p>KONTINENT</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>-- The Bulgarian-Russian gas company Topenergy's shareholders' meeting in Moscow did not decide on a capital rise from 120 million levs to $5 million at a shareholders meeting on Friday expecting the Bulgarian government to grant it concession rights on gas pipelines running through Bulgaria.</p>
<p>The energy minister Roumen Ovcharov said that a concession will be granted by October 15.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria is expected to sign today the contract for the sale of Sheraton Sofia Balkan Hotel to South Korea's industrial giant Daewoo for $22.3 million.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>-- Some 60 million levs have been withdrawn from the Varna branch of Bulgaria's second largest credit institution, the State Savings Bank, on Friday to rumors that depositors' accounts might be blocked for seven years.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet approved a final list of big state-owned firms that it plans to privatise by the end of the year at a closed door session on Sunday.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
