<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70074" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Sept 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Sept 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- Despite the motion by Poland's Culture Minister Zdzislaw Podkanski, the Patent Office has upheld the Siedlce-based Polmos liqueur distillery's right to use Frederick Chopin's profile to advertise its product, patent office President Wieslaw Kotarba said.</p>
<p>- Poland's egg imports were worth $5.7 million in 1996's first half, showing soaring growth from the $850,000 in the same period last year. Most of the imports came from CEFTA countries, the Foundation for Agricultural Assistance said.</p>
<p>- The Szczecin shipyard has completed construction of a 22,990 DWT container ship for a Cypriot contractor. The vessel can carry up to 1726 containers.</p>
<p>- France Telecom has produced a digital network development programme for TPSA, Poland's telecom monopolist, which will fulfil the country's needs until the year 2010. The French company stressed the programme's low infrastructure costs, adapting capacity and service continuity.</p>
<p>- The newly-opened five star Warsaw Sheraton Hotel and Towers provides 350 beds and office space for rental. The hotel's construction cost $80 million, Sheraton European division President Robert Cotter said.</p>
<p>- A congress of Poland's non-governmental organisations assisted by the EU's PHARE programme took place last weekend in Warsaw. It was attended by 3,000 representatives from more than 1,000 institutions and organisations operating around the country.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- Isuzu, the Japanese car maker, will invest $460 million in Poland in the construction of a diesel engine factory. Though an initial plan envisaged the factory's construction in Britain, lower production costs in Poland made Isuzu move here.</p>
<p>- The construction of a new customs-clearance truck terminal at Koroszczyn on the Polish-Belarus border has got off the ground, Poland's Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz said at a meeting with Belarus Prime Minister Mikhail Czykhir on Saturday.</p>
<p>- Fuelling statons in the Opole province in southwestern Poland have started selling diesel fuel imported from Slovakia, the price of which exceeds locally-made fuel by 0.3 zloty per litre. Polish refineries currently meet 80 percent of the country's diesel fuel domestic demand.</p>
<p>- American Home Box Office cable TV network has recently started to operate in the city of Radom, central Poland.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- Despite growing competition on Poland's mobile phone market, substantial service price cuts are not likely to take place before the second half of next year.</p>
<p>- The coming provincial governors' convention will present a proposal for regional air connections operated by local air taxi services. Polish Airlines LOT, the country's major airline, provides inefficient services resulting in a loss of air traffic passengers, Wroclaw provincial governor and convention president Jerzy Zalewski said.</p>
<p>- A Canadian company has built a new computer-managed potato silo with 1200-tonne capacity in Przesmyki, central Poland.</p>
<p>- The Rejowiec sugar concern, which is part of the Lublin-Malopolska sugar holding, has started its sugar processing campaign, the plant's director Ludwik Wajcht said.</p>
<p>ZYCIE WARSZAWY</p>
<p>- The complexity of economic processes taking place in the EU is likely to put off Poland's membersip to the year 2005, former defence minister Jerzy Onyszkiewicz said.</p>
<p>- Co-ruling Polish Peasant Party (PSL) Chairman Waldemar Pawlak said he would not conduct talks on a possible future coalition with Solidarity trade union leader Marian Krzaklewski and would concentrate on the country's main economic and social problems.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
