<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700813" id="root" date="1997-07-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Markka seen on the rise as urge to tighten mounts.</title>
<headline>Markka seen on the rise as urge to tighten mounts.</headline>
<byline>Tuula Franck</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Finnish markka is undervalued despite strong economic growth and a large current account surplus, and further resistance to its strengthening risks the economy overheating, analysts say.</p>
<p>Some expect a new wave of speculation to push the currency stronger in the near term, posing a tough problem for the Bank of Finland, which has at times intervened to curb volatility, but also recently warned of mounting inflationary signs.</p>
<p>Market operators interviewed by Reuters on Monday departed from an earlier consensus view on the markka's DEM/FIM conversion rate to euros, looking to a firmer 2.75-2.95 range.</p>
<p>At end-May a Reuters poll pointed to conversion with DEM/FIM at a weaker 3.04, its central parity rate in the Exchange Rate Mechanism (ERM).</p>
<p>&quot;Keeping the Finnish currency artificially weak makes monetary policy tightening difficult, even though the economy is in the process of overheating,&quot; said Jukka Lepomaki, chief analyst at Merita Bank.</p>
<p>Hiking the tender rate, the chief monetary policy tool, would increase pressure for the markka to rise, he added.</p>
<p>Finland's tender rate is currently on par with the German repo rate at 3.00 percent, but the central bank has warned of mounting inflationary pressures, which may prompt tightening.</p>
<p>Jim O'Neill, chief currency economist at Goldman Sachs in London, said the Bank of Finland is likely to start tightening if June inflation figures due on July 15 show prices to be on the rise. In May, CPI rose by 0.9 percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>&quot;The Finnish authorities will have to use the 15 percent flutuation band (in ERM),&quot; he said, noting that in the near term, monetary conditions would likely be tightened by a stronger markka.</p>
<p>Experts said the markka is clearly undervalued at the moment -- repeating a view voiced by some overseas players earlier this year, which prompted speculative buying.</p>
<p>&quot;If the dollar stays firm on speculation of a weak euro, it looks like the markka would be 15-20 percent undervalued against the German mark,&quot; said Petteri Hirvonen, chief economist and Davy Protos in Helsinki.</p>
<p>O'Neill shared that view, saying even though Finnish inflation has been very low and productivity strong, &quot;the Finnish currency hasn't benefitted from it&quot;.</p>
<p>The markka traded around 2.9800 per mark on Monday and stood at 2.9780 per mark early Tuesday.</p>
<p>Hirvonen and Lepomaki expected a markka buying spree already this summer, mainly based on strong growth in the economy. GDP rose by 8.0 percent year-on-year in April.</p>
<p>O'Neill said the direction of the Irish pound will be key: &quot;If the (Irish) pound is revalued, it would result in similar pressures for the markka as well,&quot; he said. The Irish pound is also in the ERM.</p>
<p>O'Neill expected the markka to be converted into euros at a DEM/FIM rate of 2.75. Hirvonen forecast the conversion rate at 2.82, while Lepomaki saw it at around 2.95. The most likely time for the decision would be next spring, they said.</p>
<p>The 3.04 central parity rate in ERM has so far been widely considered the most likely fixing rate but comments by a senior official at Finance Ministry last Friday &quot;gave some more room to play (with the expected conversion rate)&quot;, said Lepomaki.</p>
<p>Martti Hetemaki, head of the ministry's economics department said the ERM central parity rate was &quot;only one method&quot; for conversion.</p>
<p>He added that it was too early to talk about the level, when even the conversion principles have not been agreed.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +3589 6805 0247, e-mail news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
