<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="700916" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks play catch-up, end 1.7 pct higher.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks play catch-up, end 1.7 pct higher.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>CHANGE</p>
<p>TSE	 6549.04 +111.30   HI 6549.04	    LO  6471.45</p>
<p>DJI	 7795.38  +73.05   GOLD (LONDON)   US$332.15  -1.55</p>
<p>FTSE	4751.40  +23.10   GOLD (NY-SPOT)  US$333.70  -1.40</p>
<p>NIKKEI   20196.42  +20.90   LME CASH NICKEL US$6800  -165.00</p>
<p>CANDLR     1.3757	     LME CASH ALUM   US$1589.0  +27.0</p>
<p>CAN 30-YR  115.46   +1.14   BRENT CRUDE     US$18.92   +0.12</p>
<p>---------------------MARKET COMMENT--------------------------</p>
<p>* Toronto's key index climbed 1.7 percent in light trading by</p>
<p>the end of Wednesday after U.S. Federal Reserve held rates</p>
<p>steady. * Also played catch-up with New York's gains Tuesday.</p>
<p>Toronto's key equities index surged more than 1.7 percent on Wednesday as investors celebrated a decision by the U.S. central bank to hold U.S. short-term interest rates steady.</p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange's 300 Composite Index climbed 111.30 points to end the day at 6549.04, just below the all-time high of 6557 set on June 16.</p>
<p>Market players widely expected the Federal Reserve to keep rates unchanged after a two-day committee meeting, but still breathed a sign of relief, RBC Dominion Securities investment adviser Ira Katzin said.  </p>
<p>Trading was modest at 82 million shares worth C$1.6 billion. The 300 Composite Index came close but failed to break its record close of 6550.61 points on June 13.</p>
<p>Investors also pushed Toronto higher in an attempt to match New York's 50-point gain on Tuesday when desks were shut down for the Canada Day holiday, Katzin said. &quot;The Canadian market also played catch-up to the U.S.'s solid performance yesterday.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial Average also soared 73 points to 7795 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A trader wondered when the TSE's recent rally would end. &quot;I'm getting nosebleeds off this market but you can't fight the tape,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>All Toronto's 14 sub-indexes gained ground, led by media, heavyweight banks, utilities, pipelines and conglomerates.</p>
<p>Advancing issues edged out declining ones 483 to 448 while 277 ended steady.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Shares in small oil firm Grad &amp; Walker Energy Corp jumped 2.35 to 13.50 and topped the most actives after Crestar Energy Inc said it agreed to acquire Grad &amp; Walker in a C$336.2 million deal.</p>
<p>Crestar offered Grad &amp; Walker holders C$13.50 in cash or 0.509 Crestar common shares for each Grad &amp; Walker common share.</p>
<p>((Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8109))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
