<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701174" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: TRANZITU TO SERVICE WB LOAN, TALK WITH SWEDFUND.</title>
<headline>TRANZITU TO SERVICE WB LOAN, TALK WITH SWEDFUND.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latvia's Baltijas Tranzitu Bank said on Wednesday that it has won the right to service a $35 million World Bank loan to credit investment projects.</p>
<p>&quot;Baltijas Tranzitu Bank has the right to use these funds to credit investment projects,&quot; the bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time, the bank has the possibility to use World Bank, Danish and EU PHARE technical help and also to start talks with the Swedish capital fund (Swedfund) on this institution entering into the capital of Baltijas Tranzitu Bank.&quot; it added.  </p>
<p>The World Bank deal was signed by the bank's president Galina Alijeva and vice-president Kaspars Krauze and the World Bank technical unit director at the finance ministry, Arnis Lagzdinsh.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement with the World Bank to use this credit line proves that Baltijas Tranzitu Bank is a stable bank, which does not aim at just getting quick profits,&quot; Alijeva said.</p>
<p>It said that it wanted to make work in the import-export sector one of its priorities and that therefore it would use the World Bank credit to finance Latvian private business projects.</p>
<p>-- Patrick Lannin, Riga newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
