<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701230" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Germany, France signal tough ride for US on NATO.</title>
<headline>Germany, France signal tough ride for US on NATO.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Dowd</byline>
<text>
<p>LONDON, July 3 Reuter) - France and Germany appeared on a collision course with the United States over the issue of NATO's expansion into Eastern Europe ahead of next week's historic Madrid summit of the Western Alliance.</p>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl threw his weight behind Romania's bid for early membership on Wednesday after meeting Romanian President Emil Constantinescu in Bonn, while Paris insisted that five former communist countries -- Romania and Slovenia as well as the three that Washington is ready to accept --- qualify for early membership.</p>
<p>France also highlighted another issue that could raise the temperature in Madrid, saying conditions were not yet ripe for it to return to full membership of NATO's military wing, which it quit in 1966 in protest at U.S. domination.</p>
<p>This set the scene for a possible summit clash between French President Jacques Chirac and U.S. President Bill Clinton on transatlantic power-sharing as well as the shape of the alliance's eastward enlargement.</p>
<p>U.S. administration officials in Washington insisted on Wednesday that Clinton, who will lead efforts to &quot;recreate&quot; NATO at the July 8-9 summit, will resist pressure to invite more than three nations to join.</p>
<p>&quot;The answer is not no, but no at this time,&quot; White House National Security Adviser Sandy Berger said when reporters asked about the U.S. attitude towards admitting Romania and Slovenia -- which Washington would rather wait for a second round of expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;I would think there'd be some lively discussion of this (at the summit) but at the end of the day ... I think it's fair to say that there will be a consensus on the three.&quot;</p>
<p>Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic are considered sure to get invitations from the summit for early membership of NATO.</p>
<p>On the issue of returning to NATO's military wing, France's Foreign Ministry said France wanted &quot;to continue discussions with its allies to seek a better balance of responsibilities between Europeans and Americans&quot;.</p>
<p>The statement made clear that Chirac, who initiated a rapprochement with NATO in 1995, shared the new left-wing government's view that Washington had not yielded sufficient power to the European allies to justify a return.</p>
<p>Paris has demanded in vain that Washington hand over NATO's key southern command, which controls the Mediterranean, to a European officer.</p>
<p>&quot;On enlargement, France reaffirms that five countries now meet the conditions for joining the alliance,&quot; the ministry said, alluding to Romania and Slovenia, as well as the three Washington accepts.</p>
<p>Clinton, who leaves for Spain late on Friday, has already declared publicly that he wants NATO to extend membership only to Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic in the hope that would quiet efforts to admit additional members.</p>
<p>Bonn and Paris dug in their heels  on the central issue of NATO enlargement as U.S. officials said Clinton, Secretary of State Madeleine Albright and Defence Secretary William Cohen will fan out across Eastern and Central Europe after the summit to explain U.S. policy on expansion of the alliance.</p>
<p>Romania's President Constantinescu saw Kohl in a last-ditch attempt to elicit support from Europe's largest NATO member, whose voice could be decisive in Madrid.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chancellor said... that the government and himself have a lot of sympathy for the Romanian desire for early NATO membership and support it,&quot; government spokesman Peter Hausmann said.</p>
<p>&quot;He indicated that this decision should be made on the basis of consensus of the 16 NATO partners in Madrid,&quot; Hausmann added.</p>
<p>Chirac said last month that he and Kohl wanted Romania and Slovenia to be allowed to join NATO from the start. Kohl did not go that far then, saying Germany wanted all five to be given a clear message at the summit that they would be part of the development of the alliance.</p>
<p>Italy has also been pressing the alliance to invite Romania and Slovenia during its July summit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
