<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70138" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares rebound, seen extending gains.</title>
<headline>Polish shares rebound, seen extending gains.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares on Monday rebounded after a two-day fall and analysts said that though the stronger buying after price-fixing signalled another gain on Tuesday, Monday's stable turnover suggested slow growth.</p>
<p>The main WIG index, currently at 14,656.5 points, set a 30-month high at 14,832.7 points last Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If more capital doesn't flow in we're not going to be able to significantly beat our recent high, rather we'll oscillate around it,&quot; said Artur Czerwonski of Bank Pekao SA brokerage.</p>
<p>Some analysts said a possible rate rise in the United States on Tuesday could be dampening foreign stock buying.</p>
<p>The main market's all-share WIG index rose 1.1 percent to 14,656.5 points and turnover inched up 0.6 percent to 104.5 million zlotys ($37.4 million) on both markets. Gainers led losers by 59 to seven with 12 stocks flat.</p>
<p>Analysts said large-cap bank stocks that showed strong selling after price-fixing such as BPH, BRE and Bank Slaski may hit a correction on Tuesday after recent gains.</p>
<p>But they said top gainer Bank Komunalny, which jumped seven percent to 24.5 zlotys ($8.8), might continue rising from last week's debut at 23 zlotys ($8.2).</p>
<p>Analysts also said biggest loser brewer Zywiec, down 6.4 percent, fell in profit-taking but should rebound on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Continuous trade turnover was at 1.7 million zlotys ($0.6 million) with biggest mover steel trader Stalexport up 3.9 percent.</p>
<p>NFI units rose 7.4 percent to 137.5 zlotys ($49.2) in a 31.3-million-zloty ($11.2 million) turnover and dipped 0.4 percent in a continuous trade turnover of 10 million zlotys ($3.6 million).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
