<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701301" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK budget too soft on consumers, industry says.</title>
<headline>UK budget too soft on consumers, industry says.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>British industry welcomed cuts in corporate taxation in the Labour government's budget on Wednesday, but expressed concern that the budget's overall impact would not cool consumer spending and interest rates would have to rise.</p>
<p>Ruth Lea, head of the policy unit at the Institute of Directors (IOD), said IOD reaction to the budget was mixed.</p>
<p>The Institute was pleased by the unexpected cut in corporation tax to 31 percent from 33, but the abolition of tax credits paid to pension funds and companies was not good news.</p>
<p>&quot;Companies will have to put more money into their pension funds,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Currently companies pay 20 percent Advance Corporation Tax on dividends, which can be claimed back by tax-exempt investors such as pension funds.</p>
<p>Lea said the budget had not done enough to dampen down consumer spending and that Chancellor of the Exchequer Gordon Brown's forecasts for consumer spending of 4.5 percent this year and four percent in 1998 were very strong.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no doubt there's not a big enough hit on the personal sector,&quot; Lea said.</p>
<p>The British Chambers of Commerce was also delighted at the reduction in corporation tax for large and small firms, which it said would encourage investment.</p>
<p>Economist Ian Fletcher said it was a good budget for investment, but the overall fiscal tightening would not be enough to prevent interest rate rises.</p>
<p>&quot;On the downside we don't think the tightening in fiscal policy is enough to circumvent further interest rate rises over the next couple of months.&quot;</p>
<p>Fletcher said most of the measures to restrain spending would not take effect until next year.  </p>
<p>The British Chambers of Commerce's view was the budget had not stamped hard enough on inflationary pressures in the economy so that interest rates would have to rise, the pound would continue to strengthen and exporters would continue to suffer.</p>
<p>Lea at the IOD was sceptical that Brown's measures to prevent overheating in housing market would be effective.</p>
<p>Brown said he would cut tax relief on mortgage interest payments to 10 percent from 15 percent from April 1998 and raise stamp duty to 1.5 percent from one percent on property sales above 250,000 stg and to two percent above 500,000.</p>
<p>Lea said these were not tough enough to calm the housing market, where prices have surged ahead particularly in the south east of the country.</p>
<p>&quot;If he thinks this will take the sting out of the housing market it won't,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>--Jane Merriman, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
