<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701456" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanian president to resign once left takes power.</title>
<headline>Albanian president to resign once left takes power.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian President Sali Berisha said on Wednesday he would resign when a leftist government took power, but tried to ensure his defeated Democratic Party stayed in control of security forces at least temporarily.</p>
<p>The Socialist Party has claimed victory in the first round of last Sunday's early general election and Berisha conceded the defeat of his Democrats less than 24 hours after polls closed. A second round takes place on July 6.</p>
<p>But Berisha and rival Socialist leaders appeared intent on flexing their political muscle until the election is over in what looks likely to be an uneasy transition of power.</p>
<p>Berisha, holding his first news conference since Sunday's election, said he expected the Socialists, reformed heirs of the communist party, to lead Albania's new administration.</p>
<p>Pressed repeatedly on whether he would therefore resign, the president, in power since 1992, said in English:</p>
<p>&quot;Definitely. There is no doubt of that. I never had the smallest doubt in that respect.&quot;</p>
<p>Berisha stressed that he had certain constitutional duties to perform before the next government was formed, suggesting he would finally hand in his resignation once the new parliament convened. Under the constitution, parliament elects and removes the head of state.</p>
<p>Berisha, Albania's first non-communist president, won plaudits in the West for trying to steer his country on the path of market reform, but later drew criticism for increasingly authoritarian rule.</p>
<p>While most of the Balkan nation remained relatively calm after months of violence, a state of emergency and 10 p.m. to 5 a.m. curfew are still in force.</p>
<p>Armoured vehicles roared around Tirana's main streets on Tuesday night and armed groups confronted each other into the early hours of the morning in the city's central Skanderbeg Square. It was impossible to identify which institutions they represented. No shots were fired and they later dispersed.</p>
<p>Control of the security forces is considered vital in a country slowly emerging from 45 years of Stalinist rule, ended by a popular revolt in 1990. The interior ministry is in charge of police and other security groups.</p>
<p>A public row on Wednesday between Berisha and interim Prime Minister Bashkim Fino over the whereabouts of Interior Minister Belul Celo demonstrated the importance of the post.</p>
<p>Fino, a Socialist appointed as prime minister on March 11 to lead a 10-party unity government ahead of the general election, denied that Celo, a member of Berisha's Democrats, had fled the country. He rejected Berisha's order to replace him with another of his loyalists.</p>
<p>&quot;Today, Mr Celo called his deputy minister saying he had not resigned and will be back in office to serve until the end of my government mandate,&quot; Fino told a news conference.</p>
<p>The Democrats remain in control of the interior ministry under a March agreement until a new government is formed.</p>
<p>But Berisha was adamant that the minister had fled and wanted to make sure his party had someone at the helm.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no interior minister and there is no commander of operations,&quot; he said. &quot;It is the right of the Democratic Party to propose (a candidate).&quot;</p>
<p>Fino's interim government was set up in the wake of unrest following the collapse of pyramid investment schemes. It agreed to prepare for elections aimed at quelling violence which has claimed the lives of more than 1,500 people.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the central electoral commission was still busily working on the results of Sunday's first round but figures were painfully slow in emerging.</p>
<p>The commission said counting was complete in 72 of 115 constituencies run under majority voting but could not say how many seats had been won by each party. Run-offs in districts where no candidate took 50 percent will be held next Sunday.</p>
<p>In 40 seats voted for under a proportional system, the Socialists scored 51.4 percent of the vote and two allied parties won a total of five percent. The Democrats had 26.5 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
