<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701492" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian c.bank urges banks to extend credits.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian c.bank urges banks to extend credits.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) on Wednesday urged local commercial banks to extend loans to firms to boost the stagnant economy and compensate for low gains from state securities, a commercial banker said.</p>
<p>&quot;The BNB suggested that banks should intensify lending aimed at helping the economy recover, which could also compensate the low yield on state treasuries,&quot; Ognian Enchev, chairman of the Association of Commercial Banks, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Speaking after a meeting with the BNB board, Enchev said that many banks still remained cautious and considered lending to the real economy a risk because of a lack of financial discipline and the slow pace of restructuring.</p>
<p>&quot;Since Bulgaria introduced the currency board system, the time for aggressive loan extension is over,&quot; Enchev said.</p>
<p>A chain of bad loans and lavish lending in the banking sector was halted last year only when the central bank placed a third of the country's banks under supervision and started bankruptcy proceedings against them.</p>
<p>On Tuesday Bulgaria launched a currency board system designed to restore confidence in its shaky banks and currency.</p>
<p>The IMF-prescribed system requires that levs in circulation be matched by foreign exchange reserves and bans central bank lending to the government and commercial banks.</p>
<p>A domestic credit rating information system, due to be set up by the central bank by year-end, will also help commercial banks' lending policy.</p>
<p>Bank closures and past three-digit interest rates have practically stopped access to credits by companies.</p>
<p>Banks have so far focused on investment in high yielding government treasuries, but recent rate cuts have made these investments less attractive.</p>
<p>The fixed exchange rate of 1,000 levs to the mark in effect since Tuesday will lead to a decline in foreign exchange trade on the local market.</p>
<p>The BNB has advised the banks to maintain liquidity through interest rates and lending policies.</p>
<p>-- Roumiana Tikholova, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-981-4145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
