<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701572" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Dangers seen in Yugoslav drive to boost output.</title>
<headline>Dangers seen in Yugoslav drive to boost output.</headline>
<byline>Gordana Kukic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economic policy aimed at boosting Yugoslav production at any cost could cause disastrous damage to the country's development base, Belgrade analysts warned on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible to achieve industrial growth on the principle of producing only 90 dinars for an investment of 100. But in that way the capital will be irretrievably lost,&quot; said Stojan Stamenkovic, leading economist of the Institute for Economic Sciences.</p>
<p>According to official statistics, Yugoslav year-on-year industry growth in May was 9.3 percent. The figures for January-May were up 7.8 percent from the same 1996 period.</p>
<p>&quot;The paradox of the economy here is that while production rises firms incur losses,&quot; Stamenkovic said.</p>
<p>In 1996, industrial output rose 7.5 percent against 1995 but the economy suffered a net loss of some 8.75 billion dinars ($1.18 billion). Gross domestic product (GDP) was 68.15 billion dinars, 76 percent up on 1995. But it fell almost nine percent in real terms.</p>
<p>The target for 1997 is a 13 percent growth of GDP and 14 percent rise in industrial output.</p>
<p>Serbia, which together with Montenegro makes up Yugoslavia, faces a shortage of cash made worse by a credit blockade and an economy in recession. It has tried to ease the shortage by selling a 49 percent stake in Telekom Srbija to Italian and Greek companies.</p>
<p>The republic, which accounts for 95 percent of Yugoslavia's GDP, raised 1.568 billion German marks from the sale. Eighty percent of this amount is already in the coffers of the Serbian Development Fund. The balance is to be paid in January.</p>
<p>The Fund said the money would be used to boost export industries, agriculture and large infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>But economists said injections of cash into working capital would not be enough to bring about permanent development because of burgeoning company losses, outdated technology and growing social tensions.</p>
<p>The economy is also burdened with a $7 billion inter-company debt accumulated since 1994 when the economy started from scratch after hyperinflation of 60 percent a day.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a mistake to renew present structures. Structural changes and new market-oriented production should be financed,&quot; said Danilo Sukovic, head of the economic research department of Institute for Social Sciences.</p>
<p>Stamenkovic said it would be a mistake to repeat what happened in 1996, when seasonally adjusted industrial output rose 14 percent from June to end-November.</p>
<p>If financial injections fuelled a similar rise in the second half of this year, industrial output could surge beyond current gloomy forecasts to exceed the 1996 level by some six percent, he said.</p>
<p>Economists fear that funds could be allocated for reasons other than market ones.</p>
<p>&quot;Entrusting the distribution to the state fund carries the risk of most of the money being spent on preserving social peace ahead of presidental and parliamentary elections later this year,&quot; said director of the Institute for Foreign Trade Radovan Kovacevic.</p>
<p>One analyst, who asked not to be named, said the ruling Socialists were obviously prepared to sell other public companies as well as Telekom.</p>
<p>Economists say the country needs some $2 billion annually for the next five years to keep its economy going. -- Belgrade Newsroom +381 11 311 4254 ($ = 4.85 Yugoslav Dinars)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
