<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701505" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>GEORGIA: Russian officials urge Georgia to let troops stay.</title>
<headline>Russian officials urge Georgia to let troops stay.</headline>
<byline>Suren Babayan</byline>
<dateline>TBILISI 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two senior delegates from Moscow held separate talks with Georgian President Eduard Shevardnadze on Wednesday to try to persuade him not to end Russia's military presence in the former Soviet republic.</p>
<p>Yuri Baturin, secretary of Russia's Defence Council, said his mission was independent from that of Boris Berezovsky, Security Council Deputy Secretary engaged in shuttle diplomacy between Georgia and its breakaway Abkhazia region.</p>
<p>&quot;We each have our own questions. The aim of my visit is military strategic issues,&quot; Baturin told reporters after meeting Shavardnadze.</p>
<p>Asked what Moscow would do if Tbilisi carried out its threat to force Russia's 1,500 peacekeepers out after a July 31 deadline, he said they would have to go, but that Georgia could end up regretting their departure.</p>
<p>Georgian officials have said they do not want to renew the mandate for the troops unless they are prepared to do more to help resolve Tbilisi's long-running conflict with the separatists which led to a bloody civil war in 1992-3.</p>
<p>Tbilisi says it will demand the troops leave unless they help Georgian refugees return home and patrol more of Abkhazia.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is such a demand then the peacekeepers will of course have to leave. But I don't think that the situation will stay calm and easy after that,&quot; Baturin said.</p>
<p>&quot;I imagine there may be a renewal of the conflict. I don't think this is in anyone's interests. That's why we have discussed this problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Berezovsky's task is to try to bring the two sides together so they can sign a lasting peace deal, but his latest diplomatic offensive is clearly linked to the approaching deadline for the Russian peacekeepers.</p>
<p>On Tuesday he held two hours of one-on-one talks with Shevardnadze and then continued negotiations with other officials. He then flew to Abkhazia and back and held another three hours of talks with Shevardnadze on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm leaving for Abkhazia, difficult negotiations are going on, the technology of the negotiations is uninturrupted momentum, momentum, momentum,&quot; he said after Wednesday's talks.</p>
<p>Behind the peace talks and future of the peacekeepers lies the reason Moscow is so interested in the success of its latest diplomatic offensive in Georgia.</p>
<p>Tbilisi has hinted that if the peacekeepers leave, the issue of three former Soviet bases on its territory will also have to be raised.</p>
<p>In March 1995, Georgia signed an agreement with Russia, which inherited the bases, allowing them to stay for 25 years, but neither side has ratified the deal.</p>
<p>Georgian military officials say the bases contain at least 20,000 troops. Russia refuses to give details on what are Moscow's only military bases outside Russia, apart from in nearby Armenia, and as such have huge strategic importance.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that it is in the interests of both countries to preserve them (the bases). But discussions on this could continue,&quot; Baturin said.</p>
<p>In May the Georgian parliament said that if Russia could not regulate the conflict in Abkhazia then Georgia would ask peacekeepers to leave and raise the issue of the bases.</p>
<p>Georgia has felt sensitive about the bases since the civil war, when Shevardnadze accused Russia of giving the separatists military help and equipment in order to help dismember his state and force it to join the Moscow-led Commonwealth of Independent States, which groups most former Soviet republics.</p>
<p>Russia denies the charges but some of its military officers still in the region have said they acted as advisers to the Abkhaz and provided them with weapons.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GRGIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TBILISI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GEORGIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
