<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701509" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Improve record to get missile cash, US tells Minsk.</title>
<headline>Improve record to get missile cash, US tells Minsk.</headline>
<byline>Larisa Sayenko</byline>
<dateline>MINSK 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States told Belarus on Wednesday it would have to improve its human rights record if it wanted Washington to unfreeze funds intended to help Minsk destroy Soviet-era nuclear missile launch pads.</p>
<p>A senior Belarussian official said on Tuesday his country had stopped work on the sites because U.S. funding had dried up. Belarus was home to 72 SS-25 missiles, each with single nuclear warhead, when the old Soviet Union fell apart in 1991.</p>
<p>A U.S. State Department statement, faxed to Reuters by the Minsk office of the U.S. Information Service on Wednesday, said Belarus has misrepresented Washington's refusal to hand over the special aid funds to the former Soviet republic.</p>
<p>&quot;Some $40 million of planned Cooperative Threat Reduction (CTR) assistance was not released to Belarus in 1997 because the U.S. was unable to certify Belarus for compliance with the human rights requirements mandated by the CTR programme,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;Congress requires (this) for all countries receiving CTR funds,&quot; it added. &quot;We urge the government of Belarus to demonstrate a commitment to the observance of human rights and to avoid misrepresenting the facts.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States was due to provide $119 million for the destruction of the launch pads.</p>
<p>Last November, Belarus shipped the last warhead and missile to Russia under the START-1 international arms reduction treaty. Another two former Soviet republics, Ukraine and Kazakhstan, also transfered nuclear warheads to Russia.</p>
<p>About $60 million has already been spent and another instalment of $19 million was on the way, already authorised by Congress, the statement said.</p>
<p>Ivan Pashkevich, deputy head of President Alexander Lukashenko's administration, said on Tuesday Belarus had halted work because Washington had suspended further aid.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not have our own funds and are not going to borrow them somewhere else,&quot; Pashkevich told reporters. &quot;After the Americans stopped their aid we stopped all work on demolishing the pads.&quot;</p>
<p>Belarus has been sharply criticised by the United States and international human rights watchdogs for its human rights records. Lukashenko, who last November won sweeping powers in a constitutional referundum, takes a tough line on political opposition and independent media.</p>
<p>Some opposition politicians have been jailed for short terms and several newspapers forced to publish abroad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
