<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701553" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: U.N.'s Klein named as Westendorp deputy in Bosnia.</title>
<headline>U.N.'s Klein named as Westendorp deputy in Bosnia.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. General Jacques Klein has been named as one of two deputies to Carlos Westendorp, the international community's newly-appointed representative in Bosnia, Westendorp's office said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Klein is currently the administrator of the last Serb region in Croatia -- Eastern Slavonia. He is in charge of 5,000 United Nations peacekeepers who have run the region since January 1996 and who are due to leave by January next year.</p>
<p>Simon Haselock, spokesman for the international High Representative to Bosnia, told reporters after announcing Klein's appointment that Westendorp had asked the Americans to provide the name of someone with experience of the region.</p>
<p>Westendorp said in a statement he &quot;warmly welcomed&quot; Jacques Klein onto his staff.</p>
<p>&quot;He will bring with him considerable knowledge of the politics of the area through his experience and outstanding work...in Eastern Slavonia. I look forward very much to working with him in the months ahead,&quot; the statement read.</p>
<p>Tall, imposing and affable, Klein took a straight-talking approach to his task of preparing Eastern Slavonia for reintegration into Croatia and was respected by both sides for his impartiality and principled approach.</p>
<p>His replacement in Eastern Slavonia has not yet been named though sources said it would possibly be American diplomat William Walker.</p>
<p>Klein will replace Michael Steiner, a German diplomat who served as deputy for 18 months. A second deputy's post has also been created which German diplomat Gerd Wagner is expected to fill.</p>
<p>Bosnian Moslem leaders had lobbied Western governments to retain Steiner as deputy and local newspapers organised petitions on his behalf. His supporters viewed him as a tireless mediator who helped forge compromises within the troubled Moslem-Croat federation.</p>
<p>The High Representative's office has much less power than the post Klein held in Croatia. Westerndorp is charged with overseeing and coordinating civilian aspects of the Dayton peace treaty that ended the Bosnian war in November 1995.</p>
<p>He succeeds former Swedish prime minister Carl Bildt, who served 18 months in the post.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
