<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701792" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine officer casts doubt on &quot;Dirty War&quot; claim.</title>
<headline>Argentine officer casts doubt on &quot;Dirty War&quot; claim.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Argentine air force raised questions on Tuesday about a newspaper interview with a former air force chaplain who said military chaplains had known about human rights crimes during the &quot;Dirty War.&quot;</p>
<p>The newspaper Pagina 12's interview with a 76-year-old man identified only as Antonio would, if verified, be the first admission that Roman Catholic chaplains knew the military juntas that ruled from 1976 to 1983 were using wholesale kidnap, torture and murder in their campaign against suspected leftists.</p>
<p>Official estimates say 10,000 people &quot;disappeared&quot; in the Dirty War. Human rights groups say the figure is nearer 30,000.</p>
<p>&quot;Soldiers took them away and held them in concentration camps. If they stuck to their stance against the government, Argentina and democracy, they disappeared,&quot; Antonio was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>He appeared to be justifying the armed forces' action, saying, &quot;They wanted to purify the atmosphere, which was communist.&quot;</p>
<p>The only other clue to Antonio's identity was the claim he had been captured and held prisoner during the Falkland Islands War with Britain in 1982. But one air force officer told Reuters, &quot;There was only one chaplain captured in the Malvinas (the Argentine name for the Falklands), and he is still in the force.</p>
<p>&quot;The air force is surprised at all this, and at the moment, we are investigating what it's all about,&quot; the officer said.</p>
<p>Argentina's armed forces made a dramatic apology two years ago for their role in the terror, but the Church conducted only a lukewarm &quot;examination of conscience&quot; over its position on the crimes of military governments.</p>
<p>While members of the clergy were abducted and killed by the juntas, witnesses speak of military chaplains blessing the torturers and trying to get detainees to give information.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
