<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701789" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: BP to shift regional head to Venezuela.</title>
<headline>BP to shift regional head to Venezuela.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-07-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil giant British Petroleum Co Ltd said on Tuesday it would post a Latin American regional director in Caracas &quot;in the next few weeks&quot;, shifting the position away from Bogota where it has traditionally been based.</p>
<p>The post is currently held by Bogota-based John Doust, who is also the head of BP's Colombian unit BP Exploration (BPX). A BP spokesman said Doust would not be moving to Venezuela but that the position would be filled by a new appointee.</p>
<p>Doust, the spokesman said, would leave Colombia to return to Britain &quot;before the end of the year&quot;.</p>
<p>The spokesman rejected suggestions that BP's regional power base was being moved to Venezuela because of the protracted wrangle between BP and the state-run oil company Ecopetrol over the contract terms for the huge Piedemonte block in eastern Colombia.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason for this (move) is simply because our business in Colombia is mature while business in Venezuela is young and needs the support of a senior person with experience and knowledge to give BP's business a push there,&quot; the spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>BP has had a presence in Colombia for about the last decade but only set up in Venezuela about three years ago.</p>
<p>BP is the major partner in Colombia's Cusiana-Cupiagua block, which is expected to be producing about 500,000 barrels a day by early 1998 and has major stakes in the Central and Ocensa pipelines.</p>
<p>The spokesman was unable to say what BP's daily production figure in Venezuela was.</p>
<p>He said BPX's operations would continue to be run from Bogota while the new Latin American director would run Venezuelan and other region-wide operations.</p>
<p>The spokesman was unable to say who had been appointed to the post of Latin American regional director or who would replace Doust as head of BPX.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
