<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701726" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONTSERRAT: Montserrat volcano hits island's food supplies.</title>
<headline>Montserrat volcano hits island's food supplies.</headline>
<dateline>OLVESTON, Montserrat 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A spectacular volcanic eruption on the tiny Caribbean island of Montserrat is threatening food supplies, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;(Food) is a problem right now,&quot; government spokesman Herman Sargeant said, noting that the eruption had ripped through the island's farming belt.</p>
<p>&quot;The heavy concentration of gases and ash caused ... plants to wither, and that is very bad indeed ... A countless number of animals were killed as a result of the pyroclastic flow.&quot;</p>
<p>Last Wednesday, part of the giant dome of magma growing inside the British territory's Soufriere Hills volcano collapsed, dousing much of the island with ash and sending a pyroclastic flow -- a fast-moving rain of superheated gases and rock -- toward the eastern end of the island.</p>
<p>Seven villages were flattened and authorities have confirmed the deaths of nine people. After a week of searching in areas deep in ash, Montserrat authorities were still listing 24 people as missing.</p>
<p>The government has announced no plan for a complete evacuation of the 39-square-mile (104 sq km) eastern Caribbean island, although its airport was expected to remain closed and more than half of its land area was ordered evacuated.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that once the people of Montserrat continue to work steadfastly together, we can and will make northern Montserrat a place we can be proud of and where our families can live and our friends can continue to visit us,&quot; Montserrat Chief Minister Bertrand Osborne said in an address to the nation after the eruption.</p>
<p>He was due to address the island's population again on Wednesday evening by radio.</p>
<p>Scientists at the Montserrat Volcano Observatory said on Wednesday residents should be prepared for ash cloud eruptions and pyroclastic flows to continue. &quot;Everyone should continue to stay alert, and listen to Radio Montserrat for any announcements,&quot; they said in a report.</p>
<p>Montserrat's Soufriere Hills volcano roared to life on July 18, 1995, after nearly four centuries of virtual dormancy.</p>
<p>By last week, Montserrat's population had dropped to only 6,800 from 11,000 when the volcano awoke. And island residents said the outgoing ferry service to nearby Antigua inaugurated after last Wednesday's eruption was far more crowded than the boats bringing people in.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MONT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OLVESTON, Montserrat"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONTSERRAT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
