<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701832" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Media grill HK's Tung on rights, Taiwan, maids.</title>
<headline>Media grill HK's Tung on rights, Taiwan, maids.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's new leader Tung Chee-hwa fielded questions from civil rights to the future of Filipina maids on Wednesday at his first news conference since the end of British rule.</p>
<p>Handpicked by Beijing for the job, Tung stressed capitalist Hong Kong's special autonomous status within China and said both sides needed to get to know each other better.</p>
<p>&quot;Hong Kong has been separated from the motherland for some years,&quot; he said. &quot;I don't think the people of Hong Kong know the motherland very well.&quot;</p>
<p>Hong Kong was reintegrated into China on Tuesday when more than 150 years of British rule ended. Under a 1984 accord, Hong Kong will be a Special Administrative Region (SAR) of China and its super-capitalist ways are to be left intact for 50 years.</p>
<p>Tung, a former shipping magnate, acknowledged that in the short term there would be conflicts with Beijing, which must be settled through dialogue.</p>
<p>But he stressed that the long-term interests of China and Hong Kong were the same.</p>
<p>&quot;The more prosperous we are, the more we contribute to China's continued modernisation. The more prosperous China is, Hong Kong becomes even more prosperous,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tung was relaxed and jovial, casually answering an array of questions from hundreds of local and international journalists who packed the news conference hall.</p>
<p>He gracefully dodged tough questions and drew laughter with his quips as he shifted from English to Cantonese to Mandarin.</p>
<p>Tung was asked repeatedly about Hong Kong's soaring property market and what he intended to do to ensure that people would be able to afford housing.</p>
<p>&quot;Property prices have been zooming up, which has a negative impact on the whole community,&quot; he said. &quot;At the appropriate time, we will take resolute action.&quot;</p>
<p>But he could not be drawn on what that action might be and suggested it would be revealed in his economic policy statement in October.</p>
<p>Pressed on relations with nationalist Taiwan now that Hong Kong was part of China, Tung pledged dialogue and predicted the future of Taipei's official presence would be settled soon.</p>
<p>Taiwan's representative office in Hong Kong is currently a travel agency.</p>
<p>Speaking the day after 10,000 people had demonstrated for democracy in Hong Kong on the first day of Chinese rule, Tung said protests would always be allowed.</p>
<p>&quot;I have repeated many times that demonstrations so long as they are lawful and peaceful can go right ahead,&quot; Tung said.</p>
<p>But he made clear that he was uncomfortable with the idea of marching in the streets.</p>
<p>&quot;Would I do it this way? Obviously not, because I think there are many channels open for good communication. I would have thought of a better way of communicating.&quot;</p>
<p>His one flash of anger came when he was asked if he would try to calm the waters between his administration and critics in the pro-democracy movement.</p>
<p>Tung noted the Democratic Party had pushed a string of laws through the elected colonial parliament before it was dissolved on Monday and replaced by a Beijing-appointed assembly.</p>
<p>&quot;Each one of these laws, each one of these amendents, is being studied by the administration and we will do what is necessary to protect this community,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tung said he would visit the United States but that no date had been set and acknowledged that three of his children have U.S. passports, having been born in America.</p>
<p>Pressed on whether Hong Kong's 150,000-strong Filipino community -- the largest foreign group -- had anything to fear now that the territory was part of communist China, he said no.</p>
<p>&quot;Filipino domestic help is very much a part of our community and hopefully will be for a long, long time to come,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
