<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701837" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks soar, baht dives on currency float.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks soar, baht dives on currency float.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Charles</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai equity investors gave a hearty thumbs up to Thailand's move to float the beleaguered baht on Wednesday, pushing the battered bourse up nearly eight percent in busy dealings.</p>
<p>&quot;The market sure likes it,&quot; said one foreign analyst.</p>
<p>The baht plunged to a record low against the dollar after the government announced that the currency would be floated in order to end uncertainty over Thailand's exchange rate policy.</p>
<p>Equity analysts and traders said the surprise, de facto devaluation was sorely needed to boost the stock market, which has recently slumped to eight-year lows.</p>
<p>The Stock Exchange of Thailand ended up 7.87 percent, or 40.93 points, at 568.21 on turnover of 10.4 billion baht.</p>
<p>The flotation effectively devalued the baht by 15-20 percent in offshore markets as the central bank dropped its pegged rate system against a basket of currencies and allowed market forces to determine the rate.</p>
<p>Foreign exchange were mainly on the sidelines as they waited for Bank of Thailand to set the new baht reference against the U.S. dollar. The central bank plans to publish a baht/dollar reference rate each day based on the baht's trading average.</p>
<p>The baht was quoted  in offshore markets late on Wednesday at a rate of 28.80/29.60 following the early morning announcement by the central bank. In the domestic market it was at 27.50/28.50 to the dollar.</p>
<p>But stock market investors were upbeat.</p>
<p>Trade was dominated by foreign institutions as many local investors chose to remain on the sidelines until a clearer picture of Wednesday's currency changes emerged, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a tremendous buildup of funds that were waiting to go into the market if there was a devaluation or, as it happened, a flotation,&quot; George Morgan, country manager for ABN Amro Hoare Govett, told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>Another analyst said many investors had been waiting to buy because Thai stocks were selling at very attractive prices.</p>
<p>&quot;We were waiting for this (the flotation),&quot; he said. &quot;It was needed to asure investors.&quot;</p>
<p>Many stocks in the traditionally strong bank sector rose their 10 percent limit. On the foreign board, where there are no trading limits, some jumped more than 100 percent.</p>
<p>One analyst said the sharp jump in foreign prices may represent an over-reaction, and said there would likely be some rejigging following the initial knee-jerk reaction.</p>
<p>Richard Henderson, head of research at Krungthai Thanakit Plc, said the market gains would likely continue.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's the beginning rather than the end,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The flotation is the latest in a series of surprise but decisive measures by authorities to try to boost markets and the economy, which is suffering its worst slump in more than a decade amid slowing growth, sharply lower exports and a troubled finance sector.</p>
<p>The latest move also impacted regional stock and money markets, and several governments reacted quickly to avoid any harmful ripple effect.</p>
<p>The Philippines sold hundreds of millions of dollars and forced up interest rates to shield its currency.</p>
<p>Manila stocks fell to close nearly two percent lower on Wednesday as wild swings in the foreign exchange market scared stock market investors.</p>
<p>For the first time in years, Bank Negara Malaysia used its own name to intervene in the foreign exchange market as it sold dollars early on Wednesday, dealers said.</p>
<p>The actual amount of dollars sold was thought to be small and more of a token resistance by the bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
