<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701884" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia sees 1997 inflation below six percent.</title>
<headline>Indonesia sees 1997 inflation below six percent.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia on Wednesday welcomed a fall in inflation during June, and said it expected the year-on-year rate to fall below six percent in calendar 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Inflation in June fell 0.17 percent. This is very positive for our economy. I think inflation in calendar 1997 will be below six percent,&quot; Planning Minister Ginanjar Kartasasmita said.</p>
<p>Figures released earlier showed that Indonesia's consumer price index (CPI) fell 0.17 percent month-to-month in June, after a rise of 0.19 percent in May.</p>
<p>The year-on-year rate slipped to 4.98 percent, compared with 5.08 percent in May.</p>
<p>Indonesia posted an inflation rate of 6.47 percent for the 1996 calendar year against 8.64 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Low inflation means our economic development is sound. It can boost our economic growth,&quot; Ginanjar said.</p>
<p>Central Bank Governor Sudradjad Djiwandono reiterated that reining in inflation was the main aim of economic policy-makers because lower inflation would allow interest rates to decline.</p>
<p>&quot;The important thing on monetary policy is to get inflation lower and lower. Low inflation will enable us to cut interest rates further,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ginanjar also said the government would continue trying to trim its current account deficit.</p>
<p>The World Bank has warned Indonesia's current account deficit is likely to swell to $10.1 billion, or four percent of GDP, in fiscal 1997/98 (April-March) from $8.82 billion in 1996/97.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
