<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701900" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Mazda, Ford to study Philippines car venture--Jiji.</title>
<headline>Mazda, Ford to study Philippines car venture--Jiji.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mazda Motor Corp and Ford Motor Co have reached a general agreement to start a feasibility study to produce &quot;Asian cars&quot; in the Philippines, Jiji news agency reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The joint venture would be owned 45 percent each by the two companies and the rest by local investors. It would produce 60,000 cars annually for marketing in Asian countries, Jiji said.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot confirm or deny the Jiji report at the moment,&quot; a Mazda spokesman said.</p>
<p>Jiji also said the two companies will start the feasibility study this summer to finalise a decision within this year.</p>
<p>If they go ahead with the Philippines car project, it would be the second joint venture in Asia between the two companies.</p>
<p>In November 1995, Mazda and Ford formed a joint venture named AutoAlliance (Thailand) Co Ltd (AAT) in Thailand to produce pickup trucks, aiming to start production in mid-1998 with a capacity of around 135,000 pickup trucks a year.</p>
<p>Mazda now assembles cars and commercial vehicles in the Philippines, where its sales stood at 10,283 units in calendar 1996, a 6.5 percent share and up from 7,589 a year earlier, the Mazda spokesman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
