<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="701913" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber ends down on baht and weak demand.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber ends down on baht and weak demand.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices fell heavily at the close, with local traders blaming the correction mostly on the negative region-wide influence exerted by the flotation of the Thai baht.</p>
<p>Competition from cheaper material in Indonesia, and summer holidays in Europe, also deprived the local market of potential buyers, said the traders.</p>
<p>&quot;The flotation of the baht affected prices in Indonesia, and Malaysia had to react by bringing prices down too,&quot; said a trader in Kuala Lumpur.  </p>
<p>The Thai government floated the baht and raised its key lending rate by two percentage points on Wednesday in an attempt to restore its battered economy. Currency analysts had, however, interpreted the move as a de facto devaluation.</p>
<p>Malaysian traders said unless local prices were adjusted accordingly to the regional fluctation, buyers would continue sidelining the Malaysian market.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got news that most U.S. buyers are flocking to Thailand and Indonesia because rubber is cheaper there,&quot; said a government trade source in Kuala Lumpur.  </p>
<p>He added that the bulk delivery latex in Thailand was going for around 180 Malaysian cents, compared to the 200-odd cents in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>At the close, the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board quoted July RSS1 buyer at 249.50 Malaysian/Singapore cents (99 U.S. cents) a kg, down 5.50 cents from Tuesday. July SMR20 buyer fell three cents to 242.</p>
<p>Trading houses offered the SMR20 at 240, SMR10 at 242, SMR5 at 254, SMR CV at 310, SMR L at 291 and drum latex at 209.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day average was at 196.79 Malaysian/Singapore cents a kg on July 1 from 198.34 on June 27.</p>
<p>The daily indicator was at 194.31 against 194.74 previously.</p>
<p>A Malaysia-based shipping agent quoted freight rates for rubber from Malaysia to Rotterdam at $700 per TEU and $1,400 per two-TEU containers.</p>
<p>-- K. Baranee Krishnaan (603-275-6834) ($1=2.5250 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
