<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702003" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed opts to keep U.S. interest rates steady.</title>
<headline>Fed opts to keep U.S. interest rates steady.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve decided on Wednesday to hold interest rates steady amid signs economic growth has slowed from a sizzling first-quarter pace.</p>
<p>The announcement, which came at the end of a two-day meeting of the Fed's policy-making committee, had been widely expected and left the key federal funds rate that commercial banks charge each other for overnight money at 5.50 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the economy) ain't broken, so it shouldn't be fixed,&quot; said Robert Solow, professor emeritus of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, commenting on the Fed's decision.</p>
<p>Wall Street stock prices climbed in response to the central bank announcement, with the Dow Jones industrial average of blue chip shares ending 73.05 points higher at 7,795.38. Bond prices also closed up, with the key 30-year Treasury issue gaining 3/8 point, or $3.75 on a $1,000 bond.</p>
<p>The guessing game has already begun about what the Fed will do at its next policy-making meeting on Aug. 19. Some analysts see it raising rates as growth picks up from a second-quarter lull, but others expect no change.</p>
<p>The Fed last altered monetary policy in March, when it raised the federal funds rate by a quarter percentage point to keep the economy from overheating and to contain inflation.</p>
<p>Since the March rate increase, economic growth has slowed markedly as consumers have cut back on their purchases after an early-year spending spree. Analysts expect growth in the second quarter of somewhere between 1.5 and 2 percent, compared with a 5.9 percent annualized rate in the first quarter.</p>
<p>In the latest sign of slowing growth, the Commerce Department reported on Wednesday that factory orders tumbled by 0.7 percent in May after rising by 1.4 percent in April. Weak demand for new cars and airplanes was behind the fall.</p>
<p>Analysts said that politics also argued against a rate rise now. Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan is slated to present the Fed's semi-annual assessment of the economy to Congress on July 22 and he would have found it hard to defend a rate hike to lawmakers when growth is slowing and inflation is low.</p>
<p>The Fed's March rate rise was met with what Greenspan himself has acknowledged was an unusual amount of criticism.</p>
<p>Lawmakers on Wednesday welcomed the central bank's decision to leave interest rates unchanged -- up to a point.</p>
<p>Democratic Senator Tom Harkin, a long-time Fed critic, said the decision not to raise rates should come as a relief to the economy. But the Iowa lawmaker voiced disappointment that the central bank had not chosen to lower rates.</p>
<p>Representative Jim Saxton, Chairman of the Congressional Joint Economic Committee, said the Fed's decision seemed appropriate given that there is little evidence of a pick-up in inflation.</p>
<p>However, the New Jersey Republican chastised the central bank not being more open and explaining the reason why it had opted to leave interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>The Fed's next rate move will depend on how the economy performs after its second-quarter slowdown.</p>
<p>&quot;Greenspan is sitting there with his finger right over the button poised to move,&quot; said Bill Cheney, chief economist of Boston-based John Hancock Financial Services.</p>
<p>With the job market already very tight and many factories running flat out, a sharp economic rebound in the third quarter would raise the risk of higher inflation, possibly prompting the Fed to tighten credit in response.</p>
<p>Many economists believe that is exactly what will happen. With wages rising and the stock market strong, they said, consumers have the ability to step up spending, boosting economic growth in the process.</p>
<p>&quot;All the fundamentals are there for a very strong second half,&quot; said Cliff Waldman, an economist with the National Federation of Independent Business, an association that represents 600,000 small companies.</p>
<p>Others though see growth settling into a sustainable pace of around 2 percent to 2.5 percent in the second half of the year, allowing the Fed to stay on hold. They argue that consumers have already sated their demand for big ticket items, such as cars, and are unlikely to go on another spending spree.</p>
<p>&quot;Some pick-up in consumer spending will almost certainly occur, but we just don't see consumers binging out again,&quot; said Bruce Steinberg, chief economist at Wall Street broker Merrill Lynch &amp; Co.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
