<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702166" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Treasuries end higher, ignore FOMC no action.</title>
<headline>U.S. Treasuries end higher, ignore FOMC no action.</headline>
<byline>Steven Scheer</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries closed higher on Wednesday following the Federal Reserve's decision to leave interest rates steady.</p>
<p>The Fed's policy setting committee meeting, though, was viewed as a non-event, since private forecasters were near unanimous in their view the Fed would keep rates unchanged.</p>
<p>Rather, the market inched higher for the second straight day on another bout of short-covering, hedge fund buying and position squaring ahead of Thursday's release of the June employment report.  </p>
<p>The 30-year bond ended at about its session high of 98-27/32, up 11/32. Its yield edged down to 6.72 percent from 6.74 percent.</p>
<p>Late in the day, a large hedge fund was said to have bought bond futures, pushing Treasuries higher into the close.</p>
<p>Trading throughout the session was described as listless, with the market on guard just in case the Fed surprised players with a rate hike.</p>
<p>&quot;This decision was factored into the yield curve,&quot; said William Sullivan, director of money markets reserach at Dean Witter Securities Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market has allowed for six weeks of policy stability,&quot; Sullivan said, referring to the length of time until the next Fed meeting in mid-August.</p>
<p>While the market awaited the Fed's end-of-meeting statement, dealers covered whatever shorts remained from Tuesday, traders said.</p>
<p>Also lending mild support to Treasuries was offshore buying due to the rise in the dollar against the mark to a 40-month high of 1.7550 marks.</p>
<p>Yet, volume was fairly light, at below $70.0 billion according to GovPX.  </p>
<p>The market next turns its attention to the employment report on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;The Fed (meeting) has taken the importance out of it,&quot; said Jerry Zukowski, fixed income economist at PaineWebber Inc. &quot;We have had strong employment reports for a while and the Fed hasn't responded to it.</p>
<p>The market cares about as &quot;a matter of habit rather than being essential to policy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nonfarm payrolls are expected to have risen 222,000 in June, after a 138,000 gain in May, according to a Reuters poll. But many are forecasting figures as high as 300,000.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are going to have buyers (Thursday) no matter what,&quot; said Vincent Verterano, head trader at Nomura Securities International Inc.</p>
<p>He said that the market will be euphoric over a weak report, while others will explain away a strong report.</p>
<p>Sullivan added that a weak report could push the T-bond to test 6.55 percent and 5.90 percent on the two-year note.</p>
<p>&quot;People have to believe the Fed is on hold for an extended period,&quot; he said, noting that in a steady Fed environment a twos-bonds spread of 40 basis points is not unreasonable.  </p>
<p>Trading on Thursday could be choppy, players warned, since trading desks will be thin ahead of the July 4 holiday weekend. Some said the market will be done trading before lunch, while others figured it would wait until the minutes of the May FOMC meeting are released at 1415 EDT.</p>
<p>The market officially is set to close at 1500 EDT.</p>
<p>In late trading, the two-year note was at 99-31/32, up 1/32, to yield 6.02 percent. The five-year note was up 4/32 at 99-26/32 with a yield of 6.29 percent. The 10-year note closed up 8/32 at 101-18/32 to yield 6.41 percent.</p>
<p>The three-month bill was down one basis point at 5.09 percent, the six-month bill was down two basis points at 5.10 percent and the year bill was down one basis point at 5.33 percent.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1867 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
