<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702174" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soymeal ends lower on liquidation, soyoil up.</title>
<headline>CBOT soymeal ends lower on liquidation, soyoil up.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soymeal futures ended lower for the third straight session, hit by ongoing fund and commission house long liquidation tied to ideas demand for nearby supplies was waning, traders said.</p>
<p>Soyoil ended higher with light commercial support noted amid talk of export business in the works.</p>
<p>&quot;We are definitely starting to pick up additional (soyoil) business on the world market,&quot; said Mark Weidner, oilseeds analyst with Cargill Investor Services. &quot;World stocks are tight and this is an attractive price level. I do think we are attracting some pretty good world pricing interest.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said soyoil values in South America had risen in recent weeks while CBOT prices fell to four-year lows. China bought U.S. soyoil late last week and traders said more business was in the works to Pacific Rim countries.</p>
<p>The spot July soymeal contract led that commodity lower. Traders pointed to rationing by crushers and exporters as world buyers opted to wait for expected bumper new crop supplies or buy from Brazil.</p>
<p>Soymeal ended $7.10 to $0.70 per ton higher with July off $7.10 at $237.10. Soyoil closed 0.21 to 0.07 cent per lb higher with July up 0.21 at 21.63.  </p>
<p>On the day, commercials were light buyers of soyoil. Cargill Inc was buying the August and December while ADM and Produce Grain bought the August, traders said.</p>
<p>Tenco Inc sold 500 lots soyoil and Prudential Securities sold 200 September.</p>
<p>In soymeal, Cargill Inc sold 500 August and 300 July while Central Soya sold 300 August. ABN-AMRO Chicago Corp sold 500 lots December.</p>
<p>Soymeal futures volume was estimated by CBOT at 40,000 lots, compared with Tuesday's actual volume of 47,578 lots. Soyoil volume was pegged at 30,000 lots, against Tuesday's 30,159.</p>
<p>((Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
