<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702194" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Many stolen U.S. cars exported by thieves - study.</title>
<headline>Many stolen U.S. cars exported by thieves - study.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Many cars stolen in the United States end up in Europe or Asia, where buyers are eager to avoid a three-year wait for an American-made car, a study released on Wednesday said.</p>
<p>Newer models can bring three to five times their value when shipped to buyers in Europe or the Far East, the National Insurance Crime Bureau, a group supported by insurers that compile law enforcement statistics on stolen cars, reported.</p>
<p>&quot;Illegal exportation of stolen vehicles is a huge market,&quot; spokesman Ed Sparkman said. &quot;In Europe, if you go through the proper channels you can expect to wait three years to get a new American-made vehicle. But if you have the money you can get a (stolen) one in just a few weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>Older stolen vehicles are often destined for Latin America or local &quot;chop shops&quot; where hard-to-get parts can be worth more collectively than the car itself, the group said.</p>
<p>In all, 1.5 million cars were stolen in the United States in 1995, 60 percent of which were later recovered. The group said it believed car thefts were increasing, disputing preliminary FBI statistics showing 1996 thefts down 5 percent.</p>
<p>Of the 32 metropolitan areas with the highest auto theft rates, 19 were coastal or border towns and many were in the Sunbelt. Fresno, California, and Miami had the worst rankings, with 16,258 cars stolen in Fresno out of 517,019 registered and 40,170 stolen in Miami out of 1.3 million registered.</p>
<p>After those cities, the most likely places to lose one's car to a thief were Jersey City, New Jersey (6,782 thefts); New York (77,355); Phoenix, Arizona, (38,223); Memphis, Tennessee (16,263); and Los Angeles (102,320).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
