<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702252" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. cities boost role in global economy - survey.</title>
<headline>U.S. cities boost role in global economy - survey.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. cities have become aggressive players in the global marketplace, hoping to bolster their economies with foreign investment and tourism, according to a report released Wednesday.</p>
<p>Nearly half of the cities surveyed said they were working to promote exports of local products and more than one-third said they were actively trying to attract foreign investment, the survey, conducted by the National League of Cities, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our own cities aren't just waiting for something to happen,&quot; said Donald Borut, the league's executive director. &quot;There is an enormous amount of global activity.&quot;  </p>
<p>The league said 48 percent of U.S. municipalities have active sister-city relations with cities in other countries, 34 percent are involved in cultural exchanges and 24 percent are promoting their city to foreign tourists.</p>
<p>Thirty-five percent said they work actively with state officials, and 20 percent with federal agencies to develop partnerships focusing on international opportunities.</p>
<p>Fifty-nine percent of respondents said the increase of global economic competition has been positive or very positive for their communities, according to the survey.</p>
<p>Nearly two out of three local leaders said globalization was improving the well-being of all city residents, with high-income and highly-skilled workers gaining the most.</p>
<p>The survey was based on a random sample of mayors and other officials across the United States. A total of 476 usable responses were received, the league said.</p>
<p>((- Adam Entous, 202-898-8377))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
