<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702319" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Freed Spanish hostage says he escaped &quot;nightmare&quot;.</title>
<headline>Freed Spanish hostage says he escaped &quot;nightmare&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Spanish businessman freed after 232 days as a hostage of ETA Basque separatist guerrillas said on Wednesday he had endured a &quot;nightmare&quot; of living in a hot, cramped cell in constant fear for his life.</p>
<p>A second hostage, a prison official rescued by Civil Guards on Tuesday hours after the businessman was freed, lived in even more severe conditions. He was so desperate that when guards burst open his mouldy underground cell, the confused hostage thought they were his captors and reportedly asked them to kill him.</p>
<p>The businessman, Basque Cosme Delclaux, told a news conference: &quot;I have escaped a nightmare.&quot;</p>
<p>The accounts of Delclaux to the press and of freed prison official Jose Antonio Ortega Lara to officials offered a rare glimpse at the fear and despair of ETA hostages.</p>
<p>Delclaux is the son of a wealthy Basque industrialist and his family paid a ransom of about $10 million for his release, according to police sources. He said he did not know anything about the ransom.</p>
<p>In a cell 3.5 metres long, 90 to 120 centimetres wide and 1.9 metres high, he said he received three good meals and six cigarettes a day. Delclaux, 34, read about 80 books during his captivity in addition to EGIN, the ETA newspaper. He was also given a walkman and tapes to listen to.</p>
<p>He was guarded constantly by two captors and only interacted with one of them, who was always masked. They spoke only of banal things like sports, he said.</p>
<p>The most serious problems Delclaux faced were lack of water and toilets, heat, and his constant fear for his life. He had no toilet or running water and was given two pails of water a day for all his needs.</p>
<p>In contrast to Delclaux, who appeared robust and in good health after his ordeal, Ortega Lara, 37, emerged from 532 days in captivity visibly debilitated. He had lost 23 kg (50 lb), had to be assisted when walking and grimaced in pain when he moved.</p>
<p>While ETA, which stands for Basque Homeland and Freedom, kidnapped Delclaux for financial motives, Ortega-Lara was held as a political protest against Spain's prisoner policy.</p>
<p>Officials said Ortega-Lara, held in a cell of similar dimensions to Delclaux's, was treated like a dog. He slept on the floor in a sleeping bag and also had no running water or toilet. He never saw daylight.</p>
<p>Unlike Delclaux, who was guarded constantly, his captors visited the cell only to bring food and water..</p>
<p>Doctors who examined Ortega-Lara said his muscles had atrophied seriously because he was barely able to move. He ate only vegetables and fruits in captivity, apparently at his own request, and was malnourished.</p>
<p>He was also given ETA propaganda to read along with a few books, among them Bill Gates' &quot;The Road Ahead&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
