<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702412" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Building collapse kills several in Pakistan.</title>
<headline>Building collapse kills several in Pakistan.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Several people were killed and at least nine injured when a half-built block of flats collapsed in the southern Pakistani port city of Karachi on Wednesday, rescue workers said.</p>
<p>They said one body had been recovered from the rubble of the flattened four-storey building, but several crushed corpses were visible. Nine injured men had been rescued.</p>
<p>Fire brigade workers said they had heard trapped people screaming for help amid the rubble of the Faiza Heights apartment block in the New Karachi district.</p>
<p>&quot;Concrete fell on top of our floor with a loud bang and we were buried under it,&quot; said Muhammad Saleem, one of the injured.</p>
<p>Ambulance workers said earlier that labourers working at the site were having lunch on the second floor of the building when it collapsed. They said as many as 45 might have been buried.</p>
<p>Police, ambulance men and local volunteers were clawing through the rubble by hand as a yellow crane heaved chunks of concrete out of the way, watched by a big crowd of bystanders.</p>
<p>The cause of the disaster was not immediately clear.</p>
<p>The official news agency APP quoted a witness as saying there had been an explosion before the collapse, which had not affected nearby buildings in the same housing project.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
