<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702511" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian bonds open stronger, matching U.S. gains.</title>
<headline>Canadian bonds open stronger, matching U.S. gains.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds opened much stronger on Wednesday, building on gains made in the U.S. market yesterday when the Canadian market was closed for the Canada Day holiday, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Canada is doing catch up basically,&quot; said Barry Allan, vice-president of global fixed income with Altamira Investment Services. &quot;The bulk of the activity has been either dealers unwinding curve trades or foreign interest. The domestic buying has been very very light.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year benchmark bond rose C$1.31 to C$115.26 from Monday's close to yield 6.799 percent.  </p>
<p>The U.S. 30-year bond rose 2/32 to yield 6.74 percent. The spread between the bonds narrowed to six basis points from seven basis points at the close of trading on Monday.</p>
<p>Canadian bonds stopped trading at noon on Monday ahead of the Canada Day holiday on Tuesday. U.S. treasuries had since recorded strong gains amid growing expectations the Federal Reserve would not hike interest rates today after a meeting of its rate-setting Open Market Committee.</p>
<p>&quot;People are feeling that the Fed's not going to do anything. They're starting to build that in,&quot; said Allan.  </p>
<p>The FOMC is expected to conclude its two-day meeting with a rate decision announcement at about 1415 EDT/1815 GMT.</p>
<p>In other prices, Canada's 10-year benchmark bond rose C$0.79 to C$107.36 from Monday's close to yield 6.241 percent, compared to its U.S. equivalent, which rose 1/32 this session to yield 6.44 percent.</p>
<p>The negative spread between the bonds was 20 basis points, unchanged from the close of trading on Monday.  </p>
<p>The three-month cash T-bill yielded 3.17 percent against its U.S. equivalent, which yielded 5.23 percent.</p>
<p>((Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
