<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70264" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Critics lambaste Mexico party on &quot;reform&quot; texts.</title>
<headline>Critics lambaste Mexico party on &quot;reform&quot; texts.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Critics charged on Monday that Mexico's ruling party remained as authoritarian as ever after an assembly billed as a grand reform event saw its final texts apparently emasculated by a backroom committee.</p>
<p>The Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI), which has ruled Mexico without a break for 67 years, wound up a national assembly on Sunday with delegates thinking they had agreed on several radical reforms to party rules and doctrine.</p>
<p>Party President Santiago Onate hailed the meeting as a turning point. &quot;The PRI has renewed itself, it now contains firm hope, it has a sense of the future, and it is ready to strengthen the morality of the Republic,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But newspapers on Monday said final texts had been altered by party chiefs to remove reforms adopted by rank-and-file militants in debates held on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Important agreements approved on Saturday in the workshops of the 17th National Assembly of the PRI were not included in the final version of the party's basic documents,&quot; Reforma newspaper said.</p>
<p>&quot;Where is the change?&quot; asked El Universal in a front-page comment.</p>
<p>No final texts were circulated on Sunday to the news media or the 4,423 delegates. PRI Secretary-General Juan Millan told the closing plenary session that reading them would take too long and got the assembly to approve them on trust en bloc.</p>
<p>PRI chief spokesman Hector Gonzalez denied on Monday that there had been any manipulation of the final documents, although he also said he did not yet have the approved texts.</p>
<p>Analysts said the manoeuvre by the party leadership reminded them of the authoritarian, undemocratic PRI of old -- precisely what the assembly was supposed to bury.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course no new culture, no new PRI emerged from the 17th National Assembly. Quite the opposite,&quot; managing editor Raymundo Riva Palacio wrote in a comment in Reforma on Monday. &quot;You could sum it up like this: Welcome to the past.&quot;</p>
<p>Things looked different on Saturday when four workshops discussing party policy and rules voted through big changes that opposed privatisation of the petrochemical industry, demanded that PRI members in government donate 5 percent of their monthly salary to the party and banned party members from making deals with the opposition on elected posts.</p>
<p>Speaker after speaker railed against &quot;technocrats&quot; and free-market policies and called for an &quot;authentic nationalist, revolutionary spirit&quot; and a return to the party's left-wing roots in the 1910-17 Mexican Revolution.</p>
<p>Onate had to rush into one session and plead for order after unruly militants invaded the platform to protest against an attempt by the chair to manipulate proceedings.</p>
<p>Commentators spoke of a PRI grass-roots rebellion and even suggested that the party leadership was losing control.</p>
<p>In Sunday's final session, however, the party closed ranks behind its best-known technocrat -- Mexico's Yale-educated President Ernesto Zedillo -- dissent was silenced and the leadership looked as secure as ever.</p>
<p>The same activists who on Saturday had launched furious assaults on government policy rose to their feet to cheer and applaud Zedillo, the man who had carried those policies out. The reception followed a long party tradition that authority comes from the top -- the president of the republic.</p>
<p>&quot;The PRI's incapacity to renew itself is total,&quot; intellectual Carlos Monsivais commented after the assembly. &quot;Sunday's proceedings annulled Saturday's.&quot;</p>
<p>Also following tradition, presidential aides assured reporters after the assembly that Zedillo's government was not bound by any of the PRI's decisions and would continue to follow its free-market line.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
