<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702866" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK forwarders' body raps inadequate air security.</title>
<headline>UK forwarders' body raps inadequate air security.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>There are a number of weak links within the UK air cargo security regime, whose regulations are &quot;inadequate&quot;, said the British International Freight Association (BIFA).</p>
<p>BIFA air division manager Roger Blacklock told a news briefing that he would prepare a summary of the perceived weaknesses the association saw in the Aviation Security (Air Cargo Regulations) 1993, which came into effect in August 1994.</p>
<p>He said that on September 16, this would be presented to the next meeting of the UK Air Freight Forum, a body comprising leading airlines, forwarders and shippers, which in turn he expected would make recommendations for changes in the regulations to the British government.</p>
<p>&quot;The (UK air cargo security) regime as it is currently structured puts responsibility on 'listed' cargo agents to ascertain whether a shipper or trucker is secure,&quot; said Blacklock of BIFA, which represents primarily freight forwarders.</p>
<p>But he said that some companies with insufficient staff and because of &quot;commercial considerations&quot; were not abiding by the regulations.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that some 'listed' (approved for this role by the Department of Transport) forwarders have not been vetting their customers and that some shippers are not abiding by the criteria laid down in the regulations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The regime is inadequate and the problems need to be resolved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Blacklock added that all sectors of the air cargo industry, not just forwarders, should &quot;share the (air security) load,&quot; but he declined to expand further on the security weaknesses.</p>
<p>&quot;The regulations were rushed in...it was a political, post-Lockerbie move. It is time to produce a practical solution to the security issue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Department of Transport, in response, told Reuters that &quot;no security measures are 100 percent secure&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The regulations are as tight as they reasonably can be in a normal low-threat situation,&quot; said its principal aviation security inspector for policy development, Ken Robinson.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a 'fast-track' system that is followed in the same manner as people follow speed limits on a motorway. When an agent is found to be not enforcing the requirements, we can de-list or even prosecute him,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He stressed that the resources he had available to police the at present 497 'listed' agents were limited.</p>
<p>But Robinson said the advantages of the UK air cargo security regulations had persuaded the European Civil Aviation Conference (ECAC) to impose similar regimes in 43 European states by mid-1998.</p>
<p>&quot;And the International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) is also about to use the UK regime as a guide to what should be introduced around the world,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that two years ago he proposed that UK shippers should subscribe to a practice under which they would be vetted and validated by a third party, for example a security organisation.</p>
<p>Those shippers' cargo consignments would then be considered to be secure and therefore both forwarders and shippers would take responsibility for air security issues.</p>
<p>But he said the British Shippers' Council (BSC) had opposed this idea, even though BIFA was keen on its adoption. -Bob Murphy, Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax +5017</p>
<p>www.racs.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
