<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="702896" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold weakens to fresh 4-1/4 year low.</title>
<headline>London gold weakens to fresh 4-1/4 year low.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The gold market weakened to a fresh lowest price since March 1993 on Wednesday under pressure from speculative selling.</p>
<p>It was fixed at $331.45 per ounce, down from $333.70 on Tuesday marking its lowest fixing since March 24, 1993.</p>
<p>Dealers and analysts forecast lower prices to come for the yellow metal which has been under pressure for most of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The present price comes from a new level of short positions established by the investment funds (this week),&quot; one analyst at a major European bullion bank said.</p>
<p>It was the funds' positioning to take advantage of prices falling further that had broken the gold price out of its previous price range between $335-$340, the analyst said.</p>
<p>That in turn had induced gold producers especially in high cost areas like Australia to step up their selling campaigns to avoid even lower prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The Australians are concerned about a further interest rate cut at home and are trying to take advantage of the domestic currency moving in their favour,&quot; the analyst added.</p>
<p>Meanhwhile physical demand has slumped despite the apparent attractiveness of cheap prices.</p>
<p>Some observers even said that buyers in the recent past were now looking to sell back their gold holdings.</p>
<p>The lack of physical buying could be connected to the markets in Hong Kong being closed so far this week for the territory's hand over to Chinese rule.</p>
<p>&quot;We are waiting to see if there is a reaction on the re-entry of Hong Kong,&quot; a dealer said. Hong Kong is one of the key gold entrepot points for China.</p>
<p>Some dealers said a European central bank -- Belgium was the favourite - had been selling gold from its reserves which also explained the staggering price but others were less sure.</p>
<p>&quot;It is more likely to be a bullion bank selling possibly as a result of additional lending (to the market) by a central bank,&quot; a market analyst said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the other precious metals largely ignored gold's problems. Silver was just a couple of cents lower at $4.64/$4.66 but platinum and palladium were both down for their own reasons.</p>
<p>Platinum was indicated at $425.00/$429.00 down $15.50 and palladium was $3.00 easier at $189.00/$192.00</p>
<p>Both were weaker on news major supplier Russia would begin its delayed 1997 exporting campaign on July 10.</p>
<p>--Brian Spoors London Newsroom +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
