<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70305" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>CABINET MEETS IN MELBOURNE</p>
<p>Federal Cabinet meets in the old Victoria Barracks in Melbourne today, the first of a series of meetings away from Canberra and Sydney.</p>
<p>The venue will be an appropriate place for ministers to talk about the war-of-words they'll have with opposition parties in the Senate this Parliamentary session.</p>
<p>Many Cabinet meetings have been held in Sydney, with the Prime Minister opting to live there, and the rest have so far taken place in Canberra.</p>
<p>The Cabinet plans more long-distance meetings over the coming months, including one in Perth.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HOUSING AFFORDABILITY RISES</p>
<p>A new survey has found housing affordability in Australia is at its highest level in ten years, mainly due to steady wages growth, and falling interest rates.</p>
<p>The Wespac Bank's 1996 spring housing report shows the relationship between house prices and wages is back where it was ten years ago, with buying conditions continuing to improve.</p>
<p>Westpac's general manager of economics, Bill Evans, says it's clear it's easier to afford a house now than at any time in the last decade.</p>
<p>Westpac is also forecasting an improvement in residential construction, with New South Wales and Victoria in the best positions for recovery.</p>
<p>The bank says Western Australia's prospects continue to depend on the strength of the state's mining sector.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>AUSTRALIA HELPS VIETNAM DEVELOP PARLIAMENT</p>
<p>The speaker of the House of Representatives, Bob Halverson, says development of Vietnam's Parliament, could prompt further political reform in the country.</p>
<p>Mr Halverson has offered the assistance of Australian parliamentary officers to improve the committee system within Vietnam's National Assembly.</p>
<p>He's leading a parliamentary delegation on a five-day official visit to Vietnam, where the Assembly is still subordinate to the ruling Communist Party.</p>
<p>Mr Halverson says developments in the system can only benefit the Vietnamese and their relationship with their neighbours and  countries like Australia.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>STAND OFF AT ACI FACTORY</p>
<p>There's a stand-off at the ACI Glass Factory in Melbourne's west this morning with the company refusing to let one hundred and thirty men return to work.</p>
<p>In the latest development in a long-running dispute, the workers marched to the gates of the Spotswood factory, chanting, but were met by about 60 police blocking the entrance.</p>
<p>The unionists presented a letter from the Industrial Relations Commissioner, recommending the locked-out workers be allowed to return to work.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>REPORT ON FERAL CATS</p>
<p>A report to the Federal Government on feral cats has called for field removal experiments to be carried out in eight regions to indicate how best to protect endangered and vulnerable fauna. The Nature Conservation Agency says feral cats prey on native mammals up to two kilograms and birds up to a kilo, but the impact is greatest on smaller species weighing less than 220-grams.</p>
<p>The agency says field removal experiments are needed to determine the level of cat control that will allow endangered and vulnerable fauna to recover.</p>
<p>It recommends experiments be conducted in south-west Western Australia, the Channel Country in Queensland's far south west, the Top End, the Kimberley, Tasmania, Norfolk Island, coastal Victoria and the Pilbara.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BROWNLOW MEDAL WINNERS</p>
<p>Essendon's James Hird and Brisbane's Michael Voss have won the 1996 Brownlow Medal for the fairest and best player in the AFL.</p>
<p>Hird had to wait until the last votes of the night to join Voss at the head of the list on 21 votes, just one ahead of Saint Kilda's Nathan Burke and Footscray's Chris Grant.</p>
<p>But the biggest disappointment of the night was reserved for North Melbourne ruckman Corey McKernan who also polled 21 votes, but was ineligible to win because of suspension.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>IN AFL ...</p>
<p>Bookmakers expect North Melbourne to firm in favouritism for Saturday's AFL Grand Final against the Sydney Swans.</p>
<p>The Swans will be working to ensure their players are not over committed by outside engagements this week in the leadup to the grand final.</p>
<p>The Swans are expected to be inundated with invitations for public functions and appearances following the emotion generated by their victory over Essendon.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>RUGBY LEAGUE GRAND FINAL</p>
<p>In rugby league, Manly coach Bob Fulton says St. George will be a difficult side to beat in Sunday's rugby league grand final at the Sydney Football Stadium.</p>
<p>Manly's injury list, which includes Matthew Ridge, Terry Hill and Geoff Toovey, is expected to clear by the weekend to offer a fully fit squad for the big match.</p>
<p>Fulton says the Saints will produce a side with a range of attacking options that could prove tricky to contain.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
