<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="703239" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Loss on France's CDR assets seen at 100.2 bln Ffr.</title>
<headline>Loss on France's CDR assets seen at 100.2 bln Ffr.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The loss on assets held by French state firm CDR (Consortium de Realisation) have been evaluated at 100.2 billion francs excluding carrying costs, the Finance Ministry said on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>The estimate was given in a report prepared by the EPFR, the agency which manages the financial assistance to state bank Credit Lyonnais, whose assets slated for sale are grouped in the CDR.</p>
<p>&quot;This document confirms the size of the losses the state will have to assume on the assets held by CDR. They are evaluated at 100.2 billion francs, excluding carrying costs,&quot; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>The statement confirmed recent newspaper reports that the EPFR's loss estimate had mushroomed from 14 billion francs in 1994 to 50 billion in 1995 and over 100 billion at last count.</p>
<p>The reports put the carrying costs at 66 billion francs, raising to nearly 170 billion francs the total loss for the French state on assets bought mostly at peak market prices during Credit Lyonnais's expansion in the 1980s and early 1990s.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn has delivered copies of the EPFR report to the presidents of the National Assembly and Senate and to the finance committee heads of the two chambers &quot;in the interests of total transparency&quot;.  </p>
<p>The statement said the higher loss estimate was due in part to a deterioration in the property market. It said the report also said some of the goals set out for the CDR, namely the rapid sale of assets at the best price, were contradictory.</p>
<p>Strauss-Kahn is asking the head of the CDR to pursue legal action if there is evidence of criminal wrongdoing and reaffirming the previous government's request for an audit, the statement said.</p>
<p>He also set out an objective for a recovery of Credit Lyonnais, which is &quot;not the Credit Lyonnais of yesteryear&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
