<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="703365" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany sets stage for big launch of digital TV.</title>
<headline>Germany sets stage for big launch of digital TV.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>After two years of cloak-and-dagger corporate intrigue, Germany's media giants Bertelsmann and the wily Bavarian tycoon Leo Kirch on Wednesday appeared finally set to launch digital television in a big way.</p>
<p>In a move that breaks a long deadlock, phone giant Deutsche Telekom reached a deal with broadcaster CLT/Ufa and Kirch on digital decoders that will make digital TV available to Telekom's 17 cable TV subscribers in Germany within months.</p>
<p>In a separate but related move, French pay TV group Canal Plus approved the sale of its stake in German pay TV company Premiere, setting in motion talks that aim to divide Premiere equally between long-time rivals Bertelsmann and Kirch.</p>
<p>At the end of a fast-forward day packed with announcements, it became clear this complicated series of corporate dealings means that digital programming will become widely available in time for a Christmas marketing blitz.</p>
<p>&quot;The winner is the consumer,&quot; said Johannes Schmitz, spokesman for the Munich-based KirchGroup, which according to German media reports is heavily indebted from a lacklustre consumer demand for its DF1 digital TV system.</p>
<p>&quot;The consumer will soon have digital TV over cable and satellite, security about the technology and competition in programming,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Digital television offers CD-like picture and sound quality and allows broadcasters to pack 10 channels in the space of one and offer innovations like pay-per-view and home-shopping.</p>
<p>Premiere is the only analog pay TV in Germany with 1.5 million subscribers. Bertelsmann and Canal Plus have each held 37.5 percent of Premiere and Kirch the other 25 percent.</p>
<p>But last year Kirch broke off on his own to start DF1. DF1 was unable to strike a deal with Telekom, which owns the world's largest cable TV network, and was restricted to satellite broadcast, unable to reach the larger cable audience.</p>
<p>In the subsequent corporate warfare sides have changed in pay TV alliances several times. Global media baron Rupert Murdoch has sided with Bertelsmann, then with Kirch, then threw up his hands in frustration and left Germany altogether.</p>
<p>The latest casualty is Canal Plus. Tired of the lack of progress in Germany, it was keen to pull out of Premiere and finally agreed with Kirch to swap its Premiere shares for Kirch's 45 percent stake in Italian pay TV group Telepiu.</p>
<p>Canal Plus already owns 45 percent of Telepiu.</p>
<p>Kirch assured that a deal announced last week with Bertelsmann to divide Premiere equally was still valid.</p>
<p>&quot;We are aiming for a 50-50 partnership,&quot; said Schmitz. &quot;The digital TV market will now develop rapidly.&quot;</p>
<p>On the technical side of the arrangement, Kirch's Beta Research GmbH, which developed the &quot;D-Box&quot; decoder technology, in future will be held equally by Telekom, CLT/Ufa and Kirch and Telekom will use the D-Box standard in its cable network.</p>
<p>CLT/Ufa and Kirch will each pay Telekom a fixed price for the seven digital channels they will require and a percentage of sales from pay TV programming. Telekom will also raise cable subscription fees this autumn 15 percent to 25.90 marks.</p>
<p>The deal also sets the stage for Bertelsmann and Kirch to finalise a cooperation deal between Premiere and DF1. None of the companies would comment on the status of talks. But they seemed confident that a deal that would allow DF1 and Premiere to market each other's services would be concluded soon.</p>
<p>But the Cartel Office is scrutinising the deal.</p>
<p>Dieter Wolf, chief anti-trust watchdog, said on Tuesday that if the CLT/Ufa-Kirch deal meant merging their pay TV activities, this would be &quot;very critical&quot;.</p>
<p>The deal with Telekom also allows other companies to put together pay TV packages in competition to Premiere or DF1, but the battle between Bertelsmann and Kirch has so far kept other companies on the sidelines.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still in the pioneer phase,&quot; said Premiere spokesman Arnold Kulbatzki. &quot;We are talking about a market that doesn't really exist yet.&quot;</p>
<p>-- william.boston@reuters.com (Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097 150)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
