<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70333" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Sanxia Paints joint venture set to open.</title>
<headline>Sanxia Paints joint venture set to open.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sichuan-based Sanxia Paints Co Ltd's joint venture with two Japanese firms is set to go into formal production next month, a spokeswoman for Sanxia said on Monday.</p>
<p>The 60-million-yuan project, in which Sanxia has a 50 percent stake, will have the capacity to produce 5,000 tonnes of automobile paint a year, the spokeswoman told the China Securities Bulletin.</p>
<p>Japanese firm Kansai Paint Co Ltd holds a 45 percent stake in the Chonqqing Kansai Paint Co Ltd, with the Japan-based Asahi Trading Co Ltd holding the remaining five percent.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said the project should generate net earnings of about 10 million yuan next year and contribute about one million yuan to Shenzhen-listed Sanxia's earnings this year.</p>
<p>She added that the three partners in the project aim to market the car paint in southwestern China.</p>
<p>Sanxia was currently engaged in talks with ICI Swire Paints Ltd on joint production of paints for industrial use in the city of Chongqing in southwestern Sichuan province.  </p>
<p>A letter of intent on the project would be endorsed in October, she said, adding that each side would have a 50 percent stake in the project. She gave no futher details.</p>
<p>The official said Sanxia is also preparing to take over a state-owned paints plant in Chengdu, Sichuan's capital. Sanxia would acquire the failing plant by assuming part of its liabilities and paying some cash, she said.</p>
<p>Sanxia said in its interim report that under Chinese accounting standards it had net earnings of 7.95 million yuan in the first half of this year, compared with 5.62 million yuan in the January-June preiod of 1995.</p>
<p>The firm said the earnings surge was based on its success in reducing operating costs and in developing a new line of paints carrying higher profit margins.</p>
<p>Sanxia reported after-tax profits of 7.72 million yuan for 1995, down 57.82 percent from 18.30 million yuan the previous year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
