<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="703438" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British firms still fairly new Internet users.</title>
<headline>British firms still fairly new Internet users.</headline>
<byline>Medora Lee</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>British financial firms are still fairly new to the Internet, most having had access for only about a year, a Reuters survey published on Wednesday showed.</p>
<p>But access is expected to rise, with 82 percent seeing the Internet becoming a significant business tool in five years.</p>
<p>Only 22 of 125 respondents to the survey, carried out over the past six weeks, saw the Internet as a little significant or insignificant.</p>
<p>The poll also showed intranets, or internal nets exclusive to a set group of people, are spreading among British companies.</p>
<p>So far, only 32 of 112 firms said they had intranets, but 40 said they expected to have an internal system within the next two years. Most planned to launch one within a year.</p>
<p>&quot;There is vast potential for intranets, rather more than the Internet,&quot; said Adrian Thomas, data processing manager at Danesfield Securities Ltd, which is now setting up its intranet.</p>
<p>Though he sees the Internet playing a very significant role in how people will do business in five years, he currently sees it as insecure, slow and difficult to maintain without a specialised staff.</p>
<p>As a result, his company is focusing for now on an intranet to post manuals and company information to eliminate paper and make the company more efficient.</p>
<p>Thomas was one of 55 respondents who considered the Internet as currently insecure, while 17 said it was very insecure. Forty-nine felt secure with the Internet.</p>
<p>Websites garnered more interest, with 52 of 113 firms saying they already have one. Thirty-four said they plan to set up a site, most within six months.</p>
<p>Reuters polled British firms and foreign-owned companies with a representation in Britain for their views on the Internet. Just less than half the firms, which had a median size of 50 employees, came from the finance, banking and investment.</p>
<p>Other groups represented include commodities firms, insurers, building societies, market makers, funds, stock brokers, analytical firms, venture capitalists, ship brokers, bond credit rating agencies and syndicate managers.</p>
<p>A hundred and thirteen firms said they had Internet access. The most experienced Web surfer had been hooked up for five years and the latest newcomer, insurer Chiyodo Europe, had been wired for about a month. Another 10 said they expected to get wired within three to 12 months.</p>
<p>Of the 108 who detailed how they used the Internet, 85 percent said for communication, particularly electronic mail.</p>
<p>About 76 percent mentioned research, followed by 59 percent for reference and 54 percent to gather corporate information.</p>
<p>Nearly 39 percent said they used the Internet to check up on rivals, 23 percent said they advertised and 21 percent searched for government information.</p>
<p>About 18 percent said they logged on for other reasons, mostly to download software and get technical assistance.</p>
<p>Just above seven percent said they did business via the Internet, with four percent using the medium to confirm deals.</p>
<p>Ninety-three percent of the 122 who saw the Internet becoming at least a little significant within five years said information would be the Internet's biggest attraction.</p>
<p>Advertising was seen as the Internet's second-biggest draw at 66 percent, with transacting business a close third with 65 percent. Forty percent saw the Internet as a banking platform and 38 percent expected it to be a potential income source.</p>
<p>Eleven percent said they could also see potential for other uses with multimedia developments make video conferencing and other voice-related technologies available.</p>
<p>-- London Polling Unit: +44 171 542 2737</p>
<p>			   email: polling.unit@rtrlondon.co.uk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
