<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="703447" id="root" date="1997-07-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Enterprise hits record high on Enserch deal.</title>
<headline>Enterprise hits record high on Enserch deal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Enterprise Oil Plc jumped more than three percent to a record high on the back of its announced oil exploration venture in the Gulf of Mexico with Enserch Exploration Inc, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>A slight recovery in world oil prices and further gains in Britain's FTSE 100 share index also fuelled Enterprise's gains, they said.</p>
<p>At 0839 GMT, Enterprise was up 24-1/2p at 704p after registering its lifetime high of 706p. Volume was just over one million.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market as a whole is up already and oil prices are up very bullishly,&quot; said Shawn Reynolds, equities research analyst at Lehman Brothers. &quot;Plus this deal, which is a great deal.&quot;</p>
<p>He rated the stock an &quot;outperform&quot; and said he was revisiting his 12-month price target of 720p.</p>
<p>Enserch and Enterprise said on Tuesday they agreed to a joint oil exploration venture in the deep water of the Gulf of Mexico, whereby Enterprise will pay the U.S.-based company $65 million for a 50 percent share of its deepwater portfolio.</p>
<p>Another $35 million payment by Enterprise is contingent on drilling successes and the announcement of commercial development.</p>
<p>The deal is subject to government approvals.</p>
<p>Other oil exploration company shares were mixed, with Lasmo Plc gaining 2-1/2p to 269-1/2p and Cairn Energy Plc slipping 6p to 475p. Hardy Oil &amp; Gas Plc edged down 1-1/2p to 336p.</p>
<p>The front-month Brent crude oil contract on the International Petroleum Exchange ended Tuesday at $18.80 a barrel, up from a low of $17.32 in mid-June. Crude prices were expected to open 10-15 cents lower when trading begins on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- John Hanley, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4366</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
