<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70343" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: SAS says &quot;barging&quot; to Macau has a success.</title>
<headline>SAS says &quot;barging&quot; to Macau has a success.</headline>
<byline>Jim Gilchrist</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scandinavian Airlines System (SAS) said its &quot;pioneering&quot; use of a barge to transfer air cargo from Hong Kong to Macau airport over the past six months has been a surprising success.</p>
<p>SAS began the unusual barge service in March to feed the airline's first scheduled freighter flight from the Portuguese enclave's new airport which opened last November. South Korea's Asiana Airlines has followed suit inaugurating a similar service this month.</p>
<p>SAS said its twice weekly service to Delhi and Gothenburg using a Boeing 747-200 freighter leased from Atlas Air marked a return to the air cargo market.</p>
<p>&quot;We are operating beyond our expectations,&quot; Soren Jespersen, SAS general manager for Hong Kong, southern China, Taipei and the Philippines told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We were the pioneers of shipping from Hong Kong to the warehouse. Macau has handled it very well. It was a little awkward having a ship feed but it is only four hours transfer by sea and is extremely efficient. It's almost like going from one side of Hong Kong to another on a busy day,&quot; Jespersen said.</p>
<p>Ased about customer reaction to airfreight being transferred by barge, he said:&quot;Of course there has been some questions primarily from the forwarding industry but our biggest customers take it for granted that SAS would not undertake some second rate sea transfer.&quot;</p>
<p>He declined to give detailed information on volumes carried but informed sources say the twice weekly flights on Wednesday and Saturdays are fully booked. SAS also operate four times weekly passenger non-stop flights from Hong Kong to Copenhagen using a Boeing 767-300.s</p>
<p>&quot;The market in southern China is very strong. Scandinavia has very good trade relations and I envisage more and more shipments from southern China will go directly to Macau and onto Copenhagen when producers and buyers see our product,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said it was to early to say if the service would be expanded and was waiting to evaluate the full year's schedule.</p>
<p>&quot;Even in the very soft season we were beyond expectations and have done very well,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Macau's new airport, just a few minutes flying time from congested Kai Tak airport in Hong Kong, is thought to be keen to pay off its substantial construction costs by attracting more cargo airlines.</p>
<p>But industry observers said while costs are 20 per cent cheaper, many carriers have been adopting a 'wait and see' policy before using Macau's under-utilised facilities.</p>
<p>However airlines already flying to Macau include Singapore Airlines, Asiana Airlines, TAP-Air Portugal, Malaysia Airlines System Bhd, TransAsia Airways, Air Macau and EVA Air.</p>
<p>Jespersen said SAS chose Macau because of its close proximity to the growing market in southern China and unlike Hong Kong is open 24 hour. He thinks other airlines will follow his airline's example and also start flying into Macau.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is a good alternative for a lot of the airlines to avoid congestion at Kai Tak, he said.&quot; --Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MACAO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
