<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="703981" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Some House Republicans buck leadership on arts funds.</title>
<headline>Some House Republicans buck leadership on arts funds.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than two dozen House Republicans rallied Thursday around the beleaguered National Endowment for the Arts, which conservatives want to shut down.</p>
<p>Rep. Rick Lazio, a New York Republican, said 28 Republicans had agreed to sign his letter backing the NEA that will be sent Monday to House Speaker Newt Gingrich.</p>
<p>&quot;The federal government's modest investment in the arts is an example of wise funding,&quot; Lazio wrote.</p>
<p>He said the federal money -- $100 million this year -- produced a return both economically and culturally.</p>
<p>Lazio said big metropolitan arts organizations and museums may survive but &quot;programs that most directly affect our communities -- small dance (troupes), neighborhood theater groups, folk art festivals -- will suffer.&quot;</p>
<p>The House Appropriations Committee last week voted to spend only $10 million for the NEA -- just enough to close it down.</p>
<p>A vote by the full House could come as early as next week but the aim of the letter was to get a large enough coalition of pro-NEA Republicans and Democrats to thwart efforts to kill the arts agency.</p>
<p>The House Republican leadership has accused the NEA of being elitist and funding objectionable or immoral works. But earlier attempts to eliminate it have failed, and the agency has more support among Senate Republicans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
