<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704183" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: SOCCER-FANS SHUN RIO CHAMPIONSHIP DECIDER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FANS SHUN RIO CHAMPIONSHIP DECIDER.</headline>
<byline>Brian Homewood</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Demoralised fans shunned the chaotic Rio de Janeiro championship when only 275 people turned up to watch the decisive third-stage game between Fluminense and Botafogo.</p>
<p>Fluminense came from behind to win 2-1 but Wednesday's result meant that Vasco da Gama won the third stage, ahead of Fluminense on goal difference, and will meet Botafogo, winners of the first two stages, in the final play-off series.</p>
<p>The public lost interest in May when, with the competition about to reach its climax, the Rio football federation suddenly interrupted the action at the request of Vasco who had two players picked to play for Brazil in the Copa America.</p>
<p>As a result the Botafogo-Fluminense game, which had been expected to attract a bumper crowd of around 80,000 people to the Maracana stadium, was postponed at four days' notice.</p>
<p>The new date had  been announced late on Monday and Wednesday's game was played in a small stadium in a distant suburb of Rio.</p>
<p>Flamengo, who also had a chance of winning the third stage, had already agreed to take part in other tournaments this week and said they advised the federation they could not fulfil two fixtures which had been rescheduled for Tuesday and Thursday.</p>
<p>However, the federation replied by awarding 1-0 walkover wins to their respective opponents Americano and Vasco da Gama.</p>
<p>To add to the general confusion, Flamengo say they still want to play the games and have hinted they will take legal action against the federation's walkover decision.</p>
<p>They were backed on Wednesday by Fluminense president Alvaro Barros. He said he wanted Flamengo to finish their games as this could open the gate for Fluminense to reach the final, depending on the results.</p>
<p>Another problem is that the final play-off series between Botafogo and Fluminense, which could last from one to three matches, now clashes with the opening rounds of the Brazilian championship starting on Saturday.</p>
<p>In Brazil state championships are played in the first half of the year, with the national championship following in the second.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
