<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704113" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TENNIS-HINGIS BREEZES THROUGH, NOVOTNA ON FORM.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-HINGIS BREEZES THROUGH, NOVOTNA ON FORM.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Laurence</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top seed Martina Hingis ended Anna Kournikova's dream Wimbledon debut on Thursday to move into her third consecutive grand slam final where she will meet sentimental favourite Jana Novotna.</p>
<p>Hingis, who became the youngest grand slam winner this century by winning the Australian Open in January, added yet another record to her name by beating the unseeded Russian prodigy 6-3 6-2 in just over an hour.</p>
<p>The battle of the two 16-year-olds, however, failed to live up to its expectations as a showpiece of the new look the women's game will take into the millennium.</p>
<p>It was left to the veterans Novotna, at 28, and Arantxa Sanchez Vicario, 25, to carry the flag for the women's game.</p>
<p>Third seeded Novotna, who said her father had watched the match from his hospital bed in her home town of Brno in the Czech Republic, charged the net at every opportunity on her way to beating Sanchez Vicario 6-4 6-2.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see two contrasts of style (on Saturday) which will make for good tennis,&quot; said Novotna, who has been a crowd favourite at Wimbledon after losing the 1993 final to Steffi Graf when she had been within reach of victory.</p>
<p>Novotna and Sanchez Vicario, who parted ways acrimoniously two years ago after dominating women's doubles, exchanged bitter words in the lead up to the match.</p>
<p>The spat appeared to spill over onto the court, both players attacking every shot with aggression, opting for sheer power instead of poise.</p>
<p>Hingis becomes the youngest Wimbledon finalist in the Open era, surpassing the previous record of 18 years set by Graf in 1987.</p>
<p>Kournikova, nine months younger than her Swiss rival, charged into the semifinals with displays of brute power and pinpoint accuracy. But on a cold, bleak day on centre court she showed only glimpses of the panache which saw her upset the likes of fourth seed Iva Majoli and Anke Huber on the way to her first grand slam semifinal.</p>
<p>The Russian held serve just once, leaving a lukewarm Hingis the job of just waiting for a mistake.</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn't one of my best performances at this tournament,&quot; said Hingis. &quot;I tried to kind of keep the ball in the game and waited for the mistakes...she made more mistakes than winners.&quot;</p>
<p>As a showcase for the future of women's tennis, it turned out to be flatter than English bitter beer served in the bars in the court surrounds.</p>
<p>&quot;I did my best, but I have played a lot of tennis in the past week and was tired,&quot; said Kournikova after the match.</p>
<p>The Russian added: &quot;I didn't want to be scared. I just wanted to go for my shots.&quot;</p>
<p>A moody Hingis, who lost her first match of the year to Iva Majoli in the French Open final last month, held serve in the seventh and ninth games taking the first set in 34 minutes.</p>
<p>Kournikova, ranked 42 in the world, saved one match point in the second set with a stinging double backhanded winner, but then fired a similar shot into the net to continue Hingis's stunning run in grand slams this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
