<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704125" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MOTOR RACING-BARRICHELLO UNHURT AFTER 280 KPH CRASH.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-BARRICHELLO UNHURT AFTER 280 KPH CRASH.</headline>
<dateline>SILVERSTONE, England 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian Formula One driver Rubens Barrichello escaped unhurt from a 280 kph crash during testing at Silverstone on Thursday.</p>
<p>After walking away following a rear suspension failure, the Stewart driver said the controversial new tyre regulations proposed for next year were partly to blame for the severity of his impact.</p>
<p>Barrichello was testing the new grooved tyres which are to come into use next year.</p>
<p>He said: &quot;I don't like the new tyres, especially after the experience I have had. Something broke on the rear suspension which put me into a spin but if I had been on this year's tyres I would have just spun into the gravel.</p>
<p>&quot;The grooved tyres didn't slow me down as much and I thought that, when I was spinning in the car, it would stop. But it didn't. It went across the gravel and then there was a big boom.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be better and safer to have bigger tyres and reduce the power.&quot;</p>
<p>Mika Hakkinen's McLaren was fastest in testing for the British Grand Prix in a time one minute 22.97 seconds.</p>
<p>Michael Schumacher's Ferrari was second with 1:22.99 and Jordan's Giancarlo Fisichella third (1:23.00).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SILVERSTONE, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
