<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704387" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Italy completes set of benchmark EMU bonds.</title>
<headline>Italy completes set of benchmark EMU bonds.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy completed a portfolio of long-dated benchmark bonds in key EMU currencies with the successful launch of a 3.0 billion mark ($1.7 billion) Eurobond on Thursday, bankers said.</p>
<p>The 10-year Eurobond, priced to yield 18 basis points over Bunds, was raised from an initial 2.0 billion marks in the face of overwhelming demand.</p>
<p>&quot;The deal was very well oversubscribed, even after the add-on,&quot; a syndicate manager at joint lead manager Deutsche Morgan Grenfell said.</p>
<p>Italy has already this year issued large, liquid transactions in French francs, guilders and Ecu. These deals, as well as Thursday's mark bond, redenominate into the euro when EMU is introduced.</p>
<p>It has also issued major deals in dollars, Swiss francs and yen in 1997.</p>
<p>The deals are part of Italy's drive to familiarise European investors with its credit ahead of monetary union, bankers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Italy has now issued in all major currencies in Europe and a successful mark transaction was a strategic goal for Italy,&quot; the Deutsche official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Comments all over the world are very positive. It has been a very big success and was exactly what Italy was looking for,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Italy is the first sovereign to issue 10-year mark Eurobonds this year and investors rushed to buy the bonds, the Deutsche official said.</p>
<p>&quot;The pricing was absolutely fair and gave investors the chance to buy a bond with spread tightening potential of one or two basis points,&quot; Deutsche said.</p>
<p>Deutsche said its distribution was as follows: Germany 40 percent, France 12 percent, Netherlands 12 percent, rest of Europe 13 percent, Asia 11 percent, Britain 7 percent, and the balance in the Middle East and Switzerland.</p>
<p>SBC Warburg was the other joint lead manager.</p>
<p>($ = 1.753 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
