<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704428" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO: Zaire says U.N. must agree basic probe conditions.</title>
<headline>Zaire says U.N. must agree basic probe conditions.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Malu-Malu</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Laurent Kabila's Democratic Republic of the Congo said on Thursday that U.N. investigators must agree basic conditions if they want to launch their probe into alleged massacres of Hutu refugees as planned on July 7.</p>
<p>Kabila's National Reconstruction and Emergency Planning Minister Etienne Richard Mbaya told a news conference the probe could go ahead on time if he received an appropriate response from an advance U.N. team in the capital Kinshasa.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not the ones holding things up. It (the advance team) is not in a position to reach agreement with us on the minimum conditions that we insist on for this inquiry,&quot; Mbaya said. &quot;Our sovereignty is important to us.&quot;</p>
<p>In Geneva, Fred Eckhardt, U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan's spokesman, said negotiations were continuing. &quot;There remain a number of sticking points... We haven't given up.&quot;</p>
<p>A U.N. advance team, including Argentine forensic experts who would excavate sites suspected to contain mass graves in former Zaire, has been in Kinshasa for two weeks seeking accord on the terms for the full investigation due to start on July 7.</p>
<p>The probe follows allegations that Kabila's Tutsi-backed rebels or their Rwandan or Ugandan allies killed Rwandan Hutu refugees as their forces marched across former Zaire between October and May and toppled veteran dictator Mobutu Sese Seko.</p>
<p>The conditions outlined by Kabila's government concern the period covered by the investigation and those conducting the probe. &quot;A serious delegation must accept them,&quot; Mbaya said.</p>
<p>Kabila's government wants the team to investigate atrocities against refugees as far back as 1994 and the immediate aftermath of the genocide in Rwanda of minority Tutsis by Hutu hardliners.</p>
<p>&quot;Violations were denounced to the U.N. while Mobutu was in power (in Zaire),&quot; Mbaya said.</p>
<p>Kabila's government also refuses to accept Chilean lawyer Roberto Garreton, U.N. rapporteur or special investiagtor for the area since 1994, as a member of the mission. &quot;Garreton produced a report full of lies,&quot; Mbaya said. &quot;The U.N. has other personalities.&quot;</p>
<p>In April, Garreton accused the rebels of massacring Rwandan refugees during their push across the region in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Kabila is uncomfortable with Mr. Garreton. The Secretary-General wants to see an investigation carried out,&quot; U.N. spokesman Eckhardt said in Geneva. &quot;Our dilemma is how to reconcile these two competing agendas. The objective is to get the team in.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the Hutu refugees flooded out of Rwanda in 1994 fearing reprisals after armed Tutsis exiles returned and drove out the Hutu hardliners responsible for the genocide. Others fled from the Tutsi-dominated army in neighbouring Burundi.</p>
<p>U.N. Security Council members on Monday called on Kinshasa to cooperate with U.N. human rights investigators, with some envoys urging senior U.N. officials to help in negotiations with Kabila.</p>
<p>&quot;The members expressed their concern (and) the need for the Democratic Republic of the Congo authorities to fully cooperate with the investigation team,&quot; said Council President Sergei Lavrov of Russia after a closed-door meeting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UGANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
