<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704451" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aggressive offshore and local institutional buying pummelled bond yields to fresh 16-month lows on Thursday, bringing the market's gains to almost 80 basis points in the last two weeks.</p>
<p>At 1400 GMT, the benchmark R150 was pegged at a 14.095 percent yield -- down 14 points from Wednesday's 14.245 percent finish and compared with 14.88 percent on June 18.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been huge, huge demand across the board, the majority of it starting again in the mediums similar to yesterday,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the TK06, TK16 and E169 all rallied as players began discounting an interest rate cut, which economists expect in the second half of this year.</p>
<p>Dealers said the longer-end of the curve also attracted demand. &quot;The R153s and R184s have been the stars,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>The yield on the R184 and R153 were both last quoted at 14.12 percent from 14.295 percent and 14.265 percent respectively on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The R153 is now trading one or two points to the 150s and that hasn't happened for a long time,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Traders said, however, that it was unclear what had sparked the demand.</p>
<p>One cited stronger U.S. Treasuries, which were given a fresh fillip in early New York trade by bullish employment data in the wake of the Federal Reserve's decision not to hike U.S. interest rates late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Another trader said there had been talk in the market of a zero-coupon eurorand issue in the offing, as well as talk of an asset swap which had left a player short of the long end.</p>
<p>The assault that ensued hurled the R150 through technical resistance at 14.20 down to the 14.10 percent level where dealers said the market ran into sizeable profit-taking by a London-based institution.</p>
<p>Fears that the market was technically overbought and due for a retracement were generally shrugged off and dealers said they expected fresh gains again on Friday.  </p>
<p>On the currency market, the rand benefited from mainly offshore and exporter dollar sales which dealers said outweighed small amounts of importer demand.</p>
<p>In late trade, it was quoted at 4.5245/5265 against the dollar from 4.5295/5325 overnight.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen flows from exporters and quite a bit from offshore,&quot; a trader said. &quot;There has not been much demand.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said the rand's efforts to push below the 4.52 level had been stymied by both the local demand and the fact that the dollar had posted a fresh 40-month high against the Deutschmark.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, the rand slumped to a fresh five month low against sterling as cable rallied to its strongest level since January in the wake of the British Labour government's budget presented late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The rand was last trading at 7.6112/6208 against sterling from 7.4776/4871 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Against the mark and yen, the rand was last at 0.3864/3868 from 0.3859/3864 overnight and at 25.0768/1155 yen from 25.2372/2759 yen.</p>
<p>On the money market, three-month NCDs were quoted at between 14.75 and 14.80 percent offered, while the 90-day BA rate was slightly lower at between 15.15 and 15.35 percent from 15.20 to 15.35 percent.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank quoted the money market shortage lower at 5.379 billion rand on Wednesday from 5.901 billion rand on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange figures showed foreigners were net buyers 732.6 million rand's worth of South African bonds on Wednesday after buying 109.6 million rand's worth on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Nominal cumulative volumes on the bond market on Wednesday were 10.05 billion rand from 9.9 billion rand on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
