<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704464" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NAMIBIA: Nambia suspends immediate plans to drain Okavango.</title>
<headline>Nambia suspends immediate plans to drain Okavango.</headline>
<byline>Frauke Jensen</byline>
<dateline>WINDHOEK 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Namibia's cabinet has suspended immediate plans to tap the Okavango River after good rains, but said the water pipeline was still needed in the long term, Information Minister Ben Amathila said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cabinet considered the findings of the feasibility study into the emergency link from the Okavango River to Grootfontein and resolved that due to the good inflows to the dams, the pipeline construction project no longer needs to be considered as a humanitarian crisis,&quot; Amathila told reporters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But he said the need for the 250km pipeline from Rundu on the Okavango to Grootfontein, where it will link up with the existing network supplying the capital Windhoek, still remained.</p>
<p>Conservationists have criticised plans to drain the waters of the Okavango River saying it will disrupt the delicate ecosystem of the Okavango Delta in neighbouring Botswana.</p>
<p>The delta, the world's largest, is Botswana's main tourist destination.</p>
<p>&quot;The Okavango River-Grootfontein pipeline link requires to be further investigated immediately in terms of a detailed design...for possible implementation within the next four and a half years,&quot; Amathila said.</p>
<p>He said the Namibian government would continue consultations with Angola and Botswana, through the Okavango Basin Commission, on the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;Cabinet resolved that a full environmental assessment be undertaken to facilitate the agreement of co-basin states, Angola and Botswana, to Namibia's planned abstraction...,&quot; the minister said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Agriculture, Water and Rural Development Minister Helmuth Angula has put a motion to parliament to emphasise the importance of agreements on shared water sources to help develop its economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NAMIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINDHOEK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NAMIBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
