<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704796" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Sachs says Argentina too dependent on Brazil - paper.</title>
<headline>Sachs says Argentina too dependent on Brazil - paper.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Harvard Institute Director Jeffrey Sachs was quoted Thursday as saying that Argentina is too dependent on exports to Brazil and that Brazil will strongly devalue its currency in the next two years, further compounding that risk.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no confidence in Argentine export competitiviness and I think investors do not understand that (external) debt is paid with sales abroad,&quot; he told Clarin newspaper.</p>
<p>However, Sachs said the Argentine economy looked solid.  </p>
<p>&quot;The economic situation is good.  There is ongoing stability with economic growth.  There is confidence abroad. Unemployment is ruuning high but is decreasing.  Everything looks OK.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said Argentine products are not competitive and are too dependent on the Brazilian market.</p>
<p>&quot;The exports that grew were basically those of oil and agribusiness sectors,&quot; he said according to Clarin.  &quot;The only market for industrial Argentine products is Brazil, and with a single market countries cannot progress.&quot;</p>
<p>Sachs said both Argentina and Brazil are not very interested in enhancing their long-term exports and are closed to the rest of the world.</p>
<p>In remarks to Pagina 12 newspaper he said &quot;there will be a big Real (Brazilian currency) devaluation sometime in the next two years.</p>
<p>&quot;That doesn't necessarily imply a recession in Brazil, but it does imply a great loss of Argentine economic competitiviness vis-a-vis that of Brazil.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Guillermo Haskel, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 318-0650))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
