<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704791" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile stock rally seen gathering steam.</title>
<headline>Chile stock rally seen gathering steam.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean stocks marched higher at the opening on a wave of foreign buy orders, with investors taking positions amid speculation of good company first half results, said traders.</p>
<p>&quot;The bolsa is gaining force and within the next few days could pass 137 points -- its highest point so far this year,&quot; said Enrique Danioni, head of research at brokers Sud Americano.  &quot;If it passes this barrier, then it could reach 140 points as there's plenty of upside.&quot;</p>
<p>The 40-share index opened up 0.91 percent at 136.43 points.  </p>
<p>The IPSA reached its highest point this year of 137.15 points on June 12 before steadily slipping back.</p>
<p>Traders reported the market buoyed by the Federal Reserve's decision Wednesday to leave U.S. interest rates unchanged and by low cumulative inflation in the first six months of the year.  Chilean consumer prices rose 0.2 percent in June, bringing the increase in the first six months of the year to 2.5 percent.</p>
<p>Electricity stocks opened sharply higher with investors keen to re-enter the sector following the end of the drought and the government's recent decision on tariffs, said dealers.  </p>
<p>&quot;The future for the electricity sector is a lot clearer. All the doubts which have clouded the industry have disappeared,&quot; said Danioni.</p>
<p>Enersis was up 1.33 percent at 304 pesos, while Endesa firmed 0.79 percent to 320 pesos.</p>
<p>((-- Margaret Orgill, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595x212))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
