<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704872" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs seen aiming high after rise on LIFFE.</title>
<headline>JGBs seen aiming high after rise on LIFFE.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key September 10-year Japanese government bond futures contract is expected to open near 125.00 and test the upside on Friday, following a rise on LIFFE and a surge in U.S. Treasuries overnight, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;JGBs are likely to kick the day off with a sharp rise...of about 0.30 point above the previous day's close,&quot; said a senior trader for a city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>Traders said a sharp rise in U.S. Treasuries after the release of weaker-than-expected U.S. jobs data triggered the rise in JGBs on LIFFE. They said the market would focus on whether investors decide to buy following such a rise.  </p>
<p>&quot;We can expect new long positions (in JGB futures) to appear for awhile,&quot; said a trader for another city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>&quot;But cash bonds have not been rising to the same extent as futures recently, and the focus will be on whether cash JGBs will be bought today,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Traders said the September may rise as high as 125.30 during the day.</p>
<p>The September ended at 124.99 on LIFFE overnight, up from Thursday's Tokyo close of 124.73.</p>
<p>It moved in a range of 124.73 to 125.00 on LIFFE.  </p>
<p>Investors may not be that eager to buy if JGBs rise sharply, judging from their recent stance toward JGBs, the first trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is true that buying by investors has partly been responsible for the recent rise in JGBs. But over the last couple of days, their tendency has been to say they would like to buy if JGBs fall to around 124.00,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Dealers probably have been mainly responsible for supporting JGBs in recent days, by buying despite the cautious stance among investors, he said.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-5473-3748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
