<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704969" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo naphtha up, LSWR seen done over $17.50/bbl.</title>
<headline>Tokyo naphtha up, LSWR seen done over $17.50/bbl.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo naphtha prices were higher on Thursday in tandem with overnight crude, while 100,000 barrels of South Korean low sulphur waxy residue (LSWR) were traded at slightly over $17.50 per barrel, traders said.</p>
<p>They also said the naphtha market remained unaffected by an oil spill from the supertanker Diamond Grace, which on Wednesday hit a reef in shallow waters in Tokyo Bay and leaked an estimated 1,550 kl of crude oil.</p>
<p>The spot LSWR cargo for first-half July loading was said to have been sold to a Japanese oil firm.  </p>
<p>Open-spec naphtha was assessed at $201.75/203.00 per tonne for first-half September delivery, up from Wednesday's $200.75/201.25.</p>
<p>In spreads, first-half August/first-half September changed hands at even. It was quoted at about minus 75 to minus 50 cents earlier this week.</p>
<p>However, some traders said the deal did not reflect the general trend, adding that the contango in near-term naphtha spreads was expected to widen, rather than contract.</p>
<p>&quot;Prompt cargoes are likely to remain on the weak side with good availability for second-half August,&quot; one trader said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
