<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="704931" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: IPCO unit entering JV for energy projects.</title>
<headline>IPCO unit entering JV for energy projects.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPCO International Ltd said on Thursday its newly formed unit Gulf Asia Holdings Ltd will enter into a joint venture to develop energy-related infrastructure projects in the Middle East and Central Asia.</p>
<p>The joint venture, International Project Developers Ltd (IPD), will be formed following a shareholders agreement on June 28 with DG International Oil Ltd, a subsidiary of Saudi Arabia's Dabbagh Group Holding Co Ltd, IPCO said in a statement.  </p>
<p>IPD, which will have its headquarters in Dubai, seeks to develop, own and operate infrastructure works in power generation, transmission and distribution, water treatment and distribution facilities.</p>
<p>It will also be involved in the construction of oil and gas facilities as well as transportation systems.</p>
<p>When established, IPD will have an authorised and paid up capital of 100,000 pounds sterling divided into 100,000 ordinary shares of one pound each. Dabbagh will have a 51 percent stake in the joint venture while Gulf Asia will own 49 percent.  </p>
<p>IPCO said its investment in IPD is not expected to have any impact on the net tangible assets and earnings per share of IPCO for the financial year ending April 30, 1998.</p>
<p>Gulf Asia is a new company formed in Labuan by IPCO's Malaysian subsidiary IPCO Sdn Bhd with Promet Berhad. ($1.00=1.67 pounds)</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
