<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="705071" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Judge removes Grossberg lawyer over TV interview.</title>
<headline>Judge removes Grossberg lawyer over TV interview.</headline>
<byline>Rita Farrell</byline>
<dateline>WILMINGTON, Del. 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Delaware judge on Thursday revoked a New York attorney's permission to represent Amy Grossberg, the teenager who, along with her boyfriend Brian Peterson, is charged with murdering her newborn son and disposing of his body in a dumpster.</p>
<p>In ruling from the bench, Judge Henry DuPont Ridgely of the Delaware Superior court said remarks made by Robert Gottlieb to Barbara Walters on the ABC-TV programme &quot;20/20&quot; violated a gag order against pretrial publicity.</p>
<p>Ridgely said Gottlieb's statement on the June 6 show that &quot;Amy should not have been charged. Amy is not guilty&quot; was opinion and therefore prohibited.</p>
<p>&quot;The impact of his statements was maximized by the context of prime-time national television only 97 days before the scheduled trial,&quot; Ridgely said.</p>
<p>Although Ridgely denied prosecutor Paul Wallace's request that Grossberg also be sanctioned for appearing on the Walters show, she burst into tears after the ruling. In an affidavit before the hearing, Grossberg said, &quot;If you take Mr. Gottlieb away from me, I am terrified that I will no longer be protected.&quot;</p>
<p>Ridgely also expanded the gag order to include Grossberg and Peterson and &quot;all persons assisting or associated with the prosecutors or defence counsel in these cases.&quot; Peterson has not held any press interviews since his arrest in November.</p>
<p>Gottlieb's attorneys in the hearing, Court TV's Rikki Kleiman and Raymond Brown, said they would appeal the ruling to the Delaware Supreme Court. Ridgely refused to delay the order despite Brown's characterisation that not to do so was &quot;draconian.&quot;</p>
<p>Grossberg's former Delaware lawyer Charles Oberly, who set up the arrangements for the Walters interview, said Ridgely's ruling &quot;was a very clear message that out-of-town counsel needs to tread very carefully when they come. Delaware is not Philadelphia or New York or Washington. It's a relatively conservative state. Judge Ridgely felt a line had been crossed.&quot;</p>
<p>The trial of Grossberg and Peterson is set for Oct. 6. If convicted, they could face the death penalty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILMINGTON, Del."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
