<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="705270" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN Council willing to endorse small Congo force.</title>
<headline>UN Council willing to endorse small Congo force.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Security Council agreed in principle on Thursday to endorse a multinational, mainly African, force for the Congo but there was no immediate sign of money emerging to make it possible.</p>
<p>An African force in Brazzaville, according to U.N. special envoy Mohamed Sahnoun, would need voluntary financing and a lead country to organise the operation. Neither was available at the moment, although the Congo government has offered $1 million for peacekeepers.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan is expected to report shortly to the council on his proposals, which will probably include requests for funds to finance about 1,000 advance troops in the Congo capital, Brazzaville.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a general agreement in the council about the deployment of such a force and there was a willingness among the members...to act rapidly and constructively on the basis of proposals by the secretary-general in this respect,&quot; Council President Peter Osvald of Sweden said.</p>
<p>Sahnoun briefed council members and told a news conference later that the 1,000 soldiers should secure the airport to make sure new weapons did not arrive and patrol with opposing factions to verify that a ceasefire was honoured.</p>
<p>Diplomats said a small U.N.-organised force could eventually follow. Such a force would be financed by all members, whereby a multinational force would need funds from the participants or other countries.</p>
<p>In either case, troop-contributing countries need the legitimacy of a Security Council endorsement as Italy obtained before it led troops into Albania this year.</p>
<p>The current conflict in Congo, which has left hundreds of civilians dead, erupted on June 5 when President Pascal Lissouba tried to arrest his rival and immediate predecessor, Denis Sassou Nguesso during efforts to disband private militias ahead of elections.</p>
<p>A mid-June ceasefire was negotiated by Gabon's president Omar Bongo, heading a team of African leaders from eight countries, the mayor of Brazzaville and Sahnoun, hours after France pulled out soldiers who had evacuated foreigners.</p>
<p>But fighting has resumed and shots frequently land across the river near Kinshasa, capital of the Democratic Republic of the Congo, formerly Zaire. Sahnoun said authorities in Kinshasa told him they intended to fire back if the shooting continued.</p>
<p>&quot;A detachment at the airport can create a tremendous psychological impact and enhance a ceasefire,&quot; Sahnoun said.</p>
<p>Asked if the council was worried about sending troops before a lasting ceasefire, Sahnoun said: &quot;I noted that we could have a ceasefire for a week, we could have a ceasefire for 10 days, but we cannot guarantee a ceasefire forever because then we don't need a force.&quot;</p>
<p>France is currently reviewing its Africa policy and does not want to lead a peacekeeping force, although it has said it would help with transport or logistics.</p>
<p>African countries Botswana, Niger, Senegal and Togo as well as Bangladesh in Asia have indicated willingness to send troops, U.N. sources said. Senegal could emerge as leader of the force.</p>
<p>The United States and France, worried that the fighting in the Congo could destabilise the region again, have intervened in an effort to convince warring parties to negotiate peace under Bongo's leadership.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
