<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70532" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs end mostly off, pork bellies off sharply.</title>
<headline>CME hogs end mostly off, pork bellies off sharply.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog futures ended mostly lower on spillover pressure from other livestock and meat pits while pork belly futures finished sharply lower on commercial liquidation and technical pressure, traders said.</p>
<p>Hog futures finished 0.500 cent a lb lower to 0.300 higher with only distant August posting a gain and October off 0.125 at 57.175 cents. Pork bellies ended 1.725 to 0.700 cent a lb lower with February off most at 76.650 cents.</p>
<p>Hog futures again followed action in other meat pits in a reduced volume day, traders noted. The market appeared overbought and a break in live cattle and pork bellies sparked selling.</p>
<p>Futures were up early on Friday's bullish-looking Cold Storage report with steady cash hog indications limiting the setback later, traders said. The report showed bone-in ham stocks at 66 percent of a year ago and overall frozen pork supplies at fairly low levels, traders added.</p>
<p>Dean Witter, Rand Financials and Cargill Investor Services sold early and buying was scattered much of the day. In hog options, Lind-Waldock sold December 48 and 50 puts, pit sources said.  </p>
<p>Continued commercial long liquidation and further technical selling kept pork belly futures sharply lower. Futures turned technically weak when they failed to penetrate chart resistance near the 80.000 last week.</p>
<p>Some support developed when futures filled a gap in the chart, but prices fell again late when support lacked follow through and concern grew over weakness in cash bellies. Cash prices rose last week and may have again turned off retail demand, sources said.</p>
<p>Sell stops were touched off on the setback which propelled losses to near the day's lows at the close, traders said.</p>
<p>Friday's monthly Cold Storage report was considered neutral for futures as it reported frozen belly stocks at 18.896 million lbs, in the range of estimates of 18.1 to 25.2 million lbs.</p>
<p>LFG, E.D.&amp; F. Man and LIT division of First Options were notable sellers early while Lind-Waldock and locals were buyers, traders said. RBH and Rosenthal Collins bought late but active selling by E.D.&amp;F. Man pressured the market, pit sources said.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
