<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="705319" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Only one in four Germans want Kohl as chancellor.</title>
<headline>Only one in four Germans want Kohl as chancellor.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Only one in four Germans want Helmut Kohl to remain as their chancellor while more than half would prefer Gerhard Schroeder, the Social Democratic premier of Lower Saxony, a survey published on Thursday said.</p>
<p>The Forsa survey of 1,102 Germans, to be broadcast on ARD television's Monitor programme, said 25 percent wanted Kohl as chancellor compared to 52 percent for Schroeder, considered to be a front-running SPD candidate to challenge Kohl in 1998.</p>
<p>The poll also offered an unusual glimpse of voter sentiment by comparing ministers in Kohl's centre-right coalition government with possible &quot;shadow&quot; ministers from the opposition SPD and Greens, which could form the next government.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel received only 30 percent support against 39 percent for his SPD counterpart, Ingrid Matthaeus-Maier. But he would beat SPD chairman Oskar Lafontaine, sometimes mentioned as a possible SPD finance minister, by a score of 38 to 30.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel of the Free Democrats would win 55 percent of the vote compared to 25 percent for Joschka Fischer of the Greens.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Volker Ruehe of Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) would also fare well, taking 51 percent to 25 percent for Rudolf Scharping of the SPD.</p>
<p>Health Minister Horst Seehofer, like Waigel a member of the Bavarian Christian Social Union (CSU) allied to Kohl's CDU, would lose to Rudolf Dressler of the SPD by a score of 42 to 29.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
