<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="705347" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn plans higher deficit but within EMU target.</title>
<headline>Bonn plans higher deficit but within EMU target.</headline>
<byline>Terence Gallagher</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany is preparing a supplementary 1997 budget with a sharply higher budget deficit but it will still meet the target for joining the single European currency, a coalition source said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The budget deficit would be eight to 10 billion marks ($4.6-$5.7 billion) higher than now planned, the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>But the source said the budget would still be in line with the deficit target of 3.0 percent of gross domestic product which Germany has vowed to hit exactly to qualify for economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>Neverthless the higher 1997 deficit will force the government to make an embarrassing declaration that the economy is out of kilter, the only way it can get around a constitutional rule that its spending gap should not exceed its investment spending.</p>
<p>&quot;For 1997 we are choosing to go the route of a higher deficit,&quot; the source said. &quot;In 1998 it will be back in line.&quot;</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel will present the 1997 supplementary budget to the cabinet next Friday, together with his 1998 budget proposal.</p>
<p>Otto Lambsdorff, a senior parliamentarian in the Free Democrats (FDP), said tax increases or more stringent spending cuts needed to curb the deficit would hamper economic growth.</p>
<p>This would aggravate Germany's unemployment problem, said Lambsdorff, whos party is a junior partner in Chancellor Helmut Kohl's coalition.</p>
<p>The deficit will still be better than worst-case predictions of a 30 billion mark rise, thanks mainly to the accelerated privatisation of Deutsche Telekom AG .</p>
<p>The coalition was still debating three to four billion marks in proposed spending cuts for 1998, but the bulk of the work on the budget was done, the source said.</p>
<p>Throughout next week, Waigel will meet cabinet ministers to fine-tune the budgets for each ministry.</p>
<p>The 1998 budget will call for spending little changed from 1997 levels, and the federal deficit will fall back below the level of government investment, in line with the constitutional requirement, the source said.</p>
<p>Waigel won Transport Minister Matthias Wissmann's approval for a plan to suspend repayment of old railway debt in 1998, saving 2.8 billion marks, and repay only 300 million marks the next year.</p>
<p>The defence budget, the last remaining hurdle, is largely settled except for the financing of the Eurofighter combat jet.</p>
<p>In the next few days, Waigel will meet executives from Daimler-Benz Aerospace AG -- the German partner in the four-nation project -- to try to complete financing for Bonn's 23 billion mark order of 180 Eurofighters.</p>
<p>Waigel still aims to cut the economics ministry budget by one billion marks, labour ministry spending by two billion marks, and the research ministry budget by 300 million marks.</p>
<p>The government was reported to be seeking to cut aid to the former communist east Germany by up to 4.5 billion marks, but the coalition source doubted that would be possible, given strong resistance in the affected states.</p>
<p>Government investment in 1997 is seen at about 59.6 billion marks, and the new deficit in the supplementary budget will probably exceed that figure by a few billion marks, the coalition source said.</p>
<p>Current budget planning for 1997 foresees a deficit of 53.3 billion marks, and the government has about three billion marks in spending it can carry forward from past budgets.</p>
<p>The constitution allows the federal deficit to exceed government investment only if this is to counter a &quot;disturbance of the overall economic balance&quot;.</p>
<p>Horst Siebert, president of the Kiel-based Institute for the World Economy, said he did not think the economic situation satisfied the constitutional conditions that would allow Bonn to declare an economic emergency.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no recession. The projection for real economic growth in 1997 is about 2.6 percent. We are not threatened by recession, we forecast three percent growth in 1998,&quot; Siebert said in a television interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates are low, exports are expanding, capacity utilisation is near the normal level,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Siebert said even Germany's high unemployment was no reason to declare economic imbalance, since it was a chronic situation that had been building for the past 20 years. &quot;If we accept high unemployment as grounds for economic imbalance, the exception clause could be used every year,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
