<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="705338" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish shares end at new high, P&amp;U in spotlight.</title>
<headline>Swedish shares end at new high, P&amp;U in spotlight.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish shares ended at a new high on Thursday, opening slightly firmer but climbing in afternoon trade after New York opened positively.</p>
<p>The Stockholm general index rose 1.28 percent to 3,048.73 in average turnover of 4.52 billion crowns with all sectors posting gains.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a positive mood in the market,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>A top performer was U.S./Swedish drugs company Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn after the troubled company announced a restructuring programme. Brokers said this overshadowed confirmation of a weak second quarter.  </p>
<p>P&amp;U closed seven crowns higher at 283.5 crowns, dragging the drugs sector index up 1.39 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It is mainly due to the announcement about the restructuring,&quot; one Stockholm-based broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that there will be no gains in profits in 1997 had already been discounted in the marekt.&quot;</p>
<p>Bluechip stocks gained. Drugs heavyweight Astra rose two to 147.5 crowns.</p>
<p>Telecoms major Ericsson rose six to 311.5 crowns. It had won a $106 million contract in Chile and another major GSM contract in China worth $110 million.  </p>
<p>Brokers said there was strength in the market, as in other European markets, and it was not just from the U.S..</p>
<p>However they expected the market to be quiet on Friday with the U.S. on holiday for Independence Day and Swedish players starting to leave for summer holidays.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
