<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="705634" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: HELSINKI REACHES FOR ONE PCT GAIN, UPM ACTIVE.</title>
<headline>HELSINKI REACHES FOR ONE PCT GAIN, UPM ACTIVE.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares attempted a one percent</p>
<p>rise on Thursday in the wake of overnight U.S. gains and an</p>
<p>on-hold rate decision from the Fed, with UPM and blue-chips</p>
<p>leading a broad rally, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The general tone is positive -- we could go even higher</p>
<p>today,&quot; one broker said, as the FOX index was up about 0.8</p>
<p>percent. He added that the moderate volume was due more to a</p>
<p>scarcity of sellers than any lack of demand.</p>
<p>UPM-Kymmene was the most active share, trading up 1.90</p>
<p>markka at 126.50 after touching 126.80 in heavy 86 million</p>
<p>markka volume.</p>
<p>Brokers said investors were still showing interest in UPM</p>
<p>after its sale last week of a large chunk of Nokia stock,</p>
<p>kindling expectations it may soon make a purchase overseas.</p>
<p>Nokia traded 6.00 markka higher at 390.00, matching its</p>
<p>overnight Wall St close in fair 40 million markka dealings.</p>
<p>Merita fell 0.20 markka to 19.20 after an early assault</p>
<p>above 20.00 markka levels where it ran into profit-takers,</p>
<p>brokers said.</p>
<p>Speculation over a link-up between Merita and insurer Sampo,</p>
<p>which helped boost Merita on Wednesday, had petered out, brokers</p>
<p>said. &quot;The rumour has lost its wings,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Metra joined the bluechip rally, trading up 6.00</p>
<p>markka or 3.75 percent at a year-high 166.00 in lively 19</p>
<p>million markka trade.</p>
<p>Broker said the strong dollar helped boost cyclicals.</p>
<p>Raisio was again volatile, this time paring some of its</p>
<p>recent sharp losses and rising 15.50 markka to 374.00 in fair 14</p>
<p>million markka trade.</p>
<p>&quot;A few big overseas owners have stopped selling Raisio,&quot; one</p>
<p>broker said.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +358-0-6805 0235, news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
