<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="705812" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Mideast and African port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>Mideast and African port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>ISRAEL, June 24 - Haifa - Four vessels due, 1-2 days delay expected. 2 General cargo discharging at berth, 1 bulk discharging at berth. 2 Containers, 3 tankers loading/discharging at berth. Waiting at anchorage to discharge, 1 general cargo, 1 bulk. To load/discharge, 1 container, 1 tanker. 1 Under repair, 1 awaiting orders. Ashdod - Two to three days delay, 4 general cargo, 3 bulk discharging at berth, 2 bulk loading at berth. 1 Container, 1 tanker loading/discharging at berth. 3 General cargo waiting at anchorage to discharge, 2 bulk waiting at anchorage to load. 2 Containers waiting at anchorage to load/discharge, 2 vessels awaiting orders. Eilat - One vessel due. 1 Bulk loading at berth, 1 passenger at berth. 2 Vessels discharging at anchorage.</p>
<p>JORDAN, June 21 - Ababa - One vessel loading at berth, 4 discharging. 3 Waiting at anchorage to load, 2 to discharge, 1 awaiting orders.</p>
<p>MOZAMBIQUE, June 23 - Nacala - Port working normally (first Come, first served basis). No restriction on berthing and sailing during night time. Draft restriction of 9.5 metres at general cargo berths and 14 metres at container berths. One tugboat available. Beira - General cargo berths working normally. 24 Hour berthing/sailing for vessels up to 140 metres loa. Some restriction for larger vessels and subject to prior arrangements with port captain. Max. draft for 24 hour navigation 7.5 metres. 2 Tugs available. General access channel - 2 Waverider buoys have been deployed in the approach channel. Each buoy is an approx. diameter of 1 metre with flashing orange light with flash frequency of five one second flashes every 26 Seconds.</p>
<p>Maputo - Berthing/sailing of 24 hours for vessels up to 120 metres loa. Some restrictions for larger vessels and subject to prior arrangements with port captain. All berths fluid. Draft restriction in the channel is 9 metres less 0 metres plus rise of tide of the day. Max. draft for 24 hour navigation is 9 metres.</p>
<p>NAMIBIA, June 24 - Walvis Bay - Working normally.</p>
<p>NIGERIA, June 18 - Lagos - Working normally . No berthing delays reported. Part Harcourt - Working normally . No berthing delays. Crude terminals - Working normally.</p>
<p>SOUTH AFRICA, June 23 - Richards Bay - General cargo berths - Congested with berthing delays of approx. 48 hours. Bulk import berths - Congested with berthing delays of up to 5 days. Bulk export berths - Working normally. Bulk coal berths - 4 Vessels alongside, 7 anchored, 5 due on 24/6, 16 due by 30/6. Berthing delays of approx. 4 days at present. Durban - Container terminal - Delays of up to 60 hours can be expected whilst 2 new cranes are being positioned at container terminal. Point/New Pier/Maydon Wharf berths - General cargo working normally. Maize terminal (Maydon Wharf 8) - 1 Vessel for June, 6 for July. Bunker supplies fluid but this could change daily due to bunching of vessels.</p>
<p>East London - General cargo/combi terminal/tanker berths - Extremely busy, but no delays expected. Drydock fully booked from 1/9 to 30/9, 2 tankers due weekly. Port Elizabeth - Five vessels in port, no delays expected on general and tanker berths. Fruit berths - Vessel in port, 1 anchored awaiting instructions, 1 other vessel anchored. Ore berth - 3 Vessels due of which 1 will have 12 hours delay, another 30 hours delay. Container berth - Working 2 gantries, but very slow due to pay disputes. The dispute should be resolved this week and work should return to normal. Two vessels in port, 2 anchored, 7 due during the week. Delays of up to 48 hours can be expected.</p>
<p>Cape Town - Breakbulk berths - Working normally. Fruit berths - Fully occupied. Container terminal - Working normally, vessels berthing and working on arrival. Bunker berths - Working normally. Drydocks and repair quay - Fully occupied and booking essential. Port closed on 22/6 and 23/6 due to weather, resulting in berthing delays of 12-24 hours. Rain and strong NW winds predicted for the rest of the week. Saldanha Bay - Working normally.</p>
<p>TUNISIA, June 21 - Tunis - Five vessels in port of which 1 general cargo, 1 tor tanker discharging bitumen, 3 awaiting instructions. Rades - Four vessels in port of which 1 military, 1 discharging containers, 3 loading containers. Goulette - North side - 1 Passenger vessel, 1 cereal, 1 discharging general cargo. South side - 1 Discharging grain, 1 motor tanker discharging syrene, 1 loading bulk zinc, 2 vessels in roads. Sousse - Two vessels in port of which 1 discharging bagged sugar, 1 discharging marble chips, no waiting time. Sfax - Nine vessels operating of which 4 loading fish, 1 loading olive oil, 1 loading bulk rock phosphate, 1 discharging timber, 1 discharging general cargo, 1 discharging steel iron. Bizerta - June 24 - One vessel discharging wheat, 1 loading cement, 1 loading white products, no delays or congestion. Zarzis - No vessels in port.</p>
<p>UNITED ARAB EMIRATES, June 21 - Dubai - Containers, 27 vessels due, 3 loading at berth. General cargo, 11 vessels due, 4 discharging at berth, 5 under repair/laid up. Tankers, 4 vessels due, 2 loading at berth, 1 discharging at berth, 8 under repair/laid up.</p>
<p>YEMEN, June 23 - Hodeidah - Berths 3, 4, 57 are occupied. 4 Vessels alongside of which 2 wheat, 1 flour, 1 general cargo. 2 Vessels anchored of which 1 general cargo, 1 for loading. Berthing delays, general cargo, containers up to 1 day, bagged cargo up to 3 days, bulk cargo up to 5 days. Mokha - No vessels in port.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NAMIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
