<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706029" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Buba's Issing says Bonn must work for EMU.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Buba's Issing says Bonn must work for EMU.</headline>
<byline>Kate Kelland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing said on Thursday that Germany still had homework to do if it is to get its fiscal position in shape in time to qualify for Europe's single currency in January 1999.</p>
<p>Speaking to reporters before a seminar on European Integration, Issing said the key issue for the success of economic and monetary union (EMU) was the sustainability of public finances.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany has homework to do if we are to keep to the Maastricht deficit criterion,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;The primary concern for public finances in EMU is sustainability.&quot;</p>
<p>The Maastricht Treaty calls on EMU hopefuls to reduce budget deficits to three percent of gross domestic product this year, a task two of the main pillars of the project -- Germany and France -- are finding difficult to complete.</p>
<p>While the Bonn government is sticking to its forecast for a deficit at 2.9 percent of GDP in 1997, many economists say the ratio is likely to overshoot the Maastricht goal.</p>
<p>In France, Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn said on Thursday that he feared his country's 1997 budget deficit might be higher than 3.4 percent, adding that if it were in fact 3.4 percent the government's job would be easy.</p>
<p>German economists said that a French deficit of more than 3.4 percent would pose a major risk to currency union, with some warning that France could not hope to take part in EMU from 1999 should its budgetary position be this weak.</p>
<p>When asked what would happen to progress towards the single currency if France were to have a deficit ratio of 3.4 percent of GDP, Issing said simply :&quot;I don't know and I don't wish to make any further comment on this point.&quot;</p>
<p>Issing is generally guarded on the subject of monetary union but has made clear his support for a stability pact to ensure fiscal discipline in the euro zone and his opposition to creative accounting to make the EMU grade.</p>
<p>On Thursday Issing stressed again that there should be no bending of the Maastricht goal posts for entry to the euro.</p>
<p>&quot;The Maastricht convergence criteria must not be softened,&quot; he said. &quot;The Maastricht Treaty is a formula that has been ratified by parliaments. It must be adhered to.&quot;</p>
<p>Looking at the domestic economy, Issing said Germany's crippling unemployment levels -- now topping 4.2 million people, or 11.1 percent of the workforce -- could not be eased by loosening monetary policy.</p>
<p>On the contrary, Issing said, any easing of official rates would lead to an increase in long-term market rates, which he said would be damaging for the economic recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;I am convinced that a cut in rates would lead to a rise in long-term market rates and damage confidence in the mark. That is not the solution to Germany's problems,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Instead he said Germany and other European countries suffering from high unemployment should undertake structural reform of labour markets to increase flexibility and allow the creation of more jobs.</p>
<p>Germany has kept its headline discount and Lombard rates at 2.5 percent and 4.5 percent respectively since April 1996.</p>
<p>The central bank's last move was to cut the securities repurchase rate, or repo, to three percent in August 1996.</p>
<p>Issing said there was also no need for credit conditions to be tightened in Germany, saying that even talk of raising rates would create the impression that inflation was a concern, which was not at all the case.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no signs of inflation in Germany at the moment,&quot; he said. &quot;But we will watch carefully. The weakness of the mark creates cost pressure, but as long as that is accompanied by falling wage costs, that is offset.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
