<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706285" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Growth in UK services sector eases in June.</title>
<headline>Growth in UK services sector eases in June.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's services sector grew again in June, but the pace of expansion eased slightly, with the PMI business activity index slipping to a seasonally adjusted 62.9 from 64.2 in May, the Chartered Institute of Purchasing and Supply (CIPS) said.</p>
<p>Despite the slightly slower pace, this is still the third highest reading since the survey began a year ago.</p>
<p>New business, outstanding business and employment all grew in the month, but the pace of growth slowed.</p>
<p>The survey, sponsored by Reuters, is based on information from 500 business executives in private sector service industries, excluding retail and wholesale.  </p>
<p>&quot;Growth was generally attributable to increased confidence in the economy and the resurgence of the 'feel-good factor', especially among consumers,&quot; the CIPS said.</p>
<p>Many companies increased employment to expand capacity and meet strong growth of new business. One in five companies recruited new staff, but this latest increase in employment was seen as insufficient to boost capacity to meet the strong growth of new business.</p>
<p>And, as firms struggled to find suitably qualified staff to replace leavers, the rate of growth of employment actually fell. The employment index stood at 55.2 in June compared with 56.6 in May.  </p>
<p>&quot;In other cases, higher wages or salaries were again having to be offered to either attract new staff or retain existing staff,&quot; the survey said.</p>
<p>The resulting rise in labour costs was reflected in a further rise in average input prices in June, although the rate moderated for the second month running. The index stood at 57.4 in June compared with 59.7 in May.</p>
<p>With demand for services continuing to strengthen, some companies were able to pass on the higher costs to customers.</p>
<p>But the incidence of firms successfully raising charges remained relatively low. Whereas 15 percent of firms reported a rise in input prices, only 10 percent were able to raise charges for their services.  </p>
<p>Optimism concerning activity remained steady, with companies from across the services sector expecting business to pick up further over the next 12 months. Only five percent expect a deterioration.</p>
<p>CIPS said that back data seasonal adjustments have been revised, so annual averages for the seasonally adjusted figures have been constrained to equal the annual average of the unadjusted series.</p>
<p>This occurred in June as CIPS now has a full year's worth of data.</p>
<p>Following are the main seasonally adjusted indices from the services survey:</p>
<p>						June	  May</p>
<p>    Business activity		   62.9	  64.2</p>
<p>    Incoming new business	     60.8	  62.8</p>
<p>    Outstanding business		55.8	  57.0</p>
<p>    Employment			    55.2	  56.6</p>
<p>    Average prices charged	    53.4	  53.6</p>
<p>    Average input prices		57.4	  59.7</p>
<p>    Business expectations	     83.9	  83.0</p>
<p>-- Rosemary Bennett, London Newsroom 44 171 542 7715</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
