<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706261" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS- JULY 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS- JULY 3.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--Despite government claims to the contrary, it is looking at introducing more flexible pension systems, along the lines of those in effect in Ireland and Sweden. These systems are characterised by their &quot;optional&quot; features and a lack of emphasis on a specific retirement age and are tailored to lift the burden of pension funds having to pay out lump sums at once. --The Social Security Foundation, IKA, will sell some 30 billion drachmas worth of shares, a national economy ministry meeting decided yesterday. Since half the shares are in National Bank and IKA owes National, IKA may use its National stake to write off its debt.</p>
<p>--The failure of two brokerage firms to meet its commitments and rumours of others trading in the red dampened sentiment on the Athens Stock Exchange yesterday, driving the general price index down 1.41 percent. The developments have drawn the interest of the economic crimes squad SDOE, which is expected to begin checks on a number of firms.</p>
<p>--Alpha Credit Bank has signed a $150 million multi-currency term loan faciltity, arranger Sanwa Bank said. The arrangers of the transaction are Sai-Ichi-Kangyo Bank, Deutsche Bank, Dresdner Bank Luxembourg and the Sanwa bank.</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>--Special IKA teams are waiting on ratification of a new bill from the labour and social security ministry before they begin snap checks on companies evading the payment of social security contributions. The bill will make non-payment of contributions as serious a crime as tax evasion, with appropriate punitive measures.</p>
<p>--Katsoulias Securities has stopped all activity to calculate the extent of its debt to clients and is under investigation by the SDOE, the Capital Market Commission and the Joint Reserve Fund.</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>--SDOE has launched its campaign against graft and tax evasion in busy tourist areas such as the Cycladic islands and Corfu with snap checks.</p>
<p>--Civil servants want collective bargaining agreements in the public sector implemented and will visit National Economy and Finance Minister Yannos Papandoniou on the issue today. However, the government is reluctant to give in on this point, as it would pull the rug out from under the strict incomes policy currently being applied. </p>
<p>--Talks between the environment, town planning and public works ministry and the Bouyges Group-Thessaloniki Metro consortium for the construction of the northern port city's subway system are well under way. The ministry hopes to have everything down by September so that Prime Minister Costas Simitis can announce the contract at the International Fair.</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>--The interbank market paid up front for the expected bad news on inflation yesterday, with interest rates increasing and the drachma sliding slightly. According to the national economy ministry, the latest figures show June inflation unchanged from May figures at 5.4 percent. </p>
<p>--The rate of public inflows showed an significant improvement in June, according to the finance ministry. The rate went up to 16.0 percent from 14.5 percent the previous month.</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>--The state will put a ceiling on spending by ministries and public organisations and enterprises (DEKOs) as latest figures show that spending continues to be excessive despite repeated calls for restraint. --Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
