<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70634" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek PM Simitis wants tough &quot;can do&quot; cabinet.</title>
<headline>Greek PM Simitis wants tough &quot;can do&quot; cabinet.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's socialist Prime Minister Costas Simitis, fresh from an election win, was assembling a tough new ministerial team on Monday to push through foreign and economic policy changes.</p>
<p>Simitis has vowed to turn Greece's sprawling and inefficient bureaucracy into a &quot;hands-on&quot; meritocracy where anyone who fails to work hard will be replaced.</p>
<p>The no-nonsense approach is a far cry from his predecessor, the late socialist party founder Andreas Papandreou, who was renowned for dancing until the early hours and publicly ordering his finance minister to &quot;give it all away&quot;.</p>
<p>In his short time since inheriting Papandreou's mantle in January, Simitis has worked hard to convince the United States and the European Union that a new era in relations was at hand.</p>
<p>Western diplomats seemed delighted Simitis had come through with 162 deputies in the 300-seat parliament, saying it meant stability and a determination to change Greece's laggardly Balkan ways.</p>
<p>&quot;He is methodical and has a step-by-step approach,&quot; a Western diplomat said. &quot;He has done an exceptional job in his first eight months by reknitting tattered relations with the European Union and the United States.&quot;</p>
<p>EU diplomats expected Simitis to be more active in pushing his foreign policy and economic reforms, and applauded him for his non-confrontational approach.</p>
<p>Simitis joined the socialist party in 1974 when it was set up after a brutal seven-year military junta fell. He has served in every Papandreou cabinet but remained largely in the shadows until his one-time mentor fell ill last year.</p>
<p>Then Simitis, 60, replaced the ailing Papandreou as premier in January, scored a leadership victory to run the party after Papandreou died in June and finally cemented his grip on power by leading the socialists to a solid election victory.</p>
<p>&quot;With such a strong victory, all leadership battles are finished in our party,&quot; said a former senior socialist official.</p>
<p>Simitis is an intensely private man who seemed ill-at-ease with the public attention of campaigning. He has turned his back on the histrionics and unpredictable shifts of Papandreou.</p>
<p>While Papandreou's flamboyant antics delighted many Greeks, they left the country alienated from its main Western allies and weakened in the international arena.</p>
<p>Simitis, who trained in Germany and Britain as an economist and lawyer, has called for a &quot;new era&quot; of sacrifice and work to earn the respect of European Union partners.</p>
<p>He is the first fresh face to lead Greece in 20 years and the most pro-European and pro-Western leader in a long spell. He is comfortable hobnobbing with EU leaders in Brussels and speaks English, French and German with ease.</p>
<p>After receiving a mandate to form his new government, he set to work with a half dozen close advisers. He is expected to name the cabinet he wants and reject negotiations over who gets what.</p>
<p>&quot;My colleagues and I have the huge responsibility of leading Greece into the 21st century,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Gerassimos Arsenis is almost certain to go, partly for pushing for a $10 billion military build-up. Foreign Minister Theodoros Pangalos is another possible departure but he would go to another ministry, perhaps transport.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
