<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706305" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - FTSE to slump back towards the 4,650 area.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - FTSE to slump back towards the 4,650 area.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fiery spell of activity in the London stock market this week may now render the FTSE out of control as it makes an abrupt turn on Thursday, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>The index may slump back down to the region around 4,650, they added.</p>
<p>Uncertainty surrounding the budget may have prevented the market breaking into record territory on Wednesday but the abolition of dividend tax relief and the probability of an interest rate hike next week will weigh heavily on UK equities.</p>
<p>By 0726 GMT, the FTSE was indicated down 57.0 at 4,694.4.  </p>
<p>Many share prices in the FTSE will be slashed, the effect of which will be to create a bearish diamond shape topping pattern on a daily line chart of the index, analysts said.</p>
<p>This when a market is in an uptrend and prices then thrash about, making large swings over a certain period, and then contract. Trendlines connecting the highs and lows initially start diverging and then begin to converge -- giving the overall appearance of a diamond shape.</p>
<p>Breakout from the pattern usually occurs by a fall in prices below the supporting trendline -- which for the FTSE is at around 4,650.  </p>
<p>A fall below 4,650 could then quickly take the FTSE down to next significant support at 4,580, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Pradip Mishra, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5113</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
