<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706500" id="root" date="1997-07-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam blames foreign firms for labour unrest.</title>
<headline>Vietnam blames foreign firms for labour unrest.</headline>
<byline>John Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam took a swipe at foreign investors' labour practices on Thursday, blaming low pay, long working hours and excessive production targets for growing unrest among the ranks of local factory workers.</p>
<p>The official English-language daily Vietnam News ran a front-page article about a recent labour management workshop in Hanoi at which foreign contractors were lambasted for violating the labour law.</p>
<p>Deputy Labour Minister Le Duy Dong told the workshop that while unreasonable wages, working hours and annual leave were the main causes of strikes, physical abuse of workers was also to blame.</p>
<p>&quot;He told the workshop strikes were also caused by violent management involving punishment of workers by managers if workers violated labour discipline,&quot; Vietnam News said.</p>
<p>&quot;While (he)... conceded that Vietnamese workers did at times violate labour discipline, corporal punishment violates Vietnam's labour laws.&quot;</p>
<p>Dong said research by his ministry had shown that most labour conflicts were occurring at small-scale enterprises with investment from South Korea, Singapore and Taiwan.</p>
<p>The workshop was organised by the South Korean embassy, whose ambassador acknowledged the need for Korean employers to obey the law and understand differences of culture and language.</p>
<p>Until now, the government of Vietnam has been wary of criticising foreign labour practices because of the country's heavy dependence on investment from abroad.</p>
<p>Strikes were banned in communist-ruled Vietnam until market reforms and the opening up of the economy in the late 1980s, but the right to strike was not enshrined until a new labour law was passed three years ago.</p>
<p>Since then, the number of strikes has ballooned. Fewer than 3,000 people nationwide went on strike in 1994, while four times that number walked off their jobs in Ho Chi Minh City alone during the first three months of this year.</p>
<p>South Korean and Taiwanese contractors have come in for heavy criticism for their treatment of workers at plants under contract to the U.S. sportswear giant Nike.</p>
<p>Last week a Taiwanese supervisor of one Nike factory was sentenced to six months in prison for forcing 56 workers to jog twice around the plant perimeter in the heat of the day.</p>
<p>That factory was one of five -- three South Korean and two Taiwanese -- producing shoes for Nike in Vietnam which were named in March by a labour rights group for abuse of their workers.</p>
<p>Nike has denied the allegations and an independent review of Asian Nike plants by former U.S. ambassador to the United Nations Andrew Young found that workers were well-treated and factories &quot;clean, well-organised, adequately ventilated and well-lit&quot;.</p>
<p>But Young's report, which was released last week, said many workers were unaware of their rights.</p>
<p>It also quoted confidential audits which had found that religious holidays and days off were regularly denied to certain workers, that workers on one shift were made to work overtime against their will and some were paid &quot;training&quot; or &quot;probationary&quot; wages beyond their actual training period.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
