<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706834" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TENNIS-INJURY CLOUD HANGS OVER NOVOTNA BEFORE FINAL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-INJURY CLOUD HANGS OVER NOVOTNA BEFORE FINAL.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Third seed Jana Novotna's hopes of winning Wimbledon suffered a setback on Friday when the Czech revealed she was receiving treatment for a thigh injury.</p>
<p>Novotna, due to meet top seed Martina Hingis in Saturday's singles final, withdrew from Friday's women's doubles quarter-final due to what the Women's Tennis Association (WTA) described as a &quot;chronic&quot; thigh muscle problem.</p>
<p>In a statement, the WTA put her playing ability at 75 percent but said her chances of playing were &quot;probable&quot;.</p>
<p>Novotna suffered the injury during a previous match and the problem will be re-evaluated on Saturday.</p>
<p>Novotna, 28, has also complained of a sore knee and arm during the tournament.</p>
<p>Novotna and American Lindsay Davenport, the third seeds in the women's doubles, were due to play Sabine Appelmans of Belgium and Miriam Oremans of the Netherlands in Friday's quarter-finals.</p>
<p>The Czech right-hander has won 12 grand slam doubles titles, including three women's doubles and one mixed doubles title at Wimbledon.</p>
<p>Novotna struggled to find her form earlier in the tournament and was taken to three sets on three occasions, but on Thursday she was at her best charging the net at every opportunity to blast her way past eighth seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario in straight sets.</p>
<p>Novotna won the hearts of tennis fans at Wimbledon when she cried on the shoulder of the Duchess of Kent after losing the 1993 final to Steffi Graf when she appeared to have the match in her grasp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
