<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706865" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SOCCER-SWISS KICKOFF 1997-98 SOCCER SEASON.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SWISS KICKOFF 1997-98 SOCCER SEASON.</headline>
<byline>Steve Keating</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The curtain goes up on the 1997-98 European soccer season on Saturday when the Swiss League kicks-off -- just seven days after the destination of the last major trophy of the 1996-97 season was decided.</p>
<p>Last Saturday Barcelona beat Real Betis in the Spanish Cup final in Madrid effectively meaning there has been no close season this European summer.</p>
<p>Swiss soccer has hardly had a chance to draw breath at all with Sion having wrapped up last season's action just four weeks ago when they clinched the double by adding the Swiss Cup to their league championship title.</p>
<p>But things will be a little different than they were last month -- and even last week.</p>
<p>The Swiss League is the first in Europe to re-start following the introduction of new law changes which came into effect on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The most visible change is not actually a new law but a recommendation to referees that the four-step rule is strictly observed and that the ball is released by the goalkeeper after five seconds.</p>
<p>A change to law 12 means the goalkeeper will now concede an indirect freekick if they handle the ball directly from a throw-in, although keepers are now allowed to move laterally along their goal-line at a penalty kick.</p>
<p>Another change for Swiss fans will be the chance to see three Swiss internationals who have returned home after spells abroad.</p>
<p>Striker Marco Grassi moves from French league champions Monaco to Sion while midfielder Sebastien Fournier joins Servette from German Cup winners VFB Stuttgart.</p>
<p>Veteran defender Marc Hottiger returns to his hometown club Lausanne, having spent the last four seasons in England with Newcastle and Everton.</p>
<p>Grassi will be expected to pick up the scoring slack left by the departure of Serb Vladan Lukic who scored 15 goals last season. He has moved to Metz in France.</p>
<p>Servette, bought last season by French cable company Canal Plus, have benefitted from the cash infusion. With 4.0 million Swiss francs to spend on transfers, the Geneva club, which is preparing to move into a new stadium, used some of that money to acquire Fournier and Romanian Dan Potocianu from National Bucharest.</p>
<p>Zurich Grasshoppers have two big holes to fill after losing international midfielder Murat Yakin to Stuttgart and veteran defender Alain Geiger. Capped 110 times by his country, he has retired.</p>
<p>Grasshoppers, however, will still possess the circuit's top one-two scoring punch in Viroel Moldovan, the Swiss league's leading scorer and Kubilay Turkyilmaz.</p>
<p>Basle made numerous moves in the brief off-season signing three seasoned players from Germany: Oliver Kreuzer from Bayern Munich, Maurizio Gaudino from Eintracht Frankfurt and Juergen Hartmann from Hamburg, in an effort to turn the under-achieving club around and help fill the biggest stadium in Switzerland.</p>
<p>Aarau went Down Under in search of help, signing a pair of Australian players Ross Aloisi from Adelaide and Sydney United's David Zdrilic, who led the Australian scoring charts last season with 21 goals.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
