<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706839" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: BASEBALL-ANDRUW JONES HAS FOUR RBI AS BRAVES SMASH EXPOS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-ANDRUW JONES HAS FOUR RBI AS BRAVES SMASH EXPOS.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1997-07-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Andruw Jones tied a career high with four RBI and the Atlanta Braves scored nine times in the fourth inning en route to a 15-2 rout of the Montreal Expos Thursday.</p>
<p>Jones hit a two-run homer, his seventh, in the fourth as the Braves scored nine runs in one inning for the second time in three weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;Every time you get an at-bat you want to get another hit,&quot; Jones said. &quot;You just want to go hard and hit the ball hard so that when you get a big lead you can make your pitcher more relaxed the rest of the way. Guys just kept saying, 'here we go, keep pushing hard' and that's what we did.&quot;</p>
<p>Ryan Klesko added three hits and three RBI before being pulled in the fourth. Michael Tucker also had three hits and scored three runs for the Braves, who have won eight of their last nine.</p>
<p>&quot;We played nail-biters for three days now, so it feels good to get the pitcher some runs to work with,&quot; said Atlanta manager Bobby Cox. &quot;Every time we hit the ball it was in there, it was just one of those nights, there's not much more I can say.&quot;</p>
<p>John Smoltz (8-7) won his second straight game after losing four consecutive decisions. He gave up four hits in five scoreless innings, walking none and striking out three.</p>
<p>Montreal starter Jim Bullinger (5-8) was tagged for eight runs -- seven earned -- and six hits in 3 1/3 innings.</p>
<p>In Houston, Joe Oliver delivered a two-run single in the first and added a solo homer in the fourth as the Cincinnati Reds tied a season high with their fourth straight win, 4-3 over the Astros.</p>
<p>The Reds jumped on starter Ramon Garcia (3-7) for three runs in the first.</p>
<p>John Smiley (6-10) snapped a personal four-game losing streak.</p>
<p>In New York, Kurt Abbott collected four RBI, including a two-run double in a four-run first inning, and Livan Hernandez won his second straight start as the Florida Marlins handed the Mets their fourth consecutive loss, 10-4.</p>
<p>Jeff Conine broke out of an 0-for-12 slump with hits in his first two at-bats as Florida built an 8-0 cushion by the second inning. Ex-Met Bobby Bonilla added two hits and two RBI, helping the Marlins to their fifth win in six games. Florida's Jim Leyland posted his 900th career managerial victory.</p>
<p>The Marlins scored eight of their 10 runs with two out, stringing together five consecutive two-out hits in the top of the first against starter Armando Reynoso (6-2).</p>
<p>Hernandez (2-0) went 5 1/3 innings, giving up two runs and eight hits.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Sammy Sosa drove in two runs and rookie Jeremi Gonzalez got his third straight win as the Chicago Cubs handed the Phillies their 10th consecutive loss, 5-4.</p>
<p>Gonzalez (5-2) gave up four runs and six hits in seven innings to remain unbeaten since June 17. In his last three starts, he has allowed six runs and 12 hits in 22 1/3 innings.</p>
<p>Curt Schilling (9-8) surrendered five runs in eight innings for Philadelphia, which has lost 18 of its last 19.</p>
<p>In St Louis, Esteban Loaiza allowed two runs over six innings as the Pittsburgh Pirates won their fourth straight, beating the Cardinals 6-4.</p>
<p>Loaiza (6-5) snapped a personal three-game losing streak by scattering seven hits with a walk and five strikeouts.</p>
<p>Kevin Young, who went 3-for-5 with a pair of runs scored for Pittsburgh, had a single in the sixth, a two-run homer in the seventh and a double in the ninth.</p>
<p>Fernando Valenzuela (2-11) surrendered three runs and four hits in five innings, walking three. He remains winless since May 23 and fell to 13-8 lifetime against Pittsburgh.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
