<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="706951" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Both sides claim edge in UK's first tobacco suit.</title>
<headline>Both sides claim edge in UK's first tobacco suit.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Reaney</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A court Friday assigned a judge to hear Britain's first lawsuit by lung cancer victims who contend that two big tobacco firms failed to curb the damage of smoking.</p>
<p>The High Court named Anthony May to handle the preliminary stages of the case, which could result in multi-billion pound payments against Imperial Tobacco Group Plc and Gallaher Group Plc if the 47 plaintiffs are successful.</p>
<p>The group action is Europe's largest ever legal battle against the tobacco industry and legal experts say it could open a floodgate of similar law suits.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm delighted they've agreed to go ahead and that they've allocated a judge to deal with it speedily,&quot; said Martyn Day, the lawyer representing the cancer sufferers.</p>
<p>But Gallaher said the hearing was a very preliminary administrative step and stressed that the high court had not ruled it &quot;practical or necessary&quot; to assign a trial judge.</p>
<p>&quot;Imperial continues to be advised that we have strong defences against this and any other product liability claims,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>Gallaher Group Plc also pointed out that the court rejected Day's application for a trial judge to be assigned.</p>
<p>But Day said the tobacco giants had failed in their attempt to have the case thrown out. &quot;What I'm very pleased about is that they agreed to a very early hearing,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Day estimates that 35,000 people are diagnosed with lung cancer in Britain every year and up to 20,000 of them would have a good claim. He put the potential cost to the tobacco companies at up to one billion pounds ($1.6 billion) a year in damages.</p>
<p>Day said the plaintiffs were going to court on Monday to determine the next stage of the hearing. May has not been allocated for the whole case but, initially at least, just to decide on the next stage of the proceedings.</p>
<p>The decision, which was taken in private session, also considered whether each side had the right documents and how long the court case might last.</p>
<p>Day contended that the companies, which own brands such as Benson and Hedges, Silk Cut and Embassy and control 80 percent of the British cigarette market, were aware in the 1950s that their products were addictive and killing large numbers of people and that tar was the primary cause of death.</p>
<p>The tobacco firms say there is no proof that by reducing cigarette tar levels the smokers would not have contracted cancer.</p>
<p>The case is also the first in Britain where the lawyers for the plaintiffs, who have been denied legal aid, are working on a no-win, no-fee basis, a common practice in the United States.</p>
<p>The lawyers will get no fee if the cancer victims lose the case -- but could earn millions if they are successful.</p>
<p>The case is of particular importance following a landmark decision in the United States last month in which tobacco companies agreed to a $368.6 billion settlement with 40 states that sued the industry to recoup health costs of sick smokers.</p>
<p>The firms also admitted that their product is addictive.</p>
<p>Since the U.S. settlement, several regional health authorities, which run Britain's national health service, have been considering legal action against tobacco manufacturers.</p>
<p>The tobacco firms argue that the U.S. decision has no relevance to the British case and insist there will be no settlement.</p>
<p>Under the English legal system a single judge will deal with the claim, whereas in the United States cases are normally heard by a jury.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
