<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70695" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Peseta debt/interbank market closing report.</title>
<headline>Peseta debt/interbank market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish government bonds closed almost flat, off today's high as profit-taking emerged while dealers awaited tomorrow's Bank of Spain repo auction.</p>
<p>&quot;I am still convinced the Bank of Spain will end up waiting for the budget draft,&quot; before cutting rates, a dealer said. The government is due to present its budget this Friday.</p>
<p>Central bank repos are scheduled tomorrow, Sept 24 and then on October 3.</p>
<p>This morning a relatively strong peseta, up to 84.02 versus the mark, spurred expectations of a fast cut in official interest rates. At close the peseta was trading around 84.11/12.  </p>
<p>The 10-year spread over German Bunds dipped during the day to a record low of 184 basis points and then closed at 191. It broke resistance at 200 on Friday, having fallen considerably since last year. On September 25 1995 it was at 442.</p>
<p>&quot;Current bullishness hes spurred speculation Spain could enter EMU in phase I, and before Italy,&quot; according to a Bank of America client note. But it added: &quot;A hard look at Euro-politics does not support this view.&quot;</p>
<p>All eyes are therefore now on the budget draft to give more information to judge the likelihood of Spain's entry in time for the start of EMU.</p>
<p>-- Madrid Newsroom + 34 1 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
