<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70694" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Bunds tremble on renewed EMU confidence.</title>
<headline>German Bunds tremble on renewed EMU confidence.</headline>
<byline>Scott Miller</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Bunds fell on Monday after the weekend meeting of European Union finance ministers in Dublin was interpreted as making a single European currency more likely.</p>
<p>German bond investors have been unnerved for months at the prospect of European economic and monetary union (EMU), which they fear will lead to higher inflation and a less stable currency than the mark.</p>
<p>Analysts said the &quot;optimistic&quot; statesments from Dublin had underlined the likelihood of EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen a lot of profit taking since the Dublin meeting,&quot; said Timo Klein, market analyst at MMS International. &quot;Other European markets had been hoping for more.&quot;</p>
<p>The December Bund DTB futures contract, which has gained more than a full point the last three weeks, tumbled 38 basis points at one point on Monday, its biggest fall of the month.</p>
<p>Analysts said the drop was exacerbated by the inability of non-core European bond markets to find much good either in the Dublin meeting, triggering wide-selling which carried Bunds lower.</p>
<p>Concerns about the health of Russian President Boris Yeltsin, who faces heart surgery, also depressed sentiment.</p>
<p>The Dublin meeting marked a big step toward monetary union with the finance ministers agreeing in principle on a stability pact to enforce budgetary discipline among future members of EMU, making a single currency pact more likely.</p>
<p>The prospect of European monetary union has long worried German investors, leading the Bund yield curve to remain stubbornly steep with demand weak for bond maturities extending beyond the 1999 deadline to launch a single currency.</p>
<p>&quot;From Germany's point of view there is not a lot of good that can come from EMU,&quot; said Brian Clapp, bond market analyst at Stone &amp; McCarthy in London. &quot;There is a lot of downside risk.&quot;</p>
<p>According to conventional wisdom, EMU would allow other European countries to have a say in Europe's monetary policy, bringing with them attitudes that may favour faster economic growth and job creation at the expense of price stability.</p>
<p>But German debt markets got a second blow as a result of the meeting as other European markets likewise found little in the Dublin gathering to raise their own hopes for a speedy monetary union.</p>
<p>Bond markets outside Germany such as Italy and Sweden have benefited from the increasing likelyhood of EMU which is expected to bring lower inflation rates and greater fiscal restraint throughout Europe.</p>
<p>Some economists, such as Adolf Rosenstock at the Industrial Bank of Japan in Frankfurt, believe EMU and the fiscal responsibility that will come with it will eventually be viewed positively by German bond investors.</p>
<p>But worries about watering down EMU criteria will continue to keep Bunds warry of EMU for some time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
