<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70708" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Yeltsin health concerns have NATO worried. [CORRECTED 16:40 GMT]</title>
<headline>Yeltsin health concerns have NATO worried. [CORRECTED 16:40 GMT]</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The North Atlantic Treaty Organisation is desperately concerned for the health of Russian President Boris Yeltsin, but the alliance is pursuing a business-as-usual approach to relations with Moscow.</p>
<p>The relationship is still fraught with the physical and psychological differences that separated NATO from the Soviet Union during years of Cold War enmity, but the alliance is determined to keep open links of communication with the Kremlin.</p>
<p>&quot;We are interested in building a long-term relationship,&quot; a senior NATO diplomat said on Monday. &quot;But we are interested in this regardless of the leadership there is in Russia.</p>
<p>Privately, however, NATO sources say the 16-member alliance fears a change of leadership in Moscow would harden Russia's already steel-tipped opposition to plans for enlargement.</p>
<p>Russian doctors have recommended postponing heart surgery on Yeltsin for two months in order to help him build up his strength before the operation, leaving NATO officials unsure whether this is good or bad news.</p>
<p>&quot;On the one hand it means the need for surgery isn't critical, but on the other it means he is currently in worse shape than we thought,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>During this summer's Russian presidential elections, NATO and other Western officials -- while attempting to appear neutral -- scarcely disguised their support for Yeltsin.</p>
<p>While they maintain this was their best approach, some are now concerned they may have alienated his would-be successors should the worst befall the ailing Yeltsin.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment we seem to be negotiating in a vacuum,&quot; a source said. &quot;We can't speak to the top man so instead we are having to deal with people who may have a differant agenda.&quot;</p>
<p>These include security chief Alexander Lebed, who is due to visit NATO headquarters next week for wide-ranging talks on Russian/NATO relations.</p>
<p>Officials say NATO is keen to step up work on a U.S.-led &quot;Charter with Russia&quot;, which would formalise the alliance's relationship beyond that of participation in the Partnership for Peace programme -- an alliance of NATO and former Eastern bloc countries.</p>
<p>They have also to finalise a tit-for-tat posting of NATO observers to Moscow following the stationing of three senior Russian officers to the Supreme Headquarters Allied Powers in Europe.</p>
<p>NATO officials hope Lebed's message will not constrast too much with that of Russian Defence Minister Igor Rodionov, who is due to meet his alliance counterparts in Bergen, Norway (corrects from Sweden), later this week.</p>
<p>This was the case before the summer elections when Yevgeny Primakov -- then Russian Foreign Minister -- appeared as hardline as ever on NATO enlargement and Pavel Grachev -- then Defence Minister -- seemed to espouse a softer stance.</p>
<p>NATO diplomats, worried about the consistency of the message, appear agreed that Moscow is resigned to enlargement, but that Yeltsin -- in sickness or in health -- would be the best person with whom to negotiate their courtship.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
