<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707099" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO: Kabila's Congo to probe mystery of Lumumba's death.</title>
<headline>Kabila's Congo to probe mystery of Lumumba's death.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Malu-Malu</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Laurent Kabila's Democratic Republic of the Congo is to try to solve the mystery of nationalist independence hero Patrice Lumumba's death more than 36 years ago, promising a trial of those deemed to be in the know.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Celestin Luangy told a news conference that the trial would be one of many to shed light on politically motivated killings.</p>
<p>&quot;The trial will take place like many other trials in order to find out those responsible for politically motivated assassinations,&quot; Luangy said on Thursday.</p>
<p>He gave no details on the timing. &quot;Justice cannot be done hurriedly. We have to prepare for this trial. It will take place amid peace and serenity. Be sure, it will take place, don't be desperate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lumumba was one of the founding fathers of the Congolese nation. Labelled a Communist by jittery Western powers, he was the first prime minister of the then Republic of the Congo at independence from Belgium in 1960.</p>
<p>He is widely remembered as a powerful speaker who stood up to colonialism and demanded rights and respect for his country's nationals.</p>
<p>After less than two months in office, President Joseph Kasavubu, with whom Lumumba was at odds, sacked him. Lumumba in turn tried to sack the president.</p>
<p>The army, under future dictator Mobutu Sese Seko, then plain Colonel Joseph-Desire Mobutu, stepped in. Mobutu, who seized power in 1965 and held it for over three decades, restored Kasavubu in February 1961.</p>
<p>Lumumba was murdered a few days later in Lubumbashi in the southern mining province of Shaba.</p>
<p>Many books have been published on him but the circumstances of his death remain unclear.</p>
<p>Politically motivated killings abounded in the early 1960s as some provinces of Africa's third largest nation plunged into rebellion.</p>
<p>A national conference in the capital Kinshasa between 1992 and 1993 failed to clarify the mystery surrounding the death of Lumumba, a man whose memory commands huge popular respect along with his nationalist legacy.</p>
<p>Over 1,500 people from all over the country attended the ambitious forum which was part of promised democratic reforms and had been intended to rewrite the history of the nation and pave the way for a better future.</p>
<p>Kabila, a longtime opponent of Mobutu and a supporter of Lumumba, toppled the veteran dictator in May when his Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo marched into Kinshasa at the end of a seven-month civil war.</p>
<p>On Independence Day on Monday, older generations testified on state television to Lumumba's achievements.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
