<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707108" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANGOLA: Angola govt says UNITA retakes some diamond land.</title>
<headline>Angola govt says UNITA retakes some diamond land.</headline>
<byline>John Fleming</byline>
<dateline>LUANDA 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. officials in Angola said on Friday the government had reported losing some territory in the diamond-rich northeast of the country to the former rebel movement UNITA.</p>
<p>The spokesman for the U.N.'s peacekeeping mission in Angola, David Wimhurst, told Reuters the Luanda government reported the loss of a town called Northeast Frontier Post, on the border with the Democratic Republic of the Congo, to UNITA fighters.</p>
<p>&quot;The government tells us that five police and some civilians were killed in fighting around that town,&quot; Wimhurst said, adding that the government had also reported seven people killed in fighting in two other villages in the area.</p>
<p>There was no independent confirmation of the reports and a U.N. verification team would go to the area on Saturday, he added.</p>
<p>UNITA officials dismissed the government report as propaganda aimed at allowing the national army to step up action against the former rebel movement in the northeast, where there has been heavy fighting in recent weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;This is completely untrue. It is part of a propaganda campaign by the government. They are preparing the country for a return to war,&quot; UNITA spokesman Horacio Junjuvili told Reuters.</p>
<p>The government launched an offensive into UNITA-held areas in the region in May, which it said was aimed at rooting out armed refugees from the former Zaire.</p>
<p>But observers and Western diplomats said this was just a pretext for the Angolan army to recapture diamond territory controlled by UNITA.</p>
<p>A peace agreement ended nearly two decades of civil war in November 1994, but while the rival sides are members of a government of national unity, UNITA has refused to give up its 80 percent stake in Angola's diamond wealth.</p>
<p>Some analysts fear the country could return to full-scale fighting, but the U.N. Security Council voted unanimously on Monday to close its current peacekeeping operation and create an observer mission of 86 lighty-armed military officers and 345 civilian police.</p>
<p>Four thousand U.N. troops attached to the current mission, which began early in 1995, will stage a phased withdrawal until November.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANGOLA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
