<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707162" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - July 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - July 4.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Friday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- The Katz commission on taxation has recommended measures to clamp down on the use of benefit funds to avoid tax and to eliminate grey areas in legislation which have caused some funds to be largely unsupervised.</p>
<p>- De Beers and the National Union of Mineworkers have signed the mining industry's first two-year pay deal, providing for a 9.7 percent increase this year and an inflation-linked increase next year.</p>
<p>- The International Olympic Committee looked set to pick Rome ahead of Athens as the venue for the 2004 summer games, a Reuters survey showed.</p>
<p>- Gold plummeted $5.90 per ounce on Thursday on news that the Reserve Bank of Australia sold 167 tonnes of the precious metal, cutting its reserves by a third.</p>
<p>- Telkom posted a 61 percent rise in attributable profit to 1.95 billion rand for the year to end-March, while delivering more than 256,000 lines.</p>
<p>- Northern Province Premier Ngoako Ramatlhodi is expected to announce the appointment of a team of experts to whip his administration into shape after the release of a report on irregularities in the procurement of government buildings.</p>
<p>- Disgraced politicians, defeated military and former dignitaries of Mobutu Sese Seko's regime in former Zaire have chosen South Africa as a refuge since the takeover by Laurent Kabila's forces.</p>
<p>- - - -  </p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- There was some scope for a fall in interest rates, but this should not be over-estimated, Reserve Bank deputy governor Chris de Swart said.</p>
<p>- The value of houses built in the first quarter of this year slid 19 percent to 925.8 million rand from 1.14 billion rand in the last quarter of last year, further highlighting the slump in the residential property market, according to Central Statistical Service figures.</p>
<p>- JCI already has in place 2.5 billion rand in funding required for its acquisition of Anglo American Corp's full 27 percent holding in Lonrho.</p>
<p>- A popular tax loophole that allows employers to pay the total amount of employees' medical aid contributions could be partially closed if the government accepts the recommendation in the sixth report of the Katz commission on tax.</p>
<p>- - - -  </p>
<p>SAKE-BEELD</p>
<p>- Telecommunications utility Telkom will spend up to 53 billion rand over the next five years to double its number of connections to eight million and to modernise its network, chairman Dikgang Moseneke said.</p>
<p>- Yields on the South African capital market fell on Thursday to their lowest level in 16 months, after the yield on the benchmark government R150 bond broke through the 14.10 percent.</p>
<p>- Automobile manufacturers expect that vehicle sales in the second half of the year will come under pressure, despite their slight improvement last month.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE CITIZEN</p>
<p>- Justice Minister Dullah Omar rejected claims of government meddling in investigations against Allan Boesak, former head of the Foundation for Peace and Justice.</p>
<p>- Police, business and government officials have warned Johannesburg hawkers to stop trading in counterfeit products. Police said the most common brands being copied by fraudsters are Adidas, Fila, Hi-Tech, Nike, Reebok, Power and Converse.</p>
<p>- President Nelson Mandela will travel to Indonesia and Thailand after his official visit to Britain which begins on Monday.</p>
<p>- A Watsonian Rugby Club player from Edinburgh, Scotland, appeared in court in connection with a complaint lodged by a Cape Town woman who said she was indecently assaulted on a South African Airways flight from London on Wednesday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- The fallout of Hong Kong's reincorporation into China is about to flood South African shores in the form of fake brand- name consumer goods. Customs and border officials have been told to look out for over 100 shipping containers from China.</p>
<p>- Moves are afoot to lift legal prohibitions on the use of South Africa's sophisticated interception system, used to tap local and international telephone calls.</p>
<p>- Controversial AIDS researchers Dirk du Plessis and Callie Landauer have been rapped over the knuckles for carrying out research without the approval of the University of Pretoria's ethics committee.</p>
<p>--Johannesburg newsroom -27-11-482.1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
