<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707116" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Activists urge donors to keep pressure on Zambia.</title>
<headline>Activists urge donors to keep pressure on Zambia.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>An international human rights group urged aid donors on Friday to maintain economic pressure on Zambia's government to force progress in democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>Human Rights Watch/Africa spokesman Alex Vines said foreign governments should continue to link assistance -- particularly balance of payment support -- to the country's human rights track record.</p>
<p>&quot;This strategic use of aid to ensure compliance is all-important,&quot; Vines told a news conference.</p>
<p>Western donors cut aid to Zambia last year after the government passed a constitutional amendment keeping all major contenders out of general elections in November, including former president Kenneth Kaunda.</p>
<p>Some donor goverments have told President Frederick Chiluba's government the squeeze would be eased at a Consultative Group donors meeting in Paris on July 9, provided the government begins dialogue with the opposition.</p>
<p>But opposition parties that boycotted the poll have also rejected dialogue with Chiluba's government, saying he should call fresh elections.</p>
<p>Human Rights Watch supported the call for a new poll, and recommended that Zambia adopt a new consensus-based constitution.</p>
<p>It also urged the government to guarantee the independence of the judiciary and to uphold freedom of expression and association, which it said were still lacking.</p>
<p>Zambia, which has instituted sweeping economic reforms and a massive programme of privatising hundreds of state-owned firms, is anxious to restore normal relations with donors. It is relying on aid to fund a third of the country's $1.1 billion budget for 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
