<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707202" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian promises tough to keep, but markets happy.</title>
<headline>Russian promises tough to keep, but markets happy.</headline>
<byline>Peter Henderson</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin's promise to pay off huge wage arrears in a matter of months is good for politics, but the Russian state may have to lift billions of dollars from other pockets to fulfil it.</p>
<p>Yeltsin told Russians on Friday that the economy was turning and promised to pay off the wage arrears, which probably amount to billions of dollars, within three months to the armed forces, teachers, doctors and other public sector employees.</p>
<p>&quot;The tide has already turned,&quot; he said in his regular radio address. &quot;The slump has been stopped.&quot;</p>
<p>But hints of recovery do not mean the economy is ready to help the government to fulfil all its obligations and promises.</p>
<p>&quot;Yeltsin's commitments can be met and Russia can keep within its deficit forecast -- but at the expense of something else,&quot; said Renaissance Capital economist Roland Nash.</p>
<p>Almost every Russian financial market is setting records as new investors with high hopes pour in funds. But official figures show the economy shrunk 0.2 percent in the first five months of 1997 year-on-year and tax receipts are still low.</p>
<p>The state has not released data for federal wage arrears, but First Deputy Prime Minister Anatoly Chubais has said the armed services are owed about five trillion roubles ($870 million). Estimates from other officials are three times that figure.</p>
<p>Yeltsin said all levels of government should work to pay off public sector wage arrears, which rose two percent in June to 11 trillion roubles. But the federal government's share was unclear.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not raising the revenues they said they were going to raise but they are keeping the deficit down to the level forecast, which means they are not meeting their current commitments,&quot; Nash said. &quot;If they are not meeting their current commitments, there is no way they can meet past commitments.&quot;</p>
<p>Tax collection, the most important revenue source, has been abysmally low at about 70 percent of budgeted levels in the first half of the year, helped mainly by a one-time arrears payment by gas group Gazprom, arguably Russia's richest company, in June.</p>
<p>Gazprom, which had the largest corporate debt to the government among its various branches, paid 14 trillion roubles, or about 0.6 percent of gross domestic product in June, and it is not clear how much more the state can squeeze from industry.</p>
<p>Russia, which has successfully turned to international capital markets three times, used funds from its last Eurobond and from Gazprom to pay off pension debts. But it plans no new Eurobond before autumn, which would be after the time by which Yeltsin ordered debts to be paid.</p>
<p>&quot;Direct investment remains at a critically low level,&quot; said Finance Ministry expert group economist Viktoria Kotova, estimating 1997 direct foreign investment would be $2.7 billion.</p>
<p>The World Bank has approved an $800 million loan to cushion the social effect of reform but only $300 million will be ready immediately. The International Monetary fund made a $700 million quarterly payment of the $2.8 billion it intends to send Russia this year in May.</p>
<p>But investors are pouring funds into Russian markets, pushing the Russian Trading System index to 495.57 from under 200 in January. Average Treasury bill yields have fallen below 20 percent from about 200 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a group more dedicated to equities and is anxious to have a piece of this market for the long term,&quot; Deutsche Morgan Grenfell's chief Russian economist Kingsmill Bond said of the new funds. &quot;It is less likely to slip in and out.&quot;</p>
<p>Bond said foreigners could still be scared out of risky Russia by a sharp correction on high-flying Wall Street, but investors were looking chiefly at slow but sure industrial reform as the key to further investment.</p>
<p>-- Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
