<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707263" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Sixty Romanian firms head for share flotation -FPS.</title>
<headline>Sixty Romanian firms head for share flotation -FPS.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania said on Friday it planned to step up privatisation of state-owned companies with a new wave of stock market flotations starting next month.</p>
<p>Sorin Dimitriu, head of the State Ownership Fund (FPS), which has a controlling interest in most Romanian companies, said his agency was preparing to sell stakes in 60 companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Stakes in another five companies will be put on sale on the over-the-counter (OTC) market in two months' time, to be soon followed by another 10,&quot; he added in an interview.</p>
<p>Earlier, he told a news conference one of the country's six state-run banks, Banca Romana pentru Dezvoltare (BRD), would be privatised before the end of this year and preparations would start for selling off another bank, Banc Post.</p>
<p>Faster privatisation has been set as a goal under loan accords with international lenders. The new centrist government, in office since elections last November, has pledged to fulfil a tough reform package, including sell-offs and restructuring.</p>
<p>Dimitriu said in the interview the FPS would avoid depressing share prices by offering individual share stakes of below five percent, with the overall holding sold off in each company not exceeding 20 percent.</p>
<p>The Bucharest exchange, opened late in 1995 as Romania's first bourse in 50 years, now lists 46 stocks. Another 3,000 or so are quoted on the over-the-counter market, launched last October.</p>
<p>-- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
