<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707273" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbia to pay '97 wheat in three instalments,paper.</title>
<headline>Serbia to pay '97 wheat in three instalments,paper.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbia will buy up the entire market surplus of the 1997 wheat crop and pay it in three instalments, the Belgrade daily Politika reported on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Serbian government decided to buy all market surpluses of the 1997 wheat crop,&quot; the paper quoted Serbian Prime Minister Mirko Marjanovic as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Wheat will be paid in three instalments,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The first instalment, at the value of 40 percent of the purchased wheat, will be paid in cash to farmers, by the end of August.</p>
<p>Second and third instalments, of 30 percent of the value each, will be paid out in forward wheat contracts issued by the Serbia's Commodity Reserve Agency by the end of September and October.</p>
<p>Wheat can also be excanged for fuel, fertilisers, seeds and agricultural mechanisation, Marjanovic said.</p>
<p>The Serbian government set the purchasing price of the 1997 wheat crop at 1.1 dinars per kilo.</p>
<p>The price for the 1996 wheat crop was 0.9 dinars per kilo.</p>
<p>Although the World wheat market price has been on decline in the past year and stands at only 0.60 dinars per kilo for the local farmers, the government decided to subsidise producers to the price of 1.1 dinars per kilo, Marjanovic said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is subsidising the wheat price by 83 percent compared to the world market price,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We wanted to protect the interests of our farmers having in mind their enormous efforts and contribution to overall economic and social stability of the country,&quot; Marjanovic said.</p>
<p>Serbia is expected to yield 2.749 million tonnes out of a total of 2.8 million tonnes of wheat expected to be harvested in Yugoslavia this year on some 800,000 sown hectares.</p>
<p>The rest is to be produced in Montenegro, Serbia's tiny ally in the Yugoslav federation.</p>
<p>The Serbian Chamber of Commerce has estimated the 1997 wheat market surplus at 1.6 million tonnes. -- Gordana Kukic, Belgrade Newsroom +381 11 311 4254 ($1=5.7809 Yugoslav dinars)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
