<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707248" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia's SBI ends firm, further gains expected.</title>
<headline>Slovenia's SBI ends firm, further gains expected.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenia's SBI index ended 0.18 percent higher on Friday, extending its winning streak to 12 days -- and traders forecast there was more to come.</p>
<p>&quot;I think shares will rise gradually at least for half a year as foreigners are likely to continue investing here,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The SBI index rose 0.18 percent or 2.6 points to 1,460.1, taking its gains to 15.6 percent this week alone.</p>
<p>Market participants forecast the index could easily rise to between 1,800 and 1,900 points by the end of the year if the buying momentum remains at the current pace.</p>
<p>Overall eight shares rose, seven fell and three were flat, while 10 were untraded. But turnover fell to 481.5 million tolars from 874.2 million.</p>
<p>&quot;There were some shares falling today, which may be a reaction to recent high gains but I think mostly domestic participants were selling,&quot; said Crt Jakhel, a trader at brokerage Nika.</p>
<p>Bank Probanka was the top gainer, jumping 8.93 percent to 22,450 tolars on volume of 190 shares.</p>
<p>Market participants said the bank rebounded from yesterday's 9.80 percent fall and added that news that Daiwa Europe was allowed by the Bank of Slovenia to buy 2.94 percent of the bank also contributed to the share's gains.</p>
<p>Drug maker Lek had the highest turnover, jumping 6.58 percent to 34,000 tolars on volume of 6,508 shares for total turnover of 215.7 million tolars.</p>
<p>Brokerage Primofin led decliners, tumbling 9.95 percent to 9,050 tolars on volume of only 13 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
