<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707295" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - July 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - July 4.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Sarajevo press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DNEVNI AVAZ</p>
<p>- The president of Bosnia's Serb entity, Biljana Plavsic, orders the dissolution of the assembly and scheduled new elections for September 1 to prevent &quot;disaster&quot;.</p>
<p>- The Bosnian Serb government said Plavsic's decision was unconstitutional.</p>
<p>- It is clear that former Bosnian Serb president Radovan Karadzic still wields strong political influence and has a destructive influence on the peace process, the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) mission said.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Serb army General Pero Colic said the military will not intervene and called for the crisis to be resolved politically.</p>
<p>- The European Union and the Moslem-Croat federation signed a memorandum of understanding worth 9.8 million dollars for improvement of Sarajevo's water supply system.</p>
<p>- The federation government agreed on a draft law which would repeal import privileges for soldiers, war invalids, civilian war victims, refugees and Bosnians working abroad.</p>
<p>- Bosnia's Council of Ministers is close to completing memorandum with the International Monetary Fund, which is one of the last conditions for holding a donors' conference, Boro Bosic, Serb co-chairman of the council, said.</p>
<p>- Many words were spoken but no concrete issues were solved, said chief of the Mostar regional office of the High Representative, Sir Martin Garrod, after the cantonal parliament once again failed to adopt constitutional amendments on power-sharing between Moslems and Croats.</p>
<p>- Karadzic, Bosnian Serb interior minister Dragan Kijac, and the Serb member of collective presidency, Momcilo Krajisnik, are taking very dangerous actions which violate the peace accords, U.S. envoy Robert Gelbard said.</p>
<p>- The car factory UNIS in the Sarajevo suburb of Vogosca will start post-war car production in July next year in cooperation with German Volkswagen A.G., general menager of the company Faruk Smailbegovic said.</p>
<p>- The independent televison network OBN established with international funds has started broadcasting for the first time from the Serb entity as well from a studio in Banja Luka. -- Sarajevo newsroom +387-71-663-864</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
