<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707284" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - July 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - July 4.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Slovenia's friday morning newspapers:</p>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>- A session of the states of the Central European Free Trade Agreement (CEFTA) that comprises Slovenia, Slovakia, the Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland and Romania, starts on Friday. Delegations of CEFTA members will be led by economy ministers.</p>
<p>- The Slovenian government said on Thursday it would privatise 80 percent of its troubled ironworks Slovenske Zelezarne.</p>
<p>- Slovenian parliament on Thursday passed the new law on government, increasing the number of ministries to 15.</p>
<p>- Parliamentary parties are due to sign a cross-party agreement on Friday on cooperation in Slovenia's efforts to join the European Union.</p>
<p>- Representatives of neighbouring Italy, Austria and Slovenia on Thursday issued a statement supporting common candidacy for the 2006 winter Olympics, which would be the first games to be held on the territory of three countries.</p>
<p>- Over 20 Slovenian companies said they would participate in Bosnia's largest fair in Zenica in autumn.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- Judges and prosecutors in Ljubljana are pushing for construction of a new court, saying that their current situation is unbearable.</p>
<p>VECER</p>
<p>- State secretary at the Foreign Ministry Ivo Vajgl met Sir Arthur Watts, international coordinator of negotiations on succession of assets between the states of former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>FINANCE</p>
<p>- The government said on Thursday it would issue a three-year bond on July 23 to the value of up to five billion tolars ($31.5 million) in order to cover the budget deficit.</p>
<p>- Producer prices in June rose by 0.8 percent compared to May and 6.2 percent compared to June 1996, the Slovenian Statistical Office reported.</p>
<p>- Slovenia's largest bank state-owned unlisted Nova Ljubljanska Banka (NLB) said it had merged with bank LB Zasavje taking the total number of banks in the group to nine. REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
