<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707480" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai banker sees permanent two-tier baht regime.</title>
<headline>Thai banker sees permanent two-tier baht regime.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading Thai banker said on Friday Thailand may follow Singapore in making its control of offshore currency supply permanent to help ward off future speculative attacks on the baht.</p>
<p>Olarn Chaipravat, president of the Thai Bankers Association, said the two-tier baht exchange system, put in place by the central bank since mid-May to block access of baht for offshore speculators, should be institutionalised with some minor adjustments.</p>
<p>&quot;The two-tier system, with some changes...for 90 percent separation of the markets, will probably be the end-scenario between offshore and onshore foreign exchange markets.</p>
<p>&quot;If it is closed 90 percent and open 10 percent, it can be the system like the one that Singapore has used for a long, long time. Singapore never allows speculators to attack the Singapore dollar from offshore sources,&quot; the banker said.</p>
<p>Heavy market attacks on the baht in May forced Thailand to switch this week from its long-standing practice of fixing the baht against a dollar-dominated basket of currencies to a new managed float.</p>
<p>The de facto devaluation sent the baht falling to 28.700 to the dollar in late Friday trading from 25.800 early this week.</p>
<p>Olarn, chief executive of the Siam Commercial Bank Plc, had been opposed to a baht devaluation.</p>
<p>The banker and economist, who had turned down past government offers of a finance ministerial job, said the weaker baht would give only a limited boost to Thai exports which, with an average 42 percent import content, would carry higher production costs.</p>
<p>&quot;(The devaluation) is like flood water reaching town, getting everybody wet. Only those who sought protection by hedging their dollar exposure managed to stay dry but even that would only be temporary,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Olarn told reporters he believed the optimal baht rate in the next three to six months would be 27.50 to the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;The devaluation was not meant to be a cure-all remedy for the Thai economy. It is a painful thing that we have to live with, to allow private sector participants to adjust by increasing competitiveness and improving productivity of companies and industries so that they can compete effectively in a globalised world market.&quot;</p>
<p>The banker said with the baht's new floating system, private business would need to closely monitor future signals of when the Bank of Thailand would intervene in defence of the currency.</p>
<p>He declined to estimate the devaluation impact on economic growth and inflation, saying it would be determined by the extent of the future loss in the baht's value.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
