<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707413" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: BP to increase Colombia output despite rebels.</title>
<headline>BP to increase Colombia output despite rebels.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Petroleum Co Plc's output from its giant Cusiana-Cupiagua field in eastern Colombia will increase to 500,000 barrels per day by the end of December or early January despite leftist rebel threats, company chiefs said.</p>
<p>With the completion of the Ocensa pipeline -- the largest in Colombia -- output will be rising from current levels of about 175,000 barrels per day to an intermediate level of 320,000 barrels by the end of this month or early next.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're a bit uncertain of the exact date (when output will be ramped up to 500,000 barrels), but it will be at the end of December or early January,&quot; John Doust, president of BP's Colombian unit BP Exploration (BPX), told Reuters.</p>
<p>Production is likely then to remain at that level for at least three years before it starts to decline, Doust said.</p>
<p>The development of the Cupiagua field, in eastern Casanare province, was recently delayed by threats by National Liberation Army (ELN) rebels against construction workers.  </p>
<p>Doust estimated the threats and attacks set the project back three to four weeks, but said this would not necessarily delay the completion of the project by the same amount, adding that time could be made up between now and the end of the year.</p>
<p>The ELN, set up by radical Roman Catholic priests in 1966, specializes in attacks on Colombia's oil infrastructure.</p>
<p>Doust rejected suggestions, however, that rebel threats would force BP's total withdrawal from Colombia, but conceded that the security issue had dictated the pace of progress on its projects.  </p>
<p>&quot;The security issue governs the pace that we deal with things. As we have said, the security situation is difficult here and it's up to the state to provide the protection. The amount of that protection will govern the pace of development of our projects,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last year, 12 percent of BP's worldwide capital expenditure was directed to Colombia. Doust said BP's Colombian production now accounts for 5 percent of the company's worldwide oil output.  </p>
<p>Iain Conn, vice-chairman of BP's Piedemonte 1 project, said that proportion was likely to remain stable as production in Colombia increased in line with an overall rise in BP's worldwide output.</p>
<p>BPX hopes to add significantly to production levels once the Piedemonte 1 field, also in eastern Colombia, comes on stream. The three hydrocarbon formations so far discovered, Pauto, Florena and Volcanera, are estimated to contain between 600 million and 1 billion barrels of condensates and some 10 trillion cubic feet of natural gas.  </p>
<p>The Piedemonte contract has been subject to protracted wrangles over the division of profits between BP and its associate, state-run oil company Ecopetrol.</p>
<p>If the contract difficulties are ironed out, Conn said the first production from Piedemonte could be expected in the second half of 1999.  </p>
<p>According to the terms of the current contract, BP must declare commercial viability on the field before March next year. By the same time as Piedemonte gas comes on stream, BP hopes to have set up a gas-fired thermoelectric plant of between 100 and 200 megawatts. The plant to be known as Termogas de Casanare will be a joint project with Ecopetrol, Bavaria and Mosbacher.  </p>
<p>As well as moving into the power generation sector, Doust said BP was continuing to look for partners and possibilities to move into the distribution of natural gas to domestic consumers. BP made an unsuccessful bid for Gas Natural, the gas distribution network in Bogota, last month.</p>
<p>((-- Karl Penhaul, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
