<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707595" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco seizes 5.8 tonnes of cocaine.</title>
<headline>Morocco seizes 5.8 tonnes of cocaine.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morocco's security forces have seized up to 5.8 tonnes of pure cocaine which washed up on Moroccan shores, the official MAP news agency reported on Friday.</p>
<p>Quoting a statement by the interior ministry, MAP said ...&quot;total drugs seized by security forces on the Atlantic coastline from Casablanca to El Jadida rose to 5.8 tonnes of pure cocaine&quot;.</p>
<p>The first cocaine was discovered last month by children playing on a Casablanca beach when they opened plastic bags and tasted the white powder inside, L'Opinion newspaper said earlier.</p>
<p>The total seized has a street value of more than $500 million, a Moroccan doctor said.</p>
<p>The drugs were smuggled from Colombia on a ship bound for southern Europe, MAP said.</p>
<p>It named the targeted area as &quot;Spanish-Portugal zone&quot;.</p>
<p>The cocaine was thrown overboard after the ship, which had a Spanish captain, had a mechanical breakdown, it said.</p>
<p>MAP said Moroccan Interior Minister Driss Basri unexpectedly visited the southern Spanish city of Malaga on Friday for talks with Spanish officials.</p>
<p>&quot;Basri started a working visit to Malaga where he met his Spanish counterpart, including the government delegate in charge of national anti-drugs plan,&quot; MAP said.</p>
<p>The minister was accompanied with senior officials from the Moroccan interior and security services, it said but gave no other details.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
