<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707527" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China interbank market rates (CHIBOR) mostly down.</title>
<headline>China interbank market rates (CHIBOR) mostly down.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is the China Interbank Offered Rate (CHIBOR) for Friday issued by the official Xinhua news agency on behalf of the People's Bank of China, the central bank.</p>
<p>The figures represent weighted averages and not closing prices and are annual percentage rates.</p>
<p>		1DAY   7DAY  20DAY  30DAY  60DAY  90DAY  120DAY</p>
<p> FRIDAY    10.273 11.006 10.965 10.919 11.119 11.880 no trade</p>
<p>THURSDAY  10.202 11.016 11.296 10.892 11.233 11.614 no trade</p>
<p>Turnover fell sharply to 725 million yuan from 2.468 billion yuan with the 20-day contract the most actively traded.  </p>
<p>Traders said trading was very dull on Friday due to a series of factors including a recent re-affirmation by the central bank that money traded on the interbank market must not flow into the stock markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank early last month re-affirmed the ban on interbank market money flowing into the stock markets, making many securities houses reduce their trading on the interbank market,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Some traders said the market was still in a holiday mood after Hong Kong's return to China, so there was only sporadic borrowing and selling on the market on Friday.  </p>
<p>Other traders said banks usually traded less on Fridays ahead of weekend, helping to depress volume today.</p>
<p>Traders said they believed the interbank rates would move in a narrow range with turnover recovering early next week.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
