<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707600" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco's bourse ends week 0.25 pct higher.</title>
<headline>Morocco's bourse ends week 0.25 pct higher.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca stock exchange closed on Friday 0.25 percent higher, lifted slightly by small gains in some stocks like oil refinery Samir and privatisation bonds, stockbrokers said.</p>
<p>The bourse all-share index closed at 638.02 points from 636.41 points on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is slighly picking up but it's difficult to say whether it will pursue that trend...shareholders are still very cautious,&quot; a broker at BMCI Securities said.</p>
<p>First tranche of privatisation bonds, issued in January 1996, rose to 1,359 from 1,355 on the previous session.</p>
<p>In the energy sector, oil refinery Samir gained seven dirhams to 358 dirhams. It was the second most traded stock during the week on the official market with more than 8,000 shares.</p>
<p>Blue-chip Banque Commerciale du Maroc closed unchanged at 860 dirhams. Banque Marocaine du Commerce Exterieur closed at 588 dirhams from 597 dirhams. More than 20,000 BMCE shares were exchanged during the week.</p>
<p>First Moroccan private conglomerate, ONA Group closed at 765 dirhams from 775 dirhams.</p>
<p>Societe Nationale d'Investissement, the second largest private group, closed unchanged at 720 dirhams.</p>
<p>Steel mill Sonasid dipped 10 dirhams to 530 dirhams.</p>
<p>Total traded volume on the official market was 24.7 million from 21.8 million.</p>
<p>On the over-the-counter market, the volume was 42.9 million from 11 million dirhams.</p>
<p>($1= 9.5 dirhams)</p>
<p>-- Newsroom 212-7 72 65 18</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
