<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707626" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian bonds close flat in lackluster trading.</title>
<headline>Canadian bonds close flat in lackluster trading.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed little changed on Friday, with the absence of a U.S. market and lack of significant news or data keeping trading activity muted, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There really was nothing going on here. The underlying theme is the slightly stronger currency, but really there's very very thin activity,&quot; said Jim Webber, director of fixed-income research with TD Securities. &quot;One trade was enough to move the market in either direction.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year benchmark bond rose C$0.18 to C$117.06 to yield 6.674 percent.  </p>
<p>The U.S. 30-year bond last traded with a yield of 6.62 percent. The spread between the bonds narrowed to five basis points from seven basis points at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>Canadian bond market activity was light, as expected, with U.S. markets closed for Independence Day. While there was no early close recommended by the Toronto Bond Traders' Association, analysts said many desks were staffed at minimal levels.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of people simply do not try to put on any kind of position or take any kind of a view on July 4th,&quot; said Webber.  </p>
<p>Looking ahead, analysts said the next major piece of economic data for North American bond markets will be the U.S. producer price index for June out on Friday. On the same day Canada will also release its employment data for June.</p>
<p>In economic news, Statistics Canada reported on Friday that labor income rose 0.5 percent in April to C$37.084 billion from C$36.889 billion in March. The news had little impact on Canadian bonds.</p>
<p>In other prices, Canada's 10-year benchmark bond rose C$0.06 to C$108.46 to yield 6.089 percent, compared to its U.S. equivalent last traded to yield 6.30 percent.  </p>
<p>The negative spread between the bonds widened to 21 basis points from 19 basis points at the close of trading on Thursday.</p>
<p>The three-month cash T-bill yielded 3.05 percent against its U.S. equivalent which yielded 5.15 percent.</p>
<p>((Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
