<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707820" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU threatens Boeing/McDonnell Douglas deal.</title>
<headline>EU threatens Boeing/McDonnell Douglas deal.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS, Belgium</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union threw down the gauntlet to Boeing Co. and McDonnell Douglas Corp. Friday, saying their planned $14 billion merger should be blocked under EU antitrust law unless it was changed.</p>
<p>EU sources said competition experts from all 15 EU countries had agreed at a meeting in Brussels that offers made to date by Boeing for the deal to pass muster were &quot;not sufficient.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If adequate remedies are not offered, the proposed concentration should be prohibited,&quot; one source said, summing up the experts' conclusions.</p>
<p>Sources said the experts -- an advisory committee -- had unanimously agreed with the European Commission competition officials that the merger would add to what was seen as Boeing's already dominant position in the aircraft industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Commitments offered so far by Boeing are not sufficient to prevent such a strengthening of dominant position,&quot; another source said.</p>
<p>The sources said the Commission, the EU's antitrust watchdog, planned in the next few days to find out whether Boeing was prepared to come up with further offers to allow the deal to go through.</p>
<p>The Commission is known to have three main concerns about the deal.</p>
<p>It opposes Boeing's exclusive contracts to supply planes to certain airlines, notably Delta, American and Continental.</p>
<p>It also worries about the effect of the deal on the defence industry, McDonnell Douglas's main sector, and on the overall size of the deal.</p>
<p>The Commission estimates that the merger would give Boeing/McDonnell Douglas a 70 market share.</p>
<p>Europe's position is in sharp contrast to that of U.S. antitrust authorities.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Trade Commission agreed four to one earlier this week not to challenge any aspect of the deal, saying McDonnell Douglas was no longer a competitive force in the commercial aircraft market.</p>
<p>It did, however, say that Boeing's exclusive contracts were &quot;potentially troubling.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
