<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707898" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Grain trade slow as rain worries farmers, traders.</title>
<headline>Grain trade slow as rain worries farmers, traders.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>European grain trade was slack this week as heavy rain slowed cereals harvesting in the south and triggered fears for quality in parts of northern Europe.</p>
<p>In France, weather concerns took cenre stage as continued rain delayed the start of the wheat and barley harvests and raised concern over new crop quality.</p>
<p>French old-crop wheat prices stabilised, helped by demand from millers and feed producers.</p>
<p>New crop prices were also stable but there was no trade as both sellers and buyers stayed put.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a status-quo this week. Dry weather is forecast for next week, this should bring sellers out and force down prices,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Rouen wheat quoted at 800 francs for spot delivery and at 860 francs for September-December delivery, both unchanged from Monday.</p>
<p>Millers were particularly worried that the wet weather could hit new crop quality.</p>
<p>Experts say the crop potential is still intact but high moisture levels could spark unwanted germination in the fields and lower protein content, a key measurement for bread-making wheat.</p>
<p>Farmers have reported germination problems in the Poitou Charentes area, while the rain has pushed back by some 10 days the start of the wheat harvest in the southwest, the Paris basin and Beauce grain belt.</p>
<p>In the Champagne-Ardennes region in the northeast rains also delayed the start of the winter barley harvest, raising fears over the quality of malting barley.</p>
<p>Operators largely ignored news the European Union had agreed to open grain export tenders for the new 1997/98 season. They said the move had been widely expected and did not mean the EU would start subsidising exports right away.</p>
<p>EU officials have said they were in no hurry to export grain as they wait to get a firmer crop picture. In addition export demand has slowed down following recent North African purchases.</p>
<p>German wheat prices edged higher towards the end of the week because sellers tightened supply under the impression that prices may have bottomed-out, brokers said.</p>
<p>Wheat sellers felt encouraged by export signals from Brussels for the new crop after the cereals management committee said it would open wheat, barley and rye tenders from the free market from July 17.</p>
<p>They added some 2.50 marks/tonne to the fob price of old crop bread wheat, with benchmark 13 percent material at 280.</p>
<p>Old crop rye was marked down by up to 5.00 marks on lack of buyers.</p>
<p>Agreement &quot;in principle&quot; by the EU to open intervention rye sales failed to lift prices.</p>
<p>New crop grains were kept steady as favourable crop weather reports outweighed impact from the EU meetings.</p>
<p>In Britain, the week ended with the market stifled by the strength of sterling, which broke five-year highs against the German mark following the UK budget on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Apart from the currency, the main issue was rain, as concern mounted over the likely quality of new crop grain after the wettest June since 1860.</p>
<p>Farmers and traders were also concerned over harvest prospects, with much of the barley crop flat as a result of the rain.</p>
<p>Old crop wheat futures were boosted, in low volume, as market players moved to cover their needs with wheat of known quality, traders said.</p>
<p>Spanish dealers said trading activity picked up during last week, but prices varied widely because of vastly different standards of crop.</p>
<p>They added that bad weather conditions had affected the quality of durum wheat.</p>
<p>Recent rainfall was also seen slowing down harvest collection in the north and impacting quality.</p>
<p>Italy's durum wheat harvest started this week in southern areas and according to first indications the product is of good quality, the Italian Institute for Agriculture Studies said.</p>
<p>Ismea added that prices were on an uptrend because of worries that yields would be lower than forecast therefore reducing total production.</p>
<p>Soft wheat was not traded in Turin on Friday as the market awaited the new product. Ismea said it may have to revise its production forecasts because heavy rains over the past two weeks have delayed harvesting activity.</p>
<p>Ismea said the first price for new crop soft wheat from Lombardy was at 290.000 lire per tonne.  </p>
<p>Some benchmark European prices were as follows (French prices exclude carrying charges, but there are no carrying charges in July. Spanish prices are for new crop, except maize.)</p>
<p>					 July 4		    June 27</p>
<p>Rouen dlvd wheat July		 800 ffr ($136)	  NA</p>
<p>Rouen dlvd wheat Sept-Dec	   860 ffr ($146)	  860</p>
<p>Rouen dlvd July			 820 ffr ($139)	  820</p>
<p>Bordeaux dlvd maize July	    825 ffr ($140)	  840</p>
<p>Bordeaux dlvd maize Oct-Dec	 850 ffr ($144)	  870</p>
<p>German Hamburg Exch br wheat   265.00 Dm ($151)	265.00</p>
<p>	     (12.5 pct spot)</p>
<p>German Hamburg Exch feed wheat 260.00 Dm  ($148)	262.50</p>
<p>UK feed wheat E. Anglia (July)  84.50 stg ($143)	85.00</p>
<p>(June)</p>
<p>UK feed barley E. Anglia (July) 82.00 stg ($138)	82.00</p>
<p>(June)</p>
<p>Spain feed wheat	  23,500-24,750 ptas ($159-167)</p>
<p>24,250-28,000</p>
<p>Spain milling wheat		25,000 ptas ($169)</p>
<p>24,000-28,000</p>
<p>Spain durum wheat		  27,500 ptas ($186)</p>
<p>25,500-28,500</p>
<p>Spain barley		22,500-23,500 ptas ($152-159) 22,250</p>
<p>Spain maize			  24,500 ptas ($166)     24,500</p>
<p>Italy wheat			   ----------	     ----------</p>
<p>Italy durum (North)		 ----------	     ----------</p>
<p>Italy durum (Centre)	370-375,000 lire ($217-220)----------</p>
<p>Italy maize		   245-246,000 lire ($144)</p>
<p>248-249,000</p>
<p>-- Compiled by Christopher Lyddon in London, +44 171 542 7928, with contributions from Paris, Hamburg, Milan and Madrid</p>
<p>One dollar equals  5.9 French Francs, 1.751 German Marks, 0.592 Pounds Sterling, 147.8 Spanish Pesetas and 1,704 Italian Lire</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
