<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707821" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French ex-tycoon Bernard Tapie gets new jail term.</title>
<headline>French ex-tycoon Bernard Tapie gets new jail term.</headline>
<dateline>MARSEILLE, France 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A French court Friday sentenced imprisoned bankrupt tycoon Bernard Tapie to an additional 18 months in jail with another 18 months suspended for embezzling funds from Marseille soccer club.</p>
<p>Tapie attorney Jean-Yves Lienard quickly said he would appeal, calling the sentence &quot;totally out of proportion&quot; to his client's alleged crime.</p>
<p>During Tapie's trial in May, a public prosecutor urged the court in the Mediterranean port city of Marseille to jail the former soccer boss for two years, with another two years suspended.</p>
<p>The 54-year-old businessman and former politician was charged with embezzling 100 million francs ($17.5 million) between 1987 and 1993 when he was president of the Marseille club.</p>
<p>All 19 of Tapie's co-defendants, who held various club posts or were otherwise involved in French soccer, were also convicted in the case and drew fines or jail terms.</p>
<p>The trial failed to determine where the embezzled funds ended up but highlighted widespread illegal practices in soccer, including false invoicing and kickbacks.</p>
<p>During the trial, Tapie admitted breaking the law with fictitious loans to star players but argued that what he had done was less illicit than other possible courses of action. He also admitted using gate money to bribe rival players to lose a 1993 match.</p>
<p>The proceedings were repeatedly suspended for medical treatment when the former political boss and leftist cabinet minister began suffering chest pains and breathing difficulties.</p>
<p>At the close of the trial, Tapie pleaded with the judge not to sentence him to additional jail time. Tapie was imprisoned earlier this year after the supreme court upheld an eight-month sentence for bribing players of league rival Valenciennes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARSEILLE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
