<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707827" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Debate rages as Ontario women bare their breasts.</title>
<headline>Debate rages as Ontario women bare their breasts.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Hopkins</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>In what is sure to be a summer to remember, some women in Ontario are taking to the Canadian province's beaches, streets and stores to test their new freedom to bare their breasts in public.</p>
<p>The arrival of warm weather in Canada's most populous province has been marked this year by topless sunbathers on public beaches, topless rollerbladers in city parks and the opening of Canada's first topless retail outlet.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a new free-thinking thing, toplessness. We think this is a cool idea. We think it's good,&quot; said David Blackstone, owner of Tom &amp; Tina's Topless Surf and Sport shop, which opened last week in the resort town of Wasaga Beach.</p>
<p>Gaping onlookers gathered as several customers -- women and men -- agreed to shop topless to promote the grand opening of the small shop at the popular beach.</p>
<p>It became legal for women in Ontario to go topless in public last December after the Ontario Court of Appeal overturned the conviction of a woman charged with indecency after she took to the streets topless on a hot summer day in 1991.</p>
<p>The court ruled the law was discriminatory since men could shed their shirts in public, paving the way for Ontario women to bare their chests as long it was not for sexual purposes.</p>
<p>The new freedom was untested through Ontario's frigid winter and chilly spring. But this summer has seen a growing number of women outdoors sporting nothing above the waist, sparking fierce debate and at least one fist-fight.</p>
<p>&quot;They were bosom buddies but bare breasts lead to bare knuckles,&quot; blared a headline in the tabloid Toronto Sun after two women got into a fight when one of them refused to put on a shirt while working in her backyard.</p>
<p>Reaction to the vogue for bare breasts has been mixed. &quot;I don't see anything wrong with it in a beach area. I don't know about walking in downtown Toronto, but there's nothing wrong with it here,&quot; said Krista Wagner, 24, a Toronto waitress who drew crowds of hooting men when she shopped topless in Wasaga Beach.</p>
<p>One man who stopped to watch Wagner disapproved.</p>
<p>&quot;These girls are attention-seekers. A woman's breast is sexual. It's not the same thing as a man...we're trying to instill something counter to our culture,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One woman, who said her whole family went topless in Italy, said the issue was blown out of proportion.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just not a big deal. People do it all over in Italy,&quot; said Linda Piscione, 35. But she admitted she would not be comfortable doffing her top in Canada.</p>
<p>&quot;I mean my friends go by the beach here and they're hanging out of the car like hounds like they've never seen (a breast) before. It's just new,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, men heading to Ontario's parks and beaches to catch a glimpse of exposed flesh may be disappointed.</p>
<p>Police said word-of-mouth traveled quickly when a topless woman was spotted, creating traffic jams on some beach roads, but &quot;confirmed sightings&quot; were few and far between.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we've been up and down the beach from one end to the other and there's not one incident, confirmed sighting,&quot;  said Ontario Provincial Police Sgt. Gary Burns.</p>
<p>Local authorities are scrambling to respond to public complaints.</p>
<p>Several municipalities have passed bylaws restricting toplessness to public beaches or parks -- not indoor pools or public buildings -- and the Ontario government has asked a federal-provincial legal committee to consider amending the federal Criminal Code to restrict the practice.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Canada's Justice Minister Anne McLellan said it would be difficult to reach a national consensus and it was up to local governments for now to deal with the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;I think a lot of Canadians feel the same way about men going topless, it's legal, but it's not particularly appealing, and you kinda wish the men would keep their shirts on as well,&quot; said the spokesman, Pierre Gratton.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
