<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="707979" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Fiery Moslem cleric launches Lebanon hunger revolt.</title>
<headline>Fiery Moslem cleric launches Lebanon hunger revolt.</headline>
<byline>Michael Georgy</byline>
<dateline>BAALBEK, Lebanon 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A fiery Shi'ite Moslem cleric launched a &quot;hunger revolt&quot; on Friday in Lebanon's eastern Bekaa Valley with a call for civil disobedience against the government.</p>
<p>More than 2,000 farmers, labourers and young men yelled and cheered in the main square of the ancient Bekaa town of Baalbek as Sheikh Sobhi Tufaili said three times: &quot;We declare civil disobedience.&quot;</p>
<p>They raised their fists in the air and some people shook sticks with bits of bread stuck on the end that symbolised what they say is widespread poverty and hunger in the region.</p>
<p>Bekaa Valley residents have suffered a heavy loss of income since Lebanon's 1975-90 civil war due to a government crackdown on illegal drugs crops which flourished there during the war and brought in hundreds of millions of dollars.</p>
<p>Tufaili accuses the government, which is spending billions of dollars on postwar reconstruction projects, of ignoring the region's plight and failing to support new crops and other measures to maintain living standards in the Bekaa.</p>
<p>Troops with armoured vehicles ringed Baalbek as Tufaili, who headed the pro-Iranian Hizbollah (Party of God) in the 1980s, arrived to launch the first stage of the revolt.</p>
<p>The crowd roared support as the fiery cleric in a black cloak and a white turban addressed them from a platform in front of Baalbek's serail (government house).</p>
<p>He told them to refuse to pay taxes and other charges and demanded that the government lower medical and education charges for Bekaa residents.</p>
<p>Tufaili says he will take his campaign further with a hunger march on Beirut to besiege the residences of President Elias Hrawi, Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri and parliament Speaker Nabih Berri if the government does not act effectively to alleviate poverty in the Bekaa.</p>
<p>Several people on the speakers' platform shouted &quot;Death to Hariri&quot; after Tufaili arrived in the square.</p>
<p>&quot;With our souls and blood we serve you, Tufaili,&quot; the crowd shouted.</p>
<p>&quot;People can't eat lunch and can't eat dinner. People are hungry. We will back the revolution and the sheikh (Tufaili) until we die,&quot; shouted a farmer addressing the crowd from a platform in front of Baalbek's government house.</p>
<p>The building was draped with a huge black cloth carrying the slogan in white letters: &quot;This is the grave of the criminal Lebanese authorities. God damn their soul.&quot;</p>
<p>Armed police stood on the roof and Lebanese army troops manned roadblocks ringing the town as busloads of Tufaili supporters drove in from other areas.</p>
<p>Only a handful of police armed with automatic rifles could be seen in the town itself. Streets leading to the main square were manned by young Tufaili militants with black bands round their foreheads. Some brandished black flags and sickles.</p>
<p>Hrawi threatened last month to prosecute Tufaili when he first announced his campaign.</p>
<p>However, the government later allotted emergency funding of 150 billion Lebanese pounds ($97 million) for Bekaa development and Interior Minister Michel al-Murr said the inaugural rally could go ahead so long as security was not endangered.</p>
<p>Baalbek has been a stronghold of Hizbollah since the movement's beginning in the early 1980s with the help of Iranian revolutionary guards. Many Western hostages kidnapped during the civil war by shadowy Moslem groups were believed to be held there.</p>
<p>Tufaili's campaign is widely seen as a challenge to the movement's leadership in Hizbollah's heartland.</p>
<p>He says the current Hizbollah leaders, who have several deputies in the Beirut parliament, are too soft. They have replied that although poverty is rife in the Bekaa Valley, Tufaili's fiery tactics are not the way to tackle the problem.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAALBEK, Lebanon"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
