<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70807" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Wockhardt forms new company.</title>
<headline>India's Wockhardt forms new company.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian pharmaceutical firm Wockhardt Ltd said it was forming a new company by merging two of its hospitals with the recently acquired company RR Medi Pharma Ltd.  </p>
<p>Wockhardt said in a statement that the merger of Medi Pharma's business with Wockhardt's hospitals would bring in a new synergy and help develop a comprehensive healthcare set-up for the benefit of its customers.</p>
<p>The new company will be called Wockhardt Healthcare Ltd., the statement said. R R Medi Pharma will issue fully-paid up equity shares to Wockhardt in exchange for its two hospitals at Bangalore and Calcutta.</p>
<p>&quot;The new set up will be formed on the basis of valuation of the hospital business to be made by the auditors of the company and the consideration for acquiring the business will be paid by issuing fully-paid up equity shares of the company,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>R R Medi Pharma, based in Madras, is a parenteral company that Wockhardt acquired last year.</p>
<p>Wockhardt said its vast marketing reach had since enabled R R medi Pharma to increase its sales 65 percent. R R Medi Pharma was able to fully utilise its production capacity and its cost of operations was significantly reduced, it said.</p>
<p>During the first five months of the current year -- April to August, 1996 -- its turnover recorded 27 percent growth, crossing the forty million-rupee mark, Wockhardt's statement said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay Newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
