<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708018" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton, Gore volunteered to call donors - LA Times.</title>
<headline>Clinton, Gore volunteered to call donors - LA Times.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton and Vice President Al Gore volunteered to make fund-raising calls seeking large donations late in 1995, the Los Angeles Times reported Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The disclosure raises new questions about the president's stated inability to remember whether he made telephone fund-raising pitches from the White House on behalf of the Democratic National Committee at a time when the Clinton-Gore team needed millions of dollars for early television advertising,&quot; the Times said.</p>
<p>The participation of Clinton and Gore in raising $187 million for last year's election was expected to be a focal point Tuesday when Senate hearings into Democratic fund-raising practices were to begin, the newspaper reported.</p>
<p>Senators were expected to seek information on whether Clinton and his aides asked wealthy Democrats for money from the White House.</p>
<p>Federal law prohibits officials from seeking campaign money on federal property.</p>
<p>The source for the Times story was described as &quot;an internal document, obtained Thursday.&quot;</p>
<p>The document was an electronic mail message from Karen Hancox, former deputy White House political director to Gore's scheduler, suggesting the president and vice president had volunteered to solicit campaign money, the newspaper reported.</p>
<p>Written in political jargon, it says:</p>
<p>&quot;The POTUS and VP offered (ON THEIR OWN) to make f r calls for the DNC.&quot;</p>
<p>POTUS is an acronym for President of the United States and f r stands for fund raising.</p>
<p>Hancox is one of 30 potential witnesses issued subpoenas to testify before the Senate committee.</p>
<p>In March, Gore received criticism after admitting that he asked for money in calls from his White House office. Gore said he was proud of what he had done and that he wouldn't do it any more.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
