<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708108" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French beet crop prospects look good - survey.</title>
<headline>French beet crop prospects look good - survey.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Heavy rain in May and June boosted French sugar beet growth and sharply improved crop prospects, planters said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Growing conditions lead us to be reasonably optimistic over yield prospects,&quot; an analyst for the French sugar beet federation told Reuters.</p>
<p>A campaign survey up to June 30 showed beet development was now five days ahead of an average year and eight days ahead of last year, he said. The survey will be officially released next week.</p>
<p>The survey showed that high moisture levels accelerated leaf and root growth. The number of beets per hectare was 101,000, in line with an average year.</p>
<p>Asked about prospects for the 1997/98 yield, the analyst said: &quot;At this stage last year we had fewer beets per hectare, the beets were less developed and we ended up with a final yield of nearly 10 tonnes. If all goes well this should be a minimum.&quot;</p>
<p>The survey showed cumulative rainfall between December 1 and June 30 reached 339 mm against 263 mm during the same period a year ago but still below the 30-year average of 390 mm.</p>
<p>Wet conditions were beneficial overall to the crops but freak hailstorms did some leaf damage. In the key Aisne producing region in the northeast two percent of the area suffered leaf damage, the analyst said.</p>
<p>But this should have no impact on final yields as the leaves had plenty of time to recover.</p>
<p>France produced 4.226 million tonnes of beet sugar last year.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5432</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
