<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708228" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Merger to create No.2 German insurer.</title>
<headline>Merger to create No.2 German insurer.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT, Germany 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Munich Re is gearing up to fuse its primary insurance units with Victoria Holding AG in a mega-merger that will create an insurance giant to rival market leader Allianz AG .</p>
<p>The deal, announced late Thursday, sent Munich Re's shares surging 10 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>Analysts said it was a good deal that will give Munich Re control of Victoria, a composite insurer that has been attracting foreign interest, without spending a single mark.</p>
<p>Under the plan, which has yet to be approved by shareholders and the German Cartel Office, Munich Re will merge its Hamburg-Mannheimer and DKV units with Victoria into a holding company, ERGO, of which it will have majority control.</p>
<p>Based in Duesseldorf, ERGO Versicherungsgruppe will have total premium income of 21 billion marks ($12 billion), more than 14 million customers, investments exceeding 100 billion marks ($57 billion) and annual profit of 380 million marks ($217 billion), based on combined 1996 results.</p>
<p>That will make it the second-largest insurer in Germany behind Allianz, Munich Re's Bavarian neighbour, which last year had global premium income of 74.6 billion marks ($42.6 billion).</p>
<p>The participants in the merger said they aimed to improve their positions at home and forge more European expansion. Existing brand names will be retained and the focus of the group will remain on personal lines.</p>
<p>&quot;The ERGO group will be excellently positioned in the German insurance market ... with a good base for expanding business in the rest of Europe,&quot; Victoria said, predicting above-average growth in sales and profits to come.</p>
<p>Munich Re currently owns 80 percent of Hamburg-Mannheimer and has an 18 percent direct stake in Victoria, as well as an indirect stake of 5.3 percent. It is expected to own between 55 and 60 percent of the merged group, pending valuations.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not buying anything new, no money is flowing, we are simply bundling existing shareholdings,&quot; a spokesman for Munich Re, or Muenchener Rueckversicherungs AG, said Friday.</p>
<p>Munich Re's shares surged 485 marks to 5,400 marks on the news and Allianz's shares advanced 7.5 percent to 396.20 marks, as hopes for further consolidation in the industry rose.</p>
<p>Analysts said the merger was an ideal blend of strengths in different segments of the insurance industry.</p>
<p>Victoria focuses on non-life business and includes Europe's leading legal protection insurer D.A.S., while life specialist Hamburg-Mannheimer includes DKV, the market leader in European private health insurance which Munich Re acquired last year.</p>
<p>The deal was also viewed as a sensible way for Munich Re to gain a stronger role in primary insurance without a costly outright takeover. Speculation had been rife for months in Germany that Victoria was poised to be sold to a foreign buyer.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a great solution,&quot; said Patrizia Novak, insurance analyst at Commerzbank AG in Frankfurt. &quot;It appears that Munich Re is getting a stronger position in primary insurance without actually having to spend.&quot;</p>
<p>Precise details of the deal have yet to be fixed. An external valuation must take place by October to establish the shares the companies will represent in the ERGO group and thus the extent of Munich Re's ownership.</p>
<p>The German Federal Cartel Office must also approve the plans. While Munich Re said it had not received any negative signals from authorities in preliminary talks, Victoria has warned that Allianz will potentially own a large chunk of the new company, which could cause problems.</p>
<p>Allianz owns 20 percent of Hamburg-Mannheimer, which would translate into a stake of about 10 percent of ERGO. Allianz said the merger could trigger a shift in its shareholding, but said it has no immediate plans for change.</p>
<p>&quot;Naturally this is a challenge,&quot; said an Allianz spokesman of the merger deal. Munich Re, a traditional ally of Allianz's with which it has a cross-shareholding deal, is widely thought to have discussed its plans with Allianz in advance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
