<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708231" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: European stocks end mixed, dollar recovers.</title>
<headline>European stocks end mixed, dollar recovers.</headline>
<byline>Medora Lee</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>European stocks closed mixed Friday despite new intra-day highs posted in London and Frankfurt and record closes in Zurich and Oslo.</p>
<p>The dollar recovered some of the losses it suffered on Thursday after expectations faded of an imminent Federal Reserve rate rise. But activity was thinned by the U.S. Independence Day holiday.</p>
<p>Gold tumbled below $325 per ounce to hit a 12-year low on fears of central bank liquidation as bullion loses its &quot;safe-haven&quot; status against turbulence in the global economy and as a hedge against inflation.</p>
<p>Prices dropped sharply after the Reserve Bank of Australia said Thursday it had sold 167 tons of gold from its reserves, reducing its holdings to 80 tons. Many analysts and dealers now see gold sliding to $300 or lower within the next couple of weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;If central banks are prowling around, there's no given level at which gold will settle,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>London's FTSE-100 index was volatile, opening lower, climbing to a record high at 4,879 and then dropping again to close in negative territory.</p>
<p>Traders attributed the swings to derivatives-related activity.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to tell how much of today's business was genuine trading and how much related to arbitrage positions in the derivatives,&quot; said Tim Huddart, Merrill Lynch UK equities strategist.</p>
<p>Exporters' stocks were London's biggest losers, suffering from worries that the pound's recent strength would cut into profits. A strong currency makes exports less competitive in world markets.</p>
<p>Germany's DAX index closed sharply higher, but off its record 3,945.68 reached early in the day.</p>
<p>Traders said shares were boosted by Wall Street's strong close overnight. The Dow Jones industrial average soared 100.43 points on Thursday to close at a record 7,895.81 after a smaller-than-expected rise in U.S. June payrolls confirmed moderating growth amid low inflation.</p>
<p>France's CAC-40 index ended slightly lower in sluggish trade, consolidating recent gains.</p>
<p>Swiss and Norwegian shares were more buoyant, each posting record high closes. Swiss stocks ended up 41.6 points at 5,846.50 and Norwegian stocks closed up 0.58 percent at the day's peak of 1,237.74.</p>
<p>Hong Kong stocks tumbled to a sharply lower close Friday as uncertainty about government plans to curb rising real estate prices rattled property stocks.</p>
<p>An initial rally of 123.79 points, following new record highs on Wall Street overnight, were quickly wiped out and the Hang Seng Index closed with a loss of 232.77 points, or 1.55 percent, at 14,822.97 after reaching a session low of 14,727.48.</p>
<p>The Tokyo stock market's benchmark Nikkei index ended below the 20,000 level, the first time it has done so since the end of May, depressed by news that construction firm Tokai Kogyo Co. Ltd decided to apply for court protection, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Nikkei average finished 153.41 points or 0.76 percent lower at 19,968.00. It last closed below 20,000 on May 27 at 19,889.89. During the session, it fell as low as 19,907.39.</p>
<p>Nikkei 225 September futures ended 260 points down at 19,910.</p>
<p>In currency markets, the dollar rebounded from session lows made after the U.S. unit slipped on Thursday on the soft U.S. jobs report. The dollar fell on perceptions the Federal Reserve would not have to raise U.S. rates at its next policy-making meeting in August to rein in growth and inflation.</p>
<p>The dollar's softness had lingered into early European trading on Friday, hitting a one-week low against the yen. But the currency subsequently found support above 113 yen and 1.75 marks.</p>
<p>In late trading, the dollar was within striking distance of a 40-month high against the mark. But with U.S. markets closed for a holiday, the dollar lacked momentum to pierce 1.7566.</p>
<p>The pound lingered just below its March 1991 high of 2.9665 against the mark. Sterling was helped by perceptions Britain will raise interest rates at next week's monetary meeting. The mark also weakened against the yen, falling to a near 23-month low before steadying at slightly higher levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing that will help the mark right now is the complete collapse of EMU (economic and monetary union),&quot; said Gerard Lyons, DKB chief economist. &quot;Given that looks very unlikely, mark/yen is a one-way bet.&quot;</p>
<p>EMU is seen hurting the mark because the single currency planned to replace participants' national currencies is expected to be softer than Germany's currency now.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
