<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708221" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Munich Re expects to own 55 to 60 pct of ERGO.</title>
<headline>Munich Re expects to own 55 to 60 pct of ERGO.</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reinsurance group Munich Re said on Friday it expected to hold a majority stake of 55 to 60 percent in ERGO Versicherungsgruppe AG, the insurance group it plans to create through the merger of its unit Hamburg-Mannheimer AG with Victoria Holding AG.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Munich Re contacted by Reuters said the merger had yet to be registered with the Federal Cartel Office but he added that preliminary talks with the office had not been negative.</p>
<p>Victoria Holding AG plans to merge with Hamburg-Mannheimer AG, which is 80 percent owned by Munich Re, in a move which will create Germany's second-largest direct insurer after Allianz AG. The plans were announced late on Thursday night.  </p>
<p>Munich Re owns an 18 percent direct stake in Victoria as well as an indirect stake of 5.3 percent.</p>
<p>The spokesman said that for Munich Re, the move meant that the swings which characterise the reinsurance business would be offset by the traditionally more stable direct insurance business.</p>
<p>ERGO would expand its business abroad but was not considering acquisitions, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Munich Re said the merger means that reinsurance and direct insurance will contribute approximately equally to its premium income.</p>
<p>ERGO will have total premium income of 21 billion marks, investments exceeding 100 billion marks, and annual profit of 380 million marks based on combined 1996 results.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
