<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708211" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares seek to stabilise after fresh record.</title>
<headline>German shares seek to stabilise after fresh record.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares sought to stabilise at fresh record highs after falling in pre-bourse IBIS computer dealings on Friday in bouts of profit-taking.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX, which reflects all-day computer dealings, was up 3.16 points at 3,942.89 after reaching another new all-time record high at 3,965.61 points on overnight Wall Street gains but the DAX slipped at times to losses in early trading.</p>
<p>The dollar falling below 1.75 marks in morning European dealings, along with U.S. financial markets being closed for a long holiday weekend, were factors that traders said prompted the early bouts of losses in the German share market.  </p>
<p>Among specific shares, insurance group Munich Re was up 207 marks at 5,230 marks after Victoria Holding AG and Munich Re unit Hamburg-Mannheimer AG said they plan to merge to create Germany's second largest insurer after Allianz AG.</p>
<p>Allianz shares were up 8.75 marks at 388.25 marks.</p>
<p>Most of the sectors that have shown strong growth this week, namely chemical and carmaker shares, posted declines.</p>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG was down 80 pfennigs at 104.35 marks after setting a new all-time high earlier this week at 105.45 marks.  </p>
<p>Chemical group Bayer AG was down 57 pfennigs at 71.25 marks and BASF AG was down 35 pfennigs at 66 marks, while sector leader Hoechst AG fell 1.20 marks to 79.10 marks.</p>
<p>Carmakers were also lower, with Volkswagen AG down 14 marks at 1,411 marks, while BMW AG was down 13.50 marks at 1,474 marks and Daimler-Benz AG was down 55 pfennigs at 145.30 marks.</p>
<p>Electronics group Siemens AG led early trading volumes, falling one mark to 103.20 marks.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
