<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708344" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: New Zealand debt futures rally, cash closes higher.</title>
<headline>New Zealand debt futures rally, cash closes higher.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>--------------(Snapshot at close)--------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close</p>
<p>FUTURES					  PHYSICAL YIELD (PCT)</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS (SEP) 92.94 (PREV 92.85)  90-DAYS  7.15 (PREV 7.15)</p>
<p>3-YR BONDS   (SEP) 93.20 (PREV 93.14)  02/01    6.77 (PREV 6.77)</p>
<p>10-YR BONDS  (SEP) 93.05 (PREV 92.95)  11/06    6.88 (PREV 6.96)</p>
<p>OVERNIGHT CASH  7.50 PCT  (PREV 6.55)  US 5-YR  6.20 (PREV 6.30)</p>
<p>NZD/USD    0.6769/76 (PREV 0.6755/62)  US 10-YR 6.31 (PREV 6.40)</p>
<p>TWI 66.25  (PREV 66.27)		    US 30-YR 6.62 (PREV 6.71)</p>
<p>RBNZ MCI  NZ/MCI 763.52 (PREV 762.77) Reuters NZ MCI -61 vs -62</p>
<p>--------------------------(JULY 4)-----------------------------</p>
<p>New Zealand bill and bond futures rallied on Friday while physical bills stayed put as cash rose by about a percentage point.</p>
<p>Initial strength in the bonds came via the U.S. market where treasuries rallied on a jobs report that suggested the Fed would not have to raise rates in the near-term future.</p>
<p>There was also strong overnight buying in the bonds and a shortage of available stock and borrowers.</p>
<p>&quot;There were really no sellers left,&quot; said a senior Wellington bond salesman.  </p>
<p>The 90-day bank bills were inhibited by the cash rising to 7.5 percent from 6.55 on Thursday and dealers expect negative carry in the short end to take its toll on the bills.</p>
<p>Although the Monetary Conditions Index did not budge and remains 12 points easier than the Reserve Bank's tolerance level, dealers said the bank should be happy at the higher cash rate and the mix of a lower currency and higher rates.</p>
<p>&quot;We're in the camp where they will leave things be and give things a little breathing space,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>But another dealer said the bank must still be close to having to tighten during an easing phase.  </p>
<p>An easing in Australia in the near future and a rate hike in Japan could strongly influence the Trade-Weighted Index.</p>
<p>&quot;There's enough potential volatility going forward from this for the bank to sit on their hands for a little while longer, but still watch the situation,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Traders expect next week's $300 million government bond tender, half of which will be the new 2009 stock, to be well supported.</p>
<p>Views from offshore on direction for New Zealand bonds and the currency are reported to be sharply divided.  </p>
<p>The focus will start to move next week to June CPI data where a lower than forecast number could see another rally in rates and a further test of the Reserve Bank's tolerance.</p>
<p>-- Simon Louisson, Wellington newsroom, 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
