<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708472" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan not considering interest rate rise now--EPA.</title>
<headline>Japan not considering interest rate rise now--EPA.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>No consideration is being given at the moment to raising Japan's interest rates, Economic Planning Agency (EPA) Vice Minister Shimpei Nukaya said on Friday.  </p>
<p>Asked whether he thought the Japanese economy was now able to withstand an interest rate rise, Nukaya said: &quot;At this moment, no consideration is being given at all to changing interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Nukaya added that although private capital investment was recovering, it would take more time to make a final judgment about the condition of non-manufacturers and smaller firms.</p>
<p>The vice minister also said the government's forthcoming monthly economic report would confirm once again that the Japanese economy was continuing a gradual recovery.  </p>
<p>He said the wording of the assessment of the economy in the report, expected to be issued next week, may change slightly from last month's report, as it will likely give an explanation of the impact of the sales tax rise in April.</p>
<p>Nukaya said it would be beneficial to confirm that the economy had sufficient underlying strength to overcome the negative effects of the tax rise.</p>
<p>The negative effects of the tax rise &quot;are unlikely to linger on and change the overall trend of the economic recovery&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>He said he believed the monthly report ought to touch on the issue of the negative effects of the tax rise as fresh data for May had been released and the spotlight was on the economy's performance during the April-June quarter.</p>
<p>He also said he would stay in his position as vice minister for another term. Senior Japanese bureaucrats' positions are reviewed around this time of year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
