<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="70856" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ultramar to merge with Diamond Shamrock.</title>
<headline>Ultramar to merge with Diamond Shamrock.</headline>
<dateline>GREENWICH, Conn. 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ultramar Corp., seeking to expand its oil refining and marketing operations into the Southwest, said on Monday it will merge with Diamond Shamrock Inc. in a stock deal worth about $975 million.</p>
<p>Ultramar said it will eliminate about 200 jobs, or about 1.2 percent of the combined company's workforce, as part of savings that are expected to total at least $75 million annually by 1998.</p>
<p>The new company, to be called Ultramar Diamond Shamrock Corp., will have revenues of more than $8 billion and be headquartered in San Antonio, Texas, where Shamrock is now based, the companies said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>Pete Smith, who will become the new company's chief financial officer, said the combination was expected to add about 7 percent to 8 percent to earnings immediately.</p>
<p>The company will become the third largest independent refiner and marketer in the country, said Jean Gaulin, chairman of Ultramar.</p>
<p>Ultramar, based in Greenwich, Conn., is one of the largest home heating oil companies in North America, primarily in the northeastern United States and eastern Canada. It also markets gasoline through 360 locations in California.</p>
<p>Diamond Shamrock is a leading refiner and marketer of petroleum products in the Southwest, including the largest-selling gasoline brand in Texas and the second largest in Colorado and New Mexico. It also takes in about $1 billion annually from convenience store merchandise.</p>
<p>The company also produces petrochemical feedstocks and operates the world's largest commercial natural gas liquids storage facility, serving the Texas Gulf Coast area.</p>
<p>&quot;We view it as positive -- and we liked both companies before the deal,&quot; said Jefferies &amp; Co. analyst Stephen Butz.</p>
<p>&quot;It is good for Ultramar to leverage Diamond's retail operation and their know-how on the merchandising side, while Ultramar is in the California market and they will get Diamond's strong presence in the Southwest,&quot; Butz said.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Diamond Shamrock stockholders will get 1.02 shares of Ultramar for each Shamrock share they own.</p>
<p>After the announcement, Diamond Shamrock's stock rose 37.5 cents to $30.625 on the New York Stock Exchange, where Ultramar gained $1.375 to $29.875.</p>
<p>Based on Ultramar's closing stock price, the deal would value Shamrock's 32 million shares at about $30.47 each and the whole deal would be worth about $975 million.</p>
<p>Diamond Shamrock Chairman, Chief Executive and President Roger Hemminghaus will become chairman and chief executive of the combined company.</p>
<p>Gaulin, chairman, chief executive and president of Ultramar, will become the new company's vice chairman, president and chief operating officer.</p>
<p>Gaulin will become Ultramar Diamond Shamrock's chief executive by the end of 1998 and will become chairman within three years thereafter, the companies said.</p>
<p>Gaulin said the company will now delay Ultramar's plans for building service stations in California and eastern Canada. The company had planned to spend about $50 million on new stations over three years. He said most of the delays will be in California.</p>
<p>Gaulin also said Ultramar was going ahead with plans to build about 600 convenience stores in Canada, noting that about 100 are in place.</p>
<p>Both chief executives said the merger grew out of the companies' exchange of information over the past few years under a technology exchange agreement. This was possible because of the lack of direct competition between the two companies, they explained.</p>
<p>The companies said the deal was expected to result in total charges of about $67 million which will be taken this year.</p>
<p>The boards of both companies have approved the merger, which is subject to shareholder and regulatory approval. The deal is expected to close at the end of this year, they said.</p>
<p>The companies said the merged company expects to pay an annual dividend of $1.10 per share, Ultramar's current payout.</p>
<p>The merger agreement also includes a $45 million backout fee to be paid by either company pulling out of the deal, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GREENWICH, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
