<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708755" id="root" date="1997-07-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: MOTORCYCLING-DOOHAN SEALS POLE AT SAN MARINO.</title>
<headline>MOTORCYCLING-DOOHAN SEALS POLE AT SAN MARINO.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>IMOLA, Italy 1997-07-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defending champion Michael Doohan took pole position for Sunday's San Marino 500cc motorcycling grand prix after Spain's Carlos Checa crashed during Saturday's final qualifying session.</p>
<p>Doohan had started the day in provisional second place behind Checa after a shaky session on Friday during which he almost smashed his Honda into a perimeter wall.</p>
<p>But the Australian dominated Saturday's qualifying, clocking one minute 48.997 seconds despite strong winds at Imola's recently modified 4.93 km circuit.</p>
<p>Checa, also riding a Honda, failed to improve on his best time from Friday of 1:49.374 and fell on his third lap. He lost control of his bike as he rounded a left-hand curve but managed to escape the crash unhurt.</p>
<p>The Spaniard, who was second behind Doohan at last weekend's Dutch grand prix, was able to remount and ride into the pits. He completed the session on his second choice bike.</p>
<p>&quot;When I was trying to improve my best lap time suddenly I lost the front (of the bike) and I crashed,&quot; he said. &quot;I think it was because of the wind and, even though I wasn't injured, my number one bike was damaged.</p>
<p>&quot;But second spot is very good... The crash didn't cause any physical problems. Tomorrow I'll take the first bike and try in it the warm-up before deciding which one to use.&quot;</p>
<p>Checa held onto second ahead of Australian Anthony Gobert, who also fell before putting Suzuki on the front row of the grid for the first time this season with a time of 1:49.652.</p>
<p>France's Olivier Jacque took pole position in the 250cc category ahead of Italy's defending champion Max Biaggi, who recovered from a fall in free practice to take second.</p>
<p>Biaggi, who was sent flying across the track when he clipped the back wheel of compatriot Luca Boscoscuro in the morning session, clocked 1:51.758 in the afternoon to edge out championship leader Ralf Waldmann, who failed to improve on his Friday best of 1:52.290.</p>
<p>Italian teenager Valentino Rossi destroyed the opposition in the 125cc category, qualifying in 1:58.886, more than half a second faster than the rest of the field.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SMARNO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IMOLA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
