<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708724" id="root" date="1997-07-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Mirror Group says H1 ad revenues rise.</title>
<headline>Mirror Group says H1 ad revenues rise.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British newspaper publisher Mirror Group Plc said on Friday its advertising revenues were comfortably ahead of the first half of last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Mirror Group's core business continues to perform satisfactorily and, as anticipated at the time of the AGM (in May), advertising revenues have strengthened following the general election and are now comfortably ahead of the first half of last year,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>Mirror, which has agreed to acquire Midland Independent Newspapers for 297 million stg, said its LIVE TV cable television channels had recorded &quot;impressive viewing and market share figures&quot; but it gave no details.</p>
<p>It said Newspaper Publishing losses continued to reduce. Mirror Group has a stake of around 46 percent in Newspaper Publishing, publisher of British national newspaper titles The Independent and The Independent on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;In the absence of unforeseen circumstances, the Mirror Group board remains confident about the outlook and expects a satisfactory outcome for the year,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
