<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708742" id="root" date="1997-07-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: MOTORCYCLING-SUPERBIKE CHAMPION CORSER QUITS GP TEAM.</title>
<headline>MOTORCYCLING-SUPERBIKE CHAMPION CORSER QUITS GP TEAM.</headline>
<dateline>IMOLA, Italy 1997-07-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>World superbike champion Troy Corser has quit his Yamaha Grand Prix team and started legal action against them for allegedly failing to meet the terms of his contract, Yamaha said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Corser, who moved into 500cc racing after winning the 1996 superbike title, said in a statement issued on Friday he would no longer race for the Yamaha World Championship Motorsports Team (WCM).</p>
<p>He said WCM did not have the budget to pay him &quot;reasonable renumeration&quot; for 1997.</p>
<p>Corser started the season with the Promotor Racing Team, which, because of financial difficulties, assigned its contracts to WCM after the Japanese Grand Prix in April.</p>
<p>The Australian said he had tried unsuccessfully to secure either the application by WCM of his original contract with Promotor or, alternatively, a new contract.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering this unacceptable situation, Troy Corser has decided not to race any further Grand Prix for the WCM Yamaha Team and has notified this decision officially to WCM, against which legal action is being instituted,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;Troy Corser is very sorry for Yamaha Motor Co...but believes everyone will understand that the present situation has been created exclusively by Promotor and WCM.&quot;</p>
<p>A Yamaha spokesman at Imola for Sunday's Grand Prix confirmed Corser's decision and told Reuters that Yamaha would take back the two bikes leased to WCM for Corser's use.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the dispute would not affect Corser's team mate Luca Cadalora of Italy who has reached a full agreement with WCM for the rest of the season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IMOLA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
