<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="708973" id="root" date="1997-07-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mars lander re-named after late space scientist Sagan.</title>
<headline>Mars lander re-named after late space scientist Sagan.</headline>
<dateline>PASADENA, Calif. 1997-07-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Pathfinder space vehicle that landed on Mars was re-named on Saturday the Carl Sagan Memorial Station, after the late space scientist.</p>
<p>&quot;Carl Sagan was a very unique individual who helped young and old alike to dream about the future and the possibilities it may hold,&quot; said Daniel Goldin, administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</p>
<p>&quot;Carl always liked to push the boundaries too, and the Mars Pathfinder mission, with its rover named Sojourner, clearly has done that,&quot; he said, announcing the re-naming of the craft that landed on Mars on Friday.</p>
<p>Sagan, a scientist and author who played a leading role in NASA's Mariner, Viking, Voyager and Galileo expeditions to other planets, died at the age of 62 last Dec. 20 -- 16 days after Pathfinder took off on its Mars expedition.</p>
<p>Talking of which, Goldin said: &quot;Its very first images contain an array of fascinating scientific questions that he (Sagan) would have loved to debate.</p>
<p>&quot;We will explore the area with his memory in mind.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PASADENA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
