<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709099" id="root" date="1997-07-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: BASEBALL-YANKEES CANCEL SIX-PLAYER TRADE WITH PADRES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-YANKEES CANCEL SIX-PLAYER TRADE WITH PADRES.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Yankees said they were calling off their six-player trade with the San Diego Padres on Saturday after slugging outfielder Greg Vaughn failed his physical examination.</p>
<p>The deal, in which the Padres sent Vaughn and two minor leaguers to the Yankees Friday night in exchange for left-hander Kenny Rogers, infielder Mariano Duncan and a minor-league pitcher, was contingent on Vaughn and Rogers passing their physicals.</p>
<p>Rogers, who underwent shoulder and elbow surgery after last year's World Series, was reportedly scheduled to be examined in San Diego on Sunday, while Vaughn was given a physical in New York on Saturday.</p>
<p>Vaughn has had surgery on his right shoulder three times, most recently after the 1994 season.</p>
<p>&quot;They knew this was part of the whole structure of the deal,&quot; said Yankees general manager Bob Watson in a telephone hook-up during New York's game Saturday against Toronto.</p>
<p>&quot;The players haven't passed the physical. He (Rogers) has to come back and join our bullpen.&quot;</p>
<p>The San Diego Padres released a statement following their 7-3 loss to the Los Angeles Dodgers, expressing surprise at the Yankees' decision.</p>
<p>&quot;The San Diego Padres and New York Yankees were both aware that two players in the proposed transaction -- Greg Vaughn and Kenny Rogers -- had undergone rotator cuff surgeries in the past.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the conclusion of the Padres medical staff that Vaughn does not have a physical condition that is likely to adversely affect his prospective ability to perform during the term of his contract. Thus, we are surprised by today's turn of events. We will continue to work to resolve the matter.&quot;</p>
<p>Vaughn, who turned 32 Thursday, is hitting just .224 with 10 homers and 24 RBI in 64 games. He had 41 home runs and 117 RBI in 145 games for Milwaukee and San Diego last season.</p>
<p>The Padres signed Vaughn to a three-year, $15 million contract in the off-season, but he has struggled most of the year and lost his starting left field job to Rickey Henderson.</p>
<p>Rogers, 32, is in the second year of a four-year, $20 million deal, but was relegated to long relief by the Yankees. Rogers is 4-4 with a 5.90 ERA in 17 games, and was bumped in the rotation in favour of Ramiro Mendoza.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
