<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709008" id="root" date="1997-07-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch rail minnow sees traffic boom in five years.</title>
<headline>Dutch rail minnow sees traffic boom in five years.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-07-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rail journeys in the Randstad conurbation of the western Netherlands can increase by 50 percent over five years with the introduction of fresh competition, Dutch railway market entrant Lovers said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe over five years there can be 50 percent more rail journeys generated by people getting out of their cars,&quot; Lovers Rail Beheer BV managing director Peter Sul said.</p>
<p>Lovers Rail on Friday announced CGEA, a unit of France's Compagnie Generale des Eaux, had taken a majority stake. Sul on Saturday confirmed that CGEA had 70 percent, with the two original Lovers rail partners holding 15 percent each.</p>
<p>Sul declined to give specific forecasts about traffic in the Randstad area, a tight grouping of the Netherlands' main cities of Amsterdam, Rotterdam, Utrecht and the Hague and populous secondary cities such as Haarlem and Leiden.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not giving any figures. We won't give any turnover rates from our business plans for competition reasons, it's part of our strategy,&quot; Sul said in an interview.</p>
<p>He said the sheer presence of a new operator would stimulate new traffic as people relished the opportunity to try a new carrier and vent their frustrations with current monopolist Nederlandse Spoorwegen, which the government wants to privatise.</p>
<p>&quot;People will come over from Nederlandse Spoorwegen (NS) because they're dissatisfied with the service,&quot; he said, also drawing a parallel to the growth in Dutch mobile phone business, which mushroomed when Libertel entered the market in 1995.</p>
<p>Lovers Rail's initial ambitions are relatively modest, with the firm aiming to run about 20-25 trains holding 400-600 passengers over routes in the Randtad with a staff of around 60 people, undercutting NS by better efficiency.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the pioneer phase. We have less overhead than the NS. When you look at the NS structure it's really overgrown,&quot; said Sul.</p>
<p>Lovers Rail, set up by a canal boat cruise firm, last year began the first private rail service in the Netherlands, running a beach service between Amsterdam and the North Sea coast over a disused stretch of track.</p>
<p>Earlier this week the firm was awarded two routes for operation from mid-1998 between Leiden and the Hague and Utrecht and Hilversum - competing with NS for high-volume traffic.</p>
<p>Sul acknowledged that Lovers was unlikely to grow to the point where it could dominate NS, which in 1996 logged a rise in passenger kilometres to 14.131 million from 13.977 million a year earlier, and made net profit of 105 million guilders.</p>
<p>&quot;Questions have been asked whether the small mouse Lovers will become a tiger with the support of CGEA. We will be an important player in the field but we won't be the tiger that takes everything over,&quot; said Sul. -- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
