<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709166" id="root" date="1997-07-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British Sunday business - July 6.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British Sunday business - July 6.</headline>
<text>
<p>PRESS DIGEST - British Business - 06 July 1997 This daily press summary is produced for Reuters by the Broadcast Monitoring Company, which is responsible for its contents. For further information on these articles or details of BMC's other international press and broadcast services call Simon McMillan on +44 (0)171 256 5130 or e-mail bmc.co@ft.com</p>
<p>SUNDAY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- TOMKINS IN U-TURN ON BUY BACKS</p>
<p>The chairman of Tomkins, Greg Hutchings, is likely to reverse the group's strategy and announce a 5 percent buy-back of the company's shares to boost its disappointing share price. Hutchings had been criticised in the City for defending the group's cash resources which he claimed were necessary to fund future acquisitions.</p>
<p>-- BANK PROBES POST-BUDGET TRADING LOSSES</p>
<p>The Bank of England is investigating the wild stockmarket movements last week ahead of the Labour government's first Budget. Some of the City's largest firms are thought to have made heavy losses because of the swing in the stockmarket and derivatives market.</p>
<p>-- BOLOGNA'S AIM TO SCORE IN LONDON</p>
<p>The Italian football club Bologna is set to become the first foreign football team to float on the London stockmarket. The club has appointed stockbroker Nomura to handle the 25m stg flotation.</p>
<p>-- BBA TO BUILD WAR CHEST WITH 250M DISPOSAL</p>
<p>The engineering group BBA is set to sell its specialist electrical division for up to 250m stg and use the money to expand its three remaining divisions - non-woven textiles, flight services and friction materials. BBA does not believe the specialist electrical division has sufficient growth potential.</p>
<p>-- NATWEST AND PRU IN TALKS</p>
<p>National Westminster Bank and the Prudential Corporation are rumoured to have had talks about a possible merger. The move follows speculation about a possible bid from rival Barclays Bank and the failed take-over talks with Abbey National AN.L. The City Takeover Panel refused to intervene last week after NatWest ask Barclays to clarify its intentions.</p>
<p>SUNDAY TIMES</p>
<p>-- GEC 'TO GROW MARCONI, HIVE OFF POWER, SELL PHONES'</p>
<p>This week GEC's managing director George Simpson will announce the sale of the power equipment and telecommunications arms as part of the group's long-awaited strategic review. The group is expected to report 1997 pre-tax profits of 1bn stg on Tuesday. GEC's defence and civil-electronics arm, Marconi, could be rapidly expanded.</p>
<p>-- TOMKINS PLANNING BUY-BACK OF SHARES</p>
<p>The chairman of Tomkins, Greg Hutchings, is likely to reverse the group's strategy and announce a 5 percent buy-back of the company's shares. Hutchings had been criticised in the City for defending the group's cash pile.</p>
<p>-- SOARING STERLING THREATENS JOBS</p>
<p>UK manufacturers are predicting redundancies and investment cut backs as sterling continues to rise. The Bank of England is expected to raise interest rates this week despite attempts by the Chancellor to dampen consumer demand in last week's Budget.</p>
<p>-- MURDOCH SAYS BSKYB IS 'OVERPRICED'</p>
<p>The chairman of News Corporation Rupert Murdoch has dismissed the recent falls in the share price of British Sky Boardcasting by saying they were overpriced. BSkyB was recently excluded from British Digital Broadcasting's successful bid for the terrestrial digital television licence by the Independent Television Commission.</p>
<p>-- CHICKENS LAY GOLDEN EGGS FOR ENERGY GROUP</p>
<p>The founding directors of Energy Power Resources are set to make millions when it offers City institutions the chance to invest in the business. The company pioneered the use of renewable energy and has 26 potential projects to generate power from poultry litter and household waste. Charterhouse has been appointed to raise 15m stg by selling half of the group's equity.</p>
<p>THE OBSERVER</p>
<p>-- INDUSTRY FEELS PRESSURE OF SOARING POUND</p>
<p>A survey by the Engineering Employers Federation this week is expected to reveal falling export orders because of the strong value of the pound. Firms are likely to cut back on recruitment as British industry's competitiveness is eroded by sterling.</p>
<p>-- BUDGET TAX CHANGES DEAL BLOW TO UNIONS' INCOME</p>
<p>Trade unions are set to lose one million pounds because of the Budget changes in the tax treatment of dividends on shares. Union staff will also have to pay extra contributions to pension funds because of the abolition of tax credits on dividends.</p>
<p>-- SIMPSON TO SIGNAL HUGE GEC SPIN-OFFS</p>
<p>GEC's managing director George Simpson is set to announce the sale of the power equipment and telecommunications arms this week as part of the firm's long-awaited strategic review. There has been growing speculation about a possible merger with British Aerospace.</p>
<p>-- AMERSHAM PLANS 500M STG SALE</p>
<p>Amersham International is set to sell 500m stg of assets following the completion of its billion pound merger with Norwegian health group Nycomed. The deal will create one of the world's leading supplier of diagnostic imaging agents.</p>
<p>-- WOOLWICH SET FOR 5.3BN STG FLOAT</p>
<p>There are rumours that the Woolwich building society could be the centre of a take-over bid from banking rivals such as Midland, NatWest or Lloyds TSB after it floats on the stockmarket on Monday.</p>
<p>INDEPENDENT ON SUNDAY</p>
<p>-- GRIM REAPER STALKS THE CITY</p>
<p>The London stockmarket is braced for a tidal wave of selling by pension funds after last week's Budget. Pension fund managers are considering whether to move some of their capital into gilts and properties away from shares after the tax credit on dividends was abolished.</p>
<p>-- BLUE CHIPS FACE 6BN STG PENSION HIT</p>
<p>The removal of ACT tax credits in the Budget will cost Britain's top 20 manufacturing companies at least 6bn stg to top up their employees pension funds. ICI expects to pay 330m stg over the next 10 years to top up its pension fund.</p>
<p>-- SHAREHOLDERS TO FEEL THE WINDFALL PAIN</p>
<p>Dividends are expected to fall in the privatised utility companies following the imposition of the 5.2bn stg windfall tax in last week's Budget. BG will announce its decision in September.</p>
<p>-- US BUYER AGREES COLLEAGUES DEAL</p>
<p>The troubled junk mail and print buying business Colleagues Group is set to announce an agreed takeover by a US company.</p>
<p>There had been rumours of a management buy-out after Colleagues market value fell from 26m to 15.5m stg after its flotation.</p>
<p>-- LEICESTER CITY JOINS MARKET</p>
<p>Leicester City football club is joining the stockmarket's junior Alternative Investment Market. The 24m stg deal has been broked by football financier Mike Edelson, a Manchester United FC director.</p>
<p>MAIL ON SUNDAY</p>
<p>-- HALIFAX TO PARTNER NATWEST ?</p>
<p>The latest speculation about a possible partner for the National Westminster Bank has centred on the Halifax. The former building society would allow NatWest to expand its retail operations. The government is unlikely to allow a take-over by Barclays because of fears over competition and possible job losses.</p>
<p>-- US GIANT EYES INVESTMENT BANKS</p>
<p>Wall Street stockbroker Smith Barney is thought to be considering a bid for the investment banking arms of Barclays or National Westminster. BZW and NatWest Markets are both struggling to compete in the global market.</p>
<p>-- GEC IN ITALIAN DEFENCE MERGER</p>
<p>GEC managing director George Simpson is set to announce the merger of GEC-Marconi with Alenia Difensa, the defence arm of Italian giant Finmeccanica. The UK and Italian governments are thought to be considering the impact on jobs and security before approving the move.</p>
<p>-- THREATS FEAR IN 4.5M STG BT CLASH</p>
<p>Businessman Derek Taylor has accused BT of intimidating him following his 4.5m stg legal action against chairman Iain Vallance and seven executives over a failed business venture. The comments were made in the specialist magazine Commercial Lawyer.</p>
<p>-- TOP BROKERS IN TROUBLE OVER LLOYD'S RESCUE</p>
<p>Sedgwick, Willis, Corroon, CE Heath, Jardine Lloyd Thompson and others could face huge bills for negligence or malpractice following last year's 3.2bn stg rescue of 34,000 Lloyd's investors. The Lloyd's Insurance Brokers' Committee has discovered that the indemnity clause agreed during the rescue may not cover brokers who did not pay their rescue contributions in full.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC on</p>
<p>    BMC +44-71-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
