<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709280" id="root" date="1997-07-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Commodities Roundup - July 7.</title>
<headline>Australian Commodities Roundup - July 7.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The drop in the price of gold in London to a 12 year low following the Reserve Bank's announcement early on Friday morning that it had sold 167 tonnes of gold dominated commodity markets on Friday.</p>
<p>New York markets were closed for the Fourth of July holiday.</p>
<p>GOLD</p>
<p>Gold's gradual pullback in recent months turned into a full-scale retreat on Friday as investors abandoned the traditional safe haven out of fear it was becoming just another asset for the world's central banks.</p>
<p>Bullion stabilised tenuously in morning European trade near a 12-year low below $325 an ounce as the full meaning of central bank sales from of one the world's leading producers took hold.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of Australia announced on Thursday it had sold 167 tonnes of gold to reduce its holdings to a much lower 80 tonnes, raising over $1.8 billion in the process.</p>
<p>Gold has been trending lower since peaking at $418 an ounce in February last year as investors -- and now, some believe, central banks -- shun it in favour of tantalising returns on booming global equity markets and other investments.</p>
<p>The slide accelerated this year on a wave of real, proposed and imagined sales from European central banks and other institutions such as the International Monetary Fund.</p>
<p>Despite the day's levelling off, analysts warn that the worst may yet be to come. &quot;It's a cascade effect now, a looking over of shoulders. These things aren't done in isolation, other central banks take note, and clearly not with a view to buy but with a view to sell,&quot; said bullion analyst Andy Smith of Union Bank of Switzerland.</p>
<p>METALS</p>
<p>Base metal trading remained sluggish during Friday's afternoon LME ring sessions, with most markets dampened by the U.S. Independence Day holiday.</p>
<p>The exception was lead, which raced to a close above $660 and a three-month high. Speculative buying partly underpinned the market, which was also catching up with zinc.</p>
<p>But there was also some belated consumer buying, as well as September tightness, traders said.</p>
<p>Last trade was at $664, up $25 from Thursday, with the close above $660 technically constructive.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, there was little to excite the market, and prices largely held around overnight levels with a late round of end-week covering positioning most metals in the plus column.</p>
<p>Copper was marooned just above $2,400, and will continue to focus on July date tightness in the short-term. The cash/threes spread narrowed slightly to around $140/150, while three months closed at $2,405.50 a tonne, up just $1.50.</p>
<p>Aluminium briefly fell under $1,600, but was rescued by some speculative support, and the market resided for the rest of the session just above $1,600. Last business was at $1,607. up $1.50.</p>
<p>Nickel prices also moved higher during the latter part of the day, moving up from the $6,900 level to close at $6,990, up $60.</p>
<p>Zinc spent the session consolidating after running up to 6-3/4 year highs on Thursday, with technicians seeing a further short-term downside correction taking place before the $1,500 level is challenged.</p>
<p>Last trade was at $1,470, down $4 from Thursday's kerb.</p>
<p>Tin inched higher in sluggish conditions, finishing at $5,550, up $20. Alloy was quoted at a stable $1,445/55 a tonne.</p>
<p>OIL</p>
<p>LONDON - World oil prices ticked lower on Friday, following through from Thursday's heavy slump as dealers took profits from gains early in the week.</p>
<p>Prices came under pressure as dealers gave the thumbs down to support from U.S. gasoline demand and saw brighter prospects for the resumption of Iraqi crude exports under the terms of the UN's food-for-oil deal.</p>
<p>North Sea Brent blend, the benchmark for international markets, closed 15 cents down at $18.07 a barrel after a 71 cent slide on Thursday.</p>
<p>But dealers said that oil prices showed no immediate sign of any further falls after Brent hit bottom in early June at $17.32 a barrel.</p>
<p>&quot;Until the market has firm proof Iraq is exporting again prices won't move far off $18,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>SUGAR</p>
<p>White sugar futures passed a slow day with prices in the most active positions trading within a 30 cents a tonne range.</p>
<p>Traders said that the current dearth of news from the physical market coupled with the absence of any lead from New York, closed for Independence Day, made for very quiet trading conditions.</p>
<p>At the close near August was trading at $319.20 a tonne, down $0.70 from Thursday, and total turnover was 444 lots.</p>
<p>With the New York market shut, the London market closed early at 1600 GMT.  </p>
<p>Last trades or bids for key Australian-interest commodities. Previous close in brackets. U.S. markets were closed on Friday.</p>
<p>LONDON</p>
<p>(LME official bid quotes)</p>
<p>Copper Grade A (LME cash official US$/tonne)     2557 (   2520)</p>
<p>Copper Grade A (LME 3-mth offiicial US$/tonne    2402 ( 2389.5)</p>
<p>Aluminium (LME cash official US$/tonne)	    1575 (   1589)</p>
<p>Aluminium (LME 3-mth official US$/tonne)	   1599 (   1612)</p>
<p>Lead (LME cash official US$/tonne)		    644 (    621)</p>
<p>Lead (LME 3-mth official US$/tonne)		   655 (  634.5)</p>
<p>Nickel (LME cash official US$/tonne)		 6820 (   6800)</p>
<p>Nickel (LME 3-mth official US$/tonne)		6915 (   6920)</p>
<p>Zinc High Grade (LME cash official US$/tonne)  1466.5 (   1448)</p>
<p>Zinc High Grade (LME 3-mth official US$/tonne    1475 (   1451)</p>
<p>Silver (spot fix USc/oz)			     454.75 (  464.5)</p>
<p>Antimony (US$/tonne bid)				 1975 (   1975)</p>
<p>Tantalite ore (US$/lb bid)				 26 (     26)</p>
<p>Platinum (stg/oz afternoon fix)		    250.65 ( 256.35)</p>
<p>Gold Bullion (US$/oz afternoon fix)		324.45 ( 332.15)</p>
<p>Raw sugar No.4 (stg/tonne last)		     159.9 (  163.1)</p>
<p>Wheat (LCE 2nd mth stg/tonne)			  81.5 (  84.25)</p>
<p>--Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
