<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709295" id="root" date="1997-07-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Prince no longer in power, Cambodia's Hun Sen says.</title>
<headline>Prince no longer in power, Cambodia's Hun Sen says.</headline>
<byline>Robert Birsel</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-07-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodian strongman Hun Sen declared on Sunday that his rival, Prince Norodom Ranariddh, was no longer prime minister, unilaterally ousting him from their shattered coalition government.</p>
<p>Hun Sen spoke in a radio broadcast after a day of heavy fighting on the streets of the capital Phnom Penh between his troops and those loyal to Ranariddh, son of King Sihanouk.</p>
<p>Hun Sen urged breakaway dissidents from Ranariddh's FUNCINPEC party to fill the prince's post of First Prime Minister. &quot;The government is ready to choose a new First Prime Minister,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The position of first prime minister is in FUNCINPEC's quota so let FUNCINPEC adopt a political figure,&quot; he said, adding that he did not want the post.</p>
<p>Fighting erupted between Hun Sen's forces and those answering to Ranariddh on Saturday and kept up through Sunday, killing at least 12 people and wounding more than 50.</p>
<p>The prince, whose party won a 1993 election organised by the United Nations, charged in a statement from Paris on Saturday that Hun Sen had launched a coup against him.</p>
<p>Cambodian radio controlled by Hun Sen later denied the accusation and said the fighting was directed against Khmer Rouge guerrilla infiltrators in the capital.</p>
<p>Ranariddh's exact whereabouts were not known but aides in Phnom Penh said he left the country on the eve of the fighting and was in France.</p>
<p>Hun Sen's forces captured FUNCINPEC party headquarters in central Phnom Penh and Ranariddh's residence in the heart of the city on Sunday.</p>
<p>By late in the day, Ranariddh's forces still held ground to the west of the city and their Tang Krasang military base near the airport.</p>
<p>A military analyst in Phnom Penh said he expected more fighting on Sunday night or on Monday when Hun Sen's forces attempted to take further FUNCINPEC positions.</p>
<p>Clashes in the Southeast Asian capital stopped as a curfew took effect at 8 p.m. (1300 GMT) on Sunday, though there was occasional gunfire later. The curfew lasts until 6 a.m. (2300 GMT).</p>
<p>Hun Sen said the situation was under control.</p>
<p>The two premiers had jointly headed an unstable coalition government formed after the U.N.-run election in 1993 which brought hopes of peace to the ravaged country after three decades of conflict inflamed by war in nearby Vietnam.</p>
<p>Last week, Hun Sen accused Ranariddh of illegally bringing Khmer Rouge defectors into Phnom Penh to bolster his forces. The first premier denied this.</p>
<p>The dreaded Maoist group, whose brutal 1975-79 rule resulted in the deaths of about one million people, has appeared to be disintegrating in recent months with the defection of key leaders and their soldiers.</p>
<p>Hun Sen was a fighter in Khmer Rouge-led forces in the 1970s before bolting to re-emerge as foreign minister and then prime minister after a 1978 Vietnamese invasion that toppled Cambodia's Maoist regime.</p>
<p>Shelling and small arms fire in Phnom Penh began before dawn on Sunday and continued sporadically through the day, spreading into the heart of Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>Among the casualties was a 38-year-old Japanese man who died after a rocket hit his house, a Foreign Ministry official in Tokyo said.</p>
<p>An official at one city hospital said medical supplies would start running out if fighting continued much longer.</p>
<p>Ranariddh's FUNCINPEC party headquarters and the French embassy next door were both heavily damaged by shellfire, officials said. No one was injured at the embassy.</p>
<p>Ranariddh's father, King Norodom Sihanouk, who has been undergoing medical treatment in Beijing, called on both sides to stop fighting and summoned the feuding co-premiers to the Chinese capital to hammer out a solution.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
