<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709228" id="root" date="1997-07-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's Yeltsin starts holiday in Karelia.</title>
<headline>Russia's Yeltsin starts holiday in Karelia.</headline>
<byline>Anatoly Verbin</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-07-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin started his holiday on Sunday at a lakeside state residence in the northwestern Russian region of Karelia, the Russian media said.</p>
<p>The Kremlin press service said it was not able to confirm the reports immediately.</p>
<p>&quot;Like you, I watched television news at 3 p.m. (1100 GMT) which said that the president's plane had landed at Petrozavodsk (capital of Karelia),&quot; a Kremlin spokesman said by telephone.</p>
<p>The Kremlin has stressed that Yeltsin's vacation was a planned one and was not linked to the state of health of the 66-year-old-leader who had a quintuple heart bypass operation last November and suffered double pneumonia in January.</p>
<p>It has not been officially announced how long Yeltsin would stay on holiday but Kremlin sources said it could last up to two months but Yeltsin intended to keep in close touch with his reformist government and senior ministers would report to him in person every week.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency said Yeltsin made no commet to local reporters at the airport and headed to the Shuyskaya Chupa pine-lined residence by a lake near Petrozavodsk, 180 km (112 miles) from the border with Finland.</p>
<p>The residence, labelled &quot;President Hotel&quot; by local journalists, had fishing facilities and an indoor tennis court, Tass said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no problems for the president with fishing,&quot; a local fishing official told Tass, adding Karelia had 62,000 lakes and 11,000 rivers.</p>
<p>Yeltsin is known to be a passionate fisherman and hunter and a doctor has said he complicated preparations for his heart surgery last year by relentless shooting at his residence near Moscow. The weapon's recoil affected his chest, the doctor said.</p>
<p>But a Karelian hunting official told Tass hunting for most types of the game was prohibited at this time of the year, but added wild boar was a possibility.</p>
<p>The Kremlin has announced that Yeltsin would spend only part of his holiday in Karelia. It did not say where he would go for the rest of his vacation but stressed he would not go to his once favourite Black Sea resort of Sochi.</p>
<p>In April Yeltsin cut short his holiday in Sochi and the Kremlin blamed bad weather though television pictures from the area showed sunshine at the time.</p>
<p>In previous years Yeltsin used to spend much of his time in Sochi swimming and playing tennis, something which he seems as yet unwilling to do after heart surgery.</p>
<p>Yeltsin returned to active work in February and has generally maintained a busy schedule, though every now and then he escapes to his country residences outside Moscow for a day or two where he works on documents, the Kremlin says.</p>
<p>During a number of foreign trips over recent months Yeltsin mostly appeared mentally alert but his physical performance seemed unsteady at times.</p>
<p>Tass said Yeltsin's wife Naina was with him but it was unclear if his younger daughter, Tatyana, was also with him.</p>
<p>Yeltsin named Tatyana, 37, his official adviser on image-making on June 30, triggering accusations of illegal nepotism from the opposition, which he ignored.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has scored a number of diplomatic successes over recent months and his main headache remains the economy.</p>
<p>He radically reshuffled the government under veteran Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin in March, putting liberals like first deputy prime ministers Anatoly Chubais and Boris Nemtsov, into key positions to boost reforms.</p>
<p>He told the Russian people on Friday the economy had finally turned the corner after years of industrial decline.</p>
<p>&quot;The breakthrough has already happened,&quot; Yeltsin declared in a radio address marking the first anniversary of his re-election for a second and final presidential term on July 3, 1996.</p>
<p>He clearly stunned Chubais, who is also Finance Minister, by demanding all huge wage arrears to public sector workers, such as teachers and doctors, to be paid within three months while the debt to the armed forces should be covered until September.</p>
<p>Chubais argued the deadline was too tight.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
