<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709326" id="root" date="1997-07-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Ramos sister endorsed as presidential bet.</title>
<headline>Ramos sister endorsed as presidential bet.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-07-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A faction of Philippine President Fidel Ramos's party on Sunday endorsed his sister, Senator Leticia Ramos-Shahani, as its candidate in the 1998 presidential elections, throwing the race for his successor wide open.</p>
<p>Shahani, a former diplomat, was the fifth senior member of the administration to declare her intention to run in the June 1998 polls.</p>
<p>The others are Vice-President and ex-movie star Joseph Estrada, Lower House Speaker Jose de Venecia, Defence Secretary Renato de Villa and Finance Secretary Roberto de Ocampo, who announced his bid on Saturday.</p>
<p>Estrada, who enjoys huge popular appeal, belongs to an opposition coalition. De Venecia, de Villa and de Ocampo are colleagues of Shahani in the administration's Lakas party.</p>
<p>They are among a dozen politicians who have expressed interest in the presidency.</p>
<p>Ramos is constitutionally barred from seeking re-election but a group of supporters has launched a signature campaign to scrap term limits on incumbent officials so he can also join the fray.</p>
<p>Shahani, addressing a meeting of the Lakas-Tao faction which backed her bid, pledged to pursue his brother's reform programme.</p>
<p>&quot;If we lose in the elections, all the achievements we have realised in the past five years will go to oblivion,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
