<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709321" id="root" date="1997-07-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Lull in Cambodia fighting as curfew takes effect.</title>
<headline>Lull in Cambodia fighting as curfew takes effect.</headline>
<byline>Katya Robinson</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-07-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fighting in the Cambodian capital appeared to have stopped late on Sunday as a curfew came into effect after a second day of heavy fighting between troops loyal to the country's rival prime ministers.</p>
<p>It was unclear whether this was just a temporary lull, or whether the battles were over for the night.</p>
<p>The Cambodian capital had been rocked by heavy fighting earlier in the day as forces under Second Prime Minister Hun Sen appeared to tighten their grip on the city.</p>
<p>Shelling and small arms fire began before dawn and continued sporadically through the day, spreading into the heart of Phnom Penh as Hun Sen's forces battled those of First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh.</p>
<p>There was heavy fighting around Ranariddh's official residence on Sunday evening and one city official said a white flag had been raised at the building. A military analyst said the prince's residence was not an important military target and the surrender of a handful of security men there was no major development. He said forces loyal to Ranariddh still controlled their main military facilities and he expected more fighting on Monday.</p>
<p>Ranariddh's FUNCINPEC party headquarters and the French embassy next door were both heavily damaged by shellfire, officials said.</p>
<p>By Sunday afternoon troops loyal to Hun Sen were moving through the city street by street as heavy fighting continued around pockets held by Ranariddh's men.</p>
<p>Military officials loyal to Hun Sen said they were demanding the surrender of Ranariddh's troops protecting some of his facilities. But Ranariddh's top military commander, General Nhiek Bun Chhay, vowed earlier that there would be no surrender.</p>
<p>At least 12 people had been killed and more than 50 wounded since the violence began, hospital sources and local news reports said. A 38-year old Japanese man died from his wounds after a rocket hit his house, a Foreign Ministry official in Tokyo said.</p>
<p>An official at one city hospital said medical supplies would start running out if the fighting continued much longer.</p>
<p>The heaviest fighting raged around key facilities under the control of forces loyal to Ranariddh, including a well-defended compound, a base near the international airport, Ranariddh's party headquarters and his residence -- all protected by his security men and troops.</p>
<p>A huge cloud of black smoke from a burning fuel station or factory hung over the city in the afternoon as several other buildings burned in the vicinity of the fighting.</p>
<p>Local authorities declared a curfew from 8 p.m. to 6 a.m. (1300 to 2300 GMT). The road to the airport remained closed and all flights in and out of the city were cancelled.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been hit by some heavy cannon,&quot; an official at the French embassy said. &quot;The ambassador's office and the office of the military attache were completely destroyed.&quot;</p>
<p>France is the former colonial power in Cambodia but there was no suggestion that the building had been deliberately targeted.</p>
<p>Fifteeen embassy staff, French and Cambodian, were in the embassy when it was hit but none was injured, he said. The embassy official said Hun Sen's troops appeared to have taken control of the FUNCINPEC headquarters next door.</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador Kenneth Quinn told reporters many soldiers loyal to Hun Sen were moving around his embassy. He said he had forcefully conveyed his concerns to officials from both sides.</p>
<p>&quot;People don't deserve to be caught up in fighting like this,&quot; Quinn said.</p>
<p>As booms echoed over the riverside city during the day, thousands of people laden with bundles of clothes, food and televisions streamed out of neighbourhoods where the fighting was heaviest. Many said they were leaving the city.</p>
<p>Markets opened briefly just after dawn and shoppers said prices had doubled overnight.</p>
<p>Hotels were packed with local residents, political officials and diplomats seeking refuge. Some hotel managers said they were running out of food.</p>
<p>Ranariddh said in a statement from Paris that Hun Sen was attempting a coup. Radio and television stations controlled by Hun Sen denied a coup was under way and urged people to remain calm as government troops were only fighting Khmer Rouge rebels.</p>
<p>Radio and television stations controlled by Ranariddh's party were off the air and most international and local telephone lines were down.</p>
<p>A member of Ranariddh's cabinet who was holed up at the prince's walled, city-centre compound told Reuters by telephone that the compound was under intermittent fire and one explosion had severely damaged one of the buildings there.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
