<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709459" id="root" date="1997-07-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: War criminals impede Bosnia peace - Shalikashvili.</title>
<headline>War criminals impede Bosnia peace - Shalikashvili.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alleged War criminals from the Bosnian conflict still at large present an obstacle to peace in the region and must be arrested, Gen. John Shalikashvili, chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;I would tell you that war criminals have been recognised from the very beginning as being a great impediment to the Dayton (peace) agreement,&quot; the general said in an interview on CNN's &quot;Late Edition.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;And so, it is terribly important that a way be found to apprehend these war criminals and bring them to justice,&quot; Shalikashvili said</p>
<p>But the general declined to say how accused war criminals should be apprehended or whether NATO should get involved, and he avoided commenting on reports on Sunday that the Central Intelligence Agency and U.S. Army Special Forces had prepared a plan to nab some alleged war criminals.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles Times on Sunday reported that the Special Forces and the CIA have prepared a secret plan to capture former Bosnian Serb President Radovan Karadzic.</p>
<p>Quoting U.S. intelligence sources, the Times said the plan was a response to Washington's growing concern that Karadzic was a major threat to long-term peace in former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>According to the newspaper, U.S. President Bill Clinton had not formally approved the plan and that he hoped increased diplomatic pressure would prompt the Bosnian Serb government to surrender Karadzic peacefully.</p>
<p>The newspaper said planning between Special Forces and the CIA Directorate of Operations began last year to capture Karadzic and take him to The Hague where he would be tried by the United Nations war crimes tribunal.</p>
<p>A senior Clinton Administration official said the continuing freedom of Karadzic and his former military commander, Gen. Ratko Mladic, was a huge obstacle to the peace process. &quot;They represent Serb aggression and the discredited notion of a Greater Serbia. They are cancerous and need to be removed,&quot; the official told the paper.</p>
<p>Karadzic and Mladic were indicted during the 1992-95 Bosnian war but no serious effort has been made to arrest them despite repeated pledges by Western powers that they would be put before the war crimes tribunal in The Hague.</p>
<p>The White House declined to confirm or deny the existence of the reported plan to kidnap Karadzic.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking at various issues related to the continued freedom of individuals who have been indicted for war crimes, including Karadzic and Mladic,&quot; White House spokesman David Johnson said. &quot;But for various reasons ... we're not going to be discussing them in detail.&quot;</p>
<p>He stressed Washington's belief the primary obligation for bringing the two to trial rested with the states of the former Yugoslavia that signed onto the 1995 Dayton peace accord.</p>
<p>Last week, U.S. State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns denied a Bosnian Serb television report that NATO peacekeepers had been ordered to arrest Karadzic and Mladic as indicted war criminals. Burns told reporters the television report was &quot;absolutely and unequivocally false&quot; and said there had been no change in the orders to NATO peacekeeping forces on their behaviour towards alleged war criminals.</p>
<p>The report, quoting unidentified Bosnian Serb security sources, said Karadzic and Mladic were to be arrested on sight and U.S. and British military units had been designated to capture them. Burns said the rule remained that if any troops &quot;encounter people who they know to be indicted war criminals they are to detain them for transfer to civilian authority so they may be arrested and then turned over to The Hague for prosecution.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
