<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709598" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Poor-credit homeowners unikely to refinance-NY Fed.</title>
<headline>Poor-credit homeowners unikely to refinance-NY Fed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Homeowners with poor credit histories and eroding equity are less likely to refinance their mortgages, even when interest rates fall and the financial incentive for refinancing appears strong, according to a Federal Reserve Bank of New York analysis in its latest &quot;Economic Policy Review.&quot;</p>
<p>The study found that &quot;credit- and/or equity-constrained homeowners are less sensitive to changes in interest rates because of their limited access to new credit, thereby short-circuiting one channel through which lower interest rates improve household cash flows and stimulate the economy.&quot; From an investment risk management perspective, the responsiveness of mortgage cash flows to interest rate changes will be significantly influenced by the credit and equity conditions of individual borrowers, the study concluded.</p>
<p>The results support other studies that have concluded that home equity strongly influences the probability of home refinancing.</p>
<p>&quot;Homeowners with poor credit histories and low equity positions cannot easily meet lenders' underwriting criteria, so they are often blocked from obtaining the replacement financing necessary to prepay their existing mortgage,&quot; according to the study.</p>
<p>The study also found, however, that a change in the overall lending environment has occurred over the past decade, probably because lenders have become more aggressive and borrowers more sophisticated.  An important element of increased lender aggressiveness has been the increase in sub-prime credit quality lending, the study concluded.</p>
<p>The status of loans on nearly 13,000 properties purchased in 19 counties across the United States between January 1984 and December 1994 were analyzed in the study.  Quantitative measures of individual homeowner credit histories and incorporate property and loan charateristics were used to determine the probability of refinancing.</p>
<p>(( -- U.S. Mortgage Unit, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
