<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709611" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Northrop Grumman debt holds on to tighter spreads.</title>
<headline>Northrop Grumman debt holds on to tighter spreads.</headline>
<byline>Nancy Leinfuss</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northrop Grumman Corp debt tightened another three basis points for a total of 18 basis points since news of its merger with aerospace giant Lockheed Martin Corp hit the market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Before news of the merger Northrop's debt was quoted 75 basis points bid, with no offer,&quot; said one high-grade trader. &quot;Since then, it has tightened substantially.&quot;</p>
<p>The defense contractor's 7.0 percent paper due 2006 was bid 57 basis points, narrowing further from Thursday's closing level of 60 basis points bid, traders said.  </p>
<p>No change was seen by market players in Lockheed Martin's seven-to-10-year debt after the merger news.</p>
<p>Last Thursday, the two firms announced their plans to merge in an $11.6 billion stock transaction.</p>
<p>The deal would allow Lockheed Martin to emerge as the sole remaining competitor of aerospace giant Boeing Co, which is in the process of buying McDonnell Douglass Corp, in a deal valued at $14 billion.  </p>
<p>After news of the merger, Moody's Investors Service Inc affirmed Lockheed Martin's A3 senior debt rating, while placing Northrop Grumman's Baa3 senior debt under review for a possible upgrade.</p>
<p>After reviewing the impact of the transaction, Moody's concluded that the technological synergies and expected cost savings from the combination would make Lockheed Martin a more competitive global defense contractor.</p>
<p>However, another credit rating agency, Standard &amp; Poor's, said it may cut Lockheed Martin's BBB-plus senior debt rating.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P also placed Northrop Grumman's BBB-minus senior debt rating under review for a possible upgrade.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically, you have two companies who were growing into their respective ratings,&quot; said Martin Knoblowitz, a defense analyst at S&amp;P, in response to the rating. &quot;Both made substantial debt-financed acquisitions during 1996, so they were not up to the metrics, so to speak, and now you have a potential merger on top of that.&quot;</p>
<p>If both firms were growing into their respective ratings, current cash flows were &quot;sub-par,&quot; making additional outflows necessary, but any such timing was unclear, Knoblowitz said.</p>
<p>&quot;That's what we have to discuss with them in terms of resolving Creditwatch,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, amid a quiet post-holiday trading session, market participants kept a watchful eye on the companies' bonds for any further movement as many players headed back from their extended holiday.</p>
<p>(( -- U.S. Corporate Bond Unit, 212-859-1675 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640047">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
