<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709794" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-MADDUX, JOHNSON NAMED ALL-STAR STARTING PITCHERS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-MADDUX, JOHNSON NAMED ALL-STAR STARTING PITCHERS.</headline>
<dateline>CLEVELAND, Ohio 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four-time Cy Young Award winner Greg Maddux of the Atlanta Braves and strikeout king Randy Johnson of the Seattle Mariners Monday were named starting pitchers for Tuesday's 68th All-Star Game.</p>
<p>Maddux, who has not pitched since throwing a masterful three-hit shutout against the New York Yankees last Wednesday, will be making his second All-Star start.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a tremendous honour,&quot; said Maddux, one of seven Braves in the All-Star Game. &quot;A lot of guys are having good years. I'm rested, I'm ready to pitch and I'm happy to be here.&quot;</p>
<p>Maddux is 11-3 with a 2.36 ERA in 18 starts with four complete games and two shutouts.</p>
<p>&quot;If it's possible, this guy is getting better,&quot; said Braves and National League All-Star manager Bobby Cox, who selected Maddux as the NL starter.</p>
<p>Yankees manager Joe Torre, who is managing the American League stars, could not select AL wins and ERA leader Roger Clemens of the Toronto Blue Jays as his starter because &quot;The Rocket&quot; pitched Sunday.</p>
<p>Clemens boasts a 13-3 record and a remarkable 1.69 ERA.</p>
<p>But Torre doesn't loose much by going with Johnson, who leads the majors with 168 strikeouts so far this season.</p>
<p>Johnson, who has not pitched since Friday at Anaheim, made his first All-Star start in 1995, but he called this selection more special after working his way back from off-season back surgery.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a form of reward for all the hard work it took to come back from the surgery,&quot; said Johnson. &quot;It's really special to be here.&quot;</p>
<p>Johnson, who is 12-2 with a 2.20 ERA in 18 starts this season, is the fourth Mariner in the AL starting lineup.</p>
<p>Outfielder Ken Griffey, who has missed the last two All-Star games due to injuries, was voted in by the fans along with shortstop Alex Rodriguez and designated hitter Edgar Martinez.</p>
<p>The All-Star festivities begin Monday at Jacobs Field with Workout Day, a warmup for fans that includes a celebrity softball game, batting practice and a home run hitting contest.</p>
<p>Larry Doby, who 50 years ago broke the American League &quot;color barrier&quot; with Cleveland shorly after Jackie Robinson became the first black player in the major leagues with the National League Brooklyn Dodgers, is the honorary AL captain.</p>
<p>Frank Robinson, a one-time manager of the Indians, has the distinction for the NL.</p>
<p>The National League has won the last three All-Star Games and leads the all-time series, 40-26-1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CLEVELAND, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
