<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709761" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-ROBBINS SHATTERS RECORD IN WINNING TOURNAMENT BY EIGHT.</title>
<headline>GOLF-ROBBINS SHATTERS RECORD IN WINNING TOURNAMENT BY EIGHT.</headline>
<dateline>SYLVANIA, Ohio 1997-07-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kelly Robbins shattered the tournament record Sunday in winning the $700,000 LPGA Jamie Farr Classic at the Highland Meadows golf Club by eight strokes.</p>
<p>Robbins, 27, shot her second successive four-under-par 67 for a 72-hole total of 19-under 265, eclipsing the mark of 15-under set by Brandie Burton in 1993 when this was a 54-hole event.</p>
<p>Tammie Green was a distant second at 11-under 273. Hall of Famer Nancy Lopez was nine strokes back at 274, followed by Vickie Odegard at 276 and Terry-Jo Myers and Karrie Webb of Australia at 277.</p>
<p>&quot;That's pretty good golf,&quot; Robbins said after taking her second tournament title of the season.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to go into the (U.S. Women's) Open on a good note,&quot; she said with a look ahead to next week's major championship in Cornelius, Oregon. &quot;It's good to see things come around.&quot;</p>
<p>Two-time defending U.S. Open champion Annika Sorenstam of Sweden took this week off.</p>
<p>Robbins's eight-stroke victory margin is the largest on the LPGA Tour since Liselotte Neumann won the 1996 Tournament of Champions by 11 shots.</p>
<p>Robbins, who also won the National Pro-Am in February, strung together four rounds of 67 or better, including a record-tying 64 Friday, to capture the $105,000 first prize. She remained third on the LPGA money list with $527,581.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYLVANIA, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
