<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="709935" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil edges up but Iraqi exports still loom large.</title>
<headline>Oil edges up but Iraqi exports still loom large.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices nudged tentatively higher on Monday after falls last week due to brighter prospects for the resumption of Iraqi oil exports.</p>
<p>But big gains are unlikely and many traders expect sideways trading over the next few days.</p>
<p>They say sluggish demand for gasoline, poor refinery margins and the prospect of Iraqi oil exports will cap any move higher.</p>
<p>&quot;Its as flat as a pancake,&quot; said Jim McLaren, oil trader at Rotterdam based Alimar BV.</p>
<p>North Sea Brent blend crude oil, the benchmark grade for international markets, was up seven cents at $18.13 a barrel at 1510 GMT on Monday.</p>
<p>Dealers watching the dripfeed of news on the likely timing of renewed Iraqi exports now are awaiting presentation of a new aid distribution plan by Iraq to U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan.</p>
<p>Iraq, which shipped some 660,000 barrels per day (bpd) under the first phase of the plan, could export nearer a million barrels daily to meet its permitted $2 billion of sales in the second phase.</p>
<p>The UN accord's renewal took effect on June 8 but Baghdad delayed restarting exports because it was unhappy with the cumbersome plan for distributing food and medicine.</p>
<p>But weighed against the bearish possibility of a resumption of Iraqi oil sales in August is the bullish prospect of a tighter than expected North Sea supply due to oilfield maintenance.</p>
<p>A Reuter survey of field operators last week found some 245,000 bpd will be lost to maintenance work.</p>
<p>Adding to the uncertain mix are a series of reports due out this week that could impact prices.</p>
<p>Dealers are awaiting a monthly oil market report from the International Energy Agency on Tuesday followed by oil stock data from the United States and Europe.</p>
<p>In particular, dealers fear that the market may  already be over anticipating winter demand for heating oil. In the United States distillate stocks, which include heating oil, are running some 17 percent above year ago levels while in Europe they are 6.6 percent above year ago levels.</p>
<p>Also, gasoline demand in the West has failed to make a big market impact this summer despite unexpected demand from Nigeria.</p>
<p>In Asia the market is also struggling to find buyers.</p>
<p>Crudes used for burning in power stations are likely to find buyers but other grades are less strong.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia slashed its crude oil prices to Asia last week and oil products are oversupplied and depressed.</p>
<p>Despite the soft tone in many areas of the market some traders remain confident that prices will manage to &quot;bridge the gap&quot; between seasonally weak summer demand and the pick up in autumn and winter.</p>
<p>&quot;There is always a tendency to underestimate demand in the oil markets,&quot; said a London based trader.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>					July 7    July 4</p>
<p>				    (1509 GMT)  (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent		   $18.22    $18.05</p>
<p>    IPE August Brent	    $18.13    $18.07</p>
<p>    NYMEX August light crude  $19.46	 -</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
