<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710046" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Randgold reviewing West Rand merger ratios.</title>
<headline>Randgold reviewing West Rand merger ratios.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African mining group Randgold and Exploration Co Ltd said on Monday that it was reviewing the ratios of the proposed merger between its Durban Roodepoort Ltd, Blyvooruitzicht Gold Mining Co Ltd and Buffelsfontein Gold Mines Ltd.  </p>
<p>It said that the review had been brought about by current market conditions and that shareholders should exercise caution in their dealings until a further announcmenet.</p>
<p>The bullion price last Thursday fell to 12-year lows after the Australian central bank announced it had sold off large amounts of its gold stocks.  </p>
<p>On May 26 Randgold announced that the merger of its three West Rand gold mines had been finalised and would involve a deal worth about 700 million rand.</p>
<p>Durban Deep was to be the vehicle for the merger and would swallow up Blyvoor and Buffels, creating a single mining company with a market capitalisation of around one billion rand.</p>
<p>Shareholders in Buffels and Blyvoor were offered 77 and 20 Durban Deep shares for every 100 shares held, involving the issue of 20.4 million new Durban Deep shares, valued at 519 million rand at the time of announcment.  </p>
<p>Blyvoor option holders were offered 20 new Durban Deep options for every 100 options held, resulting in the issue of 1.3 million new Durban Deep options valued at 13.5 million rand.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
