<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710180" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - July 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - July 7.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights of stories in the Bosnian press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DNEVNI AVAZ</p>
<p>- Interior minister and vice-minister of Mostar area Valentin Coric and Sefkija Dziho to sign an agreement on Monday on a joint police force, whose postponement was an obstacle for the functioning of the Moslem-Croat federal police. National balance of the border force will be made according to the 1991 census.</p>
<p>- Federal interior ministry says village Domislica, near town of Maglaj in central Bosnia, was shelled on June 6 from direction of nearby Croat-inhabited village of Mladosevica. No victims were reported, but the attackers threatened to kill some twenty Moslem refugees who returned to their homes in the village unless they leave.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Serb President Biljana Plavsic did not meet the Serb member of the Bosnian presidency Momcilo Krajisnik in Bijeljina on Sunday despite earlier announcements. But she met commander of the Bosnian Serb army Pero Colic in Banja Luka.</p>
<p>- Delegation of the European Association of National Parties, headed by Doris Pack, met on June 6 with the Party of Democratic Action (SDA) in Tuzla. Pack said the main goal of SDA should be to preserve Bosnia as the country of Moslems, Croats, Serbs and Jews, although &quot;I see nothing wrong if it is based on a preservation of Moslem culture and religion.&quot;</p>
<p>- Pack said the association intends to propose the SDA for now to be an observer in the association.</p>
<p>- The first international post-war horse race was held on Sunday at Butmir near Sarajevo.</p>
<p>OSLOBODJENJE</p>
<p>- Deputy interior minister in the federation Jozo Leutar has ruled out accepting policemen who are members of other national groups apart from Croats or Moslems, newspaper says. Leutar also disagreed with hiring Croats who were not members of the largest Croat political party, the Croatian Democratic Union (HDZ), until he was lobbied by the Roman Catholic Cardinal Vinko Puljic.</p>
<p>- Federation Interior Minister Mehmed Zilic says the Moslem side will allow vacancies in the ministry to be filled by Serbs as well. -- Sarajevo newsroom +387-71-663-864</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
