<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710167" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - July 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - July 7.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 7142 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Gyula Horn told a rural gathering on the weekend that all legal means must be utilized to ensure that Hungarian cropland is not obtained by foreign citizens.</p>
<p>- It would be too early to jump to conclusions regarding a State Audit Office report on the privatization of Budapest Bank that is not yet complete, prime ministerial press secretary Andras Hajdu said Saturday.</p>
<p>- Parliament will make a second attempt tomorrow to vote on a bill to transform the state news agency MTI into a shareholding company.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Gyula Horn has sent a questionnaire to 30,000 party members seeking their opinion on Socialist Party politicians and the party's election chances.</p>
<p>- Thousands of people attended a Workers' Party rally in Kerepesi cemetery Saturday to mark the 8th anniversary of the death of Hungary's communist-era leader Janos Kadar.</p>
<p>- Labor Minister Peter Kiss announced Friday that he intends to implement recommendations in a recent Organization of Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) report that the tax and social security burdens on Hungarian wages be decreased, along with an increase in the flexibility of wages and more emphasis on innovation in education and technology.</p>
<p>- The government has confirmed its intention to take up ECU 140 million in loans to improve the situation of the national railways MAV.</p>
<p>- The losing consortium in last Monday's TV broadcast tender has initiated a lawsuit challenging the ruling by the National Radio and Television Board (ORTT), and asked the court to forbid the signing of any contracts in the matter.</p>
<p>-Representatives of Germany's Deutsche Genossenschaftsbank (DG Bank) on Friday signed the contract for the bank's purchase of Takarekszovetkezeti Bank Rt.</p>
<p>- The voluntary pension fund of Hypo-Bank Rt. has received its operating license, executive director Myrtill Nadai announced Friday.</p>
<p>- European Gas Turbine of France has won the tender to provide gas turbines for the two supplementary power stations to be set up in Hungary by 1999.</p>
<p>- The textile and artificial leather manufacturer Graboplast Rt. has bought 88% of the wooden flooring maker Kecskemeti Parkettagyar Kft.</p>
<p>- A burst water main flooded part of the Castle District Sunday afternoon, damaging the foundations of buildings and opening up a 16 square-meter crater in a road surface.</p>
<p>- Two Israeli citizens, Kenig Haim and Asher Zvi Konig, removed a bronze relief functioning as an alms-box in the Kecskemet synagogue.</p>
<p>- The Customs and Finance Guard found 710 sheets of security paper used for printing Ft 5,000-notes in a printing press located in the northern outskirts of Budapest on Saturday.</p>
<p>VILAGGAZDASAG</p>
<p>- The nuclear power plant at Paks is planned to be enlarged by two blocks with production capacity of 600 MW each, Paks Atomeromu Rt. president Laszlo Marothy has announced.</p>
<p>MAGYAR NEMZET</p>
<p>- A memorial will be erected in Russia honoring the 148,000 Hungarian soldiers of the Hungarian 2nd Army who were killed in fighting in the Don bend in 1943.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
