<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710183" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - July 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - July 7.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in Serbian and Montenegrin press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories nor does it vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>			 -- S E R B I A --</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- Former Bosnian Serb President Radovan Karadzic has most contributed to convincing the Hague war crimes tribunal that indicted war criminals should be hunted down by showing there can be no peace in Bosnia while he remains in Pale, says Nasa Borba in a commentary.</p>
<p>- Some 40,000 people gathered at a rally in Banja Luka in support of Bosnian Serb President Biljana Plavsic over her rift with the rest of the leadership.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Serb Republic socialists have been instructed by Belgrade to follow a wait-and-see policy and join the winning camp in the Bosnian Serb conflict, a Bosnian Serb socialist party source said.</p>
<p>- Thousands of Belgraders flocked to the streets on Sunday night to celebrate Yugoslavia's victory at the European basketball championship in Barcelona.</p>
<p>- Former Vukovar mayor Slavko Dokmanovic was arrested by the international war crimes tribunal on the territory of Yugoslavia and not in Eastern Slavonia, Croatia, as claimed by the tribunal, says his attorney Toma Fila.</p>
<p>- Chairman of the Kosovo Albanian refugee commission condemned the recently signed agreement between Switzerland and Yugoslavia on the return of 12,500 Kosovo Albanians to Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- Ceremonies will be organised throughout Serbia to mark Jyly 7, Serbia Uprising Day.</p>
<p>- The wheat harvest will be completed according to plan and there will be enough wheat for domestic needs and for export, said Serbian Deputy Agriculture Minister Srboljub Stankovic.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVOSTI</p>
<p>- Rain slows down harvest in Yugoslavia's breadbasket region Vojvodina.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Serb President Biljana Plavsic deliberately and at a chosen moment, on orders from a foreign factor, began spreading the story about crime in the state leadership and police with the aim of creating chaos and ensuring speedy integration of the Bosnian Serb Republic in Bosnia-Herzegovina, Bosnian Serb Interior Minister Dragan Kijac says in interview.</p>
<p>- Will good companies rationally use finance from the Serbian Development Fund. Credits are very favourable, at four percent annual interst, but the problem for many companies is that they must be repaid in hard currency.</p>
<p>DEMOKRATIJA</p>
<p>- Socialists are still in the lead in Serbia with 27.5 percent, according to a telephone poll of 200 supbscribers conducted by the paper.</p>
<p>- Chances are small of current Montenegrin President Momir Bulatovic being nominated presidential candidate of Montenegro's ruling Democratic Party of Socialists, says republican prime minister Milo Djukanovic.</p>
<p>		   -- M O N T E N E G R O --</p>
<p>POBJEDA</p>
<p>- Fire is endangering Montenegro's Tara national park, a black pine forest on the UNESCO natural heritage list. -- Belgrade newsroom +381 11 311 4305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
