<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71014" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EMS/Mark feature.</title>
<headline>EMS/Mark feature.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>EMS FEATURE</p>
<p>By Mike Dolan</p>
<p>The weekend meeting of EU finance ministers (ECOFIN) was short of fresh initiatives but the level of consensus about monetary union starting in 1999 has bolstered the project's credibility in the markets, analysts said.</p>
<p>The immediate reaction to the upbeat ECOFIN was further sales of marks against its European satellite currencies, while agreement on a post-monetary union exchange rate mechanism buoyed those unlikely to be in the single-currency vanguard.</p>
<p>The French franc surged to a 3-1/2-month high at 3.3810 per mark while the European currency unit, which is widely believed will be convertible one-for-one with the new euro, surged to a 21-month high against the bruised German unit at 1.9042 marks.</p>
<p>The lira, which is unlikely to qualify for merger with the euro in 1999, was firm near two-month highs at 1004.30 per mark.</p>
<p>The mark regained some ground later during Monday's session but remained lower than Friday's close in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;The real difference is both the politicians and the market are poring over details and conditions of EMU when it happens, not if it happens,&quot; said Michael Burke, economist at Citibank.</p>
<p>As expected, the meeting reached agreement on a budgetary stability pact to come into effect after European economic and monetary union (EMU) starts in 1999 and a post-EMU ERM II.</p>
<p>These agreements were flagged in advance of the informal Dublin meeting and the fine details have yet to be released.</p>
<p>Yet, analysts said the lack of dissent at the meeting and the official comments left little doubt about the commitment to start EMU on time in 1999 among at least six countries.</p>
<p>&quot;The conclusions of the ECOFIN don't offer us any new cataclysmic development, but what the market is being squeezed into acknowledging is that the proposals are now credible and the details are practicable,&quot; said Joe Prendergast, foreign exchange strategist at U.S. investment house Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>For example, official comments that the ERM II would target the current broad 15 percent fluctuation bands would be seen as realistic by most players in the market, he said.</p>
<p>Even UK officials, traditionally the most sceptical EU delegation, acknowledged increased momentum toward EMU. &quot;I get the feeling ever more clearly that it is going to go ahead,&quot; said Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke on Saturday.</p>
<p>German finance minister Theo Waigel said he was satisfied with the agreement on the stability pact, crucial to convincing the German public of the stability of the new currency. &quot;We are following exactly the road we started on one year ago,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>France was similarly impressed by the level of agreement. &quot;This meeting has been one of the most productive we have attended,&quot; said Bank of France governor Jean-Claude Trichet.</p>
<p>Traders were wary of getting over-optimistic about a process that still has several hurdles to clear, but they said there was nothing from the weekend meeting to upset the applecart.</p>
<p>&quot;This looks like a sewn up deal and from a market point of view all the bad news seems to be factored out,&quot; said Henry Wilkes, senior trader at Switzerland's Bank Julius Baer.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a gnawing feeling everything just looks too rosy, but the stability pact is a big thing in its favour,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The passing of the bulk of the 1997 European budgets without major upset has further calmed the markets in recent weeks, with the French franc more than reversing its pre-budget jitters.</p>
<p>&quot;Credibility in EMU can be seen clearly in the Ecu's actual/theoretical spread, which has narrowed to 0.6 percent from close to one percent in recent weeks,&quot; said Prendergast at Merrill.</p>
<p>The Ecu spread measures the discount of market traded Ecu to its theoretical value derived from the constituent 12 EU currencies. The more likely EMU is perceived to be, the closer to par the spread moves and is often seen as a key barometer.</p>
<p>--London newsroom +44 171 542 6762</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
