<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710264" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: MEXICO DEBT OUTLOOK - Cetes rates to slide on vote.</title>
<headline>MEXICO DEBT OUTLOOK - Cetes rates to slide on vote.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kozak</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>With mid-term elections out of the way, Mexico's one-month Cetes rates are seen dropping as low as 18 percent as investors focus on Mexico's good economic performance, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;In our view in July the 28-day Cetes can go as low as 18 percent,&quot; said J.P. Morgan economist Alfredo Thorne.</p>
<p>Mexican markets, including money markets, rallied sharply after opening on Monday.  </p>
<p>Initial results for Sunday's elections showed the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI) lost control of the Chamber of Deputies after 68 years.</p>
<p>The PRI was, moreover, clearly beaten in the first race for Mexico City mayor this century by left-wing populist Cuauhtemoc Cardenas.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the election will have as much of an impact on them (rates) as much as basic economic fundamentals. Their (the government's) fiscal policies and the fact that inflation is coming down bode well for interest rates in the Cetes markets to come down,&quot; said one money market dealer, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>Investors began to discount the PRI setback even before the election. For example, the bellwether one-month Cetes rates fell 95 basis points to 19.95 percent at Banco de Mexico's primary auction last week, although some nervousness remained.  </p>
<p>&quot;Eighteen is probably not as low as the TIIE rate will go in this post-election period and again it is primarily on the assumption that the political risk is palpably lower than it was perceived to be as recently as last week,&quot; said Morgan Stanley Dean Witter economist Ernest &quot;Chip&quot; Brown.</p>
<p>The TIIE is a market-weighted average interbank rate that is revised each working day.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Cetes rates may go down more because you have the scarcity factor in Treasury bills as well unless the government is going to start selling more Cetes, which I think is unlikely,&quot; Brown said.  </p>
<p>With a few exceptions, the federal government has been selling 3.0 billion pesos worth of Cetes at its recent weekly auctions.</p>
<p>Economic fundamentals could derail the trend towards lower interest rates, however, as the year unfolds.</p>
<p>Inflationary pressures are seen building again after the traditionally weak summer price picture reverses itself, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sometime in August, the market will start discounting the inflation seasonality that starts in September,&quot; J.P. Morgan's Thorne said.</p>
<p>They are forecasting short-term interest rates will bounce up to 21 percent by the end of August.</p>
<p>&quot;Volatility is expected to return in late August, judging from the peso's projected weakening from 8.2 pesos per dollar in September to 8.6 pesos in December,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Dean Witter has also revised its peso outlook to 8.3 pesos per dollar at the end of December from a previously forecast 9.0 pesos per dollar at year end.</p>
<p>((-- Mexico City newsroom +525 728 9559))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
