<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710233" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Zedillo congratulates opposition victor in Mexico.</title>
<headline>Zedillo congratulates opposition victor in Mexico.</headline>
<byline>David Luhnow</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican President Ernesto Zedillo on Sunday night congratulated opposition leftist Cuauhtemoc Cardenas on winning the first mayoral election in Mexico's capital city.</p>
<p>While his Insitutional Revolutionary Party suffered its worst defeat since its founding in 1929, Zedillo praised the mid-term elections for making Mexico a full democracy after decades of single-party rule.</p>
<p>Cardenas, who broke with the PRI in 1987, claimed a landslide victory in one of the world's biggest cities, a post that until now was filled by presidential appointment.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to congratulate Mr. Cuauhtemoc Cardenas very sincerely for the triumph which he has obtained in the voting results so far available,&quot; a suprisingly content-looking Zedillo said in a live television address. &quot;I wish him the best success in his delicate task,&quot; he added, pledging federal government cooperation in running the city.</p>
<p>Preliminary results also showed the ruling party had lost control of the lower house of Congress for the first time in 68 years. But Zedillo said he was pleased the vote had shown Mexico could hold clean elections.</p>
<p>The PRI has been widely accused of using electoral fraud to hold on to power for nearly seven decades.</p>
<p>&quot;I have confidence that tomorrow all Mexicans will be able to say with pride and with unity that democracy has become institutionalized in our country,&quot; Zedillo said.</p>
<p>&quot;Mexico has made an definitive, irreversible and historic step towards democratic normality,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Zedillo said the fair election resulted from the political reforms he introduced allowing the Mexico City vote and creating an independent national electoral body.</p>
<p>Although violent incidents occurred in the southern state of Chiapas, Zedillo said the poll appeared clean enough to avoid the post-electoral bickering that has plagued past Mexican elections.</p>
<p>With half the ballots counted, the PRI had obtained 36.45 percent of the vote, short of the 42 percent needed under Mexican law to keep control of the lower house of Congress.</p>
<p>The conservative opposition National Action Party (PAN) had won 28.01 percent, and Cardenas' Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD) won a larger-than-expected 26.54 percent.</p>
<p>With 45.28 percent of returns counted in the Mexico City race, Cardenas held an unbeatable advantage of 47.51 percent support to 25.27 percent for Alfredo del Mazo, candidate of Zedillo's PRI.</p>
<p>Although likely to be at loggerheads over issues of economic policy, both men promised to work together to solve the city's woes of crime, pollution and unemployment.</p>
<p>Following Zedillo's national address, Cardenas praised the president in a victory speech to supporters, saying he had followed through on his promise of a clean election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
