<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710232" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexicans vote for change, PRI loses majority.</title>
<headline>Mexicans vote for change, PRI loses majority.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Brothers</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican voters eager for political change elected a left-wing opposition leader as mayor of their capital city on Sunday in a serious blow for Mexico's ruling party, official results showed.</p>
<p>Angered by economic crisis and revelations of corruption, voters also ended the Institutional Revolutionary Party's 68-year grip on the lower house of Congress, the preliminary results showed.</p>
<p>Cuauhtemoc Cardenas, who was expelled from the PRI in 1987 and has twice run unsuccessfully for president, was elected mayor of Mexico's sprawling metropolis in its first election.</p>
<p>With 56 percent of returns counted, Cardenas held an unbeatable lead of 47.7 percent of the votes over the PRI candidate, Alfredo del Mazo, who had 25.3 percent.</p>
<p>With 61 percent of the votes counted in the election for a new Chamber of Deputies, the Federal Electoral Institute said the PRI 36.74 percent, well short of 42 percent needed to maintain its majority under Mexican electoral rules.</p>
<p>The conservative National Action Party (PAN) had won 27.89 percent and Cardenas' PRD had a larger-than-expected 26.44 percent, the official results showed.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Zedillo congratulated Cardenas in a radio and television address to the nation and pledged the cooperation of the PRI government in running one of the world's largest cities.</p>
<p>Zedillo said the fair election was the result of political reforms he undertook after taking office in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;Mexico has taken a definitive, irreversible and historic step towards democratic normality,&quot; Zedillo said.</p>
<p>A beaming Cardenas appeared at the headquarters of his Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD) making victory signs after del Mazo conceded defeat and his supporters gathered in Mexico City's ancient Zocalo square to celebrate.</p>
<p>The PRI has won every presidential race and controlled both houses of Congress ever since it was founded in 1929.</p>
<p>Opposition parties benefited from discontent over a 30 percent decline in real wages since a severe financial crisis in 1995, and from revelations of corruption centering on the former presidency of Carlos Salinas.</p>
<p>Exit polls in the big northern industrial state of Nuevo Leon, where the PRI had claimed it was running neck and neck with the opposition, showed the PRI losing the governorship by a big margin to the right-wing National Action Party (PAN).</p>
<p>Most of the 52 million registered voters cast their ballots in peace, though some irregularities were reported at some of the 104,700 polling stations.</p>
<p>The worst problems came in the southern state of Chiapas, where mobs of angry Indians burned or destroyed dozens of polling booths and blocked roads.</p>
<p>Zapatista chief Subcommander Marcos called on the Indians last week to boycott the elections to protest against what he termed the &quot;militarization&quot; of the region by the government.</p>
<p>The Zapatistas led an armed uprising in Chiapas three years ago and peace talks have not settled the dispute.</p>
<p>All over the country, Mexicans appeared to be voting for change, either for the left-wing PRD or the right-wing PAN.</p>
<p>&quot;I prefer Cardenas. He can change the one-party system we have because he knows the system from the inside,&quot; said Eduardo Rios, a retired schoolteacher in Mexico City.</p>
<p>Industrial engineer Antonio Cruz, 35, said he chose the PAN. &quot;The PRI is a party that cannot be believed, there have been untold amounts of money stolen and they have achieved nothing for the country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cardenas, 63, the son of one of Mexico's most popular presidents, is expected to use the position of mayor as a platform for a third bid for the presidency in 2000.</p>
<p>Political reforms pushed through by Zedillo last year included holding elections for mayor of Mexico City's Federal District -- a post previously filled by a presidential nominee -- and providing generous public funding for all political parties, including the opposition.</p>
<p>The loss of a PRI majority in the lower house will have profound implications in a country where Congress has traditionally acted as a rubber stamp for the PRI president.</p>
<p>Voters also voted for a quarter of the Senate, but the PRI's majority there is so big it is not threatened.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
