<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710237" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Army chopper shot down by Colombian rebels, 29 dead.</title>
<headline>Army chopper shot down by Colombian rebels, 29 dead.</headline>
<byline>Karl Penhaul</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-07-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leftist rebels shot down an army helicopter over rugged terrain in an oil-producing region of eastern Colombia on Sunday, killing at least 25 soldiers and four civilians, the head of the army said.</p>
<p>The Russian-made Mi-17 chopper, contracted out by a civilian aviation company, was flying to a remote area in Arauca province after National Liberation Army (ELN) rebels dynamited a section of Colombia's largest oil pipeline earlier in the day, Gen. Manuel Jose Bonett said.</p>
<p>The pipeline serves the Cano Limon field operated by U.S. multinational Occidental Petroleum Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;The helicopter was taking a security force to the zone to assist pipeline repair work. It was hit in the air at a height of between 300 feet (100 metres) and 600 feet (200 metres), crashed to the ground and burst into flames,&quot; Bonett told a press conference.</p>
<p>He said ELN guerrillas had hidden in houses close to where they blew up the pipeline near the town of Arauquita and waited for the helicopter to arrive before emerging and firing on it.</p>
<p>Col. Roberto Trujillo, of the army's Second Division, said all the people on board -- one officer, two junior officers, 22 soldiers and four civilian crew members -- had died.</p>
<p>It is the highest death toll inflicted on the army by rebels since the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) raided a military base in southern Putumayo province last August, killing 31 soldiers and capturing 60 others.</p>
<p>The Cuban-inspired ELN is Colombia's second largest rebel army and was set up by radical Roman Catholic priests in 1966. It specialises in attacks on the country's key oil infrastructure.</p>
<p>Air and ground troops were sent to the area, believed to be heavily mined, to recover the dead. But one of the helicopters, a U.S.-made Blackhawk, itself came under fire as it tried to land close to the crash site before flying off unscathed, a military source said.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Gilberto Echeverri issued a statement condemning the incident &quot;not as an act of war but a terrorist attack&quot; and rejected suggestions that the downing of the helicopter was the latest sign of the guerrillas' fast-growing military capacity.</p>
<p>The attack on the pipeline, which pumps about 200,000 barrels of crude per day from Cano Limon to the Caribbean coast port of Covenas, was the 36th this year. Pumping operations were immediately halted, a spokesman for the state-run oil company Ecopetrol told Reuters.</p>
<p>Army top brass and defence experts have frequently condemned the military's use of Mi-17 helicopters for troop movements over areas where rebels operate. The craft are not equipped with heavy machine guns or rockets and are notoriously slow to manoeuvre.</p>
<p>In February of this year, 16 soldiers were gunned down by FARC rebels as they disembarked from an Mi-17 chopper near the mountain town of San Juanito a short distance east of the capital Bogota. In both cases the Mi-17s were flying into areas known to have a heavy guerrilla presence but neither had support from helicopter gunships.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
