<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710228" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexicans celebrate democracy as opposition win.</title>
<headline>Mexicans celebrate democracy as opposition win.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexicans celebrated the triumph of democracy on Monday after opposition parties won historic election victories, apparently laying to rest the ghost of past election frauds.</p>
<p>The man many Mexicans believe was cheated of the presidency in 1988 by fraud, veteran left-winger Cuauhtemoc Cardenas, trounced his opponents to become the first opposition mayor of Mexico's huge capital city, preliminary official results showed.</p>
<p>&quot;Brothers and sisters, this is the people's victory, all Mexicans have won,&quot; a smiling Cardenas told thousands of jubilant supporters jammed into Mexico City's historic Zocalo square, chanting and waving yellow flags of his Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD).</p>
<p>&quot;This is extraordinary,&quot; Sergio Aguayo, president of the non-governmental Civic Alliance which monitored the election, told Reuters. &quot;I have been fighting for democracy for 34 years and now I think we've achieved it.</p>
<p>With 85.44 percent of the votes counted, President Ernesto Zedillo's Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI) was also likely -- although not certain -- to lose its grip on the lower house of Mexico's congress.</p>
<p>Those figures gave the PRI 38.72 percent of the national vote, short of the 42.2 percent it needed for a majority under Mexico's complicated electoral system. The remainder was split almost evenly between the right-wing PAN, with 27.02 percent and Cardenas's left-wing PRD, with 25.65 percent.</p>
<p>Those results were good for the PRD, which nearly doubled its representation, but disappointing for the PAN, which had hoped to challenge the PRI as the biggest party in Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;The PRD will maintain the same policy of principles, we are not going to abandon that,&quot; PRD national leader Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador said. &quot;We are going to carry on defending the people's causes.&quot;</p>
<p>Smaller parties that fail to mount the two percent hurdle needed for representation will see their votes reassigned to the three big parties. This could benefit the PRI and analysts said it was still too early to be certain that the ruling party had lost control of the lower house of congress.</p>
<p>The PRI has held the presidency and a majority in both houses of congress ever since it was founded in 1929 and Mexicans hailed its Sunday election reverses as historic.</p>
<p>&quot;The elections of July 6 represent, perhaps, a new epoch in Mexican history,&quot; said Nobel laureate and writer Octavio Paz in a newspaper commentary on Monday. &quot;The true victor of this day has been the entire people of Mexico.&quot;</p>
<p>Financial markets rallied on news of an apparently unquestioned election result and the United States, Mexico's powerful neighbour and biggest trading partner, said it would accept the verdict of the Mexican voters.</p>
<p>The PRI also appeared to have lost for the first time the governorships of two important states to the PAN -- the northern industrial powerhouse of Nuevo Leon and the historic central state of Queretaro, where Mexico's 1917 constitution was agreed.</p>
<p>Party president Humberto Roque Villanueva put a brave face on the results, saying the PRI was still far ahead of either opposition party.</p>
<p>Commentators said the other big winner of the election night was President Ernesto Zedillo.</p>
<p>Although his party lost, Zedillo won praise all round for the democratic reforms he pushed through last year allowing for the first election of the Mexico City mayor since the 1920s and complete independence for the Federal Electoral Institute (IFE) which ran the polls.</p>
<p>&quot;Mexico has made an irreversible, definitive, historic step toward becoming a normal democracy,&quot; a smiling Zedillo said on national television shortly after the first results were announced.</p>
<p>Unusually for a top PRI official, Zedillo congratulated Cardenas &quot;very sincerely&quot; and wished him success in governing Mexico City, a huge metropolis beset by crime, pollution and corruption.</p>
<p>&quot;This was the big test for the President's commitment to democracy,&quot; said a presidential spokesman. &quot;He can't guarantee the triumph of his party but he did guarantee the triumph of democracy. That's why he was so satisfied.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
