<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710342" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: BRAZIL DEBT OUTLOOK - Banking on Eurobonds.</title>
<headline>BRAZIL DEBT OUTLOOK - Banking on Eurobonds.</headline>
<byline>John Miller</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banks, enticed by a recent change in financial regulations, are filling Brazil's new issue pipeline and are expected to remain the nation's most active players in the Eurobond primary market, debt watchers said.</p>
<p>* Banco Real said it will launch a $200 million two-tranche bond this week. The first tranche will be a $125 million three-year bond and the second will be a $75 million four-year bond. WestMerchant is lead managing the deal.  </p>
<p>Price talk on the three-year is 175-195 basis points over U.S. Treasuries. The four-year issue was expected to price at a spread of 190-210 bp.</p>
<p>* Banco BMG could also come to market this week with its $100 million eight-year bond, with puts and calls at three and five years. BankBoston is leading the deal.</p>
<p>* Bicbanco was said to be planning a $50 million eight-year bond for the week beginning July 21. ANZ is lead manager. The roadshow for that bond was expected to get under way this week.  </p>
<p>Brazilian banks recently benefitted by a Central Bank decision allowing them to park funds borrowed abroad in short-term high-yielding government securities prior to lending to Brazilian clients. The new rule, aimed at helping Brazil's current account financing needs, applies only to banks.</p>
<p>ALSO IN THE PRIMARY MARKET, the Republic of Brazil was seen launching its 10-year 200 million sterling bond soon via Barclays de Zoete Wedd and CS First Boston. Price talk puts the spread at about 250-275 bp over U.K. gilts.  </p>
<p>The bond was expected this week or next but may be delayed because of fears of rising U.K. interest rates on a recent budget agreement, traders said. lead manage its $200 million 10-year Eurobond. ABN AMRO also led Eletrobras 10 percent due 2004  ZUQU, which was priced in June 1996 at 338 bp over but has tightened to about 190 bp.</p>
<p>The Eletrobras bond was expected sometime in July.</p>
<p>IN SECONDARY TRADE, spreads on Brazilian paper widened by about five basis points on average, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Treasury market rallied but our prices stayed the same so spreads widened,&quot; said a Eurobond trader in Sao Paulo.</p>
<p>&quot;There is also too much paper in the market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((--Sao Paulo newsroom, 5511 248-5414))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
