<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710371" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ panel says cannot debate merits of RSS.</title>
<headline>NZ panel says cannot debate merits of RSS.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chairman of the panel set up to provide public information for a September referendum on compulsory superannuation said on Tuesday he hoped other groups would debate the merits of the scheme, though he could not.</p>
<p>Sir John Robertson admitted his Independent Referendum Panel's (IRP) terms of reference excluded explaining the current system or any alternatives to the Retirement Savings Scheme (RSS) launched in a White Paper on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The panel is not entering the debate on the pros and cons of the scheme. It is for somebody else, not us, to promote the contrary argument,&quot; Robertson told reporters.  </p>
<p>&quot;The panel is sensitive to current criticism that its budget is solely for information about the compulsory scheme and is not available for information about the staus quo...and it cannot move outside that task.&quot;</p>
<p>He said if voters asked his panel what would happen in the case of a &quot;no&quot; vote, he was not in a position to give information about alternatives.</p>
<p>He said he would not be repeating the government's White Paper contention that the current universal scheme was unsustainable, as this was an opinion.  </p>
<p>&quot;Any glosses which appear in the White Paper...we will not be putting forward as facts.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an opinion that the current scheme is unsustainable.&quot; Robertson said he hoped the Todd Taskforce update due at the end of July would provide information on the status quo which would help balance the debate, but the question of funding to promote the taskforce's findings was one that should be put to Social Welfare Minister Roger Sowry.  </p>
<p>The Todd Taskforce, headed by accountant Geoff Todd, was established by the government to advise it on retirement income issues, and was due to report on the state of the current universal scheme this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Todd has telegraphed there will be things in that (report) that don't agree with what was said yesterday (in the White Paper),&quot; Robertson, a former chief ombudsman, said.</p>
<p>The panel has a budget of NZ$5.65 million to publicise the proposed scheme, &quot;to provide enough factual information for those who want to, to make an informed vote&quot;.  </p>
<p>It would run a seven week multi-media campaign starting on July 28 and running until the middle of the September 5 to 26 postal voting period.</p>
<p>It would include 600 to 700 television advertisements, 253 full page adverts in daily newspapers and others in Sunday and community papers as well as a broad radio campaign targeting the young, Maori and Pacific Island voters.</p>
<p>A brochure and a summary, available in seven languages, would be sent to all households, but Robertson said a brochure being distributed during this week was a government document, not one prepared by the IRP.  </p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
