<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710395" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Gas Oil/Jet-Diesel plunge on low India award.</title>
<headline>Asia Gas Oil/Jet-Diesel plunge on low India award.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore middle distillate prices plunged on Monday with sellers offering at bargain levels on news that India bought meagre volumes of gas oil for August and cancelled its term kerosene and gas oil tenders, traders said.</p>
<p>They said India's lack of appetite in anticipation of lower prices would see the Middle East awashed with gas oil which could flow eastwards in August, coupled with talk that Iran had offered spot cargoes which intensified market jitters.  </p>
<p>State-owned Indian Oil Corp bought 165,000 barrels of gas oil in its August spot tender, lower than the expected 400,000 tonnes and even lower than the 855,000 tonnes it took for July.</p>
<p>Traders said refiners and those with barrels in tankage would sell at much lower levels this week as China was not expected to take much in the third quarter either.</p>
<p>Indonesia's projected import requirements of five million barrels for August delivery was seen as mildly supportive.</p>
<p>On Monday, three offers were seen at much lower levels of $21.30, the lowest since October 1995, but buyers remained at bay as they expect values to fall further.  </p>
<p>Two offers were seen at $21.30 per barrel for Jul 22-26 and July 27-31, signalling a cut in the contago, while a major offered at $159 per tonne ($21.35 per barrel) for July 22-26, all on a free-on-board basis.</p>
<p>Swaps gas oil already took a beating earlier on the Indian tender news with July being offered lower at $21.50, down sharply from Friday's $21.90/$22.00, while August lost 50 cents to be last quoted at $22.00/$22.10.</p>
<p>Physical jet fuel also suffered with two sellers emerging at low values of $23.60 and $23.70 per barrel for July 27-31 lifting, which also faced no bids.  </p>
<p>But traders were also hoping that prompt supplies could be soaked up marginally due to Shell's lower crude runs avaraging 49,000 tonnes per day for July, 10,000 below its normal capacity. Esso was also said to have cut runs by 10 percent about a week ago.</p>
<p>But traders said more output cuts were expected to help boost market levels.</p>
<p>(Prices in dollars per barrel)</p>
<p> MTH FOB SIN		     BUY/SELL     PREV BUY/SELL</p>
<p> JUN JET KEROSENE/KERO     23.40/23.70	 23.80/24.00</p>
<p> JUN GAS OIL 0.5% S	  21.10/21.40	 21.70/22.00</p>
<p> JUL JET/GAS OIL SWAPS	1.90/2.10	   1.90/2.10</p>
<p> JUL GAS OIL SWAPS	   21.50 sell	  21.90/22.00</p>
<p> AUG GAS OIL SWAPS	   22.00/22.10	 22.50/22.60</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
