<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710441" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China textile firm to launch 80 mln B share IPO.</title>
<headline>China textile firm to launch 80 mln B share IPO.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's Lutai Textile Co Ltd will make an initial public offering (IPO) of 80 million B shares later in July for listing in Shenzhen, lead domestic underwriter China Southern Securities said on Monday.</p>
<p>China's top securities authority, the China Securities Regulatory Commission, had already approved the IPO, said an official with the Shenzhen-based brokerage.</p>
<p>The pricing of the offer will give a 1997 prospective price earnings (P/E) ratio of eight to nine times, he said.</p>
<p>Nikko Securities (Asia) Co Ltd will be the international coordinator, the official told the Hong Kong-based newsletter China Securities Bulletin.</p>
<p>Lutai planned to use the share proceeds to expand its output of textile products which included cotton fabric, he said.</p>
<p>Based in Zibo city in eastern Jiangsu province, Lutai sold most of its products to Japan and South Korea, he said.</p>
<p>The official declined to provide the firm's earnings record, and Lutai officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Lutai had 80 million outstanding shares held by state institutions, the brokerage official said, adding the company was among the 33 mainland Chinese firms selected by Beijing to issue foreign currency B shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
