<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710505" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul shares end lower on consolidation.</title>
<headline>Seoul shares end lower on consolidation.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks closed lower on Monday as blue chips came under profit-taking after a rally last week and buying focused on a handful of theme-backed small shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like a technical correction. Most blue chips, seen overbought, faced profit-taking,&quot; said Lee Young-won, a broker at Daewoo Securities.</p>
<p>The composite index closed 5.73 points lower at 773.51.</p>
<p>&quot;Consolidation will continue in early Tuesday trading. But we may see stocks rebounding towards the close, albeit slightly,&quot; said Choo Hee-yup of Dongwon Securities.  </p>
<p>The stock index options trading opened on Monday for the first time, in slow mood.</p>
<p>The underlying contract for the At-The-Money (ATM) options, the spot month, began at 82.5. It would be set at 80.0 on Tuesday. The KOSPI 200 closed at 81.10, down from 81.94 on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Out-Of-The-Money (OTM) call options for the spot month totalled 1,332 contracts.</p>
<p>Brokers said overall sentiment was backed by improving economic fundamentals.  </p>
<p>The central bank said on Monday it lowered its forecast for this year's current account deficit to $17 billion from $18 billion.</p>
<p>Last week, South Korea said its trade account turned into a surplus in June, the first monthly trade surplus in 30 months.</p>
<p>Samsung Electronics dropped 1,500 won to 70,500, and POSCO 200 won to 65,300.</p>
<p>Shares in Hanil Leasing went limit-up on a local news report U.S. General Electric Capital Corp was trying to buy a 31.5 percent stake in the South Korean company, brokers said.</p>
<p>Hanil rose 620 won to its limit of 8,420.  </p>
<p>Trading volume totalled 38.44 million shares, compared with 29.89 million for Saturday's half-day trading.</p>
<p>Losers outpaced gainers 428 to 338 with 129 unchanged.</p>
<p>--KIM MYONG-HWAN (822) 727 5645</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
