<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710507" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel's Netanyahu defuses crisis.</title>
<headline>Israel's Netanyahu defuses crisis.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Burston</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli leader Benjamin Netanyahu quashed a cabinet crisis on Monday by putting his foreign minister in charge of Middle East peacemaking and denying hardliner Ariel Sharon control over the country's pursestrings.</p>
<p>In a surprise move, the prime minister chose lawyer and former Treasury director-general Yaacov Neeman as finance minister over former general Sharon, a champion of West Bank Jewish settlers.</p>
<p>Sharon, the national infrastructure minister, had been tipped for promotion to the post, vacant since Netanyahu's party rival Dan Meridor resigned last month in a power struggle with the prime minister over foreign exchange policy.</p>
<p>Sharon, 69, was noticeably silent after Netanyahu announced Neeman's appointment.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister David Levy, 59, had been apprehensive over Sharon encroaching on his status as coordinator of peace talks with the Palestinians and had threatened to bolt the government, leaving Netanyahu, 47, with a paper-thin majority in parliament.</p>
<p>Under an accord signed with Levy late on Monday, Netanyahu agreed Levy would be in charge of negotiations and &quot;advancing the peace process&quot;. All official meetings with the Palestinian Authority would be cleared with him in advance.</p>
<p>As it was Netanyahu was due to defeat three no-confidence motions in parliament introduced on Monday. Officials said he hoped to put Neeman's appointment to a vote on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>Investors, mindful of Sharon's reputation for lavish spending in defence of such pet projects as settlements, reacted with relief to the choice of Neeman.</p>
<p>&quot;It is good for the state of Israel that Ariel Sharon is not finance minister,&quot; economic commentator Sever Plotzker said. &quot;Ariel Sharon symbolised the Israel that closed itself off from the world, that did not integrate itself with it.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares traded on the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange notched a record high on Monday, but analysts said the gains were unconnected to the Neeman appointment. They said Sharon's nomination however would have sent the bourse skidding.</p>
<p>The prime minister, anxious to shore up support in his splintered Likud party, held talks on Monday with party legislators vying to be named science minister.</p>
<p>The post was vacated by Likud right-winger Benny Begin, son of the late Prime Minister Menachem Begin, in a spat with Netanyahu over Israel's withdrawal from most of the West Bank town of Hebron in January.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's office said the prime minister would consult &quot;from time to time&quot; with Sharon, Levy and Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai on political and military issues.</p>
<p>This was apparently a signal that the crisis over Sharon's demand to join Netanyahu's select &quot;kitchen cabinet&quot; on key policy issues had been defused. Levy had opposed the demand.</p>
<p>Neeman was likely to concern himself with microeconomic issues and leave to the Bank of Israel such macroeconomic spheres as foreign exchange rates, Plotzker said.</p>
<p>Neeman served Netanyahu briefly as justice minister, but his indictment last August on charges of obstructing justice and lying under oath forced him to leave the job after two months. A court cleared Neeman of the charges in May.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
