<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710519" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Finance offer could decide UAE plane order.</title>
<headline>Finance offer could decide UAE plane order.</headline>
<byline>Ashraf Fouad</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance packages could decide a fierce competition between three of the West's top warplane makers for a United Arab Emirates order worth up to $6 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;We are closer than ever before,&quot; an official UAE military source told Reuters on Monday of the deal, which has been on a roller coaster ride for more than two years.</p>
<p>&quot;The financial package will determine the deal. The best package will win because the (technical) capabilities on offer by the three manufacturers are very similar,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>American industry experts say some of the U.S. weapon systems on offer are superior to what European manufacturers are proposing to the UAE.</p>
<p>Industry sources said Abu Dhabi was considering innovative ways to finance the deal. The UAE military sources refused to give details of the favoured finance package but said new concepts were under consideration.</p>
<p>The market expected an announcement or a hint earlier this year but instead the oil-rich state reopened the competition bringing back the four-nation Eurofighter 2000 after Britain signed a defence pact with the UAE.</p>
<p>&quot;The announcement could come before the end of the year with actual signing of contracts starting in a year's time,&quot; said a UAE military source familiar with the deal which is crucial for Western makers seeking to secure funds for future development programmes in a shrinking market.</p>
<p>France's Dassault Aviation, offering its latest aircraft the Rafale, and Lockheed Martin Corp are the other two remaining contenders in the race for up to 80 long- range, strike aircraft.</p>
<p>The American offer faced trouble when the UAE felt promises to arm the F-16 warplanes with top-of-the-line radars, electronic warfare systems and smart weapons to meet air-to- ground and air superiority requirements were softened.</p>
<p>&quot;The Americans modified their offer. It includes HARM (High-Speed Anti-Radar Missiles), AMRAAM (Medium Range Air-to- Air Missile) and Standoff&quot; Land Attack Missiles (SLAM), said a senior UAE source.</p>
<p>The U.S. offer is facing fresh trouble with Arab states angered by what they see as Washington's failure to pressure Israel to revive Arab-Israeli peace talks.</p>
<p>The UAE could be embarrassed to finalise a deal with Lockheed if it won the competition, appearing to reward the United States at a time of growing Arab displeasure with Washington, Arab diplomats said.</p>
<p>Sources said French financial offers were not well-received</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
