<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710634" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Empty sailboat found off Massachusetts coast.</title>
<headline>Empty sailboat found off Massachusetts coast.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Coast Guard spotted a 26-foot sailboat adrift off the coast of Marblehead, Massachusetts early Monday and later found the boat's skipper floating in the ocean 13 miles away, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The unusual condition of the boat alerted the Coast Guard to take a closer look and it was discovered there was no one on board,&quot; Coast Guard Senior Chief Petty Officer Glenn Rosenholm said.</p>
<p>The boat's motor was still running and its sail was up when it was found early Monday. Hours later a Coast Guard vessel found the boat's skipper afloat three miles off the coast of Cohasset, Massachusetts, he said.</p>
<p>Angelica Savage, 36, of Wellesley, Massachusetts, was taken to a Coast Guard station in Hull where she was pronounced dead, Rosenholm said.</p>
<p>The skies were clear Sunday night when Savage sailed the sail boat Windsong from Boston Harbour, Coast Guard Petty Officer Jay Lipinski said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no small craft advisory out or anything like that,&quot; he said. &quot;We have no indication of what happened.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
