<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710658" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar falls against yen on bigger Japanese trade surplus.</title>
<headline>Dollar falls against yen on bigger Japanese trade surplus.</headline>
<byline>Alden Bentley</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar fell against the yen on Monday after Japan said its preliminary June trade surplus more than doubled from last year.</p>
<p>In early trading, the dollar tumbled almost two yen -- erasing mild overseas gains made during Friday's July 4th U.S. market holiday -- following a report that showed Japan's trade surplus rose 129 percent in the first 20 days of June in comparison with the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar is still weak against the yen,&quot; said Jeffrey Yu, a senior dealer at Sanwa Bank Ltd. &quot;The main factor is the big surplus reported overnight.&quot;</p>
<p>The decline gathered momemtum after a Japanese Ministry of Finance official said that the yen's pronounced decline against the dollar earlier this year continues to have an effect on Japan's exports, dealers said.</p>
<p>After dipping below 112 yen, the dollar steadied in New York, ending at 112.83 yen, compared with 113.82 at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>Japan's customs-cleared trade surplus rose to 453.20 billion yen, versus 197.65 billion yen last year, led by a 19 percent jump in exports.</p>
<p>The weak yen affects Japan's surplus, chiefly by making its exports less expensive overseas. As recently as 1995, Japan's huge trade surpluses strained its relations with the United States and the dollar tumbled to a record low under 80 yen.</p>
<p>The yen's buoyancy could weigh on the dollar through midweek, said traders, anticipating the release at that time of a much more comprehensive Japanese trade report that is expected to reinforce the picture of a swelling surplus.</p>
<p>The pressure on the dollar &quot;is not over,&quot; said Bob Near, a vice president of corporate foreign exchange at Bank of New York. &quot;We have to wait until Tuesday night/Wednesday morning when they get the current account from May.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar also declined against the mark as selling against the yen spilled over.</p>
<p>The mark got a lift in Europe as political pressure mounted on Bonn to delay the planned 1999 launch of Europe's single currency, the euro.</p>
<p>Any postponement of monetary union is expected to strengthen the mark by leaving intace its status as Europe's paramount currency for a while longer.</p>
<p>On Monday the Financial Times newspaper reported that Edmund Stoiber, prime minister of Bavaria and a member of the Christian Social Union led by Finance Minister Theo Waigel, called for a &quot;controlled delay&quot; to the euro.</p>
<p>Also pressuring the dollar was a jump in the mark against the pound after Britain said its industrial output declined 1.1 percent in May, the biggest drop since June 1993.</p>
<p>After falling more than a pfennig, the dollar trimmed its losses, ending at 1.7530 marks, down a touch from 1.7535 on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;People just got a little overzealous about that Financial Times article,&quot; said Alfonso Alejo, manager of corporate foreign exchange at Sakura Bank Limited.</p>
<p>In other trading, the dollar fell to 1.4612 Swiss francs, from 1.4692 Swiss on Thursday. It rose to Canadian $1.3788 from C$1.3736. The pound fell to $1.6903 from $1.6915.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
