<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71080" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WORLD BONDS - Hard to lose on EMU convergence plays.</title>
<headline>WORLD BONDS - Hard to lose on EMU convergence plays.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Thorpe</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>European convergence plays should be part of every bond investor's portfolio after this weekend's meeting of European finance officials, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>The meeting gave a single European currency a major boost and will drive the bonds of high-yielding countries like Italy, Sweden and Spain closer still to the European core.</p>
<p>Investors would be unwise to buck the trend, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though it looks an expensive game, it's still the only real game to play for outperformance in Europe,&quot; said David Brown, chief European economist at Bear Stearns in London.</p>
<p>The weekend gathering of finance ministers and central bankers at Dublin Castle brought European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) a big step closer to reality, anlaysts said.</p>
<p>Not only did finance ministers give their political commitment to a single currency starting in 1999, but they also began to hammer out the mechanics.</p>
<p>Ministers agreed a stability pact designed to ensure fiscal discipline once EMU begins, a new exchange rate mechanism (ERM II) linking the euro to those outside, and greater legal certainty for banks and businesses running up to 1999.</p>
<p>The meeting crowned a week of supportive developments for convergence trades, Brown said.</p>
<p>The Netherlands, France, and Sweden all presented 1997 budgets designed to bring their deficits to within the three percent deficit-to-GDP target required under EMU.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the French franc confirmed its recovery after the pre-budget bruising it had suffered since August and the mark continued to retreat on the other European crosses, Brown said.</p>
<p>&quot;The litmus test to the health of convergence near-term really comes from the franc,&quot; Brown said. &quot;The fact that it quite clearly got itself out of jail last week...has given another reassuring nudge to sentiment in Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>The mark hit a three-and-half-month low against the franc on Monday at 3.3845/50 on the back of the weekend's negotiations.</p>
<p>With European interest rate unlikely to move dramatically higher any time soon, there is little to lose, analysts said.</p>
<p>Brown forecast the spread between 10-year Italian and German bond yields will shrink to 225 basis points by the end of 1996 from 283 currently, the Spanish/German gap to 150 from 185 and the Swedish/German gap to under 100 from 147.</p>
<p>Juli Collins-Thompson, economist at Yamaichi International in London, said Italian bonds faced a potentially tense week.</p>
<p>September inflation data due out in the next two days would be supportive, but the 1997 budget -- expected by the end of the week -- may cause problems. The Communist Refoundation Party was expected to fight proposed cuts in health and pension spending.</p>
<p>&quot;(The market) has priced in an awful lot of good news and if we see any sort of resurgence of political problems the market will correct,&quot; said Collins-Thompson.</p>
<p>She forecast the Italian/German spread will widen to 330 basis points in the short-term but saw 250 by next year.</p>
<p>Adrian Owens, European economist at Julius Baer Investments, said British gilts -- not widely regarded as a convergence candidates -- offer value at their current 180 basis points.</p>
<p>&quot;If we get a Labour victory at the next election and they decide to move ahead...then of course the UK yield is going to move in sharply,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also said for investors wishing to remain within the European core, there was value to be had at short ends.</p>
<p>The yield spread between two-year French and German bonds is currently trading at 48 basis points.</p>
<p>&quot;If you think EMU is going to go ahead in two years' time, there's a chance that spread will come down to zero,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>More tantalising, however, was the Italian/German two-year spread, currently at 438 basis points and set to shrivel as Italian interest rate cuts eventually come through, he said.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
