<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="710892" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - July 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - July 7.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Bangladesh press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE DAILY STAR</p>
<p>Security for President Shahabuddin Ahmed and Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina may be tighthened further, following recent recovery of a smuggled rocket launcher.</p>
<p>Opposition leader Begum Khaleda Zia on Sunday criticised a section of intellectuals for saying that Bangladesh did not require army.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>Bangladesh parliament on Monday unanimously adopted a resolution condemning printing and publishing of &quot;obscene and blasphemous posters&quot; on the holy Quran and the prophet in the occupied territory of Palestine.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina returned home late on Sunday after a six-day official trip to Japan.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGLADESH OBSERVER</p>
<p>A contingent of 21 army personnel from Bosnia is due to arrive in Dhaka shortly to receive training from Bangladesh Military Academy.</p>
<p>Some 38 ships remained stranded in the jetty and outer anchorage of the Chittagong Port as the strike by dock workers continued for the fourth consecutive day on Sunday.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL EXPRESS</p>
<p>Export earnings from major items, including readymade garments, leather and frozen foods, fell short of their targets during the last fiscal year (July'96-June'97).</p>
<p>The imposition of import surcharge and VAT on computers at both retail and wholesale level would hit hard the growth of computer know-how, Bangladesh Computer Society said. REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
