<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71088" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Coffee producers and consumers meet, ACPC follows.</title>
<headline>Coffee producers and consumers meet, ACPC follows.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Coffee Organization (ICO) on Monday began a week-long meeting of producers and consumers with technical and practical issues firmly on the agenda.</p>
<p>The ICO, which groups 58 world consumers and producers, kicked off its meeting with an introductory Council session and key issues this week will centre on coffee promotion and ICO-backed projects.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be some interesting technical presentations. And there will be discussions of various projects,&quot; said ICO spokesman Pablo Dubois said.</p>
<p>The Association of Coffee Producing Countries (ACPC), representing some 80 percent of world output, will hold a meeting of its technical group on Friday and a full Council meeting on Saturday.</p>
<p>ACPC Secretary General Roberio Oliviera said the technical group on Friday will analyse figures for the group's 1995/96 export programme and figures for the first two months of the group's 1996/97 programme.</p>
<p>The ACPC last met in May when it agreed a new plan to limit green coffee exports from its 14 members to 53.5 million 60-kg bags in the year to June 1997 against 48.9 million in 1995/96.</p>
<p>In May Robusta coffee futures were trading at $1,970 a tonne, but have since slipped to their lowest level in over two years at $1,475 a tonne.</p>
<p>When asked if the ACPC was concerned about recent price falls, Oliviera said, &quot;We are always concerned about the price evolution, especially when prices fall. We will analyse the market situation -- it is on the agenda,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But traders said they are not expecting fireworks.</p>
<p>&quot;The Association will contemplate the effectiveness of last year's and this year's export plans, so nothing substantial is expected to emerge from this gathering,&quot; broker GNI said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the ICO is expected to present its own analysis of the market situation.</p>
<p>Consumer delegates said they would welcome a presentation on the world market situation by ICO executive director, Celsius Lodder.</p>
<p>During the ICO's May meeting, Lodder did not draft an official document analysing the market nor issue market-sensitive forecasts which angered some delegates.</p>
<p>&quot;It is crucial for an international commodity organisation to discuss the market situation,&quot; said one delegate.</p>
<p>Dubois said other presentations this week will include a report on wilt disease in Zaire, and a presentationn by a LIFFE official on the robusta coffee contract.</p>
<p>-- Julia Meehan, London newsroom +4471 542 79 28</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
