<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71096" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Lloyds TSB to save with Abbey.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Lloyds TSB to save with Abbey.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britian's largest retail financial services firm, Lloyds TSB Group, on Monday forecast pre-tax savings of 50 million pounds ($77.65 million) a year in three years from its buy-out of life insurer Lloyds Abbey Life.</p>
<p>In a statement detailing last week's 1.68 billion pound deal to buy the oustanding 37.4 percent of Lloyds Abbey, the company said the proposal would marginally boost earnings per share in 1997 before the main savings emerge.</p>
<p>The deal values the outstanding shares in Lloyds Abbey (LAL) at around 635 pence. For institutions that can claim a tax credit, LAL shares are worth about 648 pence, assuming a Lloyds TSB share price of 391 pence.</p>
<p>London stockbrokers Lehman Brothers said they expected the transaction to boost earnings per share by three percent in the first year before any potential cost savings from integrating the LAL businesses with Lloyds TSB operations.</p>
<p>Analysts welcomed the deal announced on Friday along with a statement that ended months of speculation over the company's management. It confirmed Sir Brian Pitman as chairman following the retirement in February of Robin Ibbs.</p>
<p>&quot;The management succession and Lloyds Abbey Life minority buy-out announcement remove the two main uncertainties affecting the Lloyds TSB Group,&quot; Lehman Brothers said in a note. &quot;This should allow the market to focus on the potential represented by the group's existing RoE (return on equity) of 30 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Lloyds TSB, whose shares lost three pence to 375.5 pence by late morning, said savings would be made through distribution, technology and adminstration of life and non-life bancassurance products and its hire purchase and leasing arms.</p>
<p>&quot;There will also be streamlining benefits which at this stage cannot be quanitified,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>Lloyds said it was aiming to achieve voluntary redundancies and staff cuts through wastage as far as possible.</p>
<p>The simplified ownership structure would create a more flexible business, creating the opportunity to cut unit costs in the combined business leading to a &quot;stronger, more competitive market position and enhanced prospects for profitable growth&quot;, Lloyds TSB said.</p>
<p>Abbey Life will remain separately run and, if the deal wins shareholder approval, three independent non-executive LAL directors will leave the board.</p>
<p>Under the deal, minority LAL investors will get six Lloyds TSB shares and 2,100 pence cash for every seven LAL shares.</p>
<p>Of the cash, 350 pence net -- 50 pence net per share -- will be by way of a special dividend from Lloyds Abbey.</p>
<p>LAL shares, which surged on Friday, rose another four pence to 624.5 pence. ($1=.6439 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
