<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="711124" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ABT sees charge for plastics restructuring.</title>
<headline>ABT sees charge for plastics restructuring.</headline>
<dateline>NEENAH, Wis. 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>ABT Building Products Corp, which makes specialty building products from engineered woods, plastics and fiber cement, said Monday it will take a charge of about $10 million to restructure its Plastics Products Group.</p>
<p>The majority of the restructuring costs are non-cash related, it added.  </p>
<p>As part of the restructuring, ABT said its Independence, Iowa, plant will be closed and equipment moved to Hopkinsville, Ky.   This will consolidate all exterior shutters, both injected molded and thermoformed, and related plastics building material accessories at the Kentucky plant. Finishing operations will also be located at Hopkinsville.</p>
<p>It also will phase out its industrial custom molded business in order to focus on specialty plastics products for the building products industry.  These moves will allow for the closure of three smaller warehouses used for industrial custom molded products near the Hopkinsville plant.  </p>
<p>All manufacturing and distribution for shutters and exterior accessories will then be concentrated at Hopkinsville.</p>
<p>A new customer service operation established last month at Charlotte, N.C., will handle all exterior products customer service activities. Shipments to the United States from the Acton, Ontario, vinyl siding plant also will be handled by the Charlotte customer service operation.</p>
<p>Three warehouses near the Acton plant will be closed and all vinyl siding warehousing and distribution will be consolidated at the newly constructed distribution center in the Milton, Ontario, area, it added.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been contemplating these moves for a period of time, and we are now in the position from a facility and customer service perspective to start implementation,&quot; George Brophy, chairman, said in a statement.  &quot;The focus of ABT in the future, as in the past, will continue to be specialty building materials.&quot;</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEENAH, Wis."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
