<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="711230" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WORLD BONDS - French OATs not for the adventurous.</title>
<headline>WORLD BONDS - French OATs not for the adventurous.</headline>
<byline>Clelia Oziel</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bonds have few thrills to offer risk-loving investors, but there may be modest gains at the long end of the curve as long as U.S. Treasuries continue to rise, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Solid domestic demand has sheltered OATs from roller-coaster trends in Europe over Economic and Monetary Union (EMU), and analysts reckoned a robust outlook for T-bonds would help the French curve flatten.</p>
<p>But gains were likely to be dwarfed by prospects in high yielders like Italy where bond convergence is still going full steam, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;When you look at the (French) yield curve there's really not much in it,&quot; said Bronwyn Curtis, chief economist at Nomura International in London.</p>
<p>&quot;It's so dependent on what's happening in Germany,&quot; she added, pointing at watertight yield spreads between France and Germany.</p>
<p>The 10-year OAT/Bund spread barely budged from around minus eight basis points on Monday despite weekend comments by Bavarian Finance Minister Erwin Huber that EMU could go ahead even in France's absence.</p>
<p>Meanwhile German Finance Minister Theo Waigel said an EMU without France would be inconceivable. He said on Monday that despite jobs measures announced by France, Paris had not put the deficit targets in question.</p>
<p>Last week, investors shrugged off French Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn's forecast that public deficit to GDP could be significantly higher in 1997 than the 3.0 percent EMU target.</p>
<p>By 1135 GMT, the September notionnel future on MATIF had set a fresh contract high of 130.18, up 22 basis points on the day.</p>
<p>But analysts said with short-end French yields looking rock-solid, the only section of the curve worth dabbling in was the long end which could benefit from the U.S. as well as a bright supply scenario.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect U.S. yields to come down further. With that you'll get European yields coming down at the longer end as well,&quot; said Curtis.</p>
<p>Some analysts thought France, boxed in by an election promise to create jobs and EMU requirements, could be edged out of its cosy trend.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is a potential for volatility,&quot; said Nick Stamenkovic, economist at DKB International in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Either it (France) reneges on its promises prompting some renewed social conflicts or it falls out with Germany leading to...a renewed bout of volatility in European bond markets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he added that with EMU generally expected to go ahead as planned with France, OATs were unlikely to deteriorate dramatically against Bunds.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the French paper was unlikely to close the gap to Bunds for some time.</p>
<p>Dominique Barbet, head of research at Banque Paribas in Paris, said a hefty bond redemption due in France in the coming weeks would underpin the market as the proceeds would mostly be reinvested in bonds.</p>
<p>He favoured the 30-year sector.</p>
<p>&quot;If you're a yield curve player then you may be interested in the 10-30s in France which is steeper than in Germany and more liquid,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nomura's Curtis said investors could also borrow the short end of the curve and invest in the long end for performance.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44-171-542 8663</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
