<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="711482" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-German government, SPD stick to guns on tax.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-German government, SPD stick to guns on tax.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's government and opposition stuck to their respective positions on Monday over Finance Minister Theo Waigel's tax reform plans, while officials from both sides began trying to find some common ground.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Peter Hausmann said Chancellor Helmut Kohl's coalition was ready to come to a common solution but not the way the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) had in mind.</p>
<p>Hausmann said the SPD simply wanted to cut some taxes and raise others to pay for them.</p>
<p>&quot;What is vitally necessary is a net reduction in the tax burden,&quot; he told a regular government news conference.</p>
<p>Hausmann was speaking as a working group from both government and opposition began laying the ground for a Thursday meeting of parliament's mediation committee.</p>
<p>The committee must find a compromise after the tax reform bill cleared the lower chamber, where Kohl's coalition has a majority, but was blocked by the SPD-dominated upper house.</p>
<p>The centre-left SPD party rejects the government's idea of cutting the top income tax rate to 39 percent from 53 percent and wants instead to lower unit wage costs.</p>
<p>It also says supplementary wage costs, extra charges on labour that are not associated with production, should be reduced or removed from unit wages and be financed elsewhere.</p>
<p>The party  has called the government's bills socially unjust and is trying to divide the coalition proposals, hinting that it could agree on certain parts but not on the coalition's broad reform.</p>
<p>Hausmann warned the SPD that it would pay a heavy price if it refused to be flexible. &quot;If the SPD blocks once again, that is a stance which normals citizens will find it hard to understand,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gerhard Schroeder, SPD premier of Lower Saxony and a leading candidate to challenge Kohl in elections next year, proposed reaching agreement on the points where the government and opposition were close but not on the overall reform.</p>
<p>&quot;I am optimistic that we could agree quickly on at least two points -- abolishing taxes on corporate trading capital and lowering supplementary wage costs,&quot; he told the Bild daily.</p>
<p>But Hausmann made clear that the government did not favour this piecemeal approach as Germany needed to cut taxes across the board to encourage both home-based and foreign companies to invest more in the country and create jobs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
