<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71169" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>OMAN: Oman hits wealth of new copper, gold deposits.</title>
<headline>Oman hits wealth of new copper, gold deposits.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>MUSCAT 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Exploration in Oman's rugged coastal hills has identified deposits of copper and gold ore, which Muscat hopes will bring more riches to the small oil producer which first mined copper 3,000 years ago.</p>
<p>Omani Ministry of Petroleum and Minerals official Mohammed Kassim al-Yafai said on Monday Japanese geologists last week hit a sulphide deposit with copper and gold reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;The last drilled hole showed excellent results as it hit more than 30 metres of massive sulphide. A rough estimate has indicated an average of about four percent copper content,&quot; Yafai, minerals director general, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The depth of the find at Ghayzayn, 150 km northwest of Muscat, was from 136.90 metres to 170.60 metres.</p>
<p>Drilling some 800 metres away hit an eight metre band of sulphide at 133 metres, with five percent copper content.</p>
<p>Last year Oman and Japan signed a deal to explore for minerals in the Al Khaburah-Rustaq block on the central Batinah coast. Japan is financing the $2.5 million two-year project and Yafai said based on the new finding it may invest more.</p>
<p>Oman already mines gold, but production of about half a tonne a year does not make it a challenger to heavyweight South Africa, which produces some 550 tonnes annually.</p>
<p>It mined an annual average of 16,000 tonnes of refined copper from 1983 to 1994, when its three mines were depleted.</p>
<p>It began importing concentrate to keep its refinery running, yielding about 24,000 tonnes of refined copper a year.</p>
<p>Yafai said last week's find was a bonus to deposits already identified at Hail al-Safil, where content is about 1.4 percent, and Raki -- both about 200 km (120 miles) from Muscat.</p>
<p>Oman has offered six concession blocks for the deposits. Yafai said they were negotiating with two firms of the 21 which applied and hoped to sign contracts by the beginning of 1997.</p>
<p>He said one was Canadian and the other an Omani firm which bid with a British company. He declined to name them.</p>
<p>If successful, they will be given two to three year licences to explore for copper and gold, after which they will have the option for a 25-year mining licence.</p>
<p>Copper ore mined at Hail would be concentrated before being trucked to the smelter about 200 km away in Sohar, Yafai said.</p>
<p>At end-1995 Oman had proven reserves of 837,000 tonnes of gold ore in Rakah with an average yield of five grams per tonne, and 13 million tonnes of copper ore with 1.4 percent copper.</p>
<p>So far this year exploration found 1.5 million tonnes more reserves of copper and 446,000 tonnes of gold ore, Yafai said. The gold reserves have a yield of about eight grams per tonne.</p>
<p>Oman, which pumps about 850,000 barrels a day of oil, is trying to diversify the economy and draw private investment.</p>
<p>Yafai said an updated 1974 mining law would be ready by March or June 1997 to make the sector more attractive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUSCAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="OMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
