<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="711644" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian Kras hopes for cheap foreign loan.</title>
<headline>Croatian Kras hopes for cheap foreign loan.</headline>
<byline>Kolumbina Bencevic</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian chocolate-maker Kras said on Monday it hoped to raise 60 million German marks ($34.3 million) from foreign lenders to finance its ambitious development plans.</p>
<p>It has mandated Germany's Bayerische Vereinsbank to arrange the syndication, due to be completed by September, company officials told a news conference.</p>
<p>It recently adopted a new business strategy until 2000 requiring hefty investments to modernise its outdated production lines and opening new facitilies.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a choice of going more slowly without any big changes...or face up to the challenges more aggressively. Our management board opted for the second scenario,&quot; said Boris Marcac, president of Kras's board.</p>
<p>The confectioner plans to spend some 51 million marks to revamp existing capacity and expand in the next three years, Marcac said. He said &quot;our own resources do not suffice to enforce bigger changes in the short-term.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Bayerische's offer included repayment over six years with a one-year grace period.</p>
<p>The loan is expected to cost Kras no more than five percent per year but actual interest, based on the London Interbank Offered Rate, will be set later.</p>
<p>For the past year, Kras has tried to negotiate some form of investment with the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD). But the talks failed to produce a deal.</p>
<p>But other foreign banks were lured to Kras after Croatia got an investment grade sovereign rating, finance director Tomislav Jovic said.</p>
<p>&quot;Their terms proved to be more favourable than the European Bank's and after careful deliberations, we chose financing on commercial terms,&quot; he said. But he said the EBRD and Kras left open the possibility of further cooperation in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;We are truly indebted to the European Bank for their advice and support. Their interest to begin with was crucial,&quot; Jovic told Reuters after the conference.</p>
<p>Bayerische will immediately grant Kras a bridging loan of 20 million marks so it can repay old debts and place orders for new equipment. Another 10 million marks will be made available by year end.</p>
<p>The company plans to draw on the other 30 million mark tranche some time next year, but officials said it might still opt out if it finds &quot;cheaper funds through equity investment.&quot;</p>
<p>Kras' shareholders approved these plans at the annual meeting on July 5, empowering the board to decide on actual means of increasing the company's equity by up to 50 percent.</p>
<p>The company is already more than 50 percent privately-owned, with current and former employees controlling around 25 percent of its stock and other private investors 20.65 percent. The company also has 11.41 percent in treasury shares.</p>
<p>The rest is split between the state privatisation agency, which will put its shares into a mass voucher scheme later this year, and two state pension funds.</p>
<p>Kras is Croatia's leading confectioner, annually producing some 22,000 tonnes of chocolate, wafers and other sweet products with a 40.5-percent market share.</p>
<p>It sells 51 percent of its output domestically and exports the rest to its neighbours and other nations.</p>
<p>Last month's news of a strong 1996 net profit rise to 18.56 million kuna pushed Kras shares up on the Zagreb Stock Exchange to 460. The share price has receded since, closing last week at 425 kuna. ($ = 1.747 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
