<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="711628" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Ranariddh vows to lead Cambodian resistance.</title>
<headline>Ranariddh vows to lead Cambodian resistance.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodia First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh said in an interview published on Monday that his rival, Second Prime Minister Hun Sen, had ousted him from power and vowed to organise resistance against him.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that he has succeeded in his coup d'etat, he says he has power and legitimacy,&quot; Ranariddh said in an interview with the French daily Le Monde. &quot;The resistance will now be organised inside and outside of Cambodia.&quot;  </p>
<p>Ranariddh said he had fled his homeland for southern France on the advice of his generals before fighting broke out between his troops and forces loyal to his rival Hun Sen.</p>
<p>He said the generals had told him on Friday that Hun Sen was preparing a coup d'etat and warned him that if he remained in Cambodia and Hun Sen succeeded, &quot;we would have no one on the outside to be our ambassador&quot;.</p>
<p>On Saturday Ranariddh accused Hun Sen of staging a coup d'etat in order to derail elections set for May 1998, but a radio station loyal to Hun Sen denied the charge.</p>
<p>Ranariddh said he had not spoken to his father King Sihanouk since the outbreak of fighting although he had talked to his mother the queen. Sihanouk, in Beijing undergoing medical treatment, has urged both prime ministers to visit him to try to resolve their differences, but Hun Sen had said such a meeting would not be necessary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
