<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="711661" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Summer lull hits Oslo bourse, shares crawl higher.</title>
<headline>Summer lull hits Oslo bourse, shares crawl higher.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian shares, buoyed by blue chips, crept to a new all-time high on Monday after spending most of the session in negative territory. Dealers predicted a dull, flat week ahead with the holiday season in full swing.</p>
<p>The Total share index finished a marginal 0.08 percent up to close at 1,238.69 points in turnover of 553 million crowns. It was the 13th consecutive gain on the Oslo bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't expect any surprises this week. Most perople are on holiday and those that aren't are thinking about going,&quot; said one dealer. He added that the market had shrugged off a recent run up in short-term interest rates due to a more stable crown.</p>
<p>Trade in drugs group Nycomed remained relatively active as investors continued to swap the B stock for the A share. Nycomed announced last Tuesday a plan to merge with Britain's Amersham International.</p>
<p>Nycomed As closed flat at 144 crowns, while the Bs relinquished one crown to 134 crowns. Total turnover in the company was 86 million crowns.</p>
<p>Tanker company Frontline  FRO.OL made its debut on the Norwegian market and was the second most traded stock in volume terms at 49 million crowns. Frontline opened at 29.50 crowns and closed at 28.80 crowns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
