<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="711868" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean president's son on trial for bribery.</title>
<headline>S.Korean president's son on trial for bribery.</headline>
<byline>Yoo Choon-sik</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean President Kim Young-sam's second son went on trial on charges of bribery and tax evasion on Monday in a scandal that analysts said could affect this year's presidential elections.</p>
<p>Dressed in pale blue prison garb and his head lowered, Kim Hyun-chul admitted accepting a total of 6.61 billion won ($7.4 million) from businessmen but denied any of the money was bribes.</p>
<p>&quot;I was never asked for favours in return for the money I received,&quot; he told a Seoul criminal court.</p>
<p>Kim Hyun-chul's arrest last May dealt a serious blow to the credibility of his father ahead of presidential elections in December.</p>
<p>The president is barred from seeking re-election by the constitution, and political analysts said his son's arrest made it difficult for the president to try openly to install his protege as his successor.</p>
<p>Kim Young-sam's ability to shape South Korean politics has also been curtailed by a loans-for-kickbacks scandal involving failed Hanbo Steel Co.</p>
<p>State prosecutors accused the president's second son of taking kickbacks worth 3.22 billion won in return for favours, while accepting a further 3.39 billion won as gifts with no strings attached.</p>
<p>The younger Kim, nicknamed &quot;the crown prince&quot; by the local media, took his first kickback shortly after his father came to office in February 1993, according to the prosecution.</p>
<p>Also on trial is a former top intelligence official, Kim Ki-sup, an associate of the president's son, charged with receiving 150 million won in bribes to help obtain a business licence. He pleaded guilty to the charge.</p>
<p>Prosecutors said Kim Hyun-chul evaded taxes of 1.4 billion won on gifts from businessmen, hiding the money in accounts using borrowed names.</p>
<p>One of his father's first acts on taking power was to ban false-name accounts as part of his anti-graft campaign.</p>
<p>The move, aimed at flushing out vast sums of money squirrelled away during decades of corrupt rule by a military-backed government, led to the arrest and jailing of former presidents Roh Tae-woo and Chun Doo Hwan.</p>
<p>Opposition parties have alleged Kim Hyun-chul is the &quot;real power&quot; who pressured banks to keep loans flowing to Hanbo Steel, South Korea's second largest steelmaker.</p>
<p>The steelmaker's collapse in January shed light on a web of corruption involving politicians, bankers and businessmen.</p>
<p>Last month, the founder of Hanbo, key presidential aides, politicians and top bankers were jailed for their roles in the Hanbo scandal.</p>
<p>Prosecutors have cleared Kim Hyun-chul of any wrongdoing in the Hanbo affair but indicted him for accepting money in return for favours to businessmen in connection with cable television deals and a road-building contract.</p>
<p>Opposition parties allege the president's 1992 election campaign was partly financed by Hanbo, and that after massive overspending, unused election funds were laundered by Kim Hyun-chul.</p>
<p>President Kim has said a large sum was spent for the 1992 election but refused to yield to opposition demands to reveal details of his campaign spending.</p>
<p>South Korean laws call for a maximum penalty of life in jail for tax evasion. Under the bribery charges brought against him, Kim Hyun-chul faces a maximum five years in jail.</p>
<p>($1 = 887 won)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
