<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="711950" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia seeks ASEAN meeting on Cambodia.</title>
<headline>Indonesia seeks ASEAN meeting on Cambodia.</headline>
<byline>Lewa Pardomuan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's Foreign Minister Ali Alatas on Monday called for an emergency meeting of southeast Asian foreign ministers to discuss Cambodia, which is teetering on the brink of civil war.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is a need for ASEAN foreign ministers to gather, even though only for a short period, to discuss the situation in Cambodia,&quot; he told reporters at parliament.</p>
<p>Cambodia, together with Laos and Burma, is due to join the seven-nation Association of Southeast Asian Nations at the regular, annual meeting of foreign ministers in Kuala Lumpur last this month.</p>
<p>But Alatas said he was trying to contact Malaysian Foreign Minister Abdullah Ahmad Badawi, the current ASEAN chairman, &quot;on possibility of ASEAN foreign ministers meeting on this issue&quot;.</p>
<p>ASEAN currently comprises Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam.</p>
<p>Both Alatas and President Suharto called for an end to the fighting in Cambodia.</p>
<p>&quot;The president said the situation in Cambodia should be resolved peacefully and the parties involved should restrain themselves,&quot; Indonesia's ambassador-at-large Nana Sutresna said after meeting Suharto.</p>
<p>Long simmering rivalry between Cambodia's co-prime ministers, former communist party chief Hun Sen and Prince Norodom Ranariddh, erupted into fighting in the capital at the weekend.</p>
<p>Suharto also discussed Cambodia with visiting Japanese vice-foreign minister Kazuo Ogura.</p>
<p>&quot;We discussed the situation in Cambodia, and we hope ASEAN will be able to make a positive contribution in finding a solution to the problem,&quot; Ogura told reporters.</p>
<p>Alatas said Indonesia was following developments in Cambodia with great concern and urged &quot;all parties to immediately cease their recourse to armed force and to solve whatever problems they may have through dialogue&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We really think that the situation is quite serious, and we are frankly disappointed that despite the commitment and the assurances they have given to us, to ASEAN, this conflict still reaches this proportion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said any ASEAN agreement on Cambodia would come from a consensus between the member countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We see this problem as an internal matter which is a conflict between two parties, and ASEAN will decide its steps together,&quot; Alatas said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
