<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712027" id="root" date="1997-07-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: FUND VIEW - Thai baht batters Asia sentiment.</title>
<headline>FUND VIEW - Thai baht batters Asia sentiment.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Davison</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's flotation of the baht will darken the cloud hanging over Southeast Asia, supplying international investors with yet another reason to avoid the region, fund managers in Hong Kong said.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect a decided lack of enthusiasm for Southeast Asia because of what happened in Thailand,&quot; said David Descalzi, senior portfolio manager at Prudential Asia.</p>
<p>Thailand's central bank floated the baht last Wednesday in a surprise move that quickly wiped about 15 percent off its value through the establishment of a new, managed float regime.</p>
<p>Few expected the currency to be floated soon after the appointment of a new finance minister.</p>
<p>The repercussions would be mixed, experts said.</p>
<p>Badly needed cuts in interest rates would ease pressure on the nation's battered financial sector, but they would take time to materialise.</p>
<p>Foreign investors adopting a longer-term perspective piled back into Thailand's stock market regardless, lifting the market's benchmark index a further 3.43 percent at the open on Monday to 679.61 points.</p>
<p>The index rose 25 percent last week in a rally driven by foreigners who approved of recent bold moves to boost the ailing Thai economy, including Wednesday's decision to scrap the baht's fixed peg to a basket of currencies.</p>
<p>But Descalzi said evidence was needed that another currency float or devaluation wasn't going to occur in other regional countries, such as Malaysia or the Philippines. Such evidence was needed to ensure a return of enthusiasm for the region.</p>
<p>There are continued signs of speculative activity in the forward or swaps market on the Malaysian ringgit following intervention to protect the ringgit and the peso by central banks in Kuala Lumpur and Manila.</p>
<p>&quot;Stock markets in the rest of the region have to some extent discounted some of the concerns,&quot; said Eugene Chung, regional strategist at SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>&quot;So I'm not terribly worried about a dramatic fall, but I think the argument still holds that in terms of vulnerability the Philippines, then Malaysia, Indonesia and Singapore are the exposed currencies and stock markets.&quot;</p>
<p>David Lui, director at Schroder Securities, argued that a gradual devaluation of all these currencies was inevitable following years of over-investment and massive capital inflows.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally, Southeast Asian currencies should gradually float downwards and allow interest rates to come off, especially with the U.S. dollar so strong,&quot; Lui said.</p>
<p>Thailand's economic fundamentals made a defence of the baht impossible, Lui said, stressing that economics, not fixed exchange rates themselves, were the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem arises not from a fixed exchange rate, but from over-spending, over-investment due to booming, high-growth economies for the past decade,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although no Asian country confronts an economic picture as bleak as Thailand's, the economies of Southeast Asia are similar, with wide current account deficits and high foreign liabilities -- and that suggests similar problems are going to crop up elsewhere.</p>
<p>Lui expects Malaysia to experience difficulties first, but said its central bank regulation of the banking sector will mitigate the problems.</p>
<p>The Philippines is in a later stage of the economic cycle, suggesting a two-year delay in the economic effects of asset price inflation in some parts of the property sector.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
