<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71219" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oregon measure may raise tax increase hurdle - S&amp;P.</title>
<headline>Oregon measure may raise tax increase hurdle - S&amp;P.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's Corp warned on Monday that an Oregon ballot measure would reduce the likelihood of passing taxes submitted to voters and could reduce the financial flexibility of localities.</p>
<p>Measure 46 would require approval from at least 50 percent of all registered voters for any new tax or revenue increases. The current authorization requirement is for only a majority of those who actually turn out to vote.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said the measure, which will appear on the November ballot, could have long-term negative credit implications for municipal issuers in the state.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said in Monday's CreditWeek Municipal newsletter that passage of Measure 46 was likely to reduce the likelihood of passing tax or revenue measures submitted to the voters, as voter turnout is rarely large enough to result in majority approval by those registered.</p>
<p>The credit implications of this measure include the potential for reduced financial flexibility in the form of both revenues available to pay for operations and the ability to meet infrastructure needs, S&amp;P sid.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said the main effect of this measure would be to limit the ability of local government to pass general obligation bonds to fund infrastructure during a time of substantial growth in the economy.</p>
<p>While some governments may try to substitute lease financings for general obligation debt, S&amp;P said this option is limited because governments would need to cover lease payments out of operating budgets.</p>
<p>&quot;Credit quality could be at risk to the extent governments were to overburden operating budgets with lease payments or to the extend that needed infrastructure was not funded,&quot; the rating agency said.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said Measure 46's language imposes the same voter approval requirement on general obligation bond's authorized since November 1990. This retroactivity may or may not be upheld in court, the rating agency said. --Adam Entous, 415-677-2511</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
