<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71233" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Sept 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Sept 23.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following business stories Monday:</p>
<p>* Time Warner Inc's acquisition of Turner Broadcasting System Inc presents the first clear chance in years for Time Warner to boost its stock price.</p>
<p>* A new survey of home computer users shows the majority of Internet users now gain access through direct service providers rather than commercial providers like America Online or Compuserve, which is mostly owned by H&amp;R Block Inc.</p>
<p>* The Omnicom Group, the world's second-largest advertising company, is forming a division to concentrate on interactive marketing and media.</p>
<p>* International news is diminishing in the top weekly news magazines.</p>
<p>* The Canadian Broadcasting System is cutting 2,500 jobs and changing its broadcast strategy to use more Canadian content.</p>
<p>* The chairman of Lloyd's of London is touring the United States to raise new business after the insurer neared the brink of collapse just months ago.</p>
<p>* A group of big banks is urging governments and the International Monetary Fund to stop using public money to aid developing countries going through fiscal crises.</p>
<p>* Questions have arisen about actions taken by Bob Dole when, as Senate majority leader, the merger of Union Pacific Corp and Southern Pacific Rail came before Congress.</p>
<p>* Echelon Corp, which makes computer control networks for the home, could become a household name, although there are risks.</p>
<p>* Naming a new business has become an exercise in patience, especially for high-tech companies.</p>
<p>* Newspaper business managers are implementing joint, cooperative ventures like printing delivery agreements.</p>
<p>* General Motors Corp is giving its old headquarters to the city of Detroit for use as a new city hall.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk  (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
