<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712483" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST- EUROPE SEEN HITTING DEL MONTE H1.</title>
<headline>FORECAST- EUROPE SEEN HITTING DEL MONTE H1.</headline>
<byline>Ellis Mnyandu</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tough trading conditions in the European canned fruit market and internal worries are likely hit South Africa's Del Monte Royal Foods Ltd when it reports its interim earnings next week, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But, while expecting a fall in earnings, the majority of analysts polled by Reuters declined to give numbers, saying a recent profit warning by the company made forecasts redundant.</p>
<p>&quot;The first half is going to be absolutely disastrous and that can be said with confidence, without putting a number to it,&quot; said an analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Del Monte's traditional canned fruit mainstay continued to be weakened by rife competition in Europe while a good fruit crop swelled supplies and pushed prices lower over the past year, they said.</p>
<p>Del Monte is due to announce results for the six months ended May 31, next Wednesday.</p>
<p>Two out of the 10 analysts polled by Reuters for an interim consensus forecast ranged Del Monte's earnings per share between 15.5 cents and 19.89 cents from 22.1 cents in the first half of the previous year.</p>
<p>The dividend was seen between five and a flat 7.5 cents.</p>
<p>The remaining analysts declined to give forecasts and said the firm's profit warning issued last month told an obvious story.</p>
<p>Del Monte said it expected earnings to fall at interim and full-year stages due to a restructuring and difficult trading conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;They've already put out a cautionary and from my understanding the conditions on the international markets, particularly the European market which is the major market they operate in are quite tough,&quot; Carolyn Windsor of stockbroking firm Investec Securities told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe there's been an increase in the supplies of (canned) fruit products going into that market,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>She said Del Monte could save face by shifting from canned-type fruit business to fresh fruit juices where the market is still largely static.</p>
<p>&quot;I think generally the feeling is that they might shift some of the focus away from canned-type products into fruit juices which seems to have worked quite well for them.&quot;</p>
<p>But another analyst who also asked not to be identified said:&quot;The fruit juice market is also a very difficult one, it's got a very high barrier to entry and it's not a very easy market to get control of and I just don't think their juices are going to pull them through that much.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said recent management difficulties, which saw Del Monte replace the bulk of the company's management crew in Italy last year, were also causing anxiety about the group's ability to manage itself through current hard times.</p>
<p>Analysts said Del Monte's exposure to many different currencies and their fluctuations due to the firm's far-flung production areas, such as the Philippines, Italy, Greece and Kenya, made it difficult to provide a comprehensive forecast.</p>
<p>Furthermore, analysts saw no support offered to Del Monte by its mainly confectionery and biscuit businesses locally, where consumer spending continued to be stunted by high interest rates.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
