<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712454" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-SUNS RE-SIGN CHAPMAN, WILLIAMS AND LLAMAS.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-SUNS RE-SIGN CHAPMAN, WILLIAMS AND LLAMAS.</headline>
<dateline>PHOENIX, Arizona 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>After talking point guard Kevin Johnson out of retiring last month, the Phoenix Suns took another big step toward keeping the team intact Tuesday by re-signing guard Rex Chapman, forward/center John &quot;Hot Rod&quot; Williams and centre Horacio Llamas.</p>
<p>The trio of free agents each signed one-year contracts, the team announced. The Suns last week also re-signed free agent forwad Mark Bryant.</p>
<p>&quot;This brings together our nucleus, which competed at higher-than-expected levels last season,&quot; said Suns general manager Bryan Colangelo.</p>
<p>&quot;Rex's return solidifies the guard rotation that proved successful last season while Hot Rod's presence provides us with the necessary reinforcements in the middle.&quot;</p>
<p>Chapman averaged 13.8 points and 2.8 assists in 65 games last season, but exploded during the playoffs for an average of 24.2 points per game in five contests. He converted an NBA playoff-record nine three-pointers and scored 42 points in Game 1 of Phoenix's first-round series with Seattle.</p>
<p>&quot;I had opportunities to go a few other places,&quot; Chapman said. &quot;Ultimately, I wanted to be back in Phoenix. It is a place that was there for me when others were not.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can stay healthy, with KJ (Kevin Johnson), Mark (Bryant) and Hot Rod back, this will be a very fun year.&quot;</p>
<p>Chapman, 29, has averaged 15.5 points in an injury-plagued nine-year career with Charlotte, Washington, Miami and Phoenix.</p>
<p>Williams, 34, spent the last two years with the Suns after playing his first nine seasons with the Cleveland Cavaliers. He averaged eight points and a career-best 8.3 rebounds, while leading the team with 88 blocked shots last year.</p>
<p>Llamas, the first Mexican-born player in NBA history, appeared in 20 games for the Suns last season, averaging 1.7 points and one rebound.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHOENIX, Arizona"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
