<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712530" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>LITHUANIA: MEDIENOS PLAUSHAS SEES HIGHER H1 PROFIT.</title>
<headline>MEDIENOS PLAUSHAS SEES HIGHER H1 PROFIT.</headline>
<dateline>VILNIUS 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cardboard company Medienos Plaushas said on Tueday that it expects its net profit to rise to two million litas in the first half of the year from 1.3 million litas in the same period of 1996.</p>
<p>The company also said that its sales in the first six months of the year rose to 21.7 million litas from 20 million litas in the same period last year.  </p>
<p>&quot;We managed to work according to the planned schedule in the first half of the year and we see our net profit to be two million litas in the period,&quot; the company's director general Petras Chesna told Reuters.</p>
<p>The company said earlier that planned to have a net profit for the whole year of four million litas.</p>
<p>Medienos Plaushas posted a net profit of 1.675 million litas for the first five months of the year and a 1.7 million litas audited net profit for 1996.</p>
<p>Medienos Plaushas, a corrugated cardboard maker and the sole egg container producer in the Baltic countries, is one of the blue chip companies on the Vilnius bourse.</p>
<p>The share capital of the company stands at 28.1 million litas and around 14 percent of it is held by foreign investors, Estonia's Hansapank among them.</p>
<p>The company said earlier that it has agreed with the Bank of New York to convert around 30 percent of its current shares into global depository receipts (GDRs) in July or in early August.</p>
<p>-- Andrius Vilkancas, Vilnius newsroom +370 2 22 35 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VILNIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LITHUANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
