<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712586" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Red Cross denies Diana about-turn on Bosnia trip.</title>
<headline>Red Cross denies Diana about-turn on Bosnia trip.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British Red Cross on Tuesday denied reports from Sarajevo that Princess Diana had pulled out of a planned trip to Bosnia because she might have ended up meeting the wife of wanted war criminal Radovan Karadzic.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the Red Cross said Bosnia was one of a number of countries Diana had considered visiting as part of her campaign with the Red Cross against the use of landmines but that a visit had not been firmly planned.</p>
<p>However, a Western official in Sarajevo said the princess had cancelled a planned visit there &quot;due to political sensitivities&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a concern she would meet Mrs Karadzic, wife of the indicted war criminal, and therefore the visit is not taking place at all,&quot; the official told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;When Mrs Karadzic is no longer president of local Red Cross in Bosnian Serb territory, then the visit will be renegotiated,&quot; the official, who asked not to be named, said.</p>
<p>Ljiljana Karadzic is the head of the Serb Republic of Bosnia's Red Cross, an organisation not officially recognised by the International Federation of the Red Cross.</p>
<p>Her husband is wanted by the United Nations to face genocide charges dating from the Bosnian war.</p>
<p>The princess would have had reason to visit Bosnia in the coming months because the Red Cross is about to launch a &quot;Mines Awareness Programme&quot; there and her spokeswoman said she was keen to make further visits in the anti-landmine campaign.</p>
<p>But the Red Cross spokeswoman said similar programmes in other countries such as Cambodia might prove more interesting for the princess and provide better publicity for the campaign.</p>
<p>Diana -- former wife of heir to the throne Prince Charles -- made a high profile visit to Angola earlier this year to highlight the Red Cross campaign against landmines and to publicise the fact that it was an issue she felt strongly about.</p>
<p>If she has been obliged to cancel a trip to Bosnia, it will be the second time she has been forced into diplomatic backtracking in her mission to get landmines banned.</p>
<p>Last month, she cancelled a visit to the British parliament to hear a discussion about landmines after opposition Conservative members of parliament objected that, as a royal, she had no right to get involved in politics.</p>
<p>In the same week, the princess apologised after taking her under-age son to see a film sympathetic to the outlawed Irish Republican Army (IRA).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
