<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712690" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Polished performance from S.Africa furniture firms.</title>
<headline>Polished performance from S.Africa furniture firms.</headline>
<byline>Nicole Mordant</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The furniture sector on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange has rallied in recent weeks on hopes of an interest rate cut and as industry sales pick up after a sluggish start to the year.</p>
<p>Since last month the furniture index has climbed to one record high after another, boosted by strong gains in firms Protea Furnishers Ltd (Profurn), Ellerine Holdings Ltd and Amalgamated Retail Ltd (Amrel).</p>
<p>Analysts said on Tuesday that expectations of solid financial results and rumours of at least one firm eyeing an acquisition have also fuelled price rises.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole furniture sector is looking healthy especially with the potential for an interest rate cut and the effect that this could have for the man in the street,&quot; one dealer on the Johannesburg bourse said.</p>
<p>Early on Tuesday the furniture index was at a fresh peak of 1,945.8, bringing its gains since it started its latest climb at the end of May to more than 20 percent. Ellerine has soared to 36.00 rand from around 28.00, Profurn to 200 cents from around 140 and Amrel from around 10.00 rand to near 13.00 rand.</p>
<p>Signs that South Africa's economy is slowing have heightened expectations of a one-point cut in high interest rates, which economists think possible by the end of the third quarter and a certainty by the end of the year, reducing some of the strain on consumers' pockets.</p>
<p>Frans Jordaan, the director of the Furniture Traders Association of South Africa told Reuters that furniture sales had suddenly improved in April -- the latest available figures -- after remaining fairly flat since December last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The total sales of furniture and appliances in April are up 12.3 percent on April 1996 at current prices. That's about seven percent real growth which is a far cry from the two percent growth in March,&quot; Jordaan said.</p>
<p>Indications were that May would also be strong, he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said that continued sturdy results from some of the biggest furniture firms, in the face of tough trading conditions, had also heartened investors.</p>
<p>Heavyweights Ellerine and the JD Group Ltd both upped first half earnings. Although annual results from Associated Furniture showed a steep slide and Amrel a dip, both were seen in line for a better six months.</p>
<p>Profurn financial director Gavin Walker said that his firm would post robust earnings for the six months to June 30, helped by good trading results in neighbouring states.</p>
<p>Profurn has recently been the object of speculation that it is looking to buy the furniture division of struggling South African Breweries Ltd group retailer O.K. Bazaars, but Walker denied any talks were taking place.</p>
<p>Jordaan said the furniture sector would truly come into its own once government's housing programme, which has been hit by a number of setbacks and trails delivery promises to previously disadvantaged communities, moved into high gear.</p>
<p>&quot;Until affordable housing and delivery take place on a scale that is significant we will not see a major upturn in the sale of furniture,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I46700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
