<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712631" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenyan woman launches presidential campaign.</title>
<headline>Kenyan woman launches presidential campaign.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenyan opposition legislator Charity Kaluki Ngilu launched her presidential campaign on Tuesday by offering herself as a one-term &quot;bridge&quot; to ensure constitutional reforms that clear the way to proper democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;I seek a one-term mandate as a bridge between the present undemocratic and oppressive system that Kenyans have rejected, and the future democratic one that Kenyans are yearning for,&quot; she told a news conference also attended by 100 supporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I do believe that in those five years, I will have rendered the needed service to our country. It is only after this one term and when democratic institutions are ready and in place that the phrase 'let the people decide' will have meaning,&quot; added Ngilu, a 45-year-old politician and business executive.</p>
<p>Political analysts see Ngilu as an untainted politician who could be a potential compromise candidate for an opposition which is deeply divided mainly on personal and tribal lines.</p>
<p>Top politicians in the ruling Kenya African National Union (KANU) party have described a possible Ngilu candidature as formidable and a serious challenge to President Daniel arap Moi's 19-year reign.</p>
<p>Nevertheless Moi, 73, is almost certain to win another five-year term from this year's presidential and parliamentary elections, for which no dates have been set, because the opposition is so split.</p>
<p>Ngilu began her presidential bid in earnest a day after nine people were killed in Kenya during the most violent confrontation between protesters and police for seven years.</p>
<p>Police broke up opposition-backed protests called to press the government for constitutional reforms before presidential and parliamentary elections this year. No date has been set for the polls but a date in November or December is now likely.</p>
<p>Ngilu put those reforms at the top of her agenda, pledging to repeal all &quot;bad&quot; laws within her first 100 days in office.</p>
<p>Ngilu said she would preside over &quot;momentous change amidst continuity&quot; and targeted for attention encouraging savings, cutting government borrowing, lowering interest rates, improving tax collection and rehabilitating infrastructure.</p>
<p>Ngilu said the current breed of opposition chiefs -- Kenneth Matiba, Michael Kijana Wamalwa, Raila Odinga and Mwai Kibaki -- were too far divided to agree to one of them as a single candidate to face President Daniel arap Moi in elections.</p>
<p>Ngilu's candidature received backing from leading economist and opposition politician Professor Peter Anyang' Nyong'o and some business leaders said they saw her as a credible choice.</p>
<p>Ngilu said Kenyan society was deeply divided by ethnic animosity caused by tribal clashes in 1991 and 1992, rivalry in government positions and corruption and mismanagement of public resources. She added the opposition had meantime splintered further because of &quot;egotistical greed&quot; for the presidency.</p>
<p>She was likely to run on the banner of the Social Democratic Party, a small party but with a strong popular base.</p>
<p>Ngilu, who won her parliament seat when she ventured into politics in 1992, is married to an electrical engineer with whom she has three children -- two girls and a boy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
