<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712693" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - July 8.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - July 8.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are significant stories in the Nigerian press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- Armed robbers kill a divisional police officer in Lagos and snatch his car, says Lagos police chief Abubakar Tsav.</p>
<p>- No going back on decision to hand over power to civilians next year, says chief of defence staff Major-General Abdulsalam Abubakar in goodwill message to mark 134th anniversary of army.</p>
<p>- Maverick music star Fela Anikulapo-Kuti faces contempt charge over alleged disobedience of court order to quit his rented Lagos club, the &quot;African Shrine.&quot;</p>
<p>- Robbers raid national stadium in Lagos, carting away medical equipment worth millions of naira.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>- A shutdown of two of Nigeria's oil refineries is imminent because of government decision to further reduce crude oil allocation for local refining to 150,000 barrels per day from 250,000 bpd, says oil unions.</p>
<p>- Government chief secretary Gidado Idris criticises U.S. ambassador Walter Carrington for remarks that Nigeria has not created the right atmosphere for democracy, saying the envoy is not helping in the efforts to forge better U.S.-Nigeria ties.</p>
<p>- Provisional Ruling Council to meet in the capital Abuja on Wednesday to discuss security and economic matters.</p>
<p>- Management of Ikeja exchange of Nigeria Telecommunications Ltd in Lagos has been given seven days by the supervising minister to account for 117 million naira collected from subscribers to repair the burnt exchange.</p>
<p>- Kewalrams Chanrai Group has raised its stake in Afprint Plc to 63 percent from 57.5 percent through a 459 million capital injection.</p>
<p>- Nigeria's trade deficit with Japan trippled to $143 million last year from $44.4 million in 1995.</p>
<p>THISDAY</p>
<p>- Shell oil company appears set for showdown with four Nigerian communities that have given it up to the end of Tuesday to pay them 30 million naira compensation or be chased out of their oil-producing area.</p>
<p>- Contrary to reports, Nigerian opposition groups due to meet a Commonwealth team in London on Thursday will not canvass for expulsion of the African nation from the Commonwealth but recommend that its suspension from the group be retained.</p>
<p>- The 69-year-old Sultan of Sokoto and leader of Nigerian Moslems, Machido Abubakar married a new wife, 18-year-old Saratu Yadodo in Sokoto town in northern Nigeria on Monday in a glittering wedding ceremony.</p>
<p>($1=84.5 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
