<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712612" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks follow New York to close higher.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks follow New York to close higher.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>CHANGE				     CHANGE</p>
<p>TSE	 6580.84  +51.72   HI 6581.87	    LO  6532.78</p>
<p>DJI	 7962.31 +103.81   GOLD (LONDON)   US$320.80  +2.80</p>
<p>FTSE	4758.50  -52.20   GOLD (COMEX)    US$321.00  +2.00</p>
<p>NIKKEI   19853.89 +148.72   LME CASH NICKEL US$6815    -10.0</p>
<p>CANDLR     1.3732	     LME CASH ALUM   US$1545.0  -23.0</p>
<p>CAN 30-YR  118.14   -0.37   BRENT CRUDE     US$18.39    0.19</p>
<p>---------------------MARKET COMMENT--------------------------</p>
<p>* Toronto's key stock index closed on a high note boosted by New York and a bounce in golds, but the overall market ended mixed as declining issues edged out advances 499 to 496.</p>
<p>Toronto's key stock index climbed more than 50 points by Tuesday's close, aided by New York's rally and rebounding gold issues.</p>
<p>But the broader market ended mixed as some investors were unconvinced and sold resource stocks.</p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange's 300 Composite Index jumped 51.72 points to 6580.84, trailing the Dow Jones Industrial Average, which soared almost 104 points to 7962.</p>
<p>&quot;It's following the strength in New York...(and) getting a little bit of relief from the gold sector,&quot; said Peter Chandler, senior vice-president of C.M. Oliver &amp; Co. Ltd.  </p>
<p>The heavily resource-laden market got some respite from weaker gold bullion prices, which bounced back from 12-year lows on Monday. The closely watched Comex price in New York added US$2 to US$321 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're getting a bounce there,&quot; Chandler said. But a trader added that bullion prices, and therefore golds, would likely return to a downward trend soon.</p>
<p>Volume totaled 98 million shares worth C$1.8 billion.</p>
<p>Declining issues edged advancers 499 to 496, while 296 closed flat.</p>
<p>Only three of Toronto's 14 sub-sectors shed points: pipelines, consumer products and real estate. The rest traveled higher including golds, which climbed 2.2 percent, transportation, forestry products and influential banks.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Canada's two largest gold miners rose on the back of firmer bullion prices. Placer Dome Inc added 0.85 to 20.10 and Barrick Gold Corp, the world's third biggest gold producer, rose 1.65 to 29.45.</p>
<p>* IPL Energy Inc was halted on Tuesday. The Calgary-based firm said it bought a 32 percent stake in Quebec holding company Noverco Inc, making a major push into the province's natural gas business.</p>
<p>((Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8109))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
