<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712767" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Montenegro government reshuffled in power struggle.</title>
<headline>Montenegro government reshuffled in power struggle.</headline>
<dateline>PODGORICA, Yugoslavia 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Montenegrin Prime Minister Milo Djukanovic on Tuesday removed senior ministers at the demand of President Momir Bulatovic but replaced them with other supporters of his government's reform programme.</p>
<p>The reshuffle in the Montenegrin capital Podgorica was part of a running struggle between Bulatovic and Djukanovic over Montenegro's role in the Yugoslav federation with Serbia.</p>
<p>Djukanovic and his allies in the ruling DPS party say Montenegro's economic reconstruction has been sabotaged by the failure of Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic to restore links with international financial bodies since the 1995 lifting of U.N. sanctions, imposed for Serbian involvement in Bosnia's war.</p>
<p>Political sources said the shape of the government reshuffle indicated Djukanovic was favoured to win his conflict with Bulatovic, who is a Milosevic protege.</p>
<p>Although some key ministers were replaced at Bulatovic's instigation, Djukanovic refused to drop his head of state security.</p>
<p>The Montenegrin group around Djukanovic have reluctantly agreed to back Milosevic's switch from the Serbian to the Yugoslav federal presidency this month.</p>
<p>But they have refused to allow constitutional amendments which would have made the Yugoslav post more powerful.</p>
<p>Djukanovic, who has the backing of the Montenegrin opposition, said: &quot;There is a need to form a reform coalition on the federal as well as the republican level.&quot;</p>
<p>Milosevic's Socialist party (SPS) and its allies have enough seats in the federal parliament to govern without threat from an opposition coalition -- but not for a two-thirds majority required to change the constitution.</p>
<p>Since sanctions were rescinded, Milosevic has refused to meet U.S. conditions which would lift Washington's veto on Yugoslavia rejoining the International Monetary Fund and other international economic and political institutions.</p>
<p>Montenegro claims it has been an unwilling prisoner of Serbian policies.</p>
<p>Although an equal partner in the Yugoslav federation, it has a population of only 650,000 compared to Serbia's 10.5 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PODGORICA, Yugoslavia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
