<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712808" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Foreigners stay bearish on Poland, zloty slumps.</title>
<headline>Foreigners stay bearish on Poland, zloty slumps.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The zloty fell about half a percent against the currency basket on Tuesday as foreigners remained bearish on Poland despite an increase in the money market's benchmark 14-day drainage rate, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Many have already sold Polish paper and several more want to do the same as they expect the zloty to stay weak and yields to rise,&quot; said Piotr Korcz, dealer at Bank Handlowy SA.</p>
<p>Dealers said the National Bank of Poland, which last week said it may have to rise rates to further cool domestic demand, may still further increase market rates after Tuesday's 0.44 point rise to 22.59 percent for the 14-day operation.  </p>
<p>&quot;Banks were testing maximum levels at today's tender and rates could still have some room to grow,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The average yield of the central bank's 91-day NBP-bill also rose to 22.50 percent from the previous 22.30.</p>
<p>NBP officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The zloty closed at 0.94/0.89 percent above the trading band centre after hitting an eight-day high of 1.52/1.46 percent from parity on Monday.</p>
<p>It was at 3.2930/50 to the dollar, down from 3.2640/85 on Monday and at 1.8760/70 to the mark, down from 1.8695/15.  </p>
<p>&quot;The zloty should bounce between 1.0 and 0.5 percent above parity in the near-term,&quot; said Piotr Czyzewski, forex dealer at ING Bank in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Dealers said the vast majority of capital inflows linked to the London floatation of KGHM Polska Miedz SA already went through the market, with the effect on the zloty largely offset by foreign investor withdrals from Polish treasuries.</p>
<p>Many foreigners turned sour on Poland as its external balance has rapidly deteriorated in 1997, signalling that a Czech-style fianancial crisis could be down the road for Poland unless it takes more radical action to cool domestic demand.</p>
<p>Despite the reverse repo rate rise and 91-day NBP-bill yield rise O/N and T/N offers eased almost 0.7 point to 22.25/22.60 percent.</p>
<p>However, one month deposit offers disappeared after the announcement of the new NBP rates and two month deposits rose 0.3 point to 23.0 percent. Three-month deposit offers rose 0.2 point to 22.90 percent.</p>
<p>-- Wojciech Moskwa +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
