<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="712956" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks roar to sixth straight record close.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks roar to sixth straight record close.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican shares shed some of their earlier gains, but still left even the recent slew of impressive gains far behind to notch up their sixth record close in a row on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said foreign and domestic investors crowded a market basking in euphoria in the wake of smoother than expected mid-term elections on Sunday, amid a strong tailwind blowing from Wall Street.</p>
<p>Final closing prices showed the blue chip IPC share index had soared 79.90 points, or 1.69 percent, to a new record of 4,821.14.  </p>
<p>&quot;Basically, what we are seeing is that players who stayed on the sidelines last week are rushing in on the benefits of great elections,&quot; a desk trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are overweighting Mexico in their portfolios, and there has been a slew of country recommendations favoring Mexico, cutting Chile and Brazil,&quot; he added. &quot;Furthermore, forecasts have been upgraded for key indicators.&quot;</p>
<p>A Salomon Brothers report released on Tuesday said the brokerage was &quot;shifting weight to Mexico from Chile,&quot; as short-term risk in Mexico had been reduced by &quot;the perceived integrity of the July 6 elections.&quot;  </p>
<p>Caspian Research meanwhile issued a report raising their year-end target for the IPC to 5,500 points from 4,700, based on &quot;clean, transparent and peaceful&quot; mid-term elections.</p>
<p>Mexico held elections on Sunday for the lower house of Congress, one quarter of the Senate, several state governors and for the first time in modern history, Mexico City mayor.</p>
<p>Analysts noted the elections were relatively free of fraud allegations, and the ruling Institutional Revolutionary Party gracefully accepted preliminary returns showing it had suffered its worst setback since 1929.  </p>
<p>Dealers said they had so many buy orders the bourse needed to impose trading halts and use a screen-trading back-up system to handle a record level of more than 8,200 deals settled.</p>
<p>&quot;We were spinning around like firecrackers,&quot; one floor trader said.</p>
<p>Trading volume and turnover were very heavy at more than 199 million shares and $350 million, respectively.</p>
<p>Dealers said blue chips and ADRs led the rally.</p>
<p>&quot;Most ADRs are flying and foreigners flooded the market,&quot; another floor trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Telmex has been pulling up the market since this morning, Bancomer is going crazy, and they're also fighting to buy Cemex,&quot; a desk trader said.</p>
<p>Telfonos de Mxico (Telmex), which has the heaviest weighting on the IPC, gained 15 centavos to 20.75 pesos, a peso record.</p>
<p>The telecom's ADRs advanced 7/8 to 52-3/4, their highest level since the December 1994 peso crisis. The Dow Jones meanwhile gained 103.81 to end at a record of 7,962.31.</p>
<p>Bancomer, one of Mexico's biggest financial firms, gained 28 centavos to 4.70 pesos.  </p>
<p>Dealers said financial stocks in general gained on expectations forecast cuts in domestic interest rates would ease their past-due loans burdens.</p>
<p>Bancomer and Telmex together accounted for some 23 percent of all shares traded.</p>
<p>Cement maker Cemex meanwhile climbed 1.40 pesos to 37.90 pesos.</p>
<p>On the broad market, gainers far outstripped decliners, by 92 to 26, out of a total of 134 stocks that changed hands.</p>
<p>(( --Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7907))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
