<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713050" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RGC to buy Peru copper/gold  project. [CORRECTED 11:34 GMT]</title>
<headline>RGC to buy Peru copper/gold  project. [CORRECTED 11:34 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mineral sands and metals miner RGC Ltd said on Tuesday it had agreed to pay up to US$37 million for a copper/gold project in Peru.</p>
<p>&quot;RGC has reached agreement on the major commercial terms for purchase of the Cerro Corona copper/gold project in northern Peru,&quot; RGC said.</p>
<p>The purchase price would be made up of a deposit of US$2 million payable on a more detailed purchase agreement and either a payment of US$34 million on completion of due diligence or three further payments totalling US$37 million over three years, RGC said.</p>
<p>Due diligence was expected to be completed in early 1998, it said.</p>
<p>Cerro Corona is a copper/gold deposit at an altitude of 3,500 metres in the Western Cordillera of the Andes in northern Peru. </p>
<p>It is about 600 km (375 miles) north of the Peruvian capital, Lima, and 90 km (56 miles) north of the city of Cajamarca. </p>
<p>The region includes the Yanacocha gold mine, Minero Peru's Michiquillay copper/gold property and Cambior's La Granja copper project.</p>
<p>Previous work carried out on Cerro Corona has estimated it contains total measured, indicated, inferred and potential resources of 378,956,000 tonnes of sulphide ore with 0.465 grams per tonne of gold and 0.291 percent copper. (corrects tonnage, copper ratio)</p>
<p>RGC said it planned to develop a large open pit mine with an overall stripping ratio of about 1.6 tonnes of waste per tonne of ore.</p>
<p>It planned to mine and process 35,000 tonnes per day of sulphide ore to produce a copper/gold concentrate. The mine had a life on present sulphide ores of at least 12 years followed by oxide ore processing.</p>
<p>RGC said it expected average annual production of about 52,000 tonnes of copper in concentrate and 230,000 ounces of gold in concentrate. Production of copper/gold concentrate during the early years would exceed the annual average.</p>
<p>Barrick Gold Corp announced in October it would not proceed with the Cerro Corona project and took a C$38 million after-tax charge to third quarter earnings for costs incurred at the mine.</p>
<p>Barrick said while Cerro Corona's gold and copper mineralization was substantial, further exploration has found the extent of the find was not sufficient to meet Barrick's criteria for development.</p>
<p>A spokesman for RGC was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>RGC's shares were down 19 cents at A$4.06 at 3.10 p.m. (0510 GMT) in an overall weaker market.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800 (c) Reuters Limited 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
