<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713046" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - July 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - July 9.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>Super: what you won't be told: Treasurer Winston Peters's rationale for compulsory superannuation will not be included in a $5.6 million public information campaign because it might not be true. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Merger of ministries will cost jobs: A merger between the Agriculture and Forestry ministries and a restructuring of the Agriculture Ministry's service delivery arm would mean a loss of jobs, the minister for both portfolios, Lockwood Smith, said on Tuesday. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Women MPs unite to fight scheme: Opposition to the government's compulsory superannuation scheme was reinforced by a cross-party group of women MPs on Tuesday. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Super cost to business 'substantial': Businesses should not be turned into &quot;free public servants&quot; because the government wanted to shift the burden of superannuation from the public to the private sector, Wellington Chamber of Commerce chief executive Claire Johnstone said on Tuesday. Page 15.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Cook Islands economy hit hard by Winebox inquiry fallout: The Cook Islands economy appears to have been hit hard by the fallout from the Winebox inquiry, according to figures in the latest Asian Development Bank annual report. Page 18.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE PRESS</p>
<p>Police probe how MP got diary: The police diplomatic protection squad at Parliament is investigating how an opposition MP got hold of a missing diary belonging to NZ First MP Tuku Morgan. Page 1.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Real life makes RSS unworkable -- Upton: Environment Minister Simon Upton is continuing to oppose the Retirement Savings Scheme, saying people do not live their lives in &quot;nice, neat, straight lines&quot;. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Creech outlines govt's teacher programme: The government's $40 million programme to boost teacher numbers includes 1500 extra trainee places in the next three years, recruitment from overseas, and increasing the number of Maori teachers, Education Minister Wyatt Creech said on Tuesday. Page 3.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Govt crackdown on new casinos: The government proposes to toughen the rules for setting up casinos. Page 8.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Macraes seen as buyer in shake-out: Macraes Mining is a potential predator and Otter Gold Mines a potentially attractive takeover target in the shake-out in the Australasian gold industry, says New Zealand mining analyst Paul Richardson. Page 32.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>GPG pockets $2 million extra: Guinness Peat Group's short stay at the DB Group watering hole has seen Sir Richard Brierley's investment vehicle walk away with an extra $2 million in its back pocket.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Money conditions in 'comfort zone': Monetary conditions as measured by the Monetary Conditions Index (MCI) moved back within the Reserve Bank's comfort zone on Tuesday as the 90-day bank bill yield and the trade-weighted exchange rate index (TWI) climbed.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
