<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713122" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian textile firm to offer 80 mln shares.</title>
<headline>Indonesian textile firm to offer 80 mln shares.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian integrated textile firm PT Sunson Textile Manufacturer plans to offer 80 million shares to the public, or a 22.84 percent stake in the firm, on the local stock exchanges, the float's underwriter said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The company plans to offer 80 million shares on the Surabaya and Jakarta stock exchanges. The offer price is expected to be between 800 and 1,000 rupiah per share,&quot; Avi Dwipayana, president director of brokerage firm PT Trimegah Securities, told reporters.</p>
<p>Trimegah is lead underwriter of the share offering which is expected to be made in August ahead of a September listing.</p>
<p>Dwipayana said the price earnings ratio would be between seven and 10 times, with weighted average earnings per share for 1997 of 115 rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;Approximately 50 percent of the IPO proceeds will be used to pay off bank loans and the rest for business expansion through the purchase of spinning machines with some 18,000 spindles,&quot; Sunson's president director Purnawan Suriadi told reporters.</p>
<p>Sunson posted a net profit of 26.22 billion rupiah in 1996 against 23.60 billion rupiah in 1995.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
