<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713158" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Royalist to try to maintain Cambodia coalition.</title>
<headline>Royalist to try to maintain Cambodia coalition.</headline>
<byline>Sutin Wannabovorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodia's royalist Defence Minister Tea Champat plans to fly to Phnom Penh on Wednesday to try to maintain his party's position in the ruling coalition after fighting that ousted its leader Prince Norodom Ranariddh.</p>
<p>The minister, who has been stranded in Thailand since last Thursday, would fly to Phnom Penh in a chartered plane as the representative of Ranariddh's FUNCINPEC party, aides to Ranariddh told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The prince was deposed as Cambodia's first prime minister by forces of his rival, Second Prime Minister Hun Sen, after heavy fighting in Phnom Penh at the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;Tea Champat is well respected by the soldiers of both FUNCINPEC and Hun Sen's Cambodian People's Party, so he can help calm down the tense confrontation and help end the anarchy in Phnom Penh,&quot; said one of the aides, a senior FUNCINPEC official.</p>
<p>The official, who did not want to be identified, said if FUNCINPEC needed to appoint the someone in Ranariddh's place in the coalition, Tea Champat would be nominated.</p>
<p>Hun Sen says Ranariddh is no longer First Prime Minister but said that the existing coalition between his party and FUNCINPEC would continue although he has demanded the royalists nominate a replacement to Ranariddh who he called a &quot;criminal and traitor&quot;.</p>
<p>The FUNCINPEC official appealed to the international community to help mediate in the conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;We appeal to the United Nations, ASEAN, Japan, France and Australia and others to study the situation closely and come in to create national reconcilation in Cambodia, otherwise we will have a bloodbath,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another close aide to Ranariddh said that Cambodia's membership to the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) should be suspended following Ranariddh's ouster.</p>
<p>&quot;Due to chaos in Cambodia, where the capital is under the rule of anarchy, we are demanding that ASEAN suspend the resolution accepting Cambodia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cambodia was to join ASEAN later this month along with Burma and Laos.</p>
<p>On Tuesday ASEAN called for an immediate ceasefire among Cambodia's warring factions and urged Ranariddh and Hun Sen to respect Cambodia's 1991 peace accords.</p>
<p>ASEAN foreign ministers will hold an emergency meeting on Thursday in Kuala Lumpur to discuss the crisis. Malaysia is currently chairman of ASEAN, which also groups Indonesia, Brunei, the Philippines, Singapore, Vietnam and Thailand.</p>
<p>Hun Sen said in a television speech that the international community should stay out of Cambodia's affairs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
