<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713309" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. encouraged by North Korea's agreement to talk.</title>
<headline>U.S. encouraged by North Korea's agreement to talk.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Progress in dealing with North Korea is slow and unpredictable, but Pyongyang's agreement to talk about easing tensions on the Korean peninsula is encouraging, U.S. officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The isolated communist country has agreed to take part in four-party talks involving North and South Korea, the United States and China and aimed at replacing the armistice from the 1950-53 war with a peace treaty. Preliminary talks are scheduled to be held in New York next month.</p>
<p>In testimony before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee's subcommittee on East Asian and Pacific affairs, officials from the State and Defense Departments also repeated that the United States remained willing to aid famine-struck North Korea, but they made no specific new commitments to food aid.</p>
<p>Asked by Sen. Dianne Feinstein, a California Democrat, whether the United States should be doing more to fight starvation there, U.S. defense official Kurt Campbell said, &quot;We are aware of the humanitarian problem.&quot;</p>
<p>But he noted that last year the North Koreans did not have vast military training and this year &quot;we saw extensive and intensive military training.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;North Korea has made a systemic choice about how they want to use their resources,&quot; Campbell said.</p>
<p>His State Department counterpart, Charles Kartman, said the food crisis created &quot;both opportunities for progress and the danger of greater instability.&quot; He said Washington was encouraged by Pyongyang's commitment to four-party talks.</p>
<p>The Senate hearing fell on the third anniversary of the death of North Korea's long-time ruler Kim Il-sung, known as the &quot;Great Leader.&quot;</p>
<p>His son, Kim Jong-il, became the de facto leader but has not yet taken on all his father's titles. Campbell and Kartman said there were many theories about the delay but no one outside North Korea could be sure about the reasons for it.</p>
<p>&quot;North Korea remains a very opaque country,&quot; Kartman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
