<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713469" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.Y. Gov. and Assembly still at odds over prisons.</title>
<headline>N.Y. Gov. and Assembly still at odds over prisons.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York Gov. George Pataki and the Democrat Assembly Speaker on Tuesday stuck to their guns in a fight over whether the state needs costly new prisons, with the two unable to agree on even basic facts.</p>
<p>Yet the Assembly Speaker, while accusing the Republican governor of holding hostage other proposals in order to build a &quot;prison empire,&quot; held out hope that once that battle was resolved, a budget would start falling into place.</p>
<p>Asked if the state's top three lawmakers were near agreement on changing the welfare system, another big controversy, Sheldon Silver, D-Manhattan, replied: &quot;I think that we are very close to agreement on just about every other issue that's available.&quot;</p>
<p>Silver, who spoke to reporters after meeting the governor and state Senate Majority Leader Joseph Bruno, R-Troy, faulted the governor for holding up property tax relief and education programs, adding economic development and what he called a &quot;real jobs program&quot; also remained outstanding.</p>
<p>Pataki highlighted school tax relief, welfare and resolving an overall spending level.</p>
<p>New York State's budget was due April 1, and it last year set a national record for by failing to approve a pact until July 13. Another leaders' meeting was expected this afternoon, as this one was cut short as Bruno had a members' conference.</p>
<p>Asked who the public should blame, Pataki took himself off the hook.</p>
<p>Saying he had proposed an budget earlier than required, he said: &quot;I think it's quite clear that the Executive is quite limited in what we can do.&quot;</p>
<p>Fiscal monitors say the state's chronic lateness hurts its credit rating.</p>
<p>Pataki, who wants three new, 750-cell prisons to relieve overcrowding, and the Assembly Speaker, could not even agree on the percentage of violent offenders now in prison, with the governor saying it was running at 51 percent, and Silver saying the level was 30 percent.</p>
<p>The two also clashed over why crime rates had fallen.</p>
<p>Pataki said one of the more important reasons was tougher sentencing laws he pushed that were putting more felons behind bars, but Silver focused on programs to put more police officers on the streets, as in New York City. His plan also would help upstate areas pay for such programs.</p>
<p>The governor defended his plan to build new prisons, which would be paid for with $650 million of bonds. Silver has decried it as an attempt to create jobs in upstate areas that are key Republican strongholds and that seemed likely to request them. But Pataki did not rule out some sort of compromise over making more use of county jails.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not to build prisons to build prisons. It's so that violent felons are not turned back on the streets of New York.&quot; Later, he added: &quot;Any proposals that meet the needs of the people of New York are acceptable to me.&quot;</p>
<p>Silver proposed raising how much counties are reimbursed to $75 to $80 a head from the present rate of $35. Noting Pataki's new prisons would not be ready for two years, he said local jails could handle immediate problems with overcrowding.</p>
<p>The Democrat also said the number of state prisoners had fallen to about 17,400 on June 26, down sharply from 20,450 a year-ago. Asked if he looked for more declines, he replied: &quot;Well, it certainly isn't going to increase.&quot; Silver was not opposed to adding capacity though his emphasis differs; he wants 800 maximum security cells and 800 drug treatment beds.</p>
<p>Pataki, however, who said the prisons were running at 133 percent of capacity, praised corrections officials for the accuracy of their projections over the past 2-1/2 years.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
