<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713450" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT wheat closes higher on fund-buying correction.</title>
<headline>CBOT wheat closes higher on fund-buying correction.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fund buying amid signals the market was technically oversold boosted CBOT soft red winter wheat futures to a higher close, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was just grossly oversold and had to correct,&quot; a trader said. &quot;You can go down only so long.&quot;</p>
<p>Wheat recently has been ratcheting to a series of contract lows and three-year lows amid reports of excellent yields in the U.S. winter wheat harvesting region.</p>
<p>Funds Tuesday bought at least eight million bushels of wheat and Cargill Inc sold five million bushels of September and sold two million December, traders said.</p>
<p>Cargill's action probably was hedge selling, the traders said.</p>
<p>The nine day relative strength index (RSI) for the July contract fell to 16.6 percent at Monday's close, a signal the market was extremely oversold. An RSI of 30 or less is considered an oversold market.</p>
<p>Support to wheat futures Tuesday also may have come from forecasts for showers this week in the U.S. winter wheat region which could slow wheat harvesting.</p>
<p>Wheat closed unchanged to 3-3/4 cents per bushel higher, with July up three at $3.16-1/2.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
