<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71351" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Coffee buyers take back seat in Germany.</title>
<headline>Coffee buyers take back seat in Germany.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>German coffee roasters were sidelined again after taking advantage of coffee price falls last week, green coffee traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Futures are headed south as the funds seem to have lost interest and as new crop pressure is building up for January onwards,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is waiting for new lows at 96 cents/lb and is otherwise limited to sporadic spot cover.&quot;</p>
<p>Dec New York arabicas last Friday closed unchanged at 103.60 cents and nearby London robustas were lower on Monday.</p>
<p>Traders said Latin American differentials should fall over the next few months as new crops were entering the supply chain. Colombians had eased from over 20 cents over futures to 12/13 for the fourth quarter and six to seven cents for 1997.</p>
<p>East African differentials should also fall amid competition in generally weak roasted coffee markets.</p>
<p>&quot;There is now a widespread belief that there will be enough green coffee around in 96/97,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Brazil's 96/97 crop is seen at 27-30 million bags and at 30-35 million in 1997/98 and Colombia has enough stocks ready for export.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders saw little market impact from Association of Coffee Producing Countries (ACPC) meetings this week in London, which will include discussions on 96/97 exports.</p>
<p>&quot;I doubt that they can boost the market, given the bearish fundamentals,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps they can hold it in a 90-110 cents range but the real issue is will they allow costly inventories rises at origin.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Consumers are irritated by ACPC retention over the past six months when certain grades were tight and producers were taking advantage rather than managing the crisis,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Sluggish outright business included Colombians, Brazils and East African arabicas. Brazils cost $105 per 50 kg fob, $3 down on the week, Colombia Excelso coffee for Oct/Nov was at $124 after $135 a week earlier and Indonesia cif robustas for October stood at $65, off $3.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
