<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713571" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Communists pledge loyalty to Socialist govt.</title>
<headline>French Communists pledge loyalty to Socialist govt.</headline>
<byline>Emmanuel Jarry</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Communist leaders on Tuesday played down differences with their allies in the Socialist-led government over policies on jobs and European monetary union, saying they remained loyal to the coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;The Communists are an integral part of the majority. Our only ambition is to embody the profound desire for change that is present in our country,&quot; the Communists' parliamentary leader Alain Bocquet told Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin at a meeting at the National Assembly.</p>
<p>The Communists oppose French participation in a planned single European currency, which the Socialists support, and have criticised the government for not moving faster to create jobs and boost the economy.</p>
<p>Jospin told his Communist allies they had to face reality and that the success of the left-wing government depended on continuous political reconciliation between its members.</p>
<p>&quot;The left is confronted with reality and we cannot escape that reality,&quot; Jospin was quoted as saying by his spokesman.</p>
<p>In response to their concerns about employment, the Communists said Jospin had promised to consider suspending public assistance for firms that proceeded with layoffs this summer.</p>
<p>But Jospin stopped short of meeting the Communists' demand that he suspend layoff programmes outright.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to be clear, the law does not permit...suspension of layoff programmes,&quot; he said. &quot;We can't do something the law doesn't allow.&quot; But Jospin told reporters he did not want to see job cut programmes multiply.</p>
<p>Jospin said the government would discuss the issue with unions and business heads to seek &quot;something, perhaps, that respects the need for economic efficiency and at the same time defends salaried employees' rights&quot;.</p>
<p>Bocquet's pledge of loyalty to the coalition government echoed statements by Communist Party leader Robert Hue who denied that party members' criticisms of Jospin signalled that the Communists might desert the coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;Absolutely not,&quot; he said in a broadcast interview when asked whether the criticisms were intended as a warning.</p>
<p>&quot;I consider the Communist Party today to be entirely within its role of a party which participates in the majority and in the government,&quot; Hue told France Inter radio.</p>
<p>The Communists' comments were meant to be constructive suggestions, &quot;to see what can be done right away to move forward&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>In 1984 the Communists split with a Socialist-led government over policy differences, and they refused a role in later Socialist governments under President Francois Mitterrand.</p>
<p>After talks with Jospin on Monday, Hue publicly urged the prime minister to take immediate action to combat France's 12.5 percent unemployment rather than put off decisions on key jobs programmes until the autumn.</p>
<p>Hue said he was not threatening the government, but said that &quot;a serious difference&quot; remained between the Socialists and Communists on the euro.</p>
<p>Meeting the Maastricht treaty criteria for monetary union, which limit public deficits to three percent of gross domestic product, would have &quot;serious consequences in terms of austerity and employment&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>Jospin ruled out more austerity during the campaign, vowing that jobs would be his top priority. But after taking office, he put off until the autumn decisions on how to implement the potentially costly programmes he had promised.</p>
<p>He said keeping these promises would have to await the results of an audit of public finances expected later this month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
