<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713653" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX remains on record trail, breaches 4,000.</title>
<headline>German DAX remains on record trail, breaches 4,000.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares forged ahead on Tuesday as the firm dollar lifted the blue chip DAX index to its sixth record close in a row.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX ended the bourse session up 33.56 points, or 0.8 percent, at 4,006.40 points, comfortably above the psychologically crucial 4,000 point-level for the first time ever.</p>
<p>In later electronic trade, the IBIS DAX index picked up even further to end the late afternoon session at a record 4,030.10 points, spurred on as the dollar stengthened to trade around 1.76 marks in later European dealings.</p>
<p>Prices had initially weakened on profit taking in the pre-bourse session, but dealers said the market had just drawn breath during a giddy ascent and was still in bullish form.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still looking at a solid uptrend,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;The dollar puts everything else, including Wall Street in the shade.&quot;</p>
<p>Nineteen blue chip stocks advanced while 11 fell in bourse dealings.</p>
<p>Electronics and engineering giant Siemens AG hit an all-time high of 110.10 marks during the bourse session amid talk of changes in its GPT telecommunications joint venture but interest waned and the share ended at 108.75 marks, up just 10 pfennigs.</p>
<p>Siemens later said it and GEC were sticking by the present ownership structure for GPT.</p>
<p>Other key gainers included Metro AG, the retailer whose shares surged on Monday after it said it was mulling buying the cash and carry business of Dutch retailer SHV Holdings.</p>
<p>Metro gained another 10.90 marks to 216.40 marks.</p>
<p>Car makers, very dollar sensitive, were broadly higher.</p>
<p>BMW came into focus after the British press said it might sell its Rover small car unit to Chrysler but the German carmaker dismissed the report as nonsense. Its shares ended the bourse session up 24 marks at 1,491 marks.</p>
<p>Volkswagen AG rose 56 marks, or nearly four percent, at 1,491 marks.</p>
<p>The German unemployment report for June had moderate impact on the market. Dealers said there was no impact from the headline figures, which showed a seasonally-adjusted 11,000 rise in June from May, but said the trend indicated that there was little risk of a rise in German interest rates.</p>
<p>On an unadjusted basis, the numbers of Germans out of work fell to 4.22 million in June from 4.26 million the month before.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
