<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71364" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss bank says favouring Mexico for funds.</title>
<headline>Swiss bank says favouring Mexico for funds.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Swiss private Bank Union Bancaire Privee said on Monday it was favouring Mexico over Argentina in asset allocation for Latin America.</p>
<p>In its latest survey of weekly trends, it said good news had been plentiful from Mexico since the announcement during the summer of second quarter growth of 7.2 per cent.</p>
<p>The August inflation figures, at 1.33 pct the lowest since the Mexican financial crisis in January 1995, the national budget surplus and lower interest rates &quot;have strengthened our positive view of Mexico's economy,&quot; the survey said.</p>
<p>Government policy &quot;will stimulate lasting growth, which will be reflected in corporate earnings,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The bank, which specialises in private and institutional asset management, said that in Argentina short-term visibility had deteriorated.</p>
<p>Though macro-economic fundamentals were perfoming well, &quot;political uncertainties are a source of anxiety,&quot; the survey said.</p>
<p>Some populist elements, the bank declared, were using the unemployment and loss of purchasing power hitting ordinary Argentines to hold up the reform process.</p>
<p>The cloudy political perspective had created an unfavourable risk/reward ratio, although parliamentary debates on economic reform in October should provide a clearer picture, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Meanwhile, we are underweighting Argentina in favour of Mexico,&quot; the survey added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
