<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713715" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India train blast latest outbreak of violence.</title>
<headline>India train blast latest outbreak of violence.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bomb blast that ripped through a passenger train in the northern Indian state of Punjab on Tuesday, killing at least 33 people, was the latest violent incident to strike the world's second most populous nation.</p>
<p>Following is a chronology of insurgency-related violence in India over the past 12 years:</p>
<p>June 1984 - Indian army storms Golden Temple in Amritsar, the Sikhs' holiest shrine, to flush out armed Sikh militants, killing about 1,000 people.</p>
<p>October 31, 1984 - Prime Minister Indira Gandhi assassinated at her residence in New Delhi by two Sikh security bodyguards.</p>
<p>November 1984 - Nearly 3,000 people hacked or burnt to death, mostly in Delhi, during anti-Sikh riots.</p>
<p>May 1985 - Sikh extremists set off bombs in and around Delhi, killing 86 people.</p>
<p>June 1985 - An Air-India aircraft explodes and crashes into sea off the coast of Ireland, killing 329 people. Sikh extremists claim responsibility.</p>
<p>July 1987 - Sikh gunmen kill 70 Hindus in Delhi.</p>
<p>June 1989 - Sikh militants gun down 24 fundamentalist Hindus exercising in Punjab park.</p>
<p>November 1989 - Sikh militants kill 21 students outside college near Amritsar.</p>
<p>January 1990 - Indian army fires on demonstrators protesting in Srinagar against a crackdown on long-simmering independence movement, killing 38 and fuelling separatist campaign.</p>
<p>April 1990 - Militants bomb Hindu procession in Punjab, killing 32.</p>
<p>May 1990 - Moulvi Mohammed Farooq, chief Moslem priest of Kashmir, shot by unidentified gunmen. At least 50 people killed when troops fire on mourners bearing his body through Srinagar.</p>
<p>June 1990 - About 30 people killed in violence on sixth anniversary of Indian army assault on Golden Temple.</p>
<p>May 1991 - Some 68 Kashmiri guerrillas killed in shootout with army. Strike called by rebels in Kashmir, 14 killed.</p>
<p>May 21, 1991 - Former Indian prime minister Rajiv Gandhi, who sent troops to Sri Lanka in 1987, assassinated by Tamil suicide bomber in southern India during election campaign.</p>
<p>October 1991 - Two bombs explode in Rudrapur Nainital district of Uttar Pradesh, killing 55 people and injuring more than 100. Punjab militants suspected.</p>
<p>December 1992 - Hindu zealots tear down a 16th-century mosque in the northern city of Ayodhya. Incident triggers sectarian riots across India in which over 3,000 people die.</p>
<p>January 1993 - Militants kill 33 troops in Kashmir. Security forces torch scores of buildings and kill 53 people in retaliation.</p>
<p>March 12, 1993 - Thirteen bombs, thought to be planted by Moslem underworld figures, explode in quick succession around Bombay, killing 263.</p>
<p>August 31, 1995 - Punjab Chief Minister Beant Singh killed with 12 others in car bomb in Chandigarh.</p>
<p>January 3, 1996 - Seven people killed and 35 injured in explosion in teeming market street in New Delhi.</p>
<p>April 27, 1996 - Twelve people killed, 20 injured in bomb blast aboard bus in Modinagar outside Delhi.</p>
<p>May 22, 1996 - Powerful car bomb kills at least 12 people, injures 52 in busy market in South Delhi. Kashmir separatists claim responsibility</p>
<p>Nov 15, 1996 - Left-wing extremists kill 13 policemen and one civilian in a rocket attack on Sirpuru village in southern Andhra Pradesh state.</p>
<p>Dec 3, 1996 - Twelve passengers killed and 37 injured in the explosion in a sleeper coach at Ambala cantonment station near Chandigarh, capital of the northern state of Punjab. No one claims responsibility.</p>
<p>Dec 30, 1996 - Bomb rips through packed train in northeast Indian state of Assam, killing at least 48 people. Police blame Bodo separatist militants.</p>
<p>July 8, 1997 - Bomb rips through passsenger train in north India killing at least 33 and injuring 62.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
