<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="713712" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - July 8.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - July 8.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for REUTERS by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi Tel:3326806, 3326813, 3326849 Fax:+91-11-3351006 E-mail: biznis@giasdl01.vsnl.net.in</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>		     -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			    TOP STORIES</p>
<p>The Hindustan Times</p>
<p>DIFFERENCES OVER ADMITTING NEW FACTION IN RULING FRONT</p>
<p>The ruling United Front's steering committee meeting scheduled for Tuesday was postponed to evolve a consensus on admitting Laloo Yadav's new Rashtriya Janata Dal party to the Front. There is no consensus even within the Janata Dal party on whether the breakaway Rashtriya Janata Dal (RJD) party should be admitted to the United Front. The declared stand of the majority of the constituents of the Front that politicians facing criminal charges should not hold public offices rules out the possibility of the RJD being a constituent of the Front as long as Laloo Yadav remains Bihar state chief minister. Yadav says he is innocent.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Times Of India</p>
<p>SECURITY SOUGHT TO ARREST BIHAR POLITICIANS</p>
<p>The Patna High Court on Monday directed the Bihar state government to declare whether it really feared widespread violence if political executives holding high offices were arrested. The court also asked the government to state whether it was in a position to contain such violence if it occurred. The court order followed a submission by the Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI) that it was unable to arrest the accused since the Intelligence Bureau felt it would lead to violence in Bihar. The CBI told the court it would not delay the arrest of top politicians charged in the fodder scandal if the state government ensured the security of its officers.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>RESERVE BANK APPROVAL NEEDED TO BUY SHARES OF TWO FIRMS</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India has told foreign institutional investors and non-resident Indians that all further purchases of shares of Infosys Technologies and the Housing Development Finance Corporation should be approved by the central bank. This is part of the Reserve Bank's procedure to monitor overseas investments in domestic companies. According to the RBI, the total purchase of the shares of these two companies in the primary and secondary markets has reached 26 percent. Since the maximum permissible limit of such purchases is only 30 percent any more purchase should be done only after the RBI's approval.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>BOMBAY BOURSE INCREASES COMPENSATION</p>
<p>The Bombay bourse has increased the maximum amount of compensation payable under the customers' protection fund for any single customer claimant to 225,000 rupees from 150,000 rupees. The new limit is higher than the limit set by the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI). It is also the highest offered by any bourse in the country, the Bombay Stock Exchange's president said. The customer protection fund was set up to compensate the investing public for defaults. A customer of any defaulting bourse member can file claims within six months from the date on which the member was declared a defaulter.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>STERLITE INDUSTRIES DENIES GAS LEAK REPORT</p>
<p>Sterlite Industries of Tuticorin in Tamil Nadu state has denied reports of toxic sulphur dioxide leaks from its copper smelter plant. Its managing director said there was no leak of any kind from the company. If there was any gas leak, it was surprising that only workers at a nearby factory were affected and nobody at Sterlite's smelter complex was affected, the managing director said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>RESERVE BANK'S EXCHANGE FLUCTUATION RESERVE DIPS</p>
<p>The crash of gold prices in the international market is likely to erode the Reserve Bank of India's (RBI) exchange fluctuation reserve by more than 10 billion rupees. The RBI has already lost about 21 billion rupees on account of the exchange risk on the entire corpus of the $2.1 billion India Development Bonds during January and February this year. The RBI books gains or losses on valuation of foreign currency and gold in a separate account and not in the profit and loss account. The fluctuation reserve can come under pressure if there is an appreciation in the rupee vis-a-vis major currencies or if there is a fall in the price of gold.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>NOKIA ALLOWED TO IMPORT MOBILE HANDSETS</p>
<p>The government has allowed telecommunciations giant Nokia to import cellular handsets through its 100 percent Indian subsidiary for sale in the domestic market. The approval followed an assurance by Nokia to the government that it would set up a local facility for manufacturing cellular telephone handsets. In its application to the Foreign Investment Promotion Board, Nokia said it would import these handsets for two years to test the Indian market and would later decide on setting up a manufacturing unit. The Nokia plans to import the handsets from group companies abroad.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>CRITERIA SET FOR GOLD IMPORTS BY BANKS</p>
<p>Scheduled commercial banks which meet five eligibility criteria set by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) can be nominated agencies to import gold, silver and platinum. According to RBI criteria, a scheduled bank should have a minimum total capital of three billion rupees, a capital adequacy ratio of nine percent, a good risk management system, a good track record in compliance with regulations, and experience in gold-related activities. All applications received before July 31 from such banks will be considered in the first instance and on an ongoing basis thereafter.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>BOMBAY GOLD PRICE FALLS TO NEW FIVE YEAR-LOW</p>
<p>Standard gold price crashed on Monday to 4,335 rupees per 10 grams on the Bombay bullion market. The price of 22 carat gold was quoted 10 rupees lower than Saturday's price at 4,010 rupees per 10 grams. Local gold prices stood at 4,755 rupees in June but lost 420 rupees in four weeks. Gold prices touched a 12-year low in world markets due to fear that central banks might offload more official gold reserves.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>JAPANESE FIRMS BAG MARUTI ORDER WORTH FIVE BLN RUPEES</p>
<p>Car maker Maruti Udyog Ltd placed orders on Monday worth five billion rupees with Kumatsu and Taikisha of Japan for a new press shop and a paint shop. The two firms were chosen through global tenders floated by Maruti Udyog. The two Japanese firms had earlier won similar contracts from the firm.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer</p>
<p>80 PCT IMPORTS VIA GREEN CHANNEL SOON</p>
<p>The government will soon allow 80 percent of imports via the green channel, the chairman of the Central Board of Excise and Customs said. He said the Board was preparing a list of imports, most of them manufacturing goods, that could be exempted from detailed examination by customs authorities. At present only superstar and star trading houses with credible past records are given such exemptions under the green channel facility.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
