<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714069" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent stable at lower levels on Iraq, IEA news.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent stable at lower levels on Iraq, IEA news.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent crude oil were stable at slightly lower levels on Tuesday following bearish reports from Iraq and the International Energy Agency (IEA,) traders said.</p>
<p>August Brent was trading at $18.12 a barrel at 1224 GMT, a fall of seven cents from Monday's close. July gas oil was $1.25 firmer at $162.50 and traders said its rise was a catch-up with Brent, which rallied strongly on Monday after the gas oil market closed.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very neutral,&quot; one broker said. &quot;We are within yesterday's range and that was more or less in Friday's range.&quot;  </p>
<p>Prices dipped initially on Tuesday after the U.N. coordinator in Baghdad said he hoped the world body would receive by 2000 GMT Iraq's food distribution plan under an oil-for-food deal.</p>
<p>The six-month $2 billion plan was renewed a month ago but Iraq's oil exports have been delayed, pending completion of the government's distribution and procurement plans.</p>
<p>Traders also said they thought bearish predictions from the International Energy Agency (IEA) had exerted a little bearish influence.  </p>
<p>The IEA said oil prices would fall further this year as burgeoning supply boosts stocks, despite higher-than-expected gasoline demand in the U.S.</p>
<p>Oil traders were also awaiting weekly U.S. oil industry data, which was expected to emerge on time on Tuesday night despite the Fourth of July holiday in the U.S.</p>
<p>Technical analysts said they saw first important support for Brent at around $18.05, then at $17.96.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 8167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
