<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714175" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Western experts meet in Morocco on $500 mln cocaine.</title>
<headline>Western experts meet in Morocco on $500 mln cocaine.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Drug experts from Europe and the United States met on Tuesday in Rabat to follow the trail of six tonnes of pure cocaine washed up on Morocco's Atlantic coast, a Western diplomat said.</p>
<p>Specialists estimate the drug, the largest amount ever seen in Morocco, has a street value of more than $500 million.</p>
<p>Initial investigations suggest it was thrown overboard when a ship taking it to southern Europe broke down and missed a rendezvous with the vessel due to run it to the Portuguese-Spanish coast.</p>
<p>Countries which sent experts to the meeting, on the invitation from Interior Minister Driss Basri, include France, Spain, Italy, Portugal, Germany, Britain and United States, the diplomat said.</p>
<p>&quot;Drug experts met this morning at the interior ministry headquarters to discuss the seized cocaine and its international implications,&quot; the diplomat, who declined to be named, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the meeting was open-ended and had no precise agenda.</p>
<p>Interior ministry officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>In a statement carried at the weekend on the official news agency MAP, the anti-narcotics team in Basri's ministry said the drug came from Colombia, had been transferred to a ship off Las Palmas and was heading towards the Portuguese-Spanish border.</p>
<p>&quot;The operation was supervised by a Spaniard who ordered the drug be thrown overboard after a machinery breakdown and the failure to rendezvous at sea with another small ship which was to have ensured the recovery of the drug,&quot; said the statement.</p>
<p>It added that with help from foreign agencies and Interpol, Moroccan police were &quot;particularly interested&quot; in a ship which had anchored in the river port of Kenitra, north of Rabat, for repair.</p>
<p>It gave no other detail on whether the ship remained at anchor or had sailed.</p>
<p>British anti-narcotics expert Derek Plumbly, on a visit to Morocco last month as the cocaine was being washed up, said at the time: &quot;One would assume that it was headed for western Europe not Morocco and that something happened at sea.&quot;</p>
<p>Morocco has shown itself particularly concerned in the past two years over drug trafficking which has focused largely on cannabis, much of it produced in the north of the African country just across the Mediterranean from Spain.</p>
<p>Last month, the Moroccan interior ministry announced it had drafted a law increasing the maximum jail term for drug traffickers to 30 years from 10 years, with a maximum fine of 800,000 dirhams ($85,000)</p>
<p>Morocco launched a crackdown on drug smuggling last year, and the interior minister said recently it had seized 103 tonnes of cannabis bound for Europe in 1996. It had also arrested more than 18,000 drug traffickers, including 342 foreigners.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
