<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714478" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Alcatel shares slip on GEC Alsthom float.</title>
<headline>Alcatel shares slip on GEC Alsthom float.</headline>
<byline>Pierre Tran</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Alcatel Alsthom slipped on Tuesday after an annoucement by General Electric Co Plc (GEC) that it wanted to float part of their 50-50 rail and power joint venture.</p>
<p>Dealers had hoped GEC would sell out.</p>
<p>At 1126 GMT, Alcatel shares were 1.26 percent down at 781 francs while the blue-chip CAC-40 index was 0.31 percent lower at 2,938.38.</p>
<p>GEC managing director George Simpson told Reuters in London it and French partner Alcatel Alsthom were considering a London and Paris flotation among their options.</p>
<p>An analyst at a leading French broker estimated the potential market capitalisation of a listed GEC Alsthom at around 45 billion francs ($7.6 billion), making it a sizeable issue of stock.</p>
<p>A flotation will be positive for Alcatel as &quot;it offers an easier, more manageable structure, it will be a more liquid participation and gain a market valuation,&quot; an equity saleswoman at a big French brokerage said.</p>
<p>But if Alcatel had obtained a majority in the venture it would have laid its hands on &quot;an enormous cash machine&quot;, an analyst said.</p>
<p>The 50-50 structure sets limits in developing the business and partners sometimes differ over direction and the need to inject capital. But each is reluctant to dilute its holding relative to the other, brokers said.</p>
<p>However, a flotation, in which both GEC and Alcatel are expected to sell a part of their holdings, would allow an orderly dilution and bring in fresh cash and put a market value on the whole GEC Alsthom business.</p>
<p>The previous French government's rejection of GEC Alsthom's bid for the state-owned nuclear power plant builder Framatome showed the limits of that 50-50 ownership, brokers said.</p>
<p>The conservative administration said GEC's presence in the bid was unacceptable as it would have led to a loss of French control over a strategic industry.</p>
<p>A reduced GEC stake in the joint venture could help relaunch that Framatome bid, a broker said.</p>
<p>GEC's move to demerge, to concentrate on defence and aerospace activities, actually helps Alcatel to realise a long-held ambition to reduce its holding in the joint venture but without losing control.</p>
<p>Market operators are hungry for details of the flotation and want to see how much GEC will put up for sale and whether Alcatel will match it in the sale of stock.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see Alcatel Alsthom dropping out of the newly listed entity, a second broker said. &quot;It will rack up cash instantly. It's too early to say Alcatel Alsthom is losing out massively.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the possibilities is a capital increase which would bring in fresh capital and reduce the present stakes, he said.</p>
<p>But Alcatel is expected to hold a blocking minority stake of about 34 percent, to retain control of GEC Alsthom, which holds sensitive technology on building the TGV high-speed train.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a positive sign in that it accelerates Alcatel's restructuring process,&quot; the second broker said. &quot;GEC Alsthom is well managed but Alcatel Alsthom needs to move up a gear.&quot;</p>
<p>GEC Alsthom contributes substantially to Alcatel's earnings and any dilution of its stake would hit earnings, he added.</p>
<p>Alcatel chairman Serge Tchuruk, appointed in 1995, has started a deep restructuring of the group, which could take a minimum two to three years to show results.</p>
<p>Tchuruk has forecast the group should more than double its operating profit in 1997 from the 1996's 2.9 billion francs. ($ = 5.907 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
