<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714492" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX continues climb to new heights.</title>
<headline>German DAX continues climb to new heights.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares kept on their record trail as bourse trade opened on Tuesday, as the firm dollar continued to fuel interest in export stocks and jobless data supported expectations for stable interest rates.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index was trading up 45.35 points, or 1.1 percent, at a new record of 4,018.19 points at 0856 GMT -- comfortably above the psychologically key 4,000 point level.</p>
<p>Prices had initially weakened on profit taking in the pre-bourse session, but dealers said the market had just drawn breath during a giddy ascent and was still in bullish form.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still looking at a solid uptrend,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar puts everything elese, including Wall Street in the shade.&quot;</p>
<p>Electronics and engineering giant Siemens AG was up 1.25 marks at 109.90 marks amid heavy trade as its partner GEC said it was reviewing the role of GPT, a telecommunications venture between GEC Alsthom and Siemens.</p>
<p>&quot;People are saying Siemens could take a larger role in the unit, and that's got some buyers interested,&quot; a Frankfurt dealer said.</p>
<p>Car makers, very dollar sensitive, were broadly higher.</p>
<p>BMW hit an early high of 1,505 marks after the British press said it might sell its Rover small car unit to Chrysler but BMW dismissed the report as nonsense.</p>
<p>The carmaker was trading up 28 marks at 1,495 marks in bourse trade. Volkswagen AG was up 69 marks, or nearly five percent, at 1,480 marks.</p>
<p>The German unemployment report for June had moderate impact on the market. Dealers said there was no impact from the headline figures, which showed a seasonally adjusted 11,000 rise in June from May, but said the trend indicated that there was little risk of a rise in German interest rates.</p>
<p>On an unadjusted basis, the numbers of Germans out of work fell to 4.22 million in June from 4.26 million the month before.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
