<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714547" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-GEC unveils future, but shares fall.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-GEC unveils future, but shares fall.</headline>
<byline>Edna Fernandes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's General Electric Co Plc on Tuesday unveiled its long awaited strategic blueprint to take it into the next century, putting defence at the heart of the group and signalling a possible float of its rail/power joint venture.</p>
<p>George Simpson, successor to veteran former managing director Lord Weinstock, announced a key shift away from the old GEC culture of joint ventures towards managed businesses and said GEC-Marconi, the defence-electronics division, will become the new &quot;heart of the group&quot;.</p>
<p>But GEC's shares reacted with disappointment, reversing some of the strong gains of recent sessions.</p>
<p>The shares were the biggest FTSE-100 loser, down 20 pence or 5.3 percent at 357.5 pence by 1511 GMT, damped down after hopes of a defence merger were dashed.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, GEC was caught up in a storm of speculation that it might announce news of a defence alliance, or merger talks with British Aerospace Plc (Bae) or Finmeccanica Spa of Italy.</p>
<p>&quot;Sometimes it is better to travel than to arrive,&quot; said one industry analyst. &quot;I thought GEC revealed more than I'd expected. But others had obviously expected concrete deals and did not get them.&quot;</p>
<p>Another analyst said he was &quot;underwhelmed by the review, adding that the timeframe for returning shareholder value was too long term at two to three years. &quot;Another disappointing year for GEC,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Simpson said GEC's new mission statement was &quot;designed to build Marconi into a global player, spanning all three principle defence electronics markets -- America, Europe and the East -- and to focus the group's industrial electronics and communications activities on existing or potential global leadership positions.&quot;</p>
<p>The future of GEC's two main joint ventures was placed under review. Simpson told Reuters that GEC and its French partner Alcatel Alsthom were considering floating their 50-50 rail and power venture GEC-ALSTHOM on the London and Paris stock exchanges.</p>
<p>&quot;We have looked at whether to demerge or float the business and that is the subject of discussion,&quot; Simpson told Reuters. &quot;On a personal basis, I think it is best.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the float option was &quot;very tax efficient&quot; and would enhance shareholder value. GEC expects a decision within the next three months. If agreed, the float could take between six and nine months to implement.</p>
<p>Explaining the rationale, Simpson said, &quot;That business has become very large. It is beginning to outgrow its parent.&quot;</p>
<p>Analaysts estimated such a float could raise a total of between three and three and a half billion pounds ($5 billion), to be split by the partners.</p>
<p>GEC is also considering &quot;repositioning&quot; its telecoms joint venture GPT which is 60 percent-owned by GEC and 40 percent-owned by Siemens AG.</p>
<p>Simpson said he had thought about selling the telecoms stake, but rejected it. &quot;Clearly one option was to sell our stake to Siemens. But I am driven by shareholder value. We will monitor the business and rewrite the charter for that business, as telecoms is a high growth area which GEC should remain in.&quot;</p>
<p>GEC said it was now committed to spending its huge cash pile -- valued by Simpson at over two billion pounds -- on investment and acquisition opportunities.</p>
<p>But he said that he was also willing to gear up if necessary. &quot;We are not averse to gearing up GEC. The mere fact that I will now do that is a very significant change in GEC's policy,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Under Weinstock, GEC traditionally maintained a highly cautious capital structure, with high levels of net cash.</p>
<p>The first call on the cash is now investment. But Simpson made clear that he would not shy from returning cash to shareholders if he ccould find suitable buying opportunities.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can consummate deals I may not be able to return any cash to shareholders. But if there is no way forward on deals, I will return cash,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The review comes against a backdrop of mounting pressure for the European defence industry to consolidate after mega-mergers seen in the U.S. between Lockheed Martin Corp and Northrop Grumman Corp plus Boeing Co and McDonnell Douglas Corp.</p>
<p>Simpson said he was aware of the need to bolster its defence position, but added that GEC-Marconi's order book was at record levels and &quot;I'm not under desperate time pressure to act.&quot;</p>
<p>He said, &quot;We are looking at Siemens Plessey (Siemens defence arm which is up for sale) and talking to Finmeccanica...&quot; He said he wanted to &quot;do these things first&quot;.</p>
<p>But he added &quot;I am sensitised to the situation with BAe and talk to them regularly as well as to Thomson-CSF in France.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly in time something will happen in European consolidation and GEC must be part of it.&quot;</p>
<p>GEC also announced its annual results, with pretax profits of 1.01 billion pounds before charges in line with forecasts.</p>
<p>However, Simpson warned that as a major exporter the strength of sterling was beginning to bite. It took 19 million pounds off profits last year and could take 45-50 million pounds off profits this year, he said. ($ = 0.594 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
