<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714560" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore renews magazine permit after ads cut.</title>
<headline>Singapore renews magazine permit after ads cut.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore said on Tuesday it had renewed the publication licence of a local magazine, reversing an earlier decision not to renew the permit due to government objections to lewd advertisements.</p>
<p>&quot;We have renewed the licence,&quot; a spokesman for the Ministry of Information and the Arts (MITA) said.</p>
<p>The renewal followed IS Magazine's agreement to adhere to strict guidelines and will come into effect on July 12.</p>
<p>The spokesman said MITA had considered the appeal from the free fortnightly publication to renew its permit and had informed the publisher.</p>
<p>MITA said earlier this month that IS Magazine had flouted guidelines issued by the ministry by printing objectionable items. It was found to have published telephone numbers offering phone sex, lewd ads and ads which promoted homosexuality.</p>
<p>The magazine's permit was not renewed when it expired on June 12.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the ministry decided to renew the licence after a meeting with the magazine's publisher and staff, who gave an assurance that the personal advertisement column would be dropped and guidelines on sexual content in local publications would be adhered to.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision was made following a meeting with IS Magazine, when IS gave an assurance that stringent editorial control will be exercised over the magazine to ensure no flouting of the ministry's guidelines in future,&quot; the spokesman said, in a written reply to queries from Reuters.</p>
<p>Singapore practises censorship and imposes restrictions on the media in various areas to protect what it views as basic values. Magazines such as Playboy, Penthouse and Cosmopolitan are not allowed in the city state.</p>
<p>The publisher of IS magazine, Gretchen Worth, welcomed the ministry's decision.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very happy to be back,&quot; Worth said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The personals section was popular among readers, but it was advertising, not editorial, and in reality it represented very little revenue to the company.&quot;</p>
<p>She said the magazine had had hundreds of calls from readers, advertisers and distributors offering their support and wishing the magazine a quick return.</p>
<p>IS Magazine is published by Hong Kong-based company Asia City Publishing Group and has an audited circulation of 25,000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
