<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714763" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASIAN EXOTICS - Regionals dampened by dollar bulls.</title>
<headline>ASIAN EXOTICS - Regionals dampened by dollar bulls.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>* Baht eased on strong commercial demand for the dollar</p>
<p>* Ringgit pressured but supported by fears of Bank Negara's presence to cap dollar rise at 2.5250</p>
<p>* Rupiah softens after government's deregulation package did not contain any band widening</p>
<p>* Singapore dollar stays weak on U.S. dollar demand.</p>
<p>* Taiwan dollar weak but off lows on central bank intervention</p>
<p>* Peso takes breather, seen at desired range. No signs of central bank intervention</p>
<p>Bulls dominated the U.S. dollar on Tuesday, pressuring most Asian currencies and prompting efforts by some central banks to shore their currencies.</p>
<p>Almost a week since the Thai government announced a managed float exchange rate system, the baht remained weak against the dollar amid persistent commercial demand for the dollar.</p>
<p>Local importers and foreign loan borrowers who needed the the dollar for payment on imported goods and loan repayments were among dollar buyers, dealers said.</p>
<p>The baht was trading at 29.130/230 against the greenback compared to 28.90/29.00 on late Monday.  </p>
<p>The Bank of Thailand set its reference rate at 28.922 to the dollar against 28.578 on Monday.</p>
<p>In the offshore market, the baht traded at 28.700/900 against 28.50/80 on Monday.</p>
<p>Dollar buying by hedge funds pressured the ringgit but upside on the dollar was capped by fears of Bank Negara's presence at 2.5250 ringgit to the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a lot of buying of dollar by hedge funds but Negara is waiting at the 2.5250 level. It will be very tight today, maybe 2.5240/50,&quot; said a delaer with a Eruopean bank in Singapore.  </p>
<p>At 0400 GMT, the ringgit was trading at 2.5240/50 to the dollar.</p>
<p>Indonesian rupiah softened against the dollar. Singapore operators were buying dollars after Indonesia's economic deregulation package did not contain the widely-speculated widening of the dollar-rupiah band, removing some of the arguments for going short in dollars.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no fresh factor to trade on. The package contains nothing about the band,&quot; the dealer said, adding that players were covering part of their short dollar positions.  </p>
<p>Spot rupiah was at 2,433.0/33.5 at 0225 GMT, compared with an opening of 2,431.00/31.75. Tomorrow and today rupiah was at 2,432.75/33.10 and 2,432.25/32.75, respectively.</p>
<p>Analysts said sentiment remained positive because the deregulation package could stimulate the stock market which had posted several record highs in the past few days.</p>
<p>A dealer in Singapore said overall trading was quiet, with a biddish tone on the dollar against the baht seen causing a slight weakening of the rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a quiet day. In the swap market, rates are trapped in a narrow range because of a two-way market,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The Singapore dollar weakened further on continued dollar buying by U.S. funds, dealers said.</p>
<p>The local currency briefly tested 1.4385 before firming to 1.4372/82 at 0400 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;It's moving in tandem with dollar/yen,&quot; said a dealer with a local bank. He added he did not expect further firmness in dollar/Sing unless dollar/yen rises sharply.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the Taiwan dollar remained weak but recovered from an eight-year low against the greenback after the central bank emerged to fend off speculation.  </p>
<p>After hitting a low of 27.935 to the dollar, the Taiwan dollar was seen trading at 27.912/915 to the dollar at 0400 GMT. It was expected to range between 27.90-94 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Philippines peso stablised after recent hectic trade following Thailand's move to a managed float exchange rate system. The peso traded within a tight range of 26.383/385 in the morning. There was no evidence of intervention by the central bank on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Syed Azman in Kuala Lumpur (603-206 2323), Mantik Kusjanto in Jakarta (6221 384-6364), Anuchit Nguyen in Bangkok (662) 652-0642 and Angela Tan in Singapore (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
