<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714889" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean businesses see won at 881.50 by yr-end.</title>
<headline>S.Korean businesses see won at 881.50 by yr-end.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean businesses expect the local currency to rise to 881.50 won against the dollar by the end of the year, a survey by the Federation of Korean Industries (FKI) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The won was trading at 887.80/90 on Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>The FKI, a powerful lobby group representing the nation's biggest conglomerates, or chaebols, attributed the forecast to a shrinking trade deficit. South Korea posted a trade surplus in June, the first since December 1994.  </p>
<p>Foreign fund inflows attracted by further capital market liberalisation would also boost the won, it said. The survey also showed the Japanese yen climbing to 111.50 versus the dollar by the end of this year. The yen was trading at 113.08/18 at 0445 GMT.</p>
<p>A rise in the U.S. trade deficit with Japan was likely to boost the yen, it said.</p>
<p>The federation said 49.5 percent of those surveyed said South Korean products were weaker than the Japanese in terms of price competitiveness.  </p>
<p>&quot;The yen needs to strengthen to at least 110 for South Korean products to gain competitiveness against Japanese products,&quot; said an FKI official.</p>
<p>But 45 percent of respondents said South Korean goods were stronger than those from all countries except Japan in terms of price competitiveness, it said.</p>
<p>In all, 300 export companies in manufacturing were surveyed, and 77 percent responded.</p>
<p>--Seoul Newsroom (822) 727 5643</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
