<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714893" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Chubu Elec to halt nuclear plant.</title>
<headline>Chubu Elec to halt nuclear plant.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chubu Electric Power Co Inc said on Tuesday it will halt development of its 2.7 million kilowatt nuclear power plant project in central Japan at least until the end of 1999, complying with requests from the local government.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our firm has decided to comply with the requests from the governor of Mie prefecture on the Ashihama nuclear power plant,&quot; Hiroji Ota, president of Chubu Electric, said in a statement released on Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Mie governor Masakazu Kitagawa on Tuesday morning met with Chubu Electric officials and asked for the withdrawal of Chubu employees from the towns of Kisei and Nanto, which would effectively halt further progress on the power plant project.</p>
<p>Chubu plans to build the Ashihama plant, with two 1.35 million kw reactors, on the border of the two towns by 2007.  </p>
<p>In an effort to unify the two towns' stance towards the project, the prefectural government of Mie is planning to set up study groups to discuss energy issues and ways to revitalise the local economy without relying on government subsidies given out to towns which house nuclear power plants.</p>
<p>Currently, Nanto is against, while Kisei is in favour of the nuclear power plant project, an official for the Mie prefectural government said.</p>
<p>Chubu Electric currently operates four nuclear reactors, with a total power generation capacity of 3.6 million kw at its Hamaoka nuclear power plant in Shizuoka prefecture on the Pacific coast.</p>
<p>The number five reactor at the Hamaoka plant, with capacity of 1.38 million kw, is slated to start commercial operation in August 2005.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Energy Desk +81-3-3432-8837</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
