<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714829" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodia clashes spread, foreigners airlifted out.</title>
<headline>Cambodia clashes spread, foreigners airlifted out.</headline>
<byline>Robert Birsel</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of foreigners scrambled aboard Thai military aircraft on Tuesday to flee Cambodia's capital Phnom Penh, but scores were trapped in the country's main tourist town by fighting in the north and northwest.</p>
<p>Phnom Penh, scene of weekend fighting between forces loyal to the country's co-premiers which claimed at least 58 lives, was quiet.</p>
<p>But markets, shops and offices remained closed after a night broken by bursts of apparently random rifle fire.</p>
<p>Fighting between forces backing Second Prime Minister Hun Sen, who now controls Phnom Penh, and troops loyal to First Prime Minister Norodom Ranariddh broke out overnight near the northern town of Siem Reap, home to the fabled Angkor Wat temple complex, a western source in the town said.</p>
<p>Local officials in the northwest of the country said there were also clashes near Sisophon, close to the Thai border.</p>
<p>Police in the southern port city of Sihanoukville said rival forces were confronting each other there.</p>
<p>The Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) on Tuesday called for an immediate ceasefire, declaring it was &quot;dismayed by and deeply regrets the unfortunate turn of events in Cambodia, resulting in the loss of innocent lives, both of Cambodian citizens and of foreigners&quot;.</p>
<p>Cambodia, along with Burma and Laos, was scheduled to join the seven-member ASEAN later this month, but the collapse of the troubled coalition headed by Ranariddh and Hun Sen has thrown this in doubt. ASEAN foreign ministers plan a special meeting on Thursday in Kuala Lumpur to discuss the situation.</p>
<p>Some 300 foreigners, most of them Thai, were evacuated from Phnom Penh on three Thai Air Force transport planes on Tuesday morning and a similar number were set to leave when the aircraft made return flights later in the day.</p>
<p>Those who alighted from the first plane when it returned to Bangkok were seen wearing yellow ribbons on their wrists as identification tags.</p>
<p>The western source in Siem Reap said fighting nearby forced cancellation of plans for a convoy on Tuesday to evacuate scores of tourists, as well as many aid workers, to the Thai border, 150 km (90 miles) to the west.</p>
<p>&quot;There's fighting outside of the city and a lot of troop movements,&quot; the source in Siem Reap said. He said there was fighting on the road between the town and the Thai border and land mines had been planted on it.</p>
<p>Siem Reap itself was quiet on Tuesday morning after the overnight fighting, which occurred when forces loyal to Ranariddh were withdrawing from Siem Reap to join comrades nearby.</p>
<p>&quot;Last night the remaining FUNCINPEC forces were able to extricate themselves from the town after a two-day standoff,&quot; the western source said, referring to Ranariddh's men. Five soldiers loyal to Hun Sen were wounded in the fighting, he said, citing a military official loyal to the Second Prime Minister.</p>
<p>Siem Reap town was under the control of Hun Sen forces, while large areas of the surrounding countryside were held by Ranariddh troops.</p>
<p>Hun Sen's forces have long outnumbered those under Ranariddh in Phnom Penh and in the east. The First Prime Minister's forces have greater strength in the north and northwest of the country.</p>
<p>Khmer Rouge guerrillas, with whom Ranariddh was negotiating peace before the fighting erupted, control remote countryside in the far north while a powerful faction of Khmer Rouge defectors controls territory along the Thai border in the west.</p>
<p>The Phnom Penh fighting began on Saturday after Hun Sen's troops moved against Ranariddh's men.</p>
<p>Hun Sen said he had to take action as Ranariddh, who left Cambodia on the eve of the fighting for Paris, was trying to smuggle Khmer Rouge defectors into the city to boost his troop strength.</p>
<p>Parts of Phnom Penh were engulfed in the fighting at the weekend before Ranariddh's men fled, leaving Hun Sen in control.</p>
<p>Hun Sen announced in a Sunday night radio broadcast that the prince, son of King Norodom Sihanouk who is now in Beijing, was no longer First Prime Minister. Ranariddh denounced the move as a coup and told reporters in France he was organising resistance.</p>
<p>Officials loyal to Hun Sen said in Phnom Penh on Tuesday that a powerful Ranariddh loyalist, Ho Sok, a secretary of state in the Interior Ministry, had been arrested the previous day.</p>
<p>One political source said he feared a roundup of officials from Ranariddh's FUNCINPEC party was imminent.</p>
<p>There were still no official casualty figures from the two days of fighting and a subsequent day of looting and random violence in the capital. A police source said preliminary investigation showed there were 58 deaths, both combatants and civilians, and as many as 200 wounded in the violence. Phnom Penh hospital sources said most casualties were civilians caught in crossfire and one city centre hospital said it was caring for 77 wounded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
