<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714943" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan outlines strict 98/99 budget guidelines--MOF.</title>
<headline>Japan outlines strict 98/99 budget guidelines--MOF.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto on Tuesday outlined strict guidelines for budgetary requests by ministries and agencies in a bid to put the state budget back on its feet, Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka said.</p>
<p>The guidelines, introduced at Tuesday's cabinet meeting, were in line with numerical targets for a wide range of spending cuts for the 1998/99 budget, which were endorsed last month by the government, Mitsuzuka said.</p>
<p>Government ministries and agencies are expected to follow the guidelines when they submit their budgetary requests at the end of August for 1998/99, starting next April 1, ministry officials said.  </p>
<p>After the budgetary requests are presented, the government will compile a state budget plan for fiscal 1998/99 and submit it to an ordinary session of parliament due to open in January.</p>
<p>In outlining the guidelines, Hashimoto also announced special allocations totalling 550 billion yen for the 1998/99 budget. They are outside the budgetary requests by government agencies, and will be used for public works projects and other areas that need an increase in spending, Mitsuzuka said.</p>
<p>The special allocations will be made up of three items -- 150 billion yen to improve Japan's distribution system, 250 billion yen to raise people's living standards by improving infrastructure such as sewerage systems, and 150 billion yen for environmental preservation and the improvement of technology and telecommunications.</p>
<p>Japanese media have reported that the creation of the special outlays, which would require approval by the prime minister, was seen as an effort by Hashimoto to ease some criticism by politicians in his own party for his avowed policy of putting uniform caps on budgetary requests.</p>
<p>In the belt-tightening scheme to reduce Japan's budget deficit in 1998/99, the government is seeking to cut public spending by seven percent and official development assistance by 10 percent.</p>
<p>Mitsuzuka said foreign aid expenditures will be allocated with special consideration given to &quot;the priority and effectiveness&quot; of the projects.</p>
<p>Hashimoto's fiscal reforms are aimed at keeping next year's general expenditures 0.5 percent below this year's levels.</p>
<p>Hashimoto has set fiscal reform as one of his top policy goals to live up to his pledge of slashing the government deficit to three percent or less of gross domestic product (GDP) by 2003.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
