<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="714970" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodia capital quiet as Thais prepare mercy flight.</title>
<headline>Cambodia capital quiet as Thais prepare mercy flight.</headline>
<byline>Robert Birsel</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodia's capital Phnom Penh was calm on Tuesday morning after a night broken by occasional bursts of rifle fire, but the shooting suggested random looting rtather than fresh conflict in the aftermath of the weekend's fighting.</p>
<p>Thailand prepared to fly aircraft into the city to take its citizens home, a day after forces under powerful second prime minister Hun Sen pushed troops loyal to ousted first prime minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh out of the city.</p>
<p>Phnom Penh authorities lifted an 8 pm to 6 pm curfew on Monday afternoon but the streets of the capital were tense and largely deserted after a day of chaotic scenes and looting.</p>
<p>At least 13 people have been killed in the fighting and one government official said the toll was as high as 150.</p>
<p>There were intermittent bursts of rifle fire throughout the night but the reason seemed to be looting or indiscipline and not conflict between the country's rival premiers.</p>
<p>A Thai military spokesman in Bangkok said an air force transport plane would make eight flights into the city's airport on Tuesday to take as many as 700 people to Thailand.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to use the word 'evacuate',&quot; an embassy official in Phnom Penh said. &quot;We are offering a service to those who would like to return. We give them the facts and let them decide whether to stay or go.&quot;</p>
<p>Phnom Penh airport has been closed since early on Saturday when fighting between troops loyal to the country's two prime ministers erupted in the city. A Cambodian civil aviation official said on Monday that the airport should reopen with two days.</p>
<p>The airport was stripped of all equipment and ransacked during looting on Monday, a senior aviation official said.</p>
<p>There were reports that the airport runway had been damaged by shelling but the Thai official said the transport plane coming in from Bangkok could land safely.</p>
<p>Tourists and aid workers in the northern town of Siem Reap were preparing to drive in convoy to Thailand on Tuesday, reporters in the town said late on Monday.</p>
<p>Siem Reap, home of the Angkor Wat temple complex, was quiet but tense and scores of expatriates were expected to make the 150 km (100 miles) drive to the Thai border town of Aranyaprathet, the reporters said.</p>
<p>About 100 expatriates, mostly aid workers, have already left Cambodia's second city Battambang, in the north-west, for Thailand.</p>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard said Australia would closely monitor developments in Cambodia and remained prepared to evacuate Australians if the situation in the troubled Southeast Asian nation worsened.</p>
<p>He said Hun Sen's military takeover was &quot;revolutionary&quot;, but would not rule out eventually recognising his new government.</p>
<p>&quot;Hun Sen is not the authorised government...and obviously his behaviour has been, how shall one put it, of a revolutionary kind,&quot; Howard told reporters in northern Queensland.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously you have to wait and see how this situation unfolds and you have to mix a presumption of legitimacy against realism,&quot; said Howard, referring to Australia's future position towards the Hun Sen government.</p>
<p>Howard said Australia was disappointed at the breakdown of the 1991 Paris peace accords that ended three decades of war and civil strife in Cambodia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
