<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="715143" id="root" date="1997-07-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia to launch benchmark bonds in Sept.</title>
<headline>Malaysia to launch benchmark bonds in Sept.</headline>
<byline>Madhav Reddy</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia will launch a series of benchmark bond issues starting September in an effort to revitalize a moribund corporate debt market, government and industry sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The long-awaited bond issues, to be launched by the government's investment arm Khazanah Holdings Bhd, will provide a price peg for corporate debt issues and an accurate interest rate expectations graph, the sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The issues have almost been finalised and it is certain that we will launch in September,&quot; a senior government official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Khazanah has planned to launch a three-year Islamic bond of 500 million ($198.41 million) to one billion ringgit in September, to be followed by a series of varying maturities of five, seven and 10 years.</p>
<p>A government-backed benchmark would provide a standard for the market against which other bonds could be priced or traded, analysts have said.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point of time one cannot even draw a yield curve, because it is fairly distorted and not in line with the market because of demand-supply imbalance,&quot; C. Rajandram, chief executive of Rating Agency Malaysia (RAM) said.</p>
<p>The benchmark bond issue was announced in the government's annual budget for 1997 in October last year.</p>
<p>Targetted for launch in the first quarter of this year, the launch of the bonds has been delayed due to protracted debate over their structuring, the sources said.</p>
<p>In an article in its monthly newsletter for June, RAM said, &quot;the proposed Khazanah benchmark issues will take the form of zero-coupon Islamic bonds based on the Al-Murabahah principles.&quot;</p>
<p>Under Islam's Sharia principles, business should be done on the basis of sale and purchase of assets. Giving loans by charging interest is considered usury.</p>
<p>Al-Murabahah refers to sale and purchase of goods at a price with built-in profit.</p>
<p>RAM said the aim of the issues was to provide risk-free debt papers over a range of maturities.</p>
<p>&quot;Through active market-making and trading of these bonds, a yield curve can then be constructed to serve as a bellwether for interest rate expectations and as a benchmark for the pricing of other bond issues,&quot; it said in the article.</p>
<p>Establishment of a benchmark bond issue would also help Malaysia achieve its aim of introducing more derivative instruments, including bond futures contracts.</p>
<p>Malaysia's bond market is languishing due to a declining supply of tradeable government paper as large infrastructure projects are increasingly privatised.</p>
<p>However, these infrastructure projects also required funding from the debt market. The government has estimated that Malaysia needs some 536 billion ringgit over the next five years to fund the large number of projects in the private and public sectors.</p>
<p>From 1991 to 1995, funds raised in the bond market increased by 21 percent to 32.4 billion ringgit compared with the previous five-year period.</p>
<p>Last year, Malaysian companies issued bonds totalling over 13 billion ringgit against 9.27 billion ringgit in 1995.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
<p>($1=2.52 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
