<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="715470" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Motorola sees 6-8 pct chip industry growth.</title>
<headline>Motorola sees 6-8 pct chip industry growth.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Motorola Inc said Wednesday it still expects a modest improvement in the worldwide semiconductor industry in 1997, but now sees growth of about six to eight percent versus 1996.</p>
<p>In a conference call with analysts, Motorola said it reduced its industry growth forecast from the 10 percent it estimated after the company's first quarter.  </p>
<p>Ed Gams, head of Motorola's investor relations, said the United States and Asian regions are the strongest, but less semiconductor industry growth is seen in Japan, where the market is affected by the strong U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>Gams said the pullback in the company's estimate is due in part to the effect of the strong dollar. Translating foreign sales into U.S. dollars reduces the overall growth rate.</p>
<p>He said industry growth in chips used in communications and automotive applications will be double-digit, but the company expects all other sectors to show single-digit growth.  </p>
<p>Late Tuesday, Motorola reported second quarter net earnings of $0.44 a share versus $0.54 a share last year. Excluding a $170 million pretax charge for its exit of the struggling dynamic random access memory (DRAM) business, earnings were $0.62 a share, easily beating the analysts' consensus estimate of $0.56 a share, according to First Call.</p>
<p>In its semiconductor division, Motorola reported sales were up 12 percent versus the first quarter and orders rose 18 percent. Gams said semiconductor prices were generally stable, and it is reasonable to expect its segment's operating margins will improve.  </p>
<p>Motorola's percentage interest in Iridium LLC, which plans a global satellite-based telecommunications network, has decreased to about 21 percent from 24 percent, as other investors entered the the consortium.</p>
<p>Twelve of the planned 66 satellites are already in orbit and are performing well, Gams said, and another five were launched today.</p>
<p>&quot;Motorola expects to record an expense of approximately $65 million in 1997 in recognition of its share of Iridium LLC's net loss for the year,&quot; Gams said, adding the expense will be concentrated in the second half of the year and is due largely to depreciation of launched satellites.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1998, Motorola expects to record a level of expense recognition of its share of Iridium LLC losses that is several times greater than the $65 million expected in 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gams said that in 1999 and beyond, however, Motorola expects to recognize few or no Iridium losses, as Motorola writes down its equity investment in Iridium.</p>
<p>The pager group is continuing to be hit by tight inventory controls by paging operators, Gams said, and Motorola expects that will continue into 1998. Second quarter pager and sales orders were significantly lower than last year, it said.</p>
<p>((--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
