<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="715537" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-DALY PULLS OUT OF OPEN DUE TO PERSONAL PROBLEMS.</title>
<headline>GOLF-DALY PULLS OUT OF OPEN DUE TO PERSONAL PROBLEMS.</headline>
<dateline>TROON, Scotland 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>John Daly, the 1995 British Open champion, has withdrawn from this year's event saying he needs to look after his &quot;personal health and well-being&quot;, organisers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Daly has been having treatment after returning to his former alcoholic habits and his withdrawal from next week's open at Royal Troon was not unexpected.</p>
<p>The American sent a letter to Michael Bonallack, secretary of the Royal and Ancient Club which runs the Open, confirming his withdrawal.</p>
<p>He had not played since he pulled out after nine holes of his second round in last month's U.S. Open at the Congressional Club near Washington and there was a question mark then over whether he would play at Troon.</p>
<p>He said then he was suffering from &quot;physical and mental fatigue&quot;.</p>
<p>His letter to Bonallack said he was &quot;saddened and discouraged not to be in the British Open this year. But my personal health and well-being require me to be elsewhere.</p>
<p>&quot;I look forward to returning to the British Open next year,&quot; Daly added in the letter.</p>
<p>Daly burst into prominence when he won the U.S. PGA title in 1991 after being the ninth alternate in the field and without a practice round on the Crooked Stick course.</p>
<p>It became apparent later that he had an alcohol problem.</p>
<p>He managed to give up drinking and in 1995 won the British Open at St Andrews in a playoff with Italian Costantino Rocca.</p>
<p>Daly had two months of rehabilitation in the Betty Ford Clinic before he signed a new contract with the Callaway Golf Company in May with the condition that he continue to participate in a structured care programme to deal with his alcoholism.</p>
<p>He returned to the Tour two weeks before the U.S. Open and made the cut both times.</p>
<p>But after pulling out at Congressional, he said: &quot;Even though I thought I was going to be strong enough to come right back and play three straight weeks on tour, I found out I was wrong. I just started feeling real weak after a few holes today and by the time I got to number nine I was physically exhausted.&quot;</p>
<p>He said then that he would take several weeks off and would embark on an intensive fitness programme, working with a nutritional specialist and a physical fitness expert.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROON, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
