<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="715534" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: CYCLING-MINALI EDGES WIN AS ANOTHER ACCIDENT HITS TOUR.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-MINALI EDGES WIN AS ANOTHER ACCIDENT HITS TOUR.</headline>
<byline>Mike Price</byline>
<dateline>LE PUY-DU-FOU, France 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian sprint specialist Nicola Minali sneaked a photo-finish victory in the fourth stage of the Tour de France as another crash, this time involving a spectator, marred the cycling classic on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Banesto's Spanish rider Vicente Garcia-Acosta, in his first Tour, followed Swiss veteran Tony Rominger, victim of a mass pile-up on Tuesday, out of the race after a crash and was taken to hospital in Nantes.</p>
<p>Garcia-Acosta and Italian Fabiano Fontanelli, who was later able to continue the race, both crashed into a woman spectator on the edge of the road around the 90-km mark. The woman, who suffered a serious head injury, was also taken to hospital.</p>
<p>A Banesto team official said: &quot;It's a big loss as he is a useful rider on all terrains.&quot;</p>
<p>Minali, who won a stage in Portsmouth, England in the 1994 Tour, edged out Frenchman Frederic Moncassin with Germany's Erik Zabel third after the 223-km leg from Plumelec covered in five hours 46 minutes 42 seconds.</p>
<p>Zabel's placing, worth a deduction of eight seconds, cut back the overall lead of Italian Mario Cipollini to four seconds.</p>
<p>Cipollini and Zabel, wearing the points leader's green jersey, fought throughout the stage for the time deductions at the three intermediate sprints with the German taking two seconds more than the Italian.</p>
<p>In the final charge, Cipollini finished fourth and out of the fight for a share of 30 seconds in deductions. But he still holds the overall leader's yellow jersey he has has worn since winning the first stage on Sunday.</p>
<p>A disappointed Moncassin said: &quot;I was strong in the sprint but it was Minali who took it in the end. Yesterday it was Zabel and before that Cipollini. I'm really disappointed.&quot;</p>
<p>Moncassin, France's best hope of a stage win in the flat early stages of the Tour, has edged ever closer without a victory.</p>
<p>&quot;I've come fourth, third, second today. I've taken all the sprint placings and I've only got one left, the best,&quot; said Moncassin, winner of the first stage in 1996, as he described his finishes in the last three stages.</p>
<p>&quot;I was really fine in this sprint, good in my legs. It was a finish that suited me well.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd like to win in Bordeaux (in Saturday's seventh stage,&quot; he added, recalling his second victory in the 19th stage in 1996.</p>
<p>The stage started at an easy pace, averaging 32 km/h, and after the crash at 90 kms, Rominger's Cofidis team mate Philippe Gaumont made a solo break that 100 kms from the finish had him a remarkable 11 minutes 20 seconds ahead, virtually the time by which he trailed Cipollini.</p>
<p>But the peloton recovered the pace of the previous stages and with 50 kms to go, Gaumont held a mere 3.50 minutes lead before being reined in and disappearing into the anonimity of the huge peloton.</p>
<p>With Cipollini holding the slimmest of leads, Thursday's fifth stage over 261.5 kms to Chatre should feature a sprinters' battle for his yellow jersey.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LE PUY-DU-FOU, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
