<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="715617" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: SLOVAK PRESIDENT BLAMES GOVT FOR NATO EXCLUSION.</title>
<headline>SLOVAK PRESIDENT BLAMES GOVT FOR NATO EXCLUSION.</headline>
<byline>Jan Krcmar</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Michal Kovac on Wednesday put the blame for Slovakia's exclusion from invitations to join NATO squarely on Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar and his government.</p>
<p>&quot;(The exclusion) is an expression of the non-acceptance of NATO member states of the policy of the current government coalition,&quot; Kovac said in a statement issued by his office.</p>
<p>&quot;It marks the failure of the government programme and is also a clear rejection of the principles and practices applied by the current ruling power in Slovakia,&quot; the president added.</p>
<p>The Bratislava daily Sme quoted Meciar as saying the decision to invite Poland, Hungary, and former federation partners the Czech Republic to start negotiations for entry to NATO was not objective.</p>
<p>&quot;It must be said that many states applied different measures in assessing eligibility for membership -- one for themselves, another for our neighbours, and another for us,&quot; Meciar was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Slovakia has repeatedly come under fire from the United States, NATO allies, and the European Union for alleged foot-dragging on democratic reforms and creating a transparent economy -- warnings Meciar has patently rejected.</p>
<p>Meciar and Kovac have been fierce enemies since the president helped oust Meciar in 1994 in a parliamentary vote of no confidence, only to have him return after winning general elections later that year.</p>
<p>An official government statement published in the pro-government daily Slovenska Republika made no mention of Slovakia's exclusion in Tuesday's NATO communique.</p>
<p>But it reiterated the government line expressing its willingness to continue cooperation with the alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;Slovakia will continue its intensive cooperation both with current NATO members but also with those central and eastern European countries invited at the Madrid summit to start talks on entry to the alliance,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>While NATO's official declaration agreed in Madrid left the door open to all European countries who fulfil NATO's requirements for membership, it made special reference to Romania and Slovenia as potential candidates.</p>
<p>&quot;We recognise with great interest and take account of the positive developments towards democracy and the rule of law in a number of southeastern European countries, especially Romania and Slovenia,&quot;</p>
<p>Nothing was said about Slovakia, despite the republic's one-time frontrunner status soon after its split with the Czech Republic in 1993.</p>
<p>Opposition parties' reaction to the apparent snub placed the on Meciar's government.</p>
<p>&quot;It is definitely clear that the (Meciar) government is unable to guarantee either the security of Slovakia or its future free existence, and has become a permanent obstacle for the integration efforts of Slovakia,&quot; a joint statement of the opposition parties said.</p>
<p>But Meciar allies have rejected saying the NATO dseciusion was biased.</p>
<p>&quot;This puts to shame those who took this decision,&quot; Eva Zelenayova, a parliamentary deputy for Meciar's Movement for a Democratic Slovakia (HZDS), told the independent radio Twist.</p>
<p>Slovak military leaders said on Wednesday that they would continue to participate in the alliance's Partnership for Peace (PfP) programme which sets up training and joint exercises with non-member countries.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sorry and sad, but not frustrated,&quot; Slovak Chief of the General Staff General Jozef Tuchyna told a news conference.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
