<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716103" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: ICA seen reporting weaker Q2 revenues.</title>
<headline>ICA seen reporting weaker Q2 revenues.</headline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's biggest construction company Empresas ICA is expected to report weaker second quarter revenues compared to the same period a year earlier, analysts said.</p>
<p>The analysts did forecast that per share earnings could be higher in the second quarter than a year earlier, depending on how the company recorded the sale of an asset.</p>
<p>&quot;The company has been very straightforward by telling us the numbers are not going to be good, and I don't believe there is any possibility for negative surprises,&quot; said Chris Hussey, an analyst with Goldman Sachs in New York.</p>
<p>Six analysts consulted by Reuters found average expectations of net profits of 1.76 pesos per share in the second quarter compared to 1.41 pesos per share in the second quarter of last year.</p>
<p>The expected large increase in the second quarter could be tied to extraordinary earnings, they said.</p>
<p>The company is seen posting a decline in revenues of 11.4 percent, to 1.785 billion pesos in the second quarter compared with 2.015 billion pesos in the second quarter of last year.</p>
<p>The company is also seen posting operating profits of 118.2 million pesos percent in the second quarter, an increase of 39.7 percent from the 84.6 million pesos in the second quarter a year ago.</p>
<p>ICA obtained about $35 million from the sale of its part of Mexpetrol, but analysts said that it was not clear whether the company would report these revenues in the quarter.</p>
<p>That uncertainty caused a wide variation in the estimates for earnings per share in the quarter.</p>
<p>But analysts added they did not expect the earnings to be spectacular.</p>
<p>&quot;If you were an investor who had not monitored the industry for a while... and suddenly you woke up and saw ICA, you would say nothing great is going on for this company,&quot; said Hussey.</p>
<p>Analysts said the expected decline in year-over-year revenues in the second quarter had already been discounted.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that it has already been discounted, and I don't think that people are betting it will be otherwise,&quot; said Sebastian Chatel, an analyst with Caspian Securities.</p>
<p>The probable shrinkage in backlog is another negative factor for the company in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;The backlog could be similar or a little higher than in the first quarter of the year, but for ICA to generate the sales that it wants to, it needs more backlog,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>ICA's backlog is seen at 705 million pesos in the second quarter of this year compared with 725 million pesos a year earlier, according to the average forecast by the six analysts.</p>
<p>((--Daniel Perez, Monterrey newsroom, +528 345 7617))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
