<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716199" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian drug capo re-sentenced after appeal.</title>
<headline>Colombian drug capo re-sentenced after appeal.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian drug baron Miguel Rodriguez Orejuela was sentenced, after a partially successful appeal on Tuesday, to 21 years behind bars for sending a 300-pound (135 kg) cocaine shipment to the United States, local radio reported.</p>
<p>Rodriguez, who headed the infamous Cali drug gang with his brother Gilberto, was originally sentenced to 24 years for the crime but had three years shaved off the term after a &quot;faceless,&quot; or anonymous, judge partially upheld his appeal, the Radionet radio network said. Justice officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Both brothers were convicted of other drug offences earlier this year and were sentenced to terms that would in practice see them walk free within six years, sparking uproar at home and abroad over the laxness of Colombian justice.</p>
<p>Once his first sentence and the 21-year term are combined, Miguel Rodriguez, the former No.2 in the Cali cartel, will technically be facing 30 years jail but could be free in much less in return for for good behaviour and voluntary study while in Bogota's maximum-security La Picota prison.</p>
<p>Rodriguez, who was captured in mid-1995, confessed to drug trafficking and received substantial sentence reductions granted under Colombian law for those who cooperate fully with justice.</p>
<p>He failed to admit, however, to sending the 300-pound load of cocaine to Tampa, Florida, via Costa Rica before his capture -- thereby getting the additional 21-year term finalised Tuesday, according to Radionet.</p>
<p>Rodriguez's lawyers maintain their client was lured into a trap because the man who purchased the illicit consignment ultimately proved to be an undercover Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) agent.</p>
<p>Under new legislation passed by Congress earlier this year, drug traffickers face up to 60 years in jail although the law cannot be applied to crimes committed before the date the law was passed -- thereby ruling out tougher sentences for the Rodriguezes.</p>
<p>The DEA estimate the Cali cartel was responsible for 80 percent of the world's cocaine supply and believe the Rodriguezes amassed personal fortunes of several billion dollars each.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
