<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716290" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Caltex to slow down Cambodia investment.</title>
<headline>Caltex to slow down Cambodia investment.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>American firm Caltex Petroleum Corp will slow investment in Cambodia pending its reassessment of the volatile political situation there, said regional vice-president Jock McKenzie on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The company has an investment of $20 million in Cambodia, including 12 service stations and an oil terminal in the western province of Sihanoukville.</p>
<p>&quot;It's rather small compared to our overall portfolio. If anything, we will probably slow down the investment. It's a bit early to make judgement as it's not really that clear what would be the ultimate outcome of the political upheaval there,&quot; McKenzie said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we will sign an agreement to set up a new service station tomorrow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Weekend fighting in Cambodia resulted in Second Prime Minister Hun Sen ousting First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh. There also was wholesale looting and violence in Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>McKenzie said one Caltex station was damaged and its first convenience store in Phnom Penh was looted just after its two-week debut.</p>
<p>He said that before the weekend fighting, Caltex had been considering investing more in Cambodia in a bid to capture 20 percent of the oil market share.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
