<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716245" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>EAST TIMOR: Organic farming boosts East Timor coffee growers.</title>
<headline>Organic farming boosts East Timor coffee growers.</headline>
<byline>Jim Della-Giacoma</byline>
<dateline>ERMERA, East Timor</dateline>
<text>
<p>Elias Pereira, a coffee grower in the misty hills of East Timor, is cheerful as he stands with a sack of freshly picked, cherry-red beans.</p>
<p>Like hundreds of his neighbours harvesting the local Arabica hybrid in the mountain districts of this former Portuguese colony, the 38-year-old is an enthusiastic convert to the new-age concept of organic farming, although his fields are devoid of many of the trappings of modern agriculture.</p>
<p>&quot;We're happy to accept the organic farming programme as it's very beneficial for us,&quot; Pereira said when he visited a selling point in the moutainous Ermera district, about 30 miles southwest of the capital Dili, with bags of coffee beans. Under a U.S.-funded organic coffee-growing programme, farmers receive more money for their harvest than for normal coffee and do not have to go through the rigours of fermenting, drying and milling the beans.</p>
<p>Officials in charge of the project funded by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) say it is a &quot;win-win&quot; situation -- the farmers are getting paid more to do less, while the consumer gets to taste a new exotic blend that is 100 percent organic and of guaranteed quality.</p>
<p>&quot;Before, we used to process the coffee ourselves using traditional methods, but now we just pick it and sell and receive a better price,&quot; Pereira said.</p>
<p>Previously, the 30,000 coffee-farming families on East Timor would pick the beans and let them ferment out of control, inevitably decreasing the coffee's taste and quality, until they had enough to pulp it on a small hand-driven mill.</p>
<p>It would then be dried on any flat space, such as a road or village square, where it would be picked at by chickens and trodden on by goats. Once dry, it would be stored in variable conditions under a hut, sometimes for months, until taken to the nearest village to sell when money was needed.</p>
<p>Now, certified organic farmers, who carry a small yellow registration card, take freshly harvested beans to the hundreds of weighing stations in the area within 12 hours of being picked.</p>
<p>The coffee is already popular for blending with other beans, and Timor organic coffee is being used by coffee retailer Starbucks Corp.</p>
<p>Farmers receive more than 1,000 rupiah (41 cents) per kilogram (2.2 pounds) for their &quot;cherry,&quot; at least 20 percent higher than if they sell the dried and ground &quot;parchment&quot; on the local market using the old method.</p>
<p>The cherry is then &quot;wet processed&quot; and dried in a chemical-free and quality-controlled environment at one of three renovated Portuguese-era processing plants in the Timor hills.</p>
<p>The coffee is then sent to Dili, where it is milled, cleaned, sorted and stored under strict conditions to maintain its organic integrity before being exported as &quot;ready-to-roast&quot; green bean.</p>
<p>&quot;By doing this, the same coffee that's always been produced in East Timor is getting an increase of between 20 and 40 percent in the fob (free on board) price,&quot; said project adviser Tony Marsh, referring to the price excluding freight and delivery.</p>
<p>Ironically, the lack of modern agricultural implements and methods in East Timor has made the region's coffee plantations ideally suited to organic farming.</p>
<p>&quot;Farmers just embraced the whole concept and we really haven't had to do much pushing at all,&quot; said Australia-based Marsh.</p>
<p>Twenty years of armed struggle against Indonesian rule in East Timor have meant the thousands of hectares (acres) of coffee trees first planted during the 400 years of Portuguese colonialism were neglected.</p>
<p>Marsh said the neglect has meant coffee has been grown almost &quot;wild,&quot; mostly by smallholders, rather than in carefully tended plantations with artificial inputs such as fertilisers and pesticides.</p>
<p>&quot;The coffee on the trees of East Timor is a good-quality coffee, similar to the coffees of Central America,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ERMERA, East Timor"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EAST TIMOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
