<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716392" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei futures end down but above lows.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei futures end down but above lows.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Nikkei futures ended weak on Wednesday amid poor sentiment on the underlying cash market where banking stocks were hit by bad debt concerns after last week's news of a construction firm's financial failure.</p>
<p>The lead Nikkei 225 September contract ended 190 points down at 19,695 after falling as low as 19,500.</p>
<p>&quot;When it broke through 19,570, it went down to 19,500 fast and I thought it would test 19,200,&quot; a trader at a Japanese brokerage said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Most people were disappointed today because foreigners started with sell orders in the cash market despite the Dow finishing up yesterday,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said the market could rebound to 19,800-19,900 level on Thursday, which would provide a good opportunity to go short again.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking at weakness in the Nikkei. I don't see why we would go above the 20,000 level again soon,&quot; a dealer with a U.S. investment house said.  </p>
<p>He said vague rumours about the failure of a regional Japanese bank and the dollar's weakness against the yen had contributed to the Nikkei's decline.</p>
<p>On Taiwan futures, the July contract ended 2.6 points higher at 398.1 on volume of 1,709 lots.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
