<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716360" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Top Philippine banks raise prime lending rates.</title>
<headline>Top Philippine banks raise prime lending rates.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines' top five commercial banks have raised their prime lending rates to as high as 21 percent following the sharp increase in the Central Bank's overnight rate, bankers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Metropolitan Bank and Trust Co, the largest commercial bank, increased its prime rate to 21 percent from 16 percent last week, a treasury official of the bank said.</p>
<p>Last month, the bank was quoting 13.25 percent for loans to its big corporate clients.</p>
<p>The loan rates are quoted on a per annum basis, and most of them are repriced every three months, depending on the prevailing bellwether Treasury bill rates.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can't get borrowers at this rate, we will just put it in the overnight facility of the Central Bank,&quot; the Metrobank official said.</p>
<p>The Central Bank raised its closely watched overnight borrowing rate to 30 percent on Monday from 26 percent after a fresh speculative attack on the Philippine peso.</p>
<p>The move drove Treasury bill rates up by as high as 150 basis points.</p>
<p>Bank of the Philippine Islands, a leader in corporate banking, said it had raised its prime lending rate to 19 percent from 14.5 percent.</p>
<p>Its &quot;super&quot; prime rate was increased to 18 percent from 13.5 percent. The super prime rate is reserved for the most valuable corporate clients, the treasury official said.</p>
<p>Far East Bank and Trust Co likewise raised its prime rates to between 18 to 20 percent from the previous week's 13 to 15 percent.</p>
<p>Philippine Commercial International Bank increased its prime rate to 21 percent from 18 percent, while its super prime rate was raised to 19 percent from 16 percent.</p>
<p>The prime rate of Philippine National Bank was the lowest at 16.5 percent, which was set on July 4. It was at 15 percent before that.</p>
<p>PNB is 49.8 percent owned by the Philippine government.</p>
<p>A senior PNB treasury official said the bank would raise its rate sometime this week.</p>
<p>-- Manila Newsroom (63 2) 841-8938 Fax 817-6267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
