<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716314" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: S. Korean bonds back in favor as economy improves.</title>
<headline>S. Korean bonds back in favor as economy improves.</headline>
<byline>Angi Li</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean bonds and notes issued in foreign currencies are gradually coming back in favor after six months of listless interest amid signs the Korean economy is getting back on track, bankers in Hong Kong said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is time to book Korean assets,&quot; one syndicate manager in Hong Kong said.</p>
<p>Bankers said there is growing demand for Korean debt issues with ratings in the &quot;A&quot; category, especially for those that have the same rating as the sovereign.</p>
<p>South Korea's foreign currency debt is rated A1 by Moody's Investors Service and AA-minus by Standard and Poor's Corp.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, A1-rated Housing and Commercial Bank launched a floating rate note issue that paid an all-in return of 35 basis points over the London Interbank Offered Rate for an effective tenor of one year.</p>
<p>The issue's generous pricing and an improved attitude toward South Korean credits should assure that the issue attracts good demand, bankers in Asia said.</p>
<p>Traders said Korean floating rate notes and certificates of deposit were attracting a better bid in Asia. They said the increased interest has not yet been reflected in any significant narrowing of spreads, but that some tightening is expected.</p>
<p>&quot;Korean floating paper is certainly on a tightening track,&quot; a trader at a European bank said.</p>
<p>In the more liquid U.S. market, fixed rate bond issues of Korean borrowers have tightened considerably.</p>
<p>For example, Korea Development Bank's 10-year Yankee bond has tightened to 82/83 basis points over comparable U.S. Treasury bonds from 88/89 basis points a week ago.</p>
<p>The positive comments from bankers contrast sharply with much harsher remarks made earlier this year.</p>
<p>Sentiment on Korea turned sour at the start of 1997 following a massive default on debt repayments by Hanbo Steel, the flagship company of Korean conglomerate Hanbo.</p>
<p>While bankers stopped short of saying they were bullish on Korea, many said that at least things had improved.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no bad news yet and we don't expect further bad news at least in short term,&quot; one banker said.</p>
<p>One factor driving the cautious enthusiasm is an improvement in the country's economic prospects, bankers said.</p>
<p>Last week, South Korea reported a trade surplus for June of US$97 million, its first surplus since December 1994 and a sharp departure from the US$426 million deficit recorded in June 1996.</p>
<p>On Monday, the government forecast a second-half growth rate of 6.3 percent, a downward revision from its previous estimate but still much better than the 5.6 percent clip of first-half 1997. For the year, the government sees growth of 6.0 percent.</p>
<p>Korea grew 7.1 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade surplus for June is definitely a positive sign that the South Korean economy is improving,&quot; said NatWest Markets economist Arthur Woo.</p>
<p>But Woo added that he believed that the government's growth predictions are too optimistic.</p>
<p>Prior to the Hanbo crisis, Korean credits were eagerly sought by international investors, particularly after the country was accepted to join the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) last December.</p>
<p>Under Bank for International Settlements rules, debt paper issued by OECD member country banks qualifies for 20 percent rather than 100 percent risk weighting, making it more lucrative for other banks to hold.</p>
<p>Bankers said the allure of Korean paper continues to be heightened by the fact that, like other Asian credits, it pays a premium to similarly rated issues of European borrowers.</p>
<p>&quot;After all, you can hardly find such high-yielding OECD paper. Investors looking for a grade A credit will naturally turn to Korea,&quot; a European banker said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843-6371</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
