<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716437" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sears expands home improvement business growth bid.</title>
<headline>Sears expands home improvement business growth bid.</headline>
<byline>Melissa George</byline>
<dateline>HOFFMAN ESTATES, Ill.</dateline>
<text>
<p>At a time when Americans spend more time each week watching &quot;This Old House&quot; on TV than shopping at the mall, Sears, Roebuck and Co. is pushing hard to expand its home improvement business.</p>
<p>Sears is tapping the rise in demand for service among ageing baby boomers and expects revenues at its Home Services division to grow to $10 billion from $3 billion in five years.</p>
<p>Many retailers, including Sears itself, have opened furniture and houseware stores to snare more customers. But Sears is now fishing for customers who want to fix up their homes instead of buy merchandise to put in them.</p>
<p>&quot;The business is growing faster than retail,&quot; said Jane Thompson, president of Sears home service division. &quot;More and more spending will be in the services to the home than the sales of product into the home.&quot;</p>
<p>Sears already is the biggest player in the home improvement market. Still much of the $160 billion industry is in the hands of store-front operators. These businesses lack a recognisable name brand, and Sears believes it can grab a bigger share by offering more improvement services, such as kitchen remodeling, and by buying competitors and forming alliances. It also is pouring $60 million into a marketing campaign this year.</p>
<p>Sears, the nation's second-largest retailer, needs new growth vehicles as sales at its old-line department stores slow. While a $4 billion store remodeling programme started in 1993 sparked steep sales increases at its mall stores, the pace of gains has begun to slow.</p>
<p>Same-store sales, or sales at stores open a year, are expected to rise just 2 percent in the second quarter compared with 9.4 percent in the same quarter last year.</p>
<p>Sears' focus on home service comes at a time when consumers are devoting little time to shopping. These days, the average shopper spends just 50 minutes in the mall each week, said the International Council of Shopping Centres.</p>
<p>&quot;When you hit age 45, you stop buying product and start buying service,&quot; said Peter Schaeffer of Dillon, Read &amp; Co. Inc.</p>
<p>Sears' home improvement business brings about a third of the Home Services division's revenues. The rest comes from appliance repair and product warranty sales.</p>
<p>To meet its ambitious growth targets, Sears is expanding. In one test market, it is doing complete kitchen and bath remodeling jobs. Its plumbers and electricians, who used to handle only simple jobs, are tackling larger projects such as home rewiring and sewer maintenance.</p>
<p>&quot;We're stretching to see how complicated we want to get,&quot; Thompson said.</p>
<p>Some experts say Sears' sales goals are lofty, especially since it is pulling together such a large network of independent contractors to handle the work. The more involved the projects get, the more risks Sears faces.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very labour-intensive,&quot; said David Sauer, publisher of Qualified Remodeler magazine. &quot;You can turn over a roofing project real quick. (Remodeling jobs) are longer-term. There's a tremendous amount of inter-play with the customer.&quot;</p>
<p>Sears got out of the home improvement business four years ago during a restructuring that eliminated 50,000 jobs, shed 113 stores and closed its big-book catalogue. Shortly afterward, it resumed the work, using a network of licensees.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know about the $10 billion (revenue target),&quot; said Thomas Tashjian of Montgomery Securities. &quot;But I do know there's significant opportunity there.&quot;</p>
<p>The business has fatter profit margins than retailing. At Sears, the Home Services division's operating margins already are above the 5 percent average for the rest of the company and should rise above 10 percent in 1998, Thompson said.</p>
<p>Sears also is hunting for acquisitions, although acquired companies will not be its main source of growth, she added.</p>
<p>Thompson expects revenues to climb to $6.5 billion or $7 billion from $3 billion without the aid of acqusitions. But to meet its ultimate goal of $10 billion in revenues, the company will need to swallow outsiders.</p>
<p>Earlier this year Sears bought Orlando, Fla.-based All America Termite and Pest Control Inc. for an undisclosed sum.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOFFMAN ESTATES, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
