<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71640" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Traders call for sharp cut in Oman official price.</title>
<headline>Traders call for sharp cut in Oman official price.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Term lifters of Oman crude are calling for a sharp cut in the official selling price of the oil to bring its value back into line, traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Oman official selling price has been too high for far too long and there are other crudes that are cheaper,&quot; a trader at a major said.</p>
<p>Traders said the monthly price set by the Oman Ministry of Petroleum and Minerals (MPM) needed to be cut 20 cents per barrel to reflect the crude's true market value.</p>
<p>&quot;They need to drop it at least 20 cents,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>For several months, the MPM price has been set at close to $1.00 over Dubai, which traders said has made it increasingly difficult to sell.</p>
<p>Trading for September barrels saw a last minute rush by the market to absorb an overhang. And with the trading focus already moving onto November liftings, traders said the October overhang is worse with as many as four/five cargoes yet to trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything I look at says dreadful,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Whether you sell the crude within your own system or to the market makes no difference. An affiliate has to justify the purchase. Whether you lose money within your own group or in the market makes no difference,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>Traders said buyers were bidding at MPM less 20 cents per barrel, compared with the last deal done at MPM less 11.5 cents. Until mid September, most Oman barrels for October had traded at MPM plus two to four cents per barrel.</p>
<p>Most Oman crude is sold in term contracts at premiums to the MPM price. Such term contract buyers who want or need to resell the crude into the spot market have to do so at a loss.  </p>
<p>A major has offered Oman at November Dubai quotes plus 85 cents -- equivalent to MPM less 10 or 11 cents -- so the liquid Dubai market could exert a stronger influence over the price.</p>
<p>Part of Oman's marketing problem has been that many refineries in Asia are facing tight or negative margins on medium grade crudes, such as Oman.</p>
<p>But they are achieving good margins on light sweet crudes because they are rich in the middle distillates currently in demand ahead of the winter season.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65 870 3081)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
