<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716578" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Arlington, Texas, council drops golf course plan.</title>
<headline>Arlington, Texas, council drops golf course plan.</headline>
<dateline>ARLINGTON, Texas 1997-06-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arlington's council on Wednesday struck down a proposal for a golf course as part of a development plan along a city creek, but will push on with other features of the project totalling about $130 million, Mayor Elzie Odom said.</p>
<p>&quot;The project is not dead in any way, it is alive and well. Only the golf course proposal has been dropped,&quot; Odom told Reuters.</p>
<p>The proposal to build an 18-hole golf course was included in a broader plan for flood control and recreational and economic development along the 11-mile long Johnson Creek which runs north-south through Arlington, which lies between Dallas and Fort Worth.</p>
<p>But the golf course proposal was strongly opposed by some local residents. It would have required demolishing about 600 homes and other structures, adding between $70 million and $100 million to the total cost of the project.</p>
<p>Odom said the city has still not decided how the money for the flood control and development effort would be raised. He said options include a sales tax hike, a general obligation bond issue, private investment, or a combination of all.</p>
<p>&quot;We have appointed a new committee to draw up plans for implementing the project and to determine how it will be financed. Right now, our estimates put the cost at about $130 million but that is very preliminary,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pete Jamieson, assistant director of Arlington's parks department, said city officials plan to meet next week with the flood control committee.</p>
<p>&quot;It'll be a sort of kickoff for the whole project,&quot; he said. &quot;Once the financing aspect is decided, I think we can start implementing the project by late next year or early 1999. The J.C. corridor plan is probably the best opportunity we have to improve the quality of life for the whole city.&quot;</p>
<p>Arlington is home to the Texas Rangers baseball team, which last year took first place in the American League's Western Division.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARLINGTON, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
