<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716681" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow Jones net income down sharply in second quarter.</title>
<headline>Dow Jones net income down sharply in second quarter.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dow Jones &amp; Co. said Wednesday its second-quarter profits fell nearly 33 percent, with operating income at its troubled financial information unit virtually disappearing.</p>
<p>Second-quarter net income dropped to $34.9 million, or 36 cents a share, compared with $52 million, or 54 cents a share, in the same quarter last year.</p>
<p>Dow Jones, which publishes The Wall Street Journal and Barron's, saw an increase in operating income from its print publications and television operations.</p>
<p>But operating profit at its financial information services unit -- which includes Dow Jones Markets, Newswires and Global Indexes -- fell nearly 100 percent to a barely break-even level of $169,000, compared with $40.3 million a year ago. Revenues dipped 4.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;While the results at our Dow Jones Markets unit continue to adversely affect earnings, our plan for reinvigorating that unit remains right on track,&quot; said Dow Jones Chairman Peter Kann.</p>
<p>Dow Jones announced in January that it planned to invest as much as $650 million over the next three years to strengthen the unit, formerly known as Telerate. Some Wall Street money managers who have taken sizeable stock positions in the company, including Michael Price, have pushed the company to sell or spin off the unit.</p>
<p>Kann said at the shareholders meeting in April that the company had considered selling the unit, merging with another company or shrinking the size of the business before finally deciding to make the $650 million investment.</p>
<p>Overall operating income fell about 15 percent in the second quarter to $78 million from $92 million in 1996, while revenues rose nearly 2 percent, to $641 million from $631 million.</p>
<p>Operating income at its business publishing segment, which includes its print publications and television operations, rose 54 percent, to $68.1 million from $44.2 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
