<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71686" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore sets plan to end telecom monopoly.</title>
<headline>Singapore sets plan to end telecom monopoly.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore announced its plans on Monday for ending Singapore Telecommunications Ltd's (SingTel) monopoly by allowing at least one other operator into the business.</p>
<p>Communications Minister Mah Bow Tan said a two-stage tender process would decide who would be allowed to compete against SingTel on basic telecommunications services, including local and international phone calls, from 1 April, 2000.</p>
<p>He said the licences to be awarded would also include services for voice telephony, lease circuits, public switched message and data services.</p>
<p>Mah said the first stage of the process would be a pre-qualification exercise held on March 1 1997. The second, for short listed candidates, would be in September 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The results of the main tender are expected to be announced in mid-1998. The successful licensee or licensees will have around 18 months before the licence commencement date of April 1 2000 to build, roll out and test their networks and services,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Singapore government had said in May it would bring forward the opening of its basic telecommunication services to April 2000 from its original date of 2007.</p>
<p>It said then that SingTel would be paid compensation of S$1.5 billion by March 1997.</p>
<p>SingTel was begun as a state enterprise, then turned into a public corporation three years ago and all Singaporean adults were offered shares in it at a discount.</p>
<p>The government's investment company, Temasek, still holds more than 80 percent of the shares.</p>
<p>Mah made the announcement at the signing ceremony for the formation of the Singapore One Infrastructure Consortium.</p>
<p>The consortium, led by the Telecommunication Authority of Singapore (TAS), is being formed to bring wide-spread multi-media services and applications to Singapore.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
