<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716815" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Ex-premier Haughey admits he received a million.</title>
<headline>Ex-premier Haughey admits he received a million.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Irish Prime Minister Charles Haughey admitted for the first time on Wednesday that he received more than a million Irish pounds from a chain store tycoon whose revelations forced a cabinet minister to resign.</p>
<p>Lawyers for Haughey told a payments-to-politicians tribunal that the money was channelled to him through a solicitor of Ben Dunne, a member of the family that owns the Dunne's Stores department store chain.</p>
<p>The admission marked an about-turn by Haughey, prime minister of Ireland three times until the early 1990s, who had hitherto, through lawyers, denied receiving money.</p>
<p>Haughey said in a statement read out by his legal team that he had misled them about the money but they had agreed to continue to represent him.</p>
<p>&quot;In making this statement I wish to make clear that until yesterday I had mistakenly instructed my legal team,&quot; his statement said.</p>
<p>It acknowledged receipt of 1.3 million Irish pounds ($2 million) from Dunne's solicitor and said the money had been raised by Des Traynor, a prominent Irish entrepreneur who is now dead.</p>
<p>The statement also admitted that Haughey had been given three cheques by Dunne in 1991 worth a total of 210,000 pounds made out to third parties.</p>
<p>&quot;I accept Mr Dunne's evidence that he handed me the 210,000 at Abbeyville in November, 1991,&quot; Haughey's statement said.</p>
<p>Dunne, who was dropped from the family business five years ago, told the tribunal earlier this year that he had given Haughey money because he had financial problems.</p>
<p>Haughey publicly led a lavish lifestyle while in office, earning him the title &quot;Champagne Charlie&quot; in the tabloid press. He was regarded until recently as a kingmaker in the Fianna Fail party, Ireland's biggest and most powerful political party.</p>
<p>The tribunal was set up after media reports said Dunne had given former Transport Minister Michael Lowry a quarter of a million pounds to renovate and extend his home.</p>
<p>Lowry subsequently resigned and was not accepted as a candidate by the Fine Gael party at elections on June 6. He stood as an Independent and won his parliamentary seat.</p>
<p>The tribunal has been told that virtually all political parties received cash from Dunne at one stage, mainly for campaigning. There has been no suggestion that the money was given in return for political favours.</p>
<p>But is has raised calls from politicians for an investigation into the funding of political parties and new rules to cover donations to public figures. ($ = 0.658 Irish Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
