<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="716999" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US official says probe eased doubts on Boeing merger.</title>
<headline>US official says probe eased doubts on Boeing merger.</headline>
<byline>David Lawsky</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>An American antitrust official said Wednesday he had once believed the Boeing -McDonnell Douglas merger was problematic, but an investigation showed McDonnell Douglas was not a major competitor.</p>
<p>But the official, Bill Baer of the Federal Trade Commission, was quick to note that European and U.S. competition authorities sometimes reach different conclusions.</p>
<p>The FTC gave unconditional clearance this month to the $14 billion merger of Boeing Co. and McDonnell Douglas Corp., after finding McDonnell Douglas alone would be too weak to compete for commercial aircraft sales.</p>
<p>&quot;When I first looked at this transaction I thought it was one that we would likely challenge,&quot; Baer said in an appearance at the United States Information Agency Foreign Press Centre.</p>
<p>But Baer, who heads the FTC's competition bureau, said his view changed after a careful review of the facts.</p>
<p>&quot;McDonnell Douglas Aircraft is not a significant competitor today and, indeed, is likely to be less significant tomorrow, down to the point of zero (so) there's not a basis for acting.&quot;</p>
<p>Baer said the FTC had to &quot;make a judgment whether we thought this transaction really involved a significant competitor -- Douglas Aircraft -- or somebody that was in sort of a death spiral, and we reached the latter conclusion.&quot;</p>
<p>The European Union is now in a critical stage of its own review of the merger, with a final vote set for July 23. Baer declined to recommend what the EU should do, noting that although competition authorities in Europe and the United States have friendly relations they sometimes reach different conclusions.</p>
<p>He cited the merger of Swiss drug giants Ciga-Geigy and Sandoz to create Novartis. The deal received approval from European competition authorities. Nonetheless, the Federal Trade Commission required a record $1 billion divestment as a condition of the deal.</p>
<p>In the Boeing case, the Europeans have expressed a concern that the merger would increase U.S. government subsidies to the firm through increased military contracts.</p>
<p>The Europeans say a 1992 agreement that is supposed to limit such subsidies has not done the job. Working level negotiators will discuss the 1992 agreement at a regularly scheduled meeting in Washington Thursday and Friday. NOVZn.S MD.N BA.N</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
