<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717061" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Frankfurt, Milan, Paris stocks roar ahead.</title>
<headline>Frankfurt, Milan, Paris stocks roar ahead.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks in Frankfurt, Milan and Paris roared ahead on Wednesday encouraged by another record close overnight on Wall Street but London lagged behind, hit by worries over higher interest rates.</p>
<p>On currency markets, the dollar was largely unchanged against the yen, shrugging off a sharp rise in Japan's current account surplus, and was steady against the mark though slightly off 41-month highs seen in early trade.</p>
<p>In precious metals, gold prices were fixed at near 12-year lows as a rally from the low levels set on Monday was weakened by fresh selling from both speculators and, some dealers said, Australian gold producers.</p>
<p>The German and Italian bourses were the best performers in morning trade, both hitting trading peaks. Paris also climbed strongly but London, Europe's biggest stock exchange, made only modest gains.</p>
<p>Frankfurt set a cracking pace, climbing over one percent to a trading high of 4,066.09 points on the blue-chip DAX index, propelled by the stronger dollar and record-breaking run on Wall Street.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to be nothing around to brake us at the moment,&quot; said a Frankfurt trader. &quot;The dollar is giving us a push, Bunds (government bonds) are helping, the U.S. is helping and there are no negative corporate stories out there. I don't see any justification for pulling out, even at these highs.&quot;</p>
<p>In Milan, stocks soared to an intra-day record as bullish sentiment took a firm grip on the bourse amid growing expectations that Italy will qualify for the first round of membership of the European single currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Money is pouring in and it looks like we could see a substantial rerating of Italy,&quot; said an equities specialist with a foreign finance house in Milan.</p>
<p>The all-share Mibtel index jumped to a peak of 13,913, a rise of just over one percent on Tuesday's close with the blue chip Mib30 hitting 21,200 -- a gain of 1.04 percent.</p>
<p>The  Paris bourse made early gains of 1.35 percent, with investors taking heart from Wall Street and the dollar, which boosts prospects for French exporting businesses as it strengthens.</p>
<p>The engine behind much of the bull run in Europe was New York's recent strength. Wall Street rose more than 100 points on the Dow Jones industrial average to close at a peak of 7,962.31 points on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It was the 30th record this year for the world's most widely watched stock index, whose previous record of 7,895.81 came only last week, and investors expressed confidence about the outlook for the U.S. economy and second-quarter earnings.</p>
<p>But London did not join in the euphoric mood, distracted by its concerns with a two-day Bank of England meeting on interest rates due to start on Wednesday and the market expecting a decision on Thursday.</p>
<p>The blue-chip FTSE index started trade down about 0.5 percent but managed to claw back the early losses to to show a gain of only 0.2 percent by lunch-time.</p>
<p>Many analysts were predicting an increase of at least 25 basis points to curb inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>&quot;The arguments over whether it is going to be 25 or 50 basis points are really semantics. Twenty five is adequate for now and everyone knows there is going to be more. Fifty looks like an indictment of the (new Labour government's first) budget,&quot; said Dresdner Kleinwort Benson strategist Philip Isherwood.</p>
<p>In currencies, the dollar slipped slightly from levels of 1.7635 marks seen in early trade, its highest level since February 1994. The Germany currency has been hurt by a subdued economic outlook for the country after Bonn reported a rise of 11,000 in unemplyment for June.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar's just grinding higher, there's no real fresh news to add to the same old story of a solid U.S. economy against a generally weak Europe,&quot; said a U.S. bank dealer.</p>
<p>The dollar also climbed slightly on the yen despite a big increase in Japan's May current account surplus. Analysts said the surplus was likely to keep a lid on dollar gains against the yen for the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>Sterling leapt to a new six-year peak of 2.9760 marks as traders awaited the likely rise in UK interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The market continues to have 3.00 marks in its sights and it looks increasingly likely that we will push through this level over a one-month horizon,&quot; said Michael Lewis, economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>On bullion markets, gold was fixed at $315.75 an ounce as it dropped on the fresh bout of selling , versus $320.80 on Tuesday. It was its lowest fix since December 11, 1985.</p>
<p>&quot;The speculator selling was evident in New York and the Far East before Europe opened. The sentiment is still very negative,&quot; said one market analyst.</p>
<p>Gold prices have collapsed since the Reserve Bank of Australia last Thursday said it had sold 167 tonnes of gold from its reserves over the past six months. This triggered heavy selling on fears other banks might follow the example.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1130 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 112.70 yen and 1.7623 marks compared to 112.57 and 1.7594 in late European trade on Tuesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1130 GMT</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index was up 11.4 points at 4,769.9.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index was up 51.19 points at 4,057.59.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 was up 38.33 points at 2,968.14.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was fixed at $315.75  per ounce, compared to Tuesday's close of $321.95. Silver was at $4.27, down nine cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
