<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717067" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: DTB plans volatility future based on DAX.</title>
<headline>DTB plans volatility future based on DAX.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Deutsche Terminboerse (DTB) said on Wednesday it planned to introduce a future based on the implied volatilities of the DAX stock index option as soon as possible.</p>
<p>It said the concept of a future based on volatility could be transfered to its other products as well, once a certain level of liquidity had been reached.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing of the introduction (of the volatility future) all depends. We want designated market makers to support the product and get the basis for liquidity,&quot; Deutsche Boerse Vice President Christian Klapproth told a news conference in London.</p>
<p>&quot;This concept is possible to transfer to other products as well but we're going to start with our most successful one,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Speaking to journalists, DTB Executive Board member Joerg Franke said the re-launch of Germany's 30-year Bund earlier this month, after its unsuccessful introduction in 1994, was an interesting development.</p>
<p>He said if the issue proved popular this time around, the DTB would think about re-issuing a long term Bund contract on the exchange.</p>
<p>Franke said the prospect of European economic and  monetary union (EMU) had acted as a catalyst for change in Europe's futures and options exchanges and noted the intense competition between the DTB and London's Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE).</p>
<p>&quot;But this is not a war. There is competition but no wars,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Franke said the DTB was just starting to enter into talks with France's MATIF again on co-operation in the French cash market. A plan to operate a joint electronic system for trading with its French counterpart broke down last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Now there are some signs we are starting to discuss co-operation in the French cash market,&quot; he told journalists.</p>
<p>He added the DTB was also talking to two exchanges in the Asian time zone following its agreement with the Singapore International Monetary Exchange (SIMEX) last month to trade some of the DTB's futures and options contracts.</p>
<p>-- Jennifer Scott, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 8682</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
