<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717260" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: New Turkish coalition paints glum economic picture.</title>
<headline>New Turkish coalition paints glum economic picture.</headline>
<byline>Daren Butler</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's new secularist government painted on Wednesday a gloomier than expected picture of the economy inherited from the former Islamist-led coalition and shied away from making bold economic promises.</p>
<p>The economy and finance ministers reinforced fears about chronic inflation and gaping deficits, injecting a dose of realism into the economic picture after months of political chaos which helped them to power last week.</p>
<p>&quot;Our aim is not to take shock decisions in the economy, but to sort out this business with fine tuning,&quot; State Minister Gunes Taner told a news conference to announce the economic plans of the left-right coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not have a magic wand in our hands, but we have knowledge and experience,&quot; said Taner, a member of the conservative and pro-market Motherland Party of Prime Minister Mesut Yilmaz.</p>
<p>Leftist Finance Minister Zekeriya Temizel, who jointly gave the news conference with Taner, said the 1997 budget deficit was expected to leap to 2,400 trillion lira ($15.9 billion) from 1,218 trillion a year earlier.</p>
<p>Islamist former prime minister Necmettin Erbakan had programmed a balanced budget for 1997, but Temizel reiterated that figures for the first half of the year showed a deficit of 720 trillion lira.</p>
<p>Budget revenues in the full year were expected to amount to 5,112 trillion lira and expenditure was likely to total 7,510 trillion, he said.</p>
<p>Taner, who is responsible for the economy, said the anticipated deficit made it necessary to plan a supplementary budget in the region of 2,500 trillion lira.</p>
<p>The new government also tore up the inflation targets of the outgoing Islamist-led coalition, which collapsed last month under pressure from the secularist establishment.</p>
<p>The finance ministry revised the end-1997 inflation target up to 80-85 percent from a previous target of 57.7 percent, new figures released on Wednesday showed. The average rate for 1997 was forecast to reach 75-80 percent.</p>
<p>Economic growth appeared to be stronger than previously anticipated.</p>
<p>The target for gross national product growth in 1997 was lifted to 5.5-6.0 percent from four percent previously.</p>
<p>Taner said he was opposed to Turkey reaching a stand-by accord with the International Monetary Fund. IMF officials visited Turkey earlier this year, but there was no agreement on such an accord.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no need for such an agreement. But we are members of the IMF and we will certainly hold talks,&quot; he said in answer to a question.</p>
<p>He also repeated a previous government pledge to refrain from intervention in interest rates and the currency markets and tighten up tax collection.</p>
<p>The government target for privatisation revenues in 1997 stood at $4 billion.</p>
<p>An ambitious sell-off timetable was a cornerstone of Erbakan's bold economic plans, who promised tens of billions of dollars in fresh revenues but failed to deliver during his one year in office.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Temizel said domestic debt at the end of June stood at 4,213 trillion lira, while foreign debt totalled $80 billion.</p>
<p>Among other finance ministry targets, 1997 exports were revised to $25.5-26 billion from $29.5 billion and the import target was revised to $45.5-46 billion from $50 billion.</p>
<p>The current account deficit was targeted to reach $4-4.5 billion in 1997, compared with an earlier target of $5.6 billion. The Turkish lira was expected to reach an average rate for 1997 of 147,000-150,000 against the dollar.</p>
<p>($1 = 150,900 Turkish lira)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
