<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717320" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Juvenile crime bill puts teens at risk, study finds.</title>
<headline>Juvenile crime bill puts teens at risk, study finds.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>New legislation aimed at making it easier to lock up juvenile criminals with adult prisoners would place thousands of teenagers at risk for rape and assault by adult prisoners, a study released on Wednesday by the Justice Policy Institute (JPI) found.</p>
<p>The Senate Judiciary Committee is due to vote on Thursday on the &quot;Violent and Repeat Juvenile Offender Act of 1997,&quot; which would make it easier to prosecute minors as adults.</p>
<p>The JPI study said young people incarcerated with adults were eight times more likely to commit suicide in adult jails.</p>
<p>Juvenile offenders were also five times more likely to report being raped and sexually attacked, twice as likely to report being beaten by prison staff and 50 percent more likely to be attacked with a weapon, the study found.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly, the new juvenile crime bill will put thousands of kids into an environment where they face real and devastating risk,&quot; JPI researcher Jason Ziedenberg said in a statement.</p>
<p>Republican legislation would make it easier to prosecute young offenders under the age of 18 as adults and could force states to transfer large numbers of young offenders to adult prisons in order to be eligible for federal funds.</p>
<p>The JPI report cited a substantial body of research which it said showed that placing youths in adult institutions leads to increased criminal behaviour after their release.</p>
<p>Currently, about 4,000 juveniles are sentenced to adult prisons and 65,000 children pass through the juvenile jail system each year, but there is very little information on rape, suicide and assault rates.</p>
<p>The report also said young offenders tended to fit the &quot;prototype&quot; of a prison rape victim. As the youngest, and often smallest, inmates on the block, they will likely face the greatest risk of being sexually attacked.</p>
<p>As a result, JPI recommended that Congress launch a two-year state-by-state evaluation of the changes in America's juvenile justice system and hold off on the juvenile crime legislation for now.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
