<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717567" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Wednesday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Wednesday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Wednesday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Nikolaus van der Pas said there was no link between the Madrid NATO summit invitation to Hungary, the Czech Republic and Poland to start entry talks immediately and the Commission's opinion on applications to join the European Union. Van der Pas added that accession to the EU was no consolation prize for countries that have not benefited from the NATO enlargement.</p>
<p>Van der Pas said spokesman Jochen Kubosch would brief in his office at 1515/1315 GMT on the electronic payments recommendation adopted by the Commission.</p>
<p>Van der Pas announced that spokesman Peter Guilford was getting engaged.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/97/622: Commission sends reasoned opinion to Greece on real estate purchase restrictions.</p>
<p>- IP/97/623: ECU 13.4 million for the protection of forests in the EU.</p>
<p>- IP/97/624: Commission asks Portugal to end aid for &quot;Empresa para a Agroalimentacao e Cereais S.A. (EPAC).</p>
<p>- IP/97/625: Commission proposes directive on environment-friendly handling of end of life vehicles.</p>
<p>- IP/97/627: Commission proposes directive on legal protection of conditional access services.</p>
<p>- IP/97/629: 1997 Report of the demographic situation in the EU.</p>
<p>- 1997 Demographic report.</p>
<p>- Eurostat news release No 49/97: EU unemployment: 10.8% again in May.</p>
<p>- Global information networks ministerial conference - Ministerial declaration.</p>
<p>- Oil bulletin No 875.</p>
<p>- Selling prices of petroleum products in Ecus.</p>
<p>- ME97/9.7: Midday Express.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
