<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717577" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French jobless rate seen steadying in H2 97-INSEE.</title>
<headline>French jobless rate seen steadying in H2 97-INSEE.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>French employment has been increasing steadily since last autumn but the large number joining the labour market in 1997 means the jobless rate will only stabilise later this year, an economist at national statistics institute INSEE said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Employment has been increasing since last autumn and it should accelerate,&quot; Alain Chappert, head of short-term economic outlooks and forecasts at INSEE, told a Paris Europlace conference.</p>
<p>&quot;But the exceptionally strong arrival on the labour market of 180,000...explains why the unemployment rate will only be stabilising in the second half of this year.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the increase in the number of people looking for work will be considerably higher than in recent years when the figure has been about 140,000 or 150,000.</p>
<p>The French unemployment rate was at 12.5 percent in April.</p>
<p>Chappert said an acceleration in French growth that started in the middle of last year was mainly the result of a recovery in industry and it continued to depend on both the behaviour and expectations of businesses in France.</p>
<p>He said &quot;this recovery is industrial, it has been mainly export-led so far&quot;. He said while there were signs businesses were starting to replenish inventories the rate of investment is still weak.</p>
<p>He welcomed an upturn in consumer sentiment in June, as shown in an INSEE survey released on Wednesday, but said the figures could have been affected by the change of government at the beginning of June.</p>
<p>&quot;It's good information, but it must not be overweighted. It's usual to have an improvement (in confidence) after an election.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the shift in French consumer confidence may be more of a correction as even though business sentiment indices in different European countries have been converging the French people have stood out as being particularly pessimistic.</p>
<p>Chappert also said he expected the French economy to be growing at a rate of about three percent at the end of 1997, up from 2.5 percent in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>The official forecast for 1997 growth is 2.3 percent although several government officials have said recently the pace of growth should be around three percent by the end of the year.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542 cla/cnn</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
