<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717501" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Chirac sure NATO will ask Romania, Slovenia in '99.</title>
<headline>Chirac sure NATO will ask Romania, Slovenia in '99.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac said on Wednesday he was sure that NATO would invite Romania and Slovenia, excluded from the first wave of alliance enlargement, to join in 1999 when it marks its 50th anniversary.</p>
<p>He also told a news conference at the close of a two-day NATO summit in Madrid he believed the first three or four new members would join the European Union in 2000 or 2001, without naming them.  </p>
<p>Chirac said he had discussed the case of Romania and Slovenia again on Wednesday with U.S. President Bill Clinton, who on Tuesday had accepted only Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic in the first wave.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is that 1999 is the 50th anniversary of NATO. It's going to be a great celebration for NATO members. I can't imagine that at the next summit on the occasion of this great anniversary, anyone will contest enlargement to Slovenia and Romania which were mentioned by name as deserving,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The French leader said there was no linkage between NATO and EU enlargement and the Europeans would not feel under any pressure to compensate unsuccessful NATO applicants by letting them into the Union if they were not economically qualified.</p>
<p>He added that NATO expansion should cost the alliance nothing because there was no longer a serious military threat to Europe, and France would not pay an extra franc towards the allied budget for enlargement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
