<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717540" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French consumer confidence up after Socialist win.</title>
<headline>French consumer confidence up after Socialist win.</headline>
<byline>Penny MacRae</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>French consumer confidence jumped sharply in June after the Socialists swept to power in a surprise election victory, according to figures released on Wednesday by national statistics institute INSEE.</p>
<p>INSEE economist Alain Chappert said there was normally a rise in consumer confidence after an election. But the improvement this time was sharper than after previous elections in 1995 and 1993.</p>
<p>INSEE's overall consumer confidence indicator jumped 10 points in June to minus 23 from minus 33 in May, which indicated that fewer respondents were pessimistic about their prospects than in the previous month.</p>
<p>The figure was the highest since the minus 21 level the indicator reached in August 1995. That was soon after Jacques Chirac was elected president on a pledge to roll back unemployment.</p>
<p>Despite economists' expectations that the jobless rate would remain stuck around a near record 12.5 percent for the rest of 1997, optimism was particularly marked about future unemployment levels, with the confidence level climbing 27 points.</p>
<p>Economists were reluctant to say that the survey marked a sea-change in household confidence in France, which has been dogged by pessimism about the sluggish economy.</p>
<p>They suggested that the findings could be more a reflection of the Socialists' election campaign platform, which also promised a war on unemployment with the creation of 700,000 jobs over a five-year period in office.</p>
<p>The Socialists also said during the campaign they were determined France would join the European single currency on time in 1999.</p>
<p>But -- unlike the previous conservative government -- they said they would not introduce any further belt- tightening to meet the criteria for monetary union.</p>
<p>The seasonally adjusted survey, which samples the views of 2,000 households, is a fairly volatile indicator and has been an unreliable tool of late to forecast spending plans, economists said.</p>
<p>Economist Stuart Thomson of Credit Agricole Indosuez said he still expected household consumption figures for June to show a drop for the second straight month.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a bit too early to be sure (of an improvement),&quot; said economist Philippe Brossard of ABN-AMRO. &quot;I'm not sure we really have an upswing there.&quot;</p>
<p>Brossard added that talk of a big budget deficit for 1997, the crucial qualifying year for monetary union, &quot;is going to depress people again&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
