<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717746" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT -Bunds to pause, pull back to 102.59.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT -Bunds to pause, pull back to 102.59.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>September Bund futures traded on LIFFE will seek some consolidation on Wednesday before making another push higher, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We held support around 102.59, a key level, yesterday,&quot; said Elizabeth Miller, technical analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in London. &quot;On candlestick charts we saw a small tweezer top, which is usually a sign of consolidataion.</p>
<p>&quot;As well as that we just managed an inside day and momentum is starting to run out of steam on the top side.&quot;</p>
<p>Miller said all these factors suggested a pause for Wednesday and some sideways consolidation within the range.  </p>
<p>At 0703 GMT, September Bund futures were at 102.91, up 15 basis points on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen a very steep climb recently and it hasn't had a rest so the chances are for the next few days it is going to take a rest,&quot; Miller said.</p>
<p>She said the contract was likely to be capped by 103.00 for this session and to the downside, below 102.59 a further prop was offered at 102.17.</p>
<p>That level was the 38 percent Fibonnacci retracement of the rally from the low on June 20 at 100.94.  </p>
<p>&quot;Key support below there at 102.00 is not expected to give way, that would be our risk level,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Technical analysts at a European bank in London said 102.00 was the first main support for Bunds, but did not see a pause in the rally.</p>
<p>&quot;The current short term acceleration mode could see anything up to 104.00,&quot; they said in a reasearch note.</p>
<p>There was also a type of flag formation from late June, which if valid would target of 103.50, they said.</p>
<p>Miller did not see 103.00 resistance being broken until next week but once through there Bunds would move towards 103.20.  </p>
<p>That level was the June 1997 contract high, she said, adding that a trendline from the daily continuation chart came in close to that level at 103.28.</p>
<p>&quot;Once we get through there, there's nothing by blue sky until the all time continuation high at 104.04,&quot; Miller said.</p>
<p>At the short end, December Euromarks were at 96.79, up one basis point on the day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
