<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717898" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs end firmer on short-covering, weak stocks.</title>
<headline>JGBs end firmer on short-covering, weak stocks.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key September 10-year Japanese government bond (JGB) futures closed firmer on Wednesday as dealers with short positions for hedging purposes covered them amid slow sales of newly launched long-term corporate bonds.</p>
<p>Chugoku Electric Power Co Inc and Tokyo Electric Power Co Inc launched 20-year straight bonds worth 50 billion yen each this afternoon, both with a coupon rate of 3.225 percent. But the issues failed to attract investors.</p>
<p>Weakness in Tokyo stocks, which saw the Nikkei average briefly fall below a key 19,500 level, was supportive, traders said. The September ended at 124.84, up 0.14 from Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Turnover was 42,466 contracts. The September fell to a session low of 124.48 shortly after the opening. But short position holders in the September were squeezed as it broke through resistant points to rise as high as 125.04 in late afternoon trade. The Nikkei-225 index dipped to 19,495.85 before closing down 156.72 points at 19,697.17.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody was happy with today's rise in JGBs,&quot; said a dealer at a city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>Many dealers were unhappy because they had sold March futures which rallied on Wednesday while they underwrote corporate bonds whose prices were not rising, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;TEPCO's straight did not sell well, Chugoku Electric's fared even worse,&quot; said a dealer at another bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>&quot;As the price of TEPCO's 10-year bond (launched on Tuesday) fell soon after its launch, investors decided to wait for the prices of the new issues (today) to fall,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The price of Tokyo Electric Power Co's (TEPCO) 2.625 percent 10-year bond issued at par on Tuesday dived to 99.40 a few hours after the launch on Tuesday due to unattractive terms on the issue.</p>
<p>It was also traded at 99.40 on Wednesday, traders said.  </p>
<p>The coupon rate of TEPCO's 10-year bond was set at a spread of six basis points above market yields of an equivalent JGB.</p>
<p>The spread is usually more than 10 basis points for an electric power company's straight bond, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's good news was that TEPCO's 10-year bond sold better than compared to its 20-year bond,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Some traders said concerns over Japan's bad loan problems revived after Tokai Kogyo Co Ltd, a medium-sized construction firm, applied for court protection on Friday.</p>
<p>Vague rumours about possible troubles at a few Japanese financial institutions circulated in the market, they said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It seems that the Bank of Japan has no choice but to keep its low interest rate policy at least until autumn,&quot; a third dealer said. &quot;Otherwise, construction and real estate firms may fail due to heavier debt burdens,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The perception among some dealers that Japan may not raise interest rates in the near future and market talk this morning that major public funds bought long-term JGBs resulted in a flattening in the JGB yield curve, traders said.</p>
<p>The yield of key 182nd 10-year JGB was down 0.025 at 2.300 percent at 0728 GMT.</p>
<p>-- Risa Maeda Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-33432-8570</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
