<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717835" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASIAN EXOTICS - Dollar gains from regional jitters.</title>
<headline>ASIAN EXOTICS - Dollar gains from regional jitters.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>* Dollar firm against most regional currencies on continuing nervousness following Thai baht float and repeated denial of devaluation reports by Philippines.</p>
<p>* Philippine peso recovers slightly after official denial of devaluation reports and heavy central bank intervention to sell dollars.</p>
<p>* Malaysian ringgit slips back after firming on early central bank intervention in Sydney markets.</p>
<p>* Indonesian rupiah eases, swaps rise on back of peso devaluation fears.</p>
<p>* Thai baht trades sluggishly but remains under pressure against dollar.</p>
<p>* Singapore dollar stays weak but in range.</p>
<p>The dollar maintained a bid tone against most regional currencies on Wednesday in the face of continuing nervousness after the de facto devaluation of the Thai baht last week.</p>
<p>A Singapore newspaper report -- the second this week -- that the Philippines was considering devaluing its peso caused another speculative attack on the currency, forcing the central bank to sell dollars heavily to calm the market.</p>
<p>Traders said the central bank may have sold $200-300 million at 26.40 pesos in early trade. The peso was quoted at 26.386/26.389 at 0440 GMT.</p>
<p>Trade and Industry Secretary Cesar Bautista denied a report in Singapore's daily Straits Times newspaper, which quoted him saying devaluation of the peso would be discussed at a Monetary Board meeting.</p>
<p>In Malaysia, the ringgit slipped back but remained relatively firm after repeated intervention by Bank Negara Malaysia to sell dollars since late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said Bank Negara sold the dollar from 2.5050 to 2.4980 ringgit through an agent bank in Sydney in the morning. But they said the amount sold was not big.</p>
<p>&quot;It may be less than $50 million,&quot; a dealer at a European bank in Singapore said.</p>
<p>Dollar/ringgit hit an early low of 2.4950 after the sales by Bank Negara, before buying by funds pushed it back above 2.50.</p>
<p>&quot;The shorts were buying back from 2.4960/70. There's a gap to be covered on the charts around 2.5050 and from there, the dollar will be a sell,&quot; another European bank dealer in Singapore said.</p>
<p>The ringgit was at 2.5040/50 to the dollar at 0440 GMT.</p>
<p>Bank Negara sold large amounts of the dollar late on Tuesday as speculators threatened to push dollar/ringgit above 2.5250, the level at which the central bank had aggressively defended the ringgit last week.</p>
<p>In Indonesia, the rupiah slipped and swap rates moved up due to fears of a peso devaluation, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said spillover fears were not as strong as when offshore operators launched an attack on the Thai baht, but there were increased swap purchases in the market.</p>
<p>Overnight swap was at 0.40/0.43 and tom/next at 0.38/0.42.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah was quoted at 2,432.00/32.30 at 0430 GMT after reaching a high of 2,433.25 from an opening of 2,431.5/32.5.</p>
<p>The Thai baht was relatively calm, especially in offshore markets, as most players preferred to stay sidelined after last week's surprise move by Thai authorities to a managed float of the currency.</p>
<p>The baht was slightly weaker in domestic markets, slipping to around 29.020/29.050 to the dollar against 29.10/29.30 late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar was still well bid. Importers have no choice but to buy the dollar. Exporters are reluctant to sell the dollar as they are waiting for it to rise further (against the baht),&quot; a local bank dealer in Bangkok said.</p>
<p>The Bank of Thailand on Wednesday announced the weighted average interbank exchange rate at 29.096 to the dollar against 28.922 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Singapore dollar recovered from the lows seen on Tuesday but remained under pressure on continued U.S. fund demand for the U.S. unit.</p>
<p>&quot;The 1.4350 level should hold well. I would like to buy the dollar/Sing on dips and sell dollar/ringgit on rallies,&quot; the European bank dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;With the dollar/mark so high, dollar/Sing should tag along,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The Singapore dollar was quoted at 1.4365/75 to the U.S. dollar at 0440 GMT.</p>
<p>-- Lilian Karunungan in Manila (632-841-8937), Syed Azman in Kuala Lumpur (603-206 2323), Mantik Kusjanto in Jakarta (6221 384-6364), Anuchit Nguyen in Bangkok (662) 652-0642 and Sonalu Desai in Singapore (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
