<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="717896" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean stocks close higher but sentiment weak.</title>
<headline>S.Korean stocks close higher but sentiment weak.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks closed higher on Wednesday in a technical rebound, but overall sentiment was weak because investors felt the market was still overvalued, brokers said.</p>
<p>News of a labour strike at a car plant of Daewoo Motor Co was ignored as investors saw little impact on the industry or the stock market, they said.</p>
<p>Han Joo Corp fell on rumours that its affiliates had defaulted on debt payments. Han Joo denied the rumours.</p>
<p>The composite index closed up 4.25 points, or 0.55 percent, at 771.99.  </p>
<p>&quot;Investors think the market would consolidate further in reaction to the last week's big gains,&quot; said Choo Hee-yup of Dongwon Securities.</p>
<p>Trade volume totalled 39.45 million shares, down from 39.55 million on Tuesday and from more than 50 million last week.</p>
<p>Daewoo Motor Co, one of South Korea's top three car makers, said on Wednesday its unionised workers had downed tools at its plant in Bupyong after wage negotiations broke up.</p>
<p>The union plans to walk out for four hours on each of the next two days following a full-day strike on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Han Joo fell 410 won to its daily limit of 4,830 won despite its denial of rumours that its affiliates Hanjoo Chemical and Hanjoo Paper had defaulted on debt payments. Hanjoo Chemical closed flat at 1,220 won.</p>
<p>Samsung Display Devices was unmoved by remarks by the company's chief executive that this year's earnings were expected to be flat at last year's level. Shares of the world's largest colour display/picture tubes ended flat at 47,000 won.</p>
<p>The Korea Development Institute's upward revision of its forecast for this year's real gross domestic product growth also had little immediate impact on the stock market.  </p>
<p>The state-run think-tank upgraded its forecast for this year's GDP growth to 6.2 percent from 6.0 percent, compared with last year's 7.1 percent growth.</p>
<p>September index futures closed down 0.10 of a point at 81.90 while the underlying KOSPI-200 index rose 0.24 to 80.33.</p>
<p>--YOO CHOON-SIK (822) 727 5646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
