<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="718090" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: PRESS DIGEST - United Arab Emirates - July 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - United Arab Emirates - July 9.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the United Arab Emirates (UAE) press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>GULF NEWS</p>
<p>- The British frigate HMS Westminster will be berthing in the capital Abu Dhabi for four days after patrolling the northern Arabian Gulf as part of the international fleet enforcing U.N. sanctions.</p>
<p>- Dubai Duty Free said its 1997 first half sales reached 345 million dirhams ($92 million), up by 21 million dirhams over the same period of 1996.</p>
<p>THE GULF TODAY</p>
<p>- The Emirates Telecommunications Corporation (Etisalat) is to be the official sponsor of the Internet World Middle East Exhibition and Conference, to be held in Abu Dhabi in February.</p>
<p>KHALEEJ TIMES</p>
<p>- Gold shops in Dubai are witnessing a surge in sales but retailers and wholesalers are reluctant to attribute it wholly to the sinking prices of gold on the international market.</p>
<p>EMIRATES NEWS</p>
<p>- Preliminary UAE Central Bank figures show that higher oil prices had a positive effect on national output and government finances during 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
