<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="718094" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>Finland: Forestries, Nokia at new highs in bullish Helsinki.</title>
<headline>Forestries, Nokia at new highs in bullish Helsinki.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>* Shares hit new life-highs as forestries track a rally in U.S.</p>
<p>paper stocks and Nokia extends its record-breaking streak after</p>
<p>U.S. rival Motorola's above-forecast Q2 earnings.</p>
<p>* .FOX index +1.36 pct at 1163.9,  .HEX +1.49 pct at 3397.4</p>
<p>* Volume 113 million markka, 40 pct in Nokia</p>
<p>* .HEF1 +1.62 pct,  .HEB1 +0.43 pct,  .HEM1 +0.43 pct</p>
<p>------------------------ (July 9) ----------------------------</p>
<p>Broad gains took indices to new highs on Wednesday as Nokia extended its rally and forestries tracked U.S. paper stocks which rose over six percent after International Paper announced restructuring plans, brokers said.</p>
<p>Nokia advanced to another record at 430.00 markka -- up 18 markka or 4.36 percent -- after Motorola reported above forecast second quarter earnings, although the U.S. rival's cellular business showed few positive signs for Nokia, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was actually a disappointment,&quot; said FIM Securities analyst Niklas Geust, but added that Motorola would rise on the report and boost interest in Nokia.  </p>
<p>The derivatives and portfolio benchmark FOX has been setting intra-session records for seven consequent sessions, last reaching 1,151.18 points on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Advancers led decliners 41 to seven, with 17 unchanged.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 245, news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
