<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71819" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: New Belgian 2007 OLO seen well bid at auction.</title>
<headline>New Belgian 2007 OLO seen well bid at auction.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian bond dealers said on Monday they expected strong demand for the new 6.25 percent, March 28, 2007 linear bond at the Treasury's monthly auction today, although the bond was already seen relatively expensive.</p>
<p>But they were not sure how much paper the Treasury would want to sell.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope that they will at least issue 30 billion francs, otherwise the new 2007 will be a collector's item, not a benchmark,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Its auction yield is seen around 6.44 to 6.45 percent, about five bp above the current 2006 benchmark's yield.  </p>
<p>The 2006 OLO was quoted with a yield of 6.39 percent, up from 6.36 percent on Friday, an unchanged 22 bp over Bunds.</p>
<p>The Treasury also auctions the June 2001 line today.</p>
<p>One dealer said that compared to the swap market, the new 2007 yield was relatively high. But he added that as many players had gone short on the new paper in the grey market last week, they would be forced to bid at high prices.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market was divided about the direction of yields and that players preferred to remain sidelined ahead of tomorrow's FOMC meeting.  </p>
<p>Dealers said that tension in the government about how police and the judiciary handled the paedophilia scandal of the past months had no influence on prices.</p>
<p>Leaks about the 1997 budget -- due to be presented next Tuesday -- had no impact either, although the government has just one week left to find some 50 billion francs of the estimated 100 billion worth of austerity measures needed to keep the deficit below three percent of GDP.</p>
<p>-- Geert De Clercq, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6813, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
