<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="718181" id="root" date="1997-07-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Gold exploration seen surviving price plunge.</title>
<headline>Gold exploration seen surviving price plunge.</headline>
<byline>K.T. Arasu</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Miners exploring for gold in Asia will be undeterred by the sharp price fall of the metal but output from high-cost operators could slow down until values improve, regional industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Exploration companies will be looking at prices four to five years down the road as their operations are not going to come onstream overnight,&quot; mining engineer M. Simatupang, adviser to the ASEAN Federation of Mining Associations, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;But for mining companies whose production costs are relatively high, it would not be cost-effective if gold prices continue to fall,&quot; he said. &quot;They might have to slow down.&quot;</p>
<p>Industry sources in the Philippines echoed Simatupang's opinions, adding that only low-cost operators would survive the price slump, which hit 12-year lows before rebounding slightly.</p>
<p>&quot;Only the ones which have low-cost operations will survive this slump,&quot; said Artemio Disini, president of Lepanto Consolidated Mining Co, one of the Phlippines' largest gold producing companies.</p>
<p>Industry sources in Hong Kong said the drop in gold prices was exacerbated by panic selling by producers who had failed to anticipate the fall despite ample signals.</p>
<p>Gold prices fell to fresh 12-year lows on July 7, with New York's August contract falling to $319.00 an ounce, a level unseen since 1985 on New York's Commodity Exchange.</p>
<p>The plunge came after the Reserve Bank of Australia said that it had sold 167 tonnes of gold from its reserves.</p>
<p>The sale of 60 percent of the bank's gold hoard sent an especially bearish signal because Australia is the world's third largest producer, after South Africa and the United States.</p>
<p>New York gold closed at $319.80-$320.30 on Tuesday, while it opened lower in Hong Kong at $318.50-$319.00 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Indonesian industry sources said foreign mining companies were showing great interest in exploring for gold in Indonesia, despite the Busang debacle that made it difficult for junior exploration companies to raise funds in capital markets.</p>
<p>Canadian exploration firm Bre-X Minerals Ltd touted its Busang property as the biggest gold find this century with reserves of some 71 million ounces, but it turned out to be the biggest mining swindle in history, and worth almost nothing.</p>
<p>The sources said nearly 120 of the 160 applications for the next batch of contracts of work (COW) were for gold exploration, compared with some 40 in the sixth-generation COW.</p>
<p>Gold output in Indonesia, ranked among the world's top 10 producers, is expected to increase to about 90 tonnes in 1997 from an estimated 83 tonnes last year, the sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;You've got to realise that it's a long time from the point we start exploring and the point we actually start to produce gold,&quot; a senior foreign miner in Indonesia said. &quot;Companies will certainly be concerned with the current price of gold, but they will be looking at the price forecast, maybe five years on.&quot;</p>
<p>In the Philippines, more than 100 foreign mining companies had sought permission to operate mining projects under the country's liberalisation programme.</p>
<p>&quot;It will not affect us...we look at prospects of a project for the long term,&quot; said Malcolm Norris, country manager of WMC Exploration Corp, a unit of Australia-based WMC Ltd.</p>
<p>Industry sources in Indonesia and the Philippines said they expected gold prices to rebound over the next few months.</p>
<p>&quot;The bears have to have their way, the speculators once they are done...we will see it (gold prices) rebounding again,&quot; one Philippine industry source said.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom + 6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
