<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="718386" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pall CEO comfortable with '97 EPS estimates.</title>
<headline>Pall CEO comfortable with '97 EPS estimates.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pall Corp's Chairman and Chief Executive Eric Krasnoff said Thursday that he was comfortable with analysts' earnings per share estimates of $1.08 to $1.10 for the fiscal year ending August 2, 1997.</p>
<p>In a telephone interview with Reuters, he said that foreign exchange rates had hurt the company by about $0.10 per share, or about four percent of sales, in fiscal '97, but that he expected the effect to taper off next year.  </p>
<p>&quot;This year exchange rates are impacting us about $0.10 per share for the year, or about four percent of sales,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;For next year, at current rates we see the effect over the year would be about 1.5 percent (of sales), all of that taking place in the first two quarters of fiscal '98.&quot;</p>
<p>Krasnoff said that earnings in fiscal '98 will also benefit to the tune of &quot;a few cents&quot; per share from the consolidation of Gelman Sciences Inc.</p>
<p>Pall had said the Gelman acquisition diluted earnings in the third quarter of fiscal 1997 by about $0.02 a share, but that no further dilution was seen in the fourth quarter.  </p>
<p>The company had achieved $15 million of synergies from the Gelman deal, Krasnoff said, exceeding its original estimate of $10 million.</p>
<p>He said Pall was not immediately looking for other acquisitions and believed it could meet its goals of earnings increases of 15 percent or more per year and revenue increases of 10 percent or more from internal growth over the next few years.  </p>
<p>With sluggish market conditions in a number of its businesses and the unfavorable impact of foreign exchange rates, the company has been hard-pressed to achieve growth in the last year or so, but Krasnoff sees the picture changing.</p>
<p>The Microelectronics sector, which suffered a slowdown for the major part of this year, was picking up again, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Going into '98 we see now an increase in our OEM (Original Equipment Manufacturer) bookings in Microelectronics, which generally is the first sign of a recovery.&quot;  </p>
<p>Krasnoff said the company was also upbeat on the blood filtration business.  Filtered blood greatly reduces the risk of infection and allergic reaction in blood transfusions, he said, and about 17 percent of all blood is now filtered.</p>
<p>In fiscal 1997, Pall's blood filter sales were about $220 million, and Krasnoff said he sees these going up by about 10 percent in the next fiscal year, propelled by the increasing use of filtration in European countries.</p>
<p>Overall regional growth would be led by Asia, excluding Japan, where the company has grown by over 33 percent each year for the last three years, Krasnoff said.</p>
<p>Weakness in the European marketplace was expected to abate somewhat. &quot;We see some modest rebound for Europe next year,&quot; Krasnoff said.  &quot;I would expect growth a little bit under 10 percent overall for our European business next (fiscal) year.&quot;</p>
<p>About 55 percent of Pall's business is done outside the United States.</p>
<p>Pall Corp designs and manufactures disposable filters and other fluid clarification and separation devices for the industrial and health care markets.</p>
<p>(( ---Kamalakshi Mehta, New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32830">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
