<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="718402" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Quaker Oats sees Q3 restructuring charge.</title>
<headline>Quaker Oats sees Q3 restructuring charge.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Quaker Oats Co said Thursday it expects to take a third-quarter pretax restructuring charge of $37 million as part of a move to consolidate its U.S. food supply chain.</p>
<p>The charge relates chiefly to closing a rice-cake plant in Gridley, Calif.  </p>
<p>In May, Quaker said, its board approved plans for an additional $12 million pretax charge that was taken in the second quarter for manufacturing consolidations in the Brazilian pasta business and the closing of an international office in Singapore.</p>
<p>Of the total $49 million in pretax charges, $40 million is non-cash, representing asset write-offs or disposals. As a result of these restructuring actions, Quaker said it expects to save an estimated $13 million annually.</p>
<p>Quaker said it expects restructuring could result in total 1997 pretax charges between $70 million and $100 million.  </p>
<p>&quot;These major restructuring actions are part of the ongoing program we announced April 23 to reduce our overhead costs and drive further efficiencies,&quot; chairman William Smithburg said in a statement. &quot;These changes further improve the operating returns from the strongest portfolio of brands in Quaker's history.&quot;</p>
<p>Quaker's brands include Gatorade sports drink; Quaker, Cap'n Crunch and Life cereals; and Rice-A-Roni, Pasta Roni and Near East side dishes.</p>
<p>In April, Quaker said it was reviewing the sale of non-core businesses and potential restructuring of certain international operations.</p>
<p>Quaker said at the time it was working on overhead cost reductions with a goal of cutting costs by $30 million over an 18-month period, in additional to removing or absorbing costs related to Snapple, the beverage business that it sold recently.</p>
<p>Quaker has also begun a search for a replacement for Smithburg, who has said he hopes to retire within a year.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
