<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="718492" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: SOCCER-MARADONA WINS RAVE REVIEWS FOR LATEST COMEBACK.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MARADONA WINS RAVE REVIEWS FOR LATEST COMEBACK.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Brown</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diego Maradona awoke to rave reviews after scoring one of Boca Juniors' goals in a 2-0 friendly win against Newell's Old Boys on his fourth comeback to Argentine soccer on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Maradona: the Legend Lives On!&quot; screamed the front page of Clarin newspaper. Rival daily La Nacion proclaimed: &quot;He's Back -- With a Goal&quot; and Pagina 12 newspaper celebrated &quot;Maradona's Return with a Goal Like the Old Days.&quot;</p>
<p>Pagina's sports pages went right over the top, calling the 36-year-old player &quot;The Sun King&quot; and suggesting he &quot;Wants His Throne Back in France&quot; -- predicting Maradona would make it to the 1998 World Cup.</p>
<p>Maradona was given a rapturous reception by a crowd of 20,000 at the Rosario city club Newell's, where he played when he made his second comeback in 1993. Fans from both sides chanted &quot;Ole, Ole, Diego, Diego!&quot; and waved flags and banners proclaiming him &quot;The Envy of the World.&quot;</p>
<p>He rewarded them with a goal five minutes into the game, from a free-kick after he had been fouled by Newell's player Diego Mateo just outside the area.</p>
<p>Making his first professional appearance in nearly a year, Maradona looked fitter than for a long time, thanks to training in the Andes and in Canada with sprinter Ben Johnson, with whom he shares the shame of a drugs ban.</p>
<p>His short frame has shed 24 pounds (11 kg) and his hair is plain black rather than dyed in the blue and yellow Boca colours as it was a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt great and I'm very happy to be back in the shirt that I love,&quot; he said in a news conference after the game, which he punctuated with acts of showmanship such as popping off the pitch to shake hands with Newell's coach Mario Zanabria and delaying a corner while talking with adoring fans.</p>
<p>In the past year the hero of Argentina's 1986 World Cup title has been trying to beat his confessed cocaine habit, been involved in a drugs scandal involving his manager Guillermo Coppola and presented a sensationalist television show.</p>
<p>His stamina has apparently suffered and Maradona went off 13 minutes into the second half to a standing ovation, leaving younger players who had never previously played alongside Argentina's sporting idol beside themselves with joy.</p>
<p>&quot;My dream has come true, to play a game with Maradona,&quot; said Newell's midfielder Damian Manso.</p>
<p>His teammates believe he is fit enough for a league comeback at home against Racing on Sunday -- with long-suffering Boca fans clinging to the hope that some Maradona magic can lift Boca out of their mid-table blues.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought he looked quick and with good reactions,&quot; said Boca's Diego Latorre. &quot;After a few games he'll get into shape for competition.&quot;</p>
<p>Maradona himself agreed that &quot;the best training is on the pitch. If this was only about running, Ben Johnson or Carl Lewis would be great players.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
