<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71868" id="root" date="1996-09-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Bombay shares close lower, politics dampens mood.</title>
<headline>Bombay shares close lower, politics dampens mood.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bombay shares ended lower in shaky trade on Monday as investors kept on the sidelines after former Prime Minister P.V. Narasimha Rao resigned as president of Congress Party over the weekend, traders said.</p>
<p>But they said prices were unlikely to fall sharply.</p>
<p>&quot;The Rao news doesn't really seem to have affected the market. It has been discounted to a great extent and we're unlikely to see any sharp movements unless it triggers off any other political problems,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing select support from foreign funds through the slide,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts say Rao's abrupt decision to quit the Congress presidency on Saturday, after a court ruling in a criminal cheating case, hastens the decline of India's oldest party and offered Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda political breathing room.</p>
<p>They say Deve Gowda is likely to benefit from the disarray in the Congress.</p>
<p>Traders said the news would worry the market but would not be construed as overly negative.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no uncertainty for the existing government. If anything, it might make them stronger,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign brokerage.</p>
<p>They said prices would stay shaky as the Congress began its search for a new leader. The Congress Working Committee is due to meet at 6 p.m. (1230 GMT) to elect a provisional new leader.</p>
<p>Possible successors include former cabinet minister A.K. Antony and Congress treasurer Sitaram Kesri.</p>
<p>Traders said tighter margins on the BSE were likely to pull volumes lower in the coming weeks. BSE said it was tightening limits on the volume of transactions in its B2 stocks group effective Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
