<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="718788" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: OPINION-Has SAfrica really slowed down - By E.Osborn.</title>
<headline>OPINION-Has SAfrica really slowed down - By E.Osborn.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Edward Osborn, consultant to Edey, Rogers (Pty) Ltd</p>
<p>The trouble is that we have to put our trust in the official estimates of the gross domestic product in judging the country's economic performance.</p>
<p>Otherwise it is a Babel of subjective statements with possible credence give to the one who shouts loudest or is in temporary favour as the Guru.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the adjuration not to shoot the pianist still holds as the national accountants in the Central Statistical Service (CSS) and the Reserve Bank are doing their best.</p>
<p>National accounting is at best an art involving a considerable flair for this type of thing and involving considerable judgement.</p>
<p>The statisticians are therefore fallible and the results of their deliberations can be misleading, which is unfortunate when the fine movements from quarter to quarter, magnified to the power of four in annualising, are supposed to indicate the changes taking place in the economy.</p>
<p>It is particularly unfortunate when patently a mistake, or slip-up to be kinder, has been made and the wrong signals are given.</p>
<p>Not that they will admit to a mistake, on questioning the figures one is smothered with cottonwool statements about statistical judgement.</p>
<p>I have written before of the troubling anomaly of the real rise in agricultural product in the fourth quarter of 1996 which not only enhanced the growth rate of the fourth quarter but pushed the rate into a negative in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>I was given to understand then that the problem lay in the lack of retrospective revision of the estimates for agriculture as the season deteriorated. But this assumed that the measurement of agriculture's contribution to GDP was based on crop forecasts.</p>
<p>Unfortunately there are no published notes on sources, methods and concepts used in the calculation of the GDP.</p>
<p>But after persistent nagging the responsible Department of Agriculture it has now become clear that the agricultural estimates are based not on crop forecasts but simply on current sales of produce on the respective markets.</p>
<p>Estimates of agriculture product at both current prices and constant prices are supplied to the CSS who then adjust them for seasonal variation. This is normally a statistical technique based on past patterns but the national accountants admit to a certain latitude in massaging the figures to iron out what appear to them as anomalies.</p>
<p>The CSS adjusts the two current price and constant price series for seasonal variation separately but there should be a consistency between the two series reflecting an implied price deflator.</p>
<p>In the latest Reserve Bank Quarterly Bulletin for June 1997 (page S-102), however, it will be seen that this consistency broke down.</p>
<p>The current price seasonally adjusted estimate for the fourth quarter of 1997 shows a fall from 24.97 billion rand to 22.84 billion rand, and a further fall to 22.23 billion rand in quarter one of 1997.</p>
<p>The constant price estimate, on the other hand, shows a rise from 15.87 billion rand to 16.35 billion rand, and a subsequent fall to 14.73 billion rand.</p>
<p>This implies that the effective price deflator fell from 1.57 to 1.40, but then rose back to 1.51.</p>
<p>This inconsistency is unacceptable. From discussions with the national accountants it would appear that the inconsistency was overlooked. At the time of preparing the estimates they had difficulties in reconciling the expenditure estimates produced by the Reserve Bank with the product estimates.</p>
<p>Expenditure growth exceeded product growth. Normally this reconciliation is affected through the so-called residual item in the table on the expenditure on the GDP.</p>
<p>On this particular occasion the reconciliation posed a real problem as indicated in the huge 9.8 billion rand residual item for current price estimates.</p>
<p>Hence a degree of massaging the constant price product estimates upwards was felt necessary, but even so a residual item of 4.1 billion rand was still required in the constant price estimates.</p>
<p>Economically speaking, with expenditure growth exceeding product growth, one would have expected a reduction in inventories and neither current price nor constant price estimates show a reduction.</p>
<p>This is where the national accountants could have effected a better reconciliation.</p>
<p>So all this points to a bad slip-up in the fourth quarter estimates of real product for agriculture.</p>
<p>If we could assume an implicit price deflator of 1.57, say, for the two quarters and that the seasonally adjusted current price estimates are correct, the real product estimate of agriculture for the fourth quarter would be 14.55 billion rand, which is a decline of 8.3 percent as opposed to the published rise of 3.0 percent and that for quarter one of 1997 14.16 billion rand.</p>
<p>The overall picture changes automatically.</p>
<p>The annualised growth of total real GDP at factor cost for the fourth quarter then changes to 0.3 percent, instead of the published 3.1 percent and that for the first quarter of 1997 changes to 0.9 percent, instead of the published -1.1 percent.</p>
<p>There has thus been sustained growth in the first quarter of 1997, as opposed to a decline, which has been widely accepted as indicative of a downturn in the economy.</p>
<p>And incidentally the full year 1996 growth is corrected downwards to 2.77 percent, as opposed to the published 2.95 percent.</p>
<p>Not that the economy is not facing problems induced by the collapse of the gold price and the general process of reducing employment.</p>
<p>These factors would be inducing a slowdown in the domestic economy unless counteracted by enhanced export performance of other industries.</p>
<p>But we are concerned here with the accuracy of the national accounts and whether there really was a downturn in the first quarter of 1997 as generally supposed.</p>
<p>The real trouble is that we shall never really know for there are further revisions to agriculture in the pipeline in respect of omitted sales of deciduous fruit which will be placed in the fourth quarter of 1996 and perhaps the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>The CSS will have the last laugh.</p>
<p>				  / / / / / / /</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article represent those of the author only. They should not be seen to represent the views of Reuters.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
