<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="718720" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Quebec battles with municipalities on deficit plan.</title>
<headline>Quebec battles with municipalities on deficit plan.</headline>
<byline>Patrick White</byline>
<dateline>QUEBEC CITY 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Quebec government is battling the French-speaking province's debt-burdened municipalities over its tough budget austerity plan.</p>
<p>As part of its bid to clean up its finances ahead of a provincial election by 1999 and a third possible referendum on independence, the separatist Quebec government wants the province's more than 1,500 municipalities to absorb C$500 million of annual expenses.</p>
<p>The move is part of the Parti Quebecois government's effort to meet its deficit target of C$2.2 billion for fiscal 1997/98 ending March 31.</p>
<p>The municipalities, their tax bases hurt by a sluggish economy and moribund property values, are protesting the move, saying they will have to raise taxes or cut services.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the Quebec Union of Municipalities countered Quebec's plan with its own proposals showing how the government could trim C$412 million from its expenditures without asking cities, towns and villages to tighten the belt.</p>
<p>&quot;If the government is serious about cleaning up its public finances without crushing the citizens with taxes, it will consent to rapidly implement our measures,&quot; said Quebec Union of Municipalities President Mario Laframboise.</p>
<p>Quebec Treasury Board President Jacques Leonard rejected the idea, saying the municipalities should look at the C$222 million of surpluses sitting in their employees' pension funds.</p>
<p>Analysts said Quebec municipalities were already heavily indebted and their tax rates among the highest in Canada.</p>
<p>&quot;In general, Quebec cities have fairly low credit ratings because their debt levels are high,&quot; said Doug Hirano, senior financial analyst at Dominion Bond Rating Service.</p>
<p>The provincial debt in Quebec, which has a population of 7.1 million, is about C$77 billion, while its municipalities, school boards and hospitals carry a debt load of C$26 billion.</p>
<p>By contrast, Ontario, with a population of 10 million, has a provincial debt of C$102 billion, with its municipalities, schools and hospitals responsible for only C$6 billion  of debt.</p>
<p>&quot;The Quebec municipalities are much weaker fiscally than those in Ontario. They are just trying to protect their turf,&quot; said Hirano.</p>
<p>((Reuters Quebec City bureau 418-648-6442))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUEBEC CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
