<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719033" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chilean government's popularity sags, poll shows.</title>
<headline>Chilean government's popularity sags, poll shows.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Floods in central Chile and scandals over shoddy public housing have eroded the popularity of President Eduardo Frei's government, an opinion poll showed on Thursday.</p>
<p>The government's overall approval rating fell to 52 percent from 58 percent in March, while the percentage not approving of its performance rose to 33 percent from 28 percent, said the survey by private polling agency Cerc.</p>
<p>The poll of 1,200 people throughout the country was conducted after rainstorms lashed central Chile, forcing about 80,000 people from their homes and leading to complaints that aid was slow to arrive.</p>
<p>The storms also exposed the appalling state of some public housing projects, where walls crumbled, roofs leaked and workers who had saved for years to buy apartments were forced to leave.</p>
<p>Protests and class boycotts by public university students demanding more funding have also eroded the government's popularity, Cerc director Carlos Huneuus said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is being punished because of the rains, the housing and the (students') strikes,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Frei's government said the drop in popularity was only to be expected following the front-page housing scandal and the floods.</p>
<p>&quot;This poll was conducted just as we were experiencing one of the worst storms of this century,&quot; said information minister Jose Brunner. &quot;It's normal that a snapshot of public opinion taken during those days shows a negative reaction. Anyone who expected the contrary doesn't understand the dynamics of public opinion.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Fifty-two percent remains extraordinarily solid support for President Frei,&quot; Brunner told reporters.</p>
<p>Sixty-one percent of Chileans held the government entirely or partly responsible for shoddy construction in public housing, and all but eight percent said they supported the students' demands for more funding and a bigger say in higher education.</p>
<p>Respondents saw socialist Public Works Minister Ricardo Lagos, a leading opponent of former military ruler General Augusto Pinochet, as the politician &quot;with the most future,&quot; the poll said. Sixty-five percent cited Lagos, followed by 43 percent for Joaquin Lavin, rightist mayor of Santiago suburb Las Condes.</p>
<p>The poll did not include a personal popularity rating for Frei, who is constitutionally barred from seeking reelection, and had a margin of error of 2.3 percentage points, Cerc said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
