<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719036" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Rescuers pull survivors from Venezuela quake ruins.</title>
<headline>Rescuers pull survivors from Venezuela quake ruins.</headline>
<byline>Omar Lugo</byline>
<dateline>CARIACO, Venezuela 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Using their bare hands to heave aside rubble, rescuers in eastern Venezuela on Thursday searched for dozens of children trapped in classrooms ruined by a powerful quake that killed at least 59 people.</p>
<p>&quot;The total number of deaths confirmed now is 59, with 322 injured,&quot; Sucre State Governor Ramon Martinez told reporters.</p>
<p>Schools and office buildings were razed by the tremor -- measured at 6.9 on the Richter scale -- crushing the children as they took end-of-term exams.</p>
<p>Searchers in this tiny Caribbean town, 295 miles (470 km) east of Caracas, rescued at least 27 of the scores of children buried in the remains of their high school, Martinez said.</p>
<p>Rescue officials said they would not rest until every person had been accounted for.</p>
<p>&quot;The number of dead and injured goes up every time they move aside the rubble,&quot; Interior Minister Jose Guillermo Andueza said.</p>
<p>About 500 families were left homeless by Venezuela's worst earthquake in three decades, officials said.</p>
<p>Cariaco, a town of about 13,000 people, bore the brunt of the quake. Scores of homes and buildings were flattened, including two schools, killing at least 41, mostly children.</p>
<p>One resident recounted pulling a young girl from the wreckage of a house. &quot;She was talking to me as we walked and, all of a sudden, I turned around and she was dead,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dozens of distraught family members milled in the street facing the Raimundo Martinez Centeno high school, staring blankly as rescue workers picked through the ruins.</p>
<p>Textbooks and broken desks lay scattered. Several limbs could be seen in the bloodied rubble.</p>
<p>For many of the pupils, Thursday was to be their last day before the summer break. &quot;Some of them were taking end of term exams,&quot; said arts teacher Tomas Pantoja as he tried to rescue a student with crippling leg and arm wounds.</p>
<p>Thanks to a sore throat, Oscar Rodriguez, 15, survived, telling a Reuters correspondent, &quot;I wasn't going to go because I was ill but a teacher convinced me.&quot;</p>
<p>Tears in his eyes, Rodriguez said, &quot;When I was arriving the building started to move as if it was on a wave and the whole thing crashed down.&quot;</p>
<p>Survivors said eight of the school's 12 classrooms were in use at the time of the quake, and four caved in. &quot;The building collapsed as if it had been hit by a bomb,&quot; Pantoja said.</p>
<p>In the historic state capital Cumana, 40 miles (60 km) west, rescue efforts concentrated on a six-story office building that fell like a pack of cards.</p>
<p>Martinez said at least 11 bodies were pulled from the ruins and another 30 rescued alive. A French citizen was among those to die in the tower block, the French embassy said. There were no other reports of foreign deaths.</p>
<p>Firemen and medics swarmed over the rubble, removing debris and trying to keep contact with those buried. Cranes and trucks stood by to remove the rubble. Stray scraps of office stationery fluttered around the site.</p>
<p>One group of survivors, trapped in the basement, kept in contact with the outside world by cellular telephones, Martinez said. Up to 70 people were thought to have been in the building at the time of the quake.</p>
<p>President Rafael Caldera briefly visited the site to see firsthand the rescue operation. He was due to visit Cariaco later Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of those hurt were children and have lost their legs and arms after they were taken from the ruins and then given very rudimentary surgery,&quot; said Ramon Ward, director of Cariaco's 30-bed Diego Carbonel hospital which has treated hundreds of patients since Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the streets of Cariaco were riven by huge cracks and the traditional mud-walled houses flattened.</p>
<p>Urban Development Minister Julio Marti said very early estimates put the cost of infrastructural damage at $8 million.</p>
<p>The quake, the worst to hit Venezuela since 1967, struck about 3:25 p.m. EDT (1925 GMT) Wednesday. The FUNVISIS seismological institute said the first tremor measured 6.9 on the open-ended Richter scale.</p>
<p>The epicentre was about 30 miles (49 km) off Venezuela's northeastern Caribbean coast and there were at least 15 aftershocks, the last in the early hours Thursday.</p>
<p>The 1967 quake, the last to cause serious damage in Venezuela, killed about 300 in the capital and surrounding area, FUNVISIS officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARIACO, Venezuela"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
