<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719021" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - July 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - July 10.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KONTINENT</p>
<p>-- Italy's Prime Minister Romano Prodi said in Madrid Bulgaria was likely to join NATO before the end of President Petar Stoyanov's mandate which expires in 2002.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- The Bulgarian National Bank said it would cut the annual main interest rate to 6.96 percent from 9.76 percent, effective from Monday.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's parliamentary commission on culture and media said it had accepted the resignation of the chiefs of the national television and radio and the state BTA news agency. Parliament is expected to discuss today the nominations for new chiefs of the state national media.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria expects to receive humanitarian aid from the United States for 100,000 Bulgarian pensioners, the Bulgarian Red Cross said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria needs investment of some $50 million to build a Hilton hotel in Sofia, Bulgaria's Deputy Prime Minister Evgeni Bakardzhiev said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet is expected today to raise license fees for opening casinos to 12.5 million levs from 2.5 million levs, finance ministry officials said.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- Police said they had cracked down on an illegal gathering organised by the Unification Church. Six preachers were fined for disturbing public order. Under Bulgarian law the church is banned from operating in the country.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria has sent an official request to Ukraine to extradite former Bulgarian deputy Doncho Dimitrov, Chief Prosecutor Ivan Tatarchev said. Dimitrov faces charges over outstanding credits to the private Crystalbank which was declared insolvent in February.</p>
<p>TRUD</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's defence ministry has approved a draft proposal to cut compulsory military service from 18 months to 12 months from January 1, Defence Minister Georgi Ananiev said.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom +359-2 981 4145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
