<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719242" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Malaysia's Perwaja withdraws FRN, plans another.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's Perwaja withdraws FRN, plans another.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian company Perwaja Terengganu's recently launched US$400 million floating rate note issue has been withdrawn, but another deal is planned.</p>
<p>The issue, which was guaranteed by the government of Malaysia, was withdrawn by the issuer and the guarantor, arranger Standard Chartered Bank said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Standard Chartered Bank has been mandated to arrange a new FRN issue with amended terms and conditions, the bank said.</p>
<p>The issue that was withdrawn had a final maturity of five years. It paid a coupon of 22 basis points and five basis points in fees.</p>
<p>A new issue could be launched as early as Friday, bankers said.</p>
<p>Perwaja, a state-owned insolvent steel maker, was found last year to have accumulated losses of 2.5 billion ringgit in losses and its previous government-appointed managers were investigated for financial mismanagement.</p>
<p>The government is now trying to privatize the company.</p>
<p>Despite the company's difficulties, bankers have shown some interest in the transaction because of the government guarantee. Investment-grade Malaysia generally is very popular with investors.</p>
<p>Bankers speculated that the issuer and the guarantor may have pulled the deal with the idea of negotiating more advantageous terms.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843-6371</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
