<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719311" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Hariri's 30-year $1 bln bond plan puzzles bankers.</title>
<headline>Hariri's 30-year $1 bln bond plan puzzles bankers.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Tarnowski</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lebanese bankers and financiers expressed surprise on Thursday at a proposal by Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri to fund emergency social spending with $1 billion worth of 30-year treasury bonds.</p>
<p>Hariri, plagued by a chronic cash shortage and worried by signs of unrest and a civil disobedience campaign in the eastern Bekaa valley, stunned cabinet ministers on Wednesday with the $1 billion bond proposal.</p>
<p>Newspapers said the proposal caused an uproar in the cabinet and two ministers walked out saying it would impose an intolerable tax burden on the country for 30 years. No decision was reached and a further meeting will be held on the issue.</p>
<p>A Beirut banker who asked not to be identified said he was amazed by the proposal. Other financiers in Beirut, where few secrets are kept for long, said they had never heard of it before Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first time I have heard about this. I don't think it is something well studied, particularly because of all this opposition in the cabinet,&quot; said M.H Bouldoukian, a former vice-governor of the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The country cannot support all these debts. One has to find out how it will pay,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Lebanon currently holds weekly auctions of treasury bills and bonds ranging from three months to two years. Financiers say the government is preparing to issue three-year bonds, but there has been no previous mention of 30-year bonds.</p>
<p>A finance house executive who asked not to be identified called the proposal ambitious.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's start first with a 10-year bond to set a benchmark. Thirty years is a little bit ambitious now, especially if it's for social development and such,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Another banker said the proposal was prepared secretly last week by Hariri, President Elias Hrawi, Bank of Lebanon Governor Riad Salameh and acting finance minister Fouad Siniora and the plan was to sell the bonds mainly in the United States.</p>
<p>But the banker added: &quot;I was amazed when I saw the mention of 30 years. I thought they meant three years.&quot;</p>
<p>If approved by the government, the bonds will require authorisation from parliament where foreign debt is a highly controversial issue.</p>
<p>Hariri's proposal followed the launch last week of a civil disobedience campaign to pressure the government to alleviate hunger and poverty in the Bekaa Valley.</p>
<p>Labour unionists, the media and opposition politicians have long complained that Hariri has ignored the plight of the poor in his multi-billion dollars drive to rebuild Lebanon.</p>
<p>The government, worried by Sheikh Sobhi Tufaili's Bekaa &quot;hunger revolt&quot;, has already announced emergency funding of $100 million for the Bekaa, but Hariri told the cabinet on Wednesday he wanted to increase this to $400 million.</p>
<p>He also proposed $600 million for education, medical care, south Lebanon and the return home of civil war refugees.</p>
<p>The 30-year t-bonds were designed to find a way round the government's cash shortage which has already caused a soaring public debt and massive annual budget deficits.</p>
<p>Public debt reached 22,622 billion Lebanese pounds ($14.7 billion) in May, close to the level of estimated GDP (Gross Domestic Product). The budget deficit of government income to expenditure was 56.3 percent for the first five months of the year compared with a 36 percent target for the year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
