<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71936" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-CARDINALS CLINCH TIE FOR CENTRAL TITLE.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-CARDINALS CLINCH TIE FOR CENTRAL TITLE.</headline>
<dateline>CINCINNATI 1996-09-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Todd Stottlemyre allowed two runs in 7-2/3 innings and Brian Jordan had three hits and two RBI as the St. Louis Cardinals clinched a tie for the National League Central Division title with a 3-2 victory over the Cincinnati Reds on Monday.</p>
<p>The loss officially eliminated the Reds.</p>
<p>The Cardinals reduced their magic number to one for clinching the Central. They can wrap up their first division crown since 1987 with a win at Pittsburgh on Tuesday or if Houston loses to the New York Mets.</p>
<p>Stottlemyre (14-11) held the Reds scoreless through the first seven innings. He surrendered six hits with three walks and struck out nine.</p>
<p>Rick Honeycutt got the final out of the eighth and Dennis Eckersley worked a perfect ninth for his 30th save as St. Louis snapped a three-game losing streak.</p>
<p>&quot;After losing the first three here, it means that much more to me to get the job done,&quot; Stottlemyre said. &quot;I had a lot of motivation coming in. This time of year, its is not hard to get up for a game.&quot;</p>
<p>In Atlanta, Jeff Blauser snapped a fifth-inning tie with a two-run single as the Atlanta Braves defeated the Montreal Expos 3-1 in the final regular-season game at Fulton-County Stadium, which was marred by a pre-game bomb threat.</p>
<p>A Braves spokesman said a bomb threat was received by telephone at the stadium, which was temporarily closed as police combed the building for 90 minutes without finding anything.</p>
<p>Greg Maddux and four relievers combined on a five-hitter as the Braves took the final four games of the five-game series. The Expos fell 2-1/2 games behind San Diego in the wild-card race.</p>
<p>In Pittsburgh, Luis Gonzalez cracked a three-run homer and Steve Trachsel allowed four hits over six innings as the Chicago Cubs notched a 4-3 victory over the Pittsburgh Pirates, who had their major league-high 11-game winning streak snapped.</p>
<p>With Pittsburgh leading 2-0 in the fourth, Brant Brown and Ryne Sandberg reached on consecutive singles before Gonzalez belted an 0-1 pitch from Jason Schmidt (5-6) over the right-field wall for his 13th homer.</p>
<p>Trachsel (13-9) gave up two runs, walked five and struck out four.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CINCINNATI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
