<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719372" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ballot questions and bond referendums by state.</title>
<headline>Ballot questions and bond referendums by state.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following is a list of upcoming ballot initiatives and measures affecting municipal finance.</p>
<p>P - passed. D - defeated. NA - not available.</p>
<p>FLORIDA</p>
<p>Sept. 2</p>
<p>--Marion County, half-cent sales tax increase for schools.</p>
<p>Sept. 4</p>
<p>--Miami referendum on whether the city should be dissolved and absorbed into the Metro-Dade County government.</p>
<p>Sept. 9</p>
<p>--Brevard County referendum on whether to refund controversial 1989 COPs issue.</p>
<p>GEORGIA</p>
<p>Sept. 16</p>
<p>--Effingham County, five-year extension of one-cent special purpose tax for infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>--Effingham County, one-cent sales tax for schools.</p>
<p>--Oconee County, one-cent sales tax for schools.</p>
<p>Nov. 4</p>
<p>--Savannah-Chatham County one-cent sales tax hike for schools.</p>
<p>ILLINOIS</p>
<p>Nov. 4</p>
<p>--DuPage County referendum to approve $75 million of GO bonds to buy 2,200 acres of open space.</p>
<p>LOUISIANA</p>
<p>July 19</p>
<p>--Lafayette City-Parish votes on $222 million of capital improvement bonds for streets, drainage and recreation.</p>
<p>NEW JERSEY</p>
<p>July 22</p>
<p>--$9.4 million Berlin Borough School District, N.J., bonds for renovation and new construction.</p>
<p>Oct. 7</p>
<p>--$5.75 million Cresskill, N.J., school bonds to renovate two elementary schools.</p>
<p>Nov. 4</p>
<p>--$20 million bond referendum to finance demolition of abandoned and dilapidated buildings in urban areas.</p>
<p>NORTH CAROLINA</p>
<p>July 8</p>
<p>--Randolph County's Trinity community votes on incorporation as separate city.</p>
<p>Oct. 7</p>
<p>--$98 million Cumberland County school GO bonds.</p>
<p>Nov. 4</p>
<p>--$500 million Mecklenburg County GO bonds for schools and jails.</p>
<p>--$25 million Alamance County school GO bonds.</p>
<p>MISSOURI</p>
<p>August 5</p>
<p>--$600,000 New Franklin GO bonds.</p>
<p>PENNSYLVANIA</p>
<p>Nov. 4</p>
<p>--Statewide referendum on a &quot;homestead exemption&quot; constitutional amendment, which would allow local governments to exempt homeowners from the property tax.</p>
<p>--Allegheny County, Pa., voters decide ballot question that would change county government from a three-member committee to a government comprised of an executive and unpaid county council.</p>
<p>--Ten Western Pennsylvania counties vote on proposed half-percent sales tax increase to build a new professional baseball stadium in Pittsburgh and expand the city's convention center.</p>
<p>SOUTH CAROLINA</p>
<p>Sept. 20</p>
<p>--$109.6 million Georgetown County GOs for schools.</p>
<p>VIRGINIA</p>
<p>Nov. 4</p>
<p>--$73.3 million Loudoun County school bond issue for school contruction and renovations.</p>
<p>WEST VIRGINIA</p>
<p>Sept. 27</p>
<p>--Statewide referendum on constitutional amendment allowing equity investment of public funds.</p>
<p>Nov. 15</p>
<p>--$98 million of Kanawha County school GOs.</p>
<p>--Renewal of Kanawha County excess levy to raise $9.93 million a year for bus and ambulance services.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
