<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719459" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Vermont June revs rise but may cut 1998 estimates.</title>
<headline>Vermont June revs rise but may cut 1998 estimates.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vermont on Thursday said it got 7.2 percent more tax revenues in June than a year-ago, but cautioned it might lower estimates for the 1998 fiscal year, citing &quot;more modest&quot; growth in the state's economy.</p>
<p>Another negative factor was a disapointing 5.7 percent drop in preliminary receipts for the Transportation Fund, when measured against the year-ago period.</p>
<p>&quot;Although revenue results in the General Fund for the year as a whole were encouraging, the profile of General Fund collections over the spring raises concerns about the revenue outlook for fiscal 1998,&quot; said Secretary of Administration, Kathleen Hoyt, in prepared remarks. Vermont started the new fiscal year on July 1.</p>
<p>Hoyt questioned whether a windfall in personal income tax estimates, which rose 30 percent due strong financial markets, would be sustained, and cited sluggish sales and use tax collections and recent dips in corporate income tax payments.</p>
<p>&quot;There is sufficient reason for healthy skepticism that the fiscal 1997 level of General Fund revenues did not reflect the current, more modest growth conditions of the Vermont economy,&quot; she added later. Estate tax collections were unexpected strong.</p>
<p>Vermont's Emergency Board, composed of the governor, and chairs of key financial committees, plans to meet later this month, and Hoyt at that time will provide revised forecasts.</p>
<p>Cumulative Transportation Fund revenue receipts through June 30 were $152 million, a 2.3 percent drop when compared with fiscal 1996. Hoyt forecast the Transportation Fund would end the year about $3.3 million shy of projections.</p>
<p>For fiscal 1997, revenues climbed 9.2 percent to $758.1 million, according to preliminary receipts. The following chart provides more details for June and 1997 revenues.</p>
<p>--Personal Income Tax, June, $35.8 million, up 9.2 percent. 1997, $323.1 million, up 15 percent.</p>
<p>--Sales and Use, June, $14.4 million, up 2.8 percent. 1997,  $183.8 million, up 0.7 percent.</p>
<p>--Rooms and Meals, June, $4.6 percent, up 9.9 percent. 1997, $64.1 million, up 3.7 percent.</p>
<p>--Corporate Income, $5.6 million, down 18.6 percent. 1997, $42.3 million, down 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>--Property Transfer, $1.3 milion, up 25.5 percent. 1997, $13.7 million, up 11.4 percent.</p>
<p>--Other, $13.5 million, up 8.8 percent. 1997, $131.7 million, up 14.7 percent.</p>
<p>--TOTAL, June $75.2 million, up 7.2 percent. 1997, $758.7 million, up 9.2 percent.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
