<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719469" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MGE spring wheat drifts to end mostly lower.</title>
<headline>MGE spring wheat drifts to end mostly lower.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>MGE spring wheat futures settled mostly lower in light volume on a general lack of buying, and traders said the market was focused on the Friday release of USDA's July crop report.</p>
<p>Traders said the market defied some pre-opening calls, which suggested prices would be supported throughout the day by bullish USDA weekly wheat export data.</p>
<p>&quot;Early on, people thought we would rally because of the export sales number, so a lot of locals stocked up early. But then nothing happened. The locals got out fast and then we just leaked all day,&quot; an MGE floor source said.</p>
<p>Traders said most players expected Friday's report to show a sharp increase in USDA's estimates of total U.S. winter wheat production and overall world wheat carryout.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody's concerned about tomorrow's report, but there's some feeling that we've already priced a big number into the market and we could end up seeing a bounce if the number isn't all that big,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>A Reuters average of analysts' estimates put hard red winter wheat production at 1.000 billion bushels. That compares to USDA's June production estimate of 921 million bushels.</p>
<p>MGE spring wheat settled 4-3/4 cents a bushel higher in spot July, while other months fell four to nine cents. September dropped four cents to $3.55-1/4.</p>
<p>The MGE estimated Thursday's spring wheat futures volume at 19.62 million bushels, up from Wednesday's volume of 15.789 million bushels.</p>
<p>((--Greg Frost, Kansas City bureau 816 561-8671))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
