<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719438" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Spot Prods--Gulf, Harbor gasolines spike higher.</title>
<headline>US Spot Prods--Gulf, Harbor gasolines spike higher.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Gulf conventional gasoline differentials shot higher late Thursday as traders chased prices higher to cover short positions.</p>
<p>New York Harbor premium grade gasoline differentials also blew out as tight supplies forced buyers to outbid each other.</p>
<p>On the NYMEX, August gasoline gained 0.37 cent to settle at 58.75 cents a gallon and August heating oil firmed 0.09 cent to end at 52.20 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>U.S. Gulf</p>
<p>Regular conventional gasoline differentials soared higher late Thursday, as refiners and traders moved to cover commitments, boosting levels above the August NYMEX price for the second day in a row.</p>
<p>&quot;There's some people short and they just keep pushing it up,&quot; one market trader said.</p>
<p>Prompt regular conventional M1 gasoline changed hands at 0.65 cent over the August NYMEX gasoline, according to market players, about 0.50 cent over the peak reached on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Prompt M1 had slipped back to about 0.40 cent under the August futures by late morning, though prices surged throughout the afternoon.</p>
<p>Conventional M1 gasoline for delivery next week was talked between flat to 0.25 cent over the August NYMEX, traders said.</p>
<p>Prompt reformulated A1 gasoline also appeared to be in short supply with very few traders in the region holding barrels.</p>
<p>&quot;I had a few calls looking for the A-grades today, but nobody would show a bid,&quot; another player said.</p>
<p>Market traders dismissed talk that the fire that shut a 20,000 barrel per day hydrocracker at Mobil's Chalmette, Louisiana had a bullish effect on differentials Thursday.</p>
<p>NEW YORK HARBOR</p>
<p>Premium gasoline remained the hot topic in the Harbor Thursday with the &quot;V2&quot; 93-octane conventional premium blend the focal point of the strength that traders said was based on bonafide tightness.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one to watch,&quot; said one trader, noting that with the Houston-to-New York arbitrage window on the Colonial Pipeline now closed, it was quite possible that with supplies as tight as they are, differentials could firm even more.</p>
<p>Prompt V2, while not confirmed done, was heard offered over a cent firmer than on Wednesday at 7.00 cents over August NYMEX unleaded.</p>
<p>Tightness in MTBE and in aromatics used to enhance octane were also cited as key to premium's strength, traders said.</p>
<p>Regular &quot;A2&quot; 87-octane reformulated gasoline also got a shot in the arm, trading at firmer levels of 0.50 cent over the August print, and possibly as high as 0.75 cent over.</p>
<p>But distillates, while enjoying solid demand so far this summer, remained a soporific trading proposition in cash markets, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;All you have to do is go outside to understand,&quot; said the Harbor trader, referring to the fine and balmy summer weather in the Northeast.</p>
<p>MIDCONTINENT</p>
<p>Markets were little changed in the Midcontinent by late day. Group Three unleaded gasoline differentials were pegged at 3.00/3.25 cents over August futures, with any months done at 2.25 cents.</p>
<p>Chicago prompt unleaded gasoline differentials were a tad lower at 2.50/3.00 cents, and the any months at about 1.75/2.00 cents.</p>
<p>Players said they saw some refiner demand in both hubs but the focus was on August barrels of gasoline.</p>
<p>The distillate side was also largely steady. Prompt low sulphur in Group Three was done at 2.60 over August futures and 2.35 cents over the print traded hands for any month barrels.</p>
<p>-- New York Oil Desk 1 212 859 1633</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
