<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719470" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Midwest direct hogs seen steady-firm - dealers.</title>
<headline>US Midwest direct hogs seen steady-firm - dealers.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Midwest direct cash hog prices on Friday were seen steady, with a firm tone amid moderate demand, particularly in the western Corn Belt, and light marketings, livestock dealers and packer buyers said.</p>
<p>Some packers need hogs to fill Friday's slaughter needs, sources said. Those seeking hogs for Saturday also could lend support if they bid higher for expected light numbers.</p>
<p>However, demand in parts of the eastern belt was expected to be lighter than in the west, on news that Indiana Packers Corp. would not slaughter on Friday because of scheduled downtime for maintenance.  </p>
<p>The light demand in the eastern belt could keep prices steady in that area, the dealers said.</p>
<p>Interior Iowa and southern Minnesota top prices for hogs delivered to the plant were seen at $59.00 to possibly $59.50.</p>
<p>Illinois top hog prices at plants were expected at $58.50, with a few possible at $59.00, sources there said. Indiana/Ohio top hog prices were seen at $59.50.</p>
<p>Some outlooks for hot, humid weather to move into the Midwest over the weekend also could lend support as packers start competing Friday for hogs to book for Monday slaughter, dealers said.</p>
<p>((Bob Janis 312-983-7347))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
