<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719560" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Illinois tollway and bond trustee file appeals.</title>
<headline>Illinois tollway and bond trustee file appeals.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Illinois State Toll Highway Authority and the trustee over nearly $1 billion of debt have filed notices of appeal with the state Supreme Court.</p>
<p>Both the Toll Authority and First National Bank of Chicago, a unit of First Chicago NBD Corp, filed their notices with the high court June 27.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Toll Authority filed a motion asking the Supreme Court to expedite consideration of its appeal of a lower court decision overturning the agency's budget practices.</p>
<p>Taxpayers challenging the Toll Authority practices have filed motions to dismiss the appeals, attorney Lee Schwartz said Thursday.</p>
<p>The Illinois Supreme Court has adjourned for the summer, but often addresses requests for expedited appeals before returning for its September term.</p>
<p>Cook County Judge Stephen Schiller found in May that the Toll Authority's budget practices failed to meet requirements.</p>
<p>Schiller entered a preliminary injunction last month and stayed its effect until December 15 to give the General Assembly an opportunity to adopt a budget and the Toll Authority time to appeal.</p>
<p>State Rep. Jeffrey Schoenberg, D-Evanston, has called a joint hearing of two House committees next Wednesday in Chicago to begin addressing the court decision as well.</p>
<p>A request by the taxpayers to make Toll Authority officials personally liable and vendors liable for spending made without proper appropriations remains pending before Schiller. The parties are due back before Schiller on August 6 on that issue.</p>
<p>The state court ruling has also prompted Moody's Investors Service, Standard &amp; Poor's and Fitch Investors Service to raise possible negative implications for the Toll Authority's approximately $979 million of outstanding debt.</p>
<p>While confident in their own budgets, officials from the Illinois Development Finance Authority, Illinois Educational Facilities Authority and Illinois Housing Development Authority have said they are closely following the litigation to see if it could affect them also.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, Chicago Newsroom, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
