<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719535" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle end up sharply on fund buying.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle end up sharply on fund buying.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle futures again rallied sharply late on active fund buying and buy stops with deferreds setting new contract highs, traders said.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle followed live cattle higher on buy stops with lower corn futures providing early strength, sources said.</p>
<p>Live cattle closed 1.225 to 0.425 cent per lb higher with August up most at 64.975 cents. February through distant August posted new contract highs with February setting a fresh high of 73.000 cents before closing at 72.775 cents.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle ended 1.025 to 0.400 cent a lb higher with August up the most at 81.125 cents. November and January posted new contract highs at 83.200 cents and 83.700 cents, respectively.</p>
<p>Live cattle futures rallied as early pressure from weak cash markets subsided and the overall tone to live markets turned firmer. Commercial short covering then turned the market up with fund technical buying adding to gains and touching off buy stops on the late rally, traders said.</p>
<p>Beef sales were active at retail meat counters over the holiday weekend and feedlot showlists were oversold, forcing packers to raise bids and pay $62 per cwt, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;All of that (fundamental strength) is switching the packer attitute toward $62 bids from $61,&quot; said Don Roose, president U.S. Commodities Inc.  </p>
<p>However, Roose said the bulk of the runup in futures came from fund buying and buy stops.</p>
<p>R.J. O'Brien, ABN Chicogo Corp, RBH, Lind-Waldock and E.D.&amp;F. Man bought August while Rosenthal Collins and R.J. O'Brien bought October, traders said. In live cattle options, commission houses sold December 72 to 76 calls and bought August 62 puts and 64 and 66 calls, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle futures also surged late as spillover momentum from the rally in live cattle added to early demand sparked by lower corn futures. Buy stops further reinforced the late advance, traders said.</p>
<p>Technically the charts point higher and fundamentally the market continues to indicate tight feeder supplies. The upcoming U.S. Cattle Inventory report should confirm tight feeder cattle numbers, they said.</p>
<p>Early analysts' estimates on the inventory report which will be released July 18, point to feeder cattle supplies running at 96.4 to 98 percent of last year as of July 1. The estimated calf crop is running 97 to 98 percent.</p>
<p>The latest CME feeder cattle index was up $0.35 at $80.75 per cwt. This is close to the recent high of $80.87 and at highest levels since April 1994.</p>
<p>R.J. O'Brien sold August early and ADM Investor Services sold late against general demand and buy stops. LIT division of First Options notably bought while Stone Traders and LFG bought August live cattle and sold August feeders. Cargill Investor Services bought June live cattle and sold January feeders early, pit sources said.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
