<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719625" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Healthdyne sees better profit margins ahead.</title>
<headline>Healthdyne sees better profit margins ahead.</headline>
<dateline>MARIETTA, Ga. 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Healthdyne Technologies Inc said Thursday it expects gross profit margins to improve further as it introduces new products.</p>
<p>In the second quarter, gross profit margin improved more than three percentage points from the first quarter of 1997 as the company shifted its product mix towards higher margin products, it said.</p>
<p>Quarterly revenue growth came from rapid acceptance of Quantum, a non-invasive ventilator; growth in the line of sleep disorders products; and increased sales of asthma management products.  </p>
<p>Healthdyne also said a &quot;major pharmaceutical company,&quot; which it did not identify, selected its asthma subsidiary to provide some products as part of the U.S. launch campaign for their recently approved anti-asthma drug.</p>
<p>Healthdyne's second quarter included a charge of $510,000, or $0.04 per share, related to expenses associated with Invacare's unsolicited hostile takeover attempt. After those expenses, which totaled $850,000 before taxes, the net earnings were $2.2 million or $0.16 per share.</p>
<p>Invacare has been seeking to acuire Healthdyne in a hostile bid since January.</p>
<p>The bid is now valued at about $200 million. Its latest offer to acquire all outstanding shares of Healthdyne common stock at $15 a share is scheduled to expire August 1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARIETTA, Ga."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
