<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719724" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Constantinescu says Romania still in EU running.</title>
<headline>Constantinescu says Romania still in EU running.</headline>
<dateline>SALZBURG, Austria 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romanian President Emil Constantinescu said on Thursday news that the European Commission would not recommend starting European Union entry talks with Romania was premature.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe this is a hasty announcement by sources in the European Commission and this does not reflect the point of view of the heads of state and governments of member countries,&quot; Constantinescu told Reuters during an economic summit here.</p>
<p>Constantinescu, whose country earlier this week narrowly missed inclusion in the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation's first wave of eastward expansion, said he still hoped Romania would be among the first East European states to join the EU.</p>
<p>&quot;I have had personal discussions with several heads of states and government and they have told me it is not their point of view (that Romania should be excluded), so I do not believe that such a decision will be taken,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Senior European Commission officials in Brussels said earlier the Commission had agreed in principle to begin talks with Poland, Hungary, the Czech Republic, Slovenia, Estonia and Cyprus.</p>
<p>The final decision will be taken in Strasbourg, France on Tuesday, a day before the EU executive officially unveils its recommendations to EU governments on which of the 10 East European applicants it should invite to start negotiations.</p>
<p>Constantinescu urged Brussels to begin membership talks with all the candidates simultaneously. &quot;I do not believe that one can begin from a hierarchy,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SALZBURG, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
