<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719798" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: American jailed in Finland for HIV manslaughter.</title>
<headline>American jailed in Finland for HIV manslaughter.</headline>
<byline>John Acher</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Finnish court sentenced an American to 14 years in prison on 17 charges of attempted manslaughter on Thursday, ruling he had unprotected sex even though he knew he had the virus that causes AIDS.</p>
<p>&quot;The defendant is found guilty of the attempts at manslaughter on the basis that he was aware of his HIV infection while committing the acts and that he concealed his disease,&quot; the court said in its judgment.</p>
<p>The court said the defendant, 36-year-old Steven Thomas from New York, had infected five of 17 women with the virus and ordered him to pay damages of 330,000 to 380,000 markka ($63,000-73,000) to each infected victim.</p>
<p>The case, which blew up in January, stunned Finland when a picture of Thomas, who is black, was splashed alongside his name in Finnish press, and police said he may have had unprotected sex with more than 100 Finnish women.</p>
<p>Police first released Thomas's name, then skin colour, and finally his picture, saying they weighed the usual right to privacy against the need to find all the victims.</p>
<p>Some Finns, including leading politicians, voiced concerns about privacy rights and said publishing the picture risked labelling a whole group of foreigners or black people as suspicious.</p>
<p>Finland has a very low rate of HIV infection -- only about 600 of the 5.1 million population -- and a relatively very small black population.</p>
<p>Markku Fredman, representing six of the victims, said the court's view was stern, &quot;but it had to be stern: the lives of five people were entirely destroyed here&quot;.</p>
<p>Thomas's lawyer Aarno Arvela said he would appeal against the sentence, which he described as one of the harshest in Finland short of life imprisonment: &quot;I hope to get understanding for the view that what he did was not deliberate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The court said Thomas committed the crimes between March 1993 and mid-December 1996, at a time when the deadly nature of the virus, transmitted through body fluids, was well known.</p>
<p>Thomas came to Helsinki in 1991 and married a Finnish woman, but later separated. He held various bar and restaurant jobs and had two children with his wife, and later a third child with another woman. He tested positive for the AIDS virus in 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;New drugs introduced in the 1990s mainly extend the patient's life and improve its quality, but do not cure the disease,&quot; the court ruled.</p>
<p>After Thomas's picture had been published the court declared the case secret, to protect the victims, and has sealed the trial documents for the next 40 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
