<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="719813" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Tunnel to future Berlin government area ruptures.</title>
<headline>Tunnel to future Berlin government area ruptures.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Cole</byline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The cement shell of a railway tunnel leading to Germany's future government quarter ruptured overnight and firefighters staged an emergency rescue operation early on Thursday to prevent its total collapse.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Berlin firefighters said they had been blasting 300 cubic litres of water per hour into the subterranean casing under Potsdamer Platz, Europe's largest construction site, to prevent its walls caving in.</p>
<p>Fire department officials said no one had been injured.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Deutsche Bahn, one of the companies building the tunnel, declined to comment on the potential cost of the accident or when work could begin again.</p>
<p>&quot;We still don't know exactly how it happened. But it may have been caused by a crack in the concrete or an imbalance in pressure,&quot; between the water in the shell and the water table beneath it, spokeswoman Claudia Ruttmann told German radio.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to have more information from divers who are investigating the site,&quot; Ruttmann said.</p>
<p>The planned 3.5-km (2.2-mile) tunnel will include tracks for an intercity rail link, a subway line and highway. It will run under the city centre and come out in front of the Reichstag parliament building in the new government complex.</p>
<p>The vast tunnel project, which is also being built by German contractors Hochtief and Holzmann, is intended to restore a traffic infrastructure destroyed during World War Two and never redeveloped during the city's 40-year division by the Berlin Wall.</p>
<p>But the construction has required feats of engineering which have left many Berliners worrying that the disruption could damage famous landmarks like the Brandenburg Gate.</p>
<p>Leaders of the IG Bau construction workers union, who are in the midst of a region-wide strike over pay, said the accident was the result of using cheap foreign labour.</p>
<p>&quot;This is what the IG Bau has been predicting for years, that a major project that was just before completion would be forced to stop and be repaired,&quot; IG Bau director Rainer Knerler told journalists.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a perfect example of what is happening on Potsdamer Platz -- that unqualified cheaper labour is being used and the quality of the work is suffering,&quot; Knerler said.</p>
<p>Deutsche Bahn rejected the union's accusations and said that until a cause for the rupture had been identified, no one could be held directly responsible.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
