<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="71994" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Stentor asks Canada telecom watchdog to deregulate.</title>
<headline>Stentor asks Canada telecom watchdog to deregulate.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's Stentor group of telephone companies said on Tuesday it has filed with the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission asking the telecommunications watchdog to stop regulating inter-exchange private line services.</p>
<p>These services allow large customers to lease dedicated capacity from the public network to run their voice, data, video and image transmissions to their various offices across the country, from Canada to the United States and internationally through the facilities of U.S. carriers or satellite provider Teleglobe Canada Inc.  </p>
<p>Stentor said it excluded from its application its dedicated local access services such as Digital Network Access service and Local Channel services.</p>
<p>The group said it asked the CRTC to rule by January 2, 1997 and, if the regulator agrees to the application, to get out of regulating these services by April 2 that year.</p>
<p>Stentor, which consists of nine telephone companies, said competition in Canada's private line market is heating up, particularly in the high-capacity area. Stentor's share of the higher capacity market is roughly 50 percent, and the group said this should fall as competitors expand their reach.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
