<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720194" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada's beauty queen loses title after conviction.</title>
<headline>Canada's beauty queen loses title after conviction.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's beauty queen was stripped of her title on Wednesday after being convicted of assault for causing bodily harm in a barroom brawl that left another woman with two black eyes and a broken nose.</p>
<p>Danielle House, formerly Miss Canada International, was given a suspended sentence and a year's probation in Newfoundland's provincial court for the attack last year on her ex-boyfriend's new girlfriend.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes she has lost her title,&quot; said Sylvia Stark, chief executive officer of the Canadian pageant. &quot;Because she is a role model, we cannot condone someone convicted of assault.&quot;</p>
<p>Annalee Gosse testified she was punched four times in the face and once in the back during a series of attacks on the night of Oct. 18.</p>
<p>The 20-year-old student was treated for a broken nose, two black eyes and a bruised left temple. She also suffered a chipped tooth and swollen lip in the attack that crown lawyers said was prompted by jealousy over the boyfriend.</p>
<p>House, whose story attracted wide media attention, said she only hit the woman once while she was trying to break free from the grasp of her old boyfriend.</p>
<p>Stark said the Canadian pageant has not lost the support of its sponsors over the incident but said the pageant did suffer because House was unable to do much charity work while the court case was under way.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
