<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720217" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: GHENT TO HELP REDEVELOP BRAZILIAN PORT OF ANTONINA.</title>
<headline>GHENT TO HELP REDEVELOP BRAZILIAN PORT OF ANTONINA.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ghent Harbour Authority is working with the Brazilian authorities at Antonina in a bid to redevelop the South American port.</p>
<p>Eddy Daniels, Ghent deputy commercial director, said the Belgian port has taken on a commercial and technical constancy role at the Brazilian port.</p>
<p>&quot;The Brazilians are financing the project and Ghent will provide the know-how,&quot; he said. Ghent will also provide staff training.    Antonina is in the same bay as the major soybean</p>
<p>exporting port of Paranagua, south of Sao Paulo. It comprises a 100,000 sq metre site.</p>
<p>A 360 metre quay wall and a new terminal on reclaimed land will be built. Work has just started and is forecast to be completed by the end of 1998 or early 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of interest in the area, especially from car manufacturers,&quot; added Daniels. Renault is in the process of building a plant near Paranagua.</p>
<p>Warehouses and coldstores will be built at Antonina as the region is a major producer of chickens, he said. Many other frozen foods are also expected to be exported from the port.</p>
<p>--Reuters Shipping News + 44 171 5421 4087, Fax 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
