<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720219" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Ireland Protestants defend right to march.</title>
<headline>N.Ireland Protestants defend right to march.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Protestant Orangemen pressed ahead on Thursday with plans to stage weekend marches through flashpoint Catholic areas of Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>A call by U.S. Representative Joseph Kennedy in Washington urging that Orange Order marches should be banned along disputed routes found no support among those who will doing the marching on Saturday in Belfast and Londonderry.</p>
<p>Kennedy said: &quot;The resolution sends a clear and simple message to the British government and to Prime Minister Tony Blair: Orange Order marches should be banned along disputed routes.&quot;</p>
<p>Such parades &quot;only serve to inflame tensions and further undermine the fragile peace process&quot;, he added.</p>
<p>An Orange march along the Catholic Garvaghy Road in Portadown last Sunday sparked some of the worst nationalist violence in the British-ruled province for many years.</p>
<p>Police on Thursday blew up a suspicious package left outside the offices of the Ulster Unionist Party (UUP), the main Protestant political party which wants Northern Ireland to say British.</p>
<p>An uneasy calm appeared to have settled on the province in the run-up to the weekend. &quot;There's not much to report. The city's quiet,&quot; a Belfast police spokesman said.</p>
<p>John Taylor, a senior member of the UUP, dismissed a suggestion that the Orange Order should take the high ground and call off its parades as &quot;nationalist propaganda&quot;.</p>
<p>An Orange Order spokesman added: &quot;We are all fearful of what might happen, but we want the parade to pass off peacefully.&quot;</p>
<p>Saturday is the &quot;glorious&quot; 12th of July, the high point of the annual marching season when Orangemen stage parades to mark the 1690 Protestant battle victory over a Catholic King.</p>
<p>The Orange Order was reported by political sources to be under intense pressure to modify its proposed marches down Belfast's Lower Ormeau Road and in the city centre of Londonderry but there was no sign it would agree to any change.</p>
<p>The centuries-old Order says it is being wrongly blamed for the violence which flared after Sunday's march along the Garvaghy Road and wants only to hold peaceful marches to celebrate its Protestant faith and British loyalty.</p>
<p>Nationalist spokesmen called for peaceful demonstrations in protest against the Orange marches.</p>
<p>Catholic leaders urged their supporters to turn up in their thousands to prevent what they see as sectarian, triumphalist parades on their doorsteps on Saturday.</p>
<p>A sports club near the Lower Ormeau Road was partly destroyed in what police said was an arson attack on Wednesday evening. Stones were thrown at bus carrying nationalists back from a demonstration was attacked and three women were hurt.</p>
<p>The general level of violence has subsided in last few days but security forces were braced for more unrest.</p>
<p>&quot;It's much quieter. But I get the feeling it's only half time,&quot; said one security source.</p>
<p>Britain has said it was sending between 400 and 500 more troops to the province to &quot;combat terrorism and help maintain law and order&quot; and back up police who are in the front line against the unrest.</p>
<p>Gerry Adams, president of Sinn Fein, the political wing of the Irish Republican Army (IRA), maintained a barrage of criticism at Britain's handling of the march issue but appealed to his Catholic supporters not to sully the community's image with riots and petrol-bombing.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to maintain the focus on where it should be and that is the British government's treatment of nationalists who are being deprived of their rights,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gerard Rice, the Ormeau Road residents' association spokesman, appealed to &quot;right-thinking Catholics across Ireland to stop work for two hours on Friday&quot; in an island-wide protest at Britain's handling of contentious parades.</p>
<p>A woman supporter of the Orange Order said: &quot;It's not Gerard Rice's road, it's a public highway.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
