<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720310" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold fixes firmer but remains cautious.</title>
<headline>London gold fixes firmer but remains cautious.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold prices opened firmer on Thursday but market concerns about new declines had far from abated, one week after a drop to 12-year lows was triggered by news that Australia's central bank had sold bullion from reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;People are a bit more bullish this morning  but there is nothing to change the overall fear,&quot; one dealer said, adding support levels holding on Wednesday had lifted sentiment a bit.</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $319.65 per ounce up from $317.30 on Wednesday afternoon and little changed from the London close of $319.50/$320.00.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been a business either side of the market and now we are waiting for New York to move,&quot; another dealer said, putting gold's likely range for the day at $317.00-$320.00.</p>
<p>The New York Comex futures option expiry on Friday suggested there was room for gold on the upside, dealers said.</p>
<p>Open interest was fairly light on the August $320, $325 and $330 puts making a route towards $328 for cash possible, a dealer said.</p>
<p>However intitial resistance at $320.00 would have to be overcome which might be helped by short covering, dealers said.</p>
<p>Gold price fell to their lowest in almost 12 years late last week on news on Thursday that the Reserve Bank of Australia had sold 167 tonnes from its reserves in the previous six months.</p>
<p>Australia is the world's third largest gold miner.</p>
<p>A London-based representative of a major Japanese trading conglomerate confirmed that his company had received its July palladium shipment from Russia scheduled for July 10.</p>
<p>Platinum shipments are expected to arrive from Moscow next week, the source added.</p>
<p>Platinum and palladium prices reached seven-year and 17-year highs respectively last month as tightness resulting from Russia being out of the market since December began to bite.</p>
<p>Palladium was indicated at $166.00/$170.00 barely changed overnight but around $17 down from the beginning of the week and around its lowest levels since mid May.</p>
<p>Platinum was steady at $396.00/$400.00 after breaching the psychologically significant $400.00 level on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said consumers were being extremely cautious about rebuilding inventories depleted since Russia stopped exporting in the expectation of lower prices to come.</p>
<p>Silver was a couple of cents firmer at $4.35/$4.37 having come off a 50 percent retracement from $4.25.</p>
<p>--Brian Spoors London Newsroom +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
