<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720350" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent softens on gas oil pre-expiry gyrations.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent softens on gas oil pre-expiry gyrations.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent crude futures were softer on Thursday as traders sold gas oil ahead of its expiry at 1100 GMT, traders said.</p>
<p>The market was also hungry for fresh news about the possibility of fresh Iraqi exorts under the country's oil-for-food deal with the United Nations.</p>
<p>August Brent crude was seven cents a barrel weaker at $18.15 at 0935 GMT. July gas oil was $1 per tonne weaker at $161.50 and August gas oil was 75 cents lower at $162.50.</p>
<p>&quot;Gas oil is coming off the board today and that has pulled Brent down with it,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Brent has also broken through a little bit of support,&quot; he added, noting that intermonth spreads on the gas oil had fallen to $1 in backwardation, from even money at the open.</p>
<p>Dealers were also awaiting fresh news from Baghdad after Iraq gave the United Nations a preliminary draft of its food distribution and procurement plans on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The U.N. coordinator in Baghdad said on Wednesday the distribution plan needed more work before it could be approved but gave no indication as to how long this would take.</p>
<p>&quot;The key news that the market is waiting for is whether or not the Iraqi plan is acceptable to the U.N.,&quot; brokers GNI said in a daily report.</p>
<p>Tightness on the physical markets in Europe was reinforced by fresh data issued by the Euroilstock Foundation on Wednesday afternoon that crude and oil product inventories had fallen in Europe in June by some 18 million barrels.</p>
<p>Technical analysts noted that the market reached a low of $18.08 both on Tuesday and Wednesday, and reached highs on the same days at $18.39 and then $18.40.</p>
<p>These are expected to provide brackets again for the market but analysts expect that if there is a move, it is more likely to be downward, with next support at $17.97.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
