<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720373" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli gestures may help kick-start peace talks.</title>
<headline>Israeli gestures may help kick-start peace talks.</headline>
<byline>Nidal al-Mughrabi</byline>
<dateline>GAZA 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinians said on Thursday mutual confidence-building measures could help jump-start Israeli-PLO peace talks frozen for four months.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, having resolved a coalition crisis that paralysed his government for weeks, appealed to Jordan's King Hussein to help put peace talks back on track.</p>
<p>Palestinian negotiator Nabil Shaath on Wednesday night discussed for three hours opening a Palestinian airport in the self-ruled Gaza Strip with Israel's Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai in Tel Aviv.</p>
<p>Shaath said the airport, construction of a port in Gaza and the opening of a safe passage for Palestinians to travel between the West Bank and Gaza -- issues agreed upon under interim peace deals but never implemented because of disputes over security arrangements -- could help jump-start the talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The airport, the sea port, the safe passage and release of prisoners and the regaining of security coordination on a tripartite basis are all measures designed to bring about sufficient confidence so we can address the more difficult question of settlements and negotiations,&quot; Shaath told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope that the meeting will lead to something concrete on the ground...Only then would I feel that confidence has been regained,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Israeli-PLO talks were suspended in March when Israel began building a new Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem. The PLO had said it would resume talks only after Israel halted the construction.</p>
<p>Palestinian and Israeli officials said Israel agreed to let the Palestinian Authority import electronic equipment necessary for opening the airport but they had yet to agree on security arrangements within the terminal.</p>
<p>Palestinian head of civil aviation Fayez Zidan said Israel had promised a written response on aviation, security and civilian matters next week when he and his Israeli counterpart would meet.</p>
<p>&quot;The coming week will prove whether yesterday's meeting was a meeting of propaganda or for the media, or whether it will be translated into facts on the ground,&quot; Zidan told Reuters.</p>
<p>The ambassadors from Egypt and the United States attended the meeting. The two countries are trying to broker a revival of peace talks.</p>
<p>Some Palestinian negotiators privately objected to the meeting, saying it signalled a PLO compromise on its demand that Israel first stop building Jewish settlements.</p>
<p>But Shaath said the PLO still insisted that Israel suspend settlement-building. Israel refuses, saying interim peace deals do not prohibit the construction.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's office said the prime minister spoke by phone on Thursday with King Hussein.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister told the king that he expects help from any element that can help advance the peace process in the region,&quot; Netanyahu's office said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;King Hussein promised to do his best to help advance the peace process,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>In the West Bank town of Hebron, Israeli soldiers fired rubber bullets at Palestinian demonstrators who pelted them with stones and hurled fire bombs during unrest sparked by Israel's shutting down of Palestinian shops in parts of the West Bank city under Israeli control.</p>
<p>The Israeli army ordered the shops closed and sent army jeeps to enforce the order in response to the firing overnight of shots at a Jewish settler's enclave. There were no reports of casualties in either incident.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
