<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72040" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Brooklyn Union units boost natgas sales.</title>
<headline>Brooklyn Union units boost natgas sales.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brooklyn Union Gas Co, the New York-based utility, is deploying deregulated subsidiaries to boost its local market share while looking ahead at opportunities in electricity, senior company officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an appropriate move at this time as the industry moves into a deregulated environment,&quot; Robert Catell, Brooklyn Union's chairman and chief executive officer, told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;It gives us more flexibility and added value to shareholders.&quot;  </p>
<p>Earlier this month, the New York Public Service Commission approved Brooklyn Union's plans to reorganize its gas distribution operations and subsidiaries into a holding company, called KeySpan Energy Corp.</p>
<p>The restructuring plan still needs SEC and shareholder approval, expected in February.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, members of the KeySpan group, independent of the regulated Brooklyn Union utility, already have been targeting the gas market and related services in the tri-state region of New York, New Jersey, and Connecticut.  </p>
<p>William Feraudo, senior vice president in the KeySpan Energy Marketing Group, said that since late May KeySpan has picked up about 1,200 customers - mostly commerical, like diners and dry cleaners - in the New York City area.</p>
<p>This translates into gas sales of about 1.2 billion cubic feet on an annualized basis.</p>
<p>Most of the new customers are in territory traditionally served by neighboring Long Island Lighting Co (Lilco) and from Brooklyn Union's own 1.1 million customers.  </p>
<p>The Public Service Commission has approved 21 marketers to sell gas to former Brooklyn Union customers using the utility's existing distribution lines. Only nine of them, including KeySpan, have actually locked up contracts.</p>
<p>Of 1,100 former Brooklyn Union customers now choosing their gas supplier, about 70 percent have signed contracts with KeySpan, while KeySpan has about 45 percent of the 1,600 former Lilco customers now arranging their own suppliers.</p>
<p>New York State so far is the only one in the Northeast to deregulate its gas market, though there are pilot programs in states like New Jersey and Massachusetts.  </p>
<p>&quot;We haven't really hit New Jersey yet, we're planning on doing that in October,&quot; Feraudo said.</p>
<p>&quot;As additional states in the Northeast open up, we'll study these too,&quot; Catell said.</p>
<p>KeySpan Energy Services Inc, another member of the group, last week launched a pilot program for residential customers, hoping to attract 1,000 users within a month, Catell said.</p>
<p>Billing will be a potentially thorny issue in this market.</p>
<p>&quot;We think we have a significant advantage over other gas marketers, coming from a utility background,&quot; said Feraudo.  </p>
<p>Through its KeySpan Energy Management Inc, the company is also offering comprehensive energy management packages, including financing, upgrading, operating and maintaining energy units, and fuel purchasing, said Feraudo.</p>
<p>He called the company &quot;fuel neutral,&quot; explaining &quot;We are not bound to gas. We very much like dual fuel systems so we can use whichever makes sense economically.&quot;</p>
<p>KeySpan Energy Management Inc already has 25 customers and, through its recent affiliation with South Jersey Energy Co, has submitted energy management proposals to about half a dozen industrial customers in southern New Jersey.  </p>
<p>&quot;We also see ourselves marketing electricity down the road as that market follows the gas industry in deregulation,&quot; Catell said.</p>
<p>Efforts by the company to enter the electricity sector have been limited by the lack of an open local market.</p>
<p>&quot;We are talking to electric partners, looking for the right combination, and think that some time in the next year we will have a partner or partners,&quot; said Feraudo.</p>
<p>He said their initial foray into electricity would be focused on the U.S. Northeast. &quot;It's the area we know best.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York Power Desk + 1 212 859 1621</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
