<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720416" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk children wear producer Ceylan to float shares.</title>
<headline>Turk children wear producer Ceylan to float shares.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's leading children's wear producer and exporter Ceylan Giyim Sanayi ve Ticaret A.S will float shares representing 20 percent of its capital in a two-day offer beginning on July 15, the company said.</p>
<p>The price will be 15,500 lira per 1,000 lira nominal value share in the offer to be lead-managed by Finans Yatirim and co-led by Is Yatirim.</p>
<p>The company will waive 37 billion lira of preemptive rights to offer them to the public when raising its capital to 185 billion lira from current 148 billion.</p>
<p>Of the total offer, 40 percent will be allocated to foreign institutions and the remaining will be sold in the domestic market.</p>
<p>The Istanbul-based Ceylan Giyim's general manager Lale Karaoglu said income from the public offer would be used to pay down bank debts and improve production.</p>
<p>&quot;Our capacity and turnover will increase with the support we will give to our allied producers. Our debts will also be closed after the public offer, so we expect our (1997) profit to easily rise to 400 billion lira,&quot; Karaoglu said.</p>
<p>Ceylan Giyim, set up 35 years ago, processes fabrics and then cuts them according to their own or customers' designs. It afterwards sends these semi-finished materials to its allied producers which complete them as children's wear.</p>
<p>Ceylan's net sales rose 94 percent to 1.48 trillion lira and net profits jumped 183 percent to 77 billion lira in 1996. Its 1997 targets are three trillion lira of sales and 400 billion of profits.</p>
<p>Karaoglu said they aimed to raise their output to 3.5 million pieces this year from 3.2 million in 1996.</p>
<p>She added that company exports which make up 80 percent of the total sales, would be increased to $18.5 million in 1997, from $14.5 million last year.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-275 08 75 ATA EKS</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
