<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72049" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Turner sees another Goodwill Games loss.</title>
<headline>Turner sees another Goodwill Games loss.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ted Turner, chairman of the board of Turner Broadcasting, said the firm again might not break when it hosts the Goodwill Games in New York City and the Nassau County in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;We certainly hope so (to make money), but they've never made money directly,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>The Goodwill Games, which Turner started in 1986 to bring together athletes from the U.S. and former Soviet Union, who were barred from competing against each other in 1980 and 1984, have yet to break even.  </p>
<p>With the end of the Cold War, the 1998 games will have a new theme, aiding children by working with the Boys and Girls Clubs of America.</p>
<p>Officials from Turner and its new merger partner, Time Warner Inc, all pointed to promotional and other benefits they expected to gain by broadcasting the games, which are expected to draw athletes from 70 countries.</p>
<p>They added that they believed the $5 million purse that the athletes, including U.S. track star Michael Johnson, two-time 1996 Olympic gold medalist, will be competing for is the biggest one ever offered. Some premier athletes, like Johnson who is helping to promote the Goodwill Games, will have &quot;separate arrangements,&quot; company officials said.</p>
<p>The president of Turner Sports, Harvey Schiller, said that the company was in talks with broadcast companies and expected to reach a pact with one to air the games over the weekend.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
