<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720563" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: NATO warns Serb hardliners not to retaliate.</title>
<headline>NATO warns Serb hardliners not to retaliate.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO Secretary-Gernal Javier Solana warned hardline Bosnian Serbs on Thursday not to retaliate for the death of a former police chief killed by NATO forces as they tried to arrest him.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not tolerate any behaviour by any of the parties contrary to the Dayton peace agreement,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Simo Srljaca, the former police chief of Prijedor, was killed earlier on Thursday when he fired on soldiers trying to arrest him on war crimes charges.</p>
<p>Solana praised NATO forces involved in the operation for their &quot;professionalism and dedication&quot;.</p>
<p>The statement said NATO-led SFOR (stabilisation force) troops had returned fire &quot;in self defence&quot; after one of the indicted men fired at them after being challenged.</p>
<p>The statement underlined that the troops' actions were undertaken under the SFOR mandate which allows troops in Bosnia to detain indicted war criminals when encountered in the course of their duties.</p>
<p>In Sarajevo, NATO said a British soldier was slightly wounded in the clash with Drljaca.</p>
<p>&quot;Indicted war crimininal Simo Drljaca, former police chief in Prijedor, opened fire on SFOR soldiers as they approached for the purpose of detaining him,&quot; said the Sarajevo statement.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the SFOR soldiers was wounded in the process. Drjlaca was killed when fire was returned in self-defence,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The NATO-led SFOR detained another suspect, Milan Kovacevic, director of a hospital in the northwest town of Prijedor, without incident in a separate operation at about 0730 GMT.</p>
<p>NATO spokesman Major Chris Riley told reporters in Sarajevo that Kovacevic would be handed over to the International Criminal Tribunal for Former Yugoslavia and later extradited to The Hague to await trial.</p>
<p>Riley said NATO's mandate in Bosnia had not changed and that there were no orders to hunt down war crimes suspects.</p>
<p>He said that SFOR troops had encountered the two suspects during their regular duties as both men held official positions.</p>
<p>Drljaca became an adviser to the Bosnian Serb interior ministry after he was forced to step down as police chief in Prijedor.</p>
<p>The alliance has ruled out &quot;man hunts&quot; and said its troops in Bosnia will only arrest suspects encountered during peacekeeping duties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
