<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720700" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: EMI unveils revamped euro banknotes.</title>
<headline>EMI unveils revamped euro banknotes.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A revamped version of banknotes for Europe's planned single currency, unveiled on Thursday, reflects small changes in design that seek to avoid any obvious reference to existing European structures.</p>
<p>The European Monetary Institute, forerunner to a planned European Central Bank, said the changes were standard procedure before the new euro banknotes were fully suitable for origination and printing.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt-based EMI said the banknotes were amended to avoid &quot;any obvious references to existing structures&quot;. Many European leaders had not wanted the banknotes to carry any sort of national symbol.</p>
<p>Drawings of the structures -- which include symbolic bridges and gateways -- appear to simplified and not in such exact detail as the original banknotes unveiled last December at a European Union summit in Dublin.</p>
<p>The structures are supposed to represent Europe's cultural history through its artistic ages -- classical, romanesque, gothic, renaissance, baroque, rococo and the ages of iron and glass architecture and 20th century building styles.</p>
<p>Revamped designs did not show all the details and security features that will be incorporated into the new banknotes, set to go into circulation in early 2002, and will be different in several aspects from the final version.</p>
<p>There are seven designs in all, one for each of the denominations in the planned banknote series -- euro 5, 10, 20, 50, 100, 200 and 500.</p>
<p>The new notes range in colour from grey to purple and differ in size to help the partially sighted and blind.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
