<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720710" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Miffed Zurich Jews close UBS bank account.</title>
<headline>Miffed Zurich Jews close UBS bank account.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zurich's Jewish Community (ICZ) has closed its account at Union Bank of Switzerland (UBS) in protest at what it deemed insensitive comments from bank executives and the sacking of a night watchman who uncovered the shredding of old documents.</p>
<p>An ICZ spokeswoman confirmed press reports on Thursday that the city's Jewish community had withdrawn around three million Swiss francs ($2 million) from its UBS account and would now bank with rival Credit Suisse.</p>
<p>&quot;We regret it on the one hand, but on the other hand we have some understanding for this,&quot; a UBS spokesman added.</p>
<p>He described the incident as one of the isolated cases in which UBS has lost clients because of controversy over Swiss banks' handling of dormant accounts from Holocaust victims.</p>
<p>ICZ closed its account at UBS at the end of June.</p>
<p>In press accounts, ICZ President Werner Rom cited the case of sacked watchman Christoph Meili and comments by UBS chairman Robert Studer for the move.</p>
<p>Studer, who once dismissed the sums in dormant accounts as &quot;peanuts&quot;, also accused Meili on Swiss television of acting for ulterior motives when he sneaked old documents out of UBS's shredding room and handed them over to Zurich Jewish leaders. ($ = 1.461 Swiss Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
