<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720716" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Le Monde July 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Le Monde July 10.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in afternoon daily Le Monde.</p>
<p>FRONT PAGE</p>
<p>-- SNCF state railway to create some 2,000 jobs in 1997.</p>
<p>-- Transports Minister Claude Gayssot expected to confirm today he does not plan to alter a reform of the SNCF approved by parliament in February 1996, which created a structure taking over railroad infrastructure as well as some 134 billion francs debt from SNCF.</p>
<p>Gayssot obtained agreement for the state to reduce SNCF debt by some 20 billion francs, to 48 billion from 68 billion.</p>
<p>-- A June 2 confidential note from outgoing Prime Minister Alain Juppe to his successor Socialist Lionel Jospin states new government would have to take tough action to prevent the public deficit rising above four percent of gross domestic product in 1998.</p>
<p>BUSINESS PAGES</p>
<p>-- CGIP replaces Daimler-Benz as largest shareholder in computer services group Cap Gemini, brings stake to 30 percent from 20 pecent.</p>
<p>-- Usinor steel group to shut down steel wire mill train in eastern town of Longwy at the end of 1998.</p>
<p>-- Price of public transportation in Paris area to rise by 3.9 percent from August 1.</p>
<p>-- Subscriber-TV channel Canal Plus to launch news-only channel in the spring of 1998, chairman Pierre Lescure says in an interview. Says Canal will not necessarily keep its 51 percent stake in Telepiu.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
