<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720729" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish bonds track bunds easier, crown dips.</title>
<headline>Swedish bonds track bunds easier, crown dips.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish yields climbed quite sharply in line with weaker foreign markets at Thursday midday, but only slightly underperformed bunds amid a gentle crown weakening, with the spread widening one basis point to 89.</p>
<p>Dealers said bond weakness mainly stemmed from a failure by bund futures to rise through technical resistance.</p>
<p>A clear recoil they had expected in the crown after sharp gains versus the mark on Wednesday did not materialise, with trade thin, dealers said.  </p>
<p>Markets across Europe suffered mild renewed EMU wobbles after a French daily suggested the French deficit may come out higher than Germany would accept.</p>
<p>Trade was also subdued ahead of a widely expected Bank of England decision to hike key rates by at least 25 basis points.</p>
<p>The six-month T-bill rate dropped one basis point to 4.11 percent, with the 10-year bond yield up five basis points to 6.46 percent. The crown softened marginally to 4.3785 versus 4.3770 crowns on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
