<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720952" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia's Robe River iron ore output tops target.</title>
<headline>Australia's Robe River iron ore output tops target.</headline>
<dateline>WICKHAM, Australia 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iron ore production is running ahead of target at Australia's Robe River Mining Co Pty Ltd due to strong demand from Japanese steelmakers, a Robe River official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are producing at a rate of 15.3 million tonnes over the first six months,&quot; said Eric Girdler, Robe River manager of railroad operations.</p>
<p>Robe River produced about 27 million tonnes in the Japanese fiscal year ended March 31 and budgeted output of only 26 million tonnes in the current year, Girdler told Reuters.</p>
<p>North Ltd owns 53 percent of and operates the mine.  </p>
<p>A minimal 1.4 percent price increase won from Japanese steel mills for the current year has resulted in a high number of Japanese orders for iron ore, Girdler said.</p>
<p>Demand over the rest of the Japanese iron ore year will determine whether Robe River maintains its current production rate, he said.</p>
<p>Robe River ore sells at a discount to to other iron ore produced in Western Australia due to its low iron grade and high moisture content but the company is assessing the possibility of developing the nearby West Angelas deposit which has a higher grade ore.  </p>
<p>The West Angelas would open up more market opportunities to sell iron ore to Chinese steel mills, said Robert Cleary, general manager of special projects for North.</p>
<p>&quot;West Angelas would give us a foot in the door,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cleary said he expects a reply from the West Australian government next week over the first stage of the environmental approval process to develop the deposit and possibly build a 330 km rail line linking the mine with the west coast.</p>
<p>Cleary said he hopes to make a recommendation to the North board in March 1998 and to the other Robe partners in May 1998 for approval for the project to go ahead.  </p>
<p>Pre production capital costs for the West Angelas were estimated by Cleary at A$1 billion.</p>
<p>Initial production would be about 10 to 12 million tonnes a year, eventually rising to 20 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Cleary said he has received &quot;sound encouragement&quot; from Robe's Japanese partners over development of West Angelas.</p>
<p>Japan's Mitsui &amp; Co Ltd group holds a 33 percent interest in Robe while a Nippon Steel Corp  5041.T unit has 10.5 percent and a Sumitomo Corp group unit holds 3.5 percent.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61 -2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WICKHAM, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
