<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="720994" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - July 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - July 10.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Chinese political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Beijing. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (8610) 6532-1921. Fax: (8610) 6532-4978.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PEOPLE'S DAILY</p>
<p>- China registers steady industrial growth during the first half with industrial sectors above township-level generating 984.9 billion yuan, up 11.6 percent year-on-year when adjusted for inflation.</p>
<p>- President Jiang Zemin tells former Japanese Prime Minister Tsutomu Hata that Japan can only pursue peaceful development if it can correctly recall its role in history.</p>
<p>- Shenzhen tax bureau withdraws a Sino-Japanese joint venture's right to use 2.0 million square metres of land after it tried to evade 120 million yuan of tax.</p>
<p>- Summer grain output in Xinjiang reaches 4.47 million tonnes, 100,000 tonnes more than last year.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>XINHUA DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>- Premier Li Peng says Sino-Japanese relations will develop in a healthy and stable manner if the joint communique and peace treaty signed by the two counties are strictly observed.</p>
<p>- Premier Li Peng tells Supreme Head of State of Malaysia Tunku Ja'afar their frequent exchanges of visits have given a constant impetus to relations.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FINANCIAL NEWS</p>
<p>- People's Insurance Company of China pays 30 million yuan compensation to Beijing Dongfang Chemical Plant for fire damage.</p>
<p>- Vice-Governor of the Central Bank Chen Yuan says China's banking sector needs to improve its payments system.</p>
<p>- The State Administration of Foreign Exchange issues foreign exchange license to the North China Power Group Finance Co Ltd.</p>
<p>- Exports of silk products in the first quarter earn $538 million, up 17.55 percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA SECURITIES</p>
<p>- The Shanghai and Shenzhen stock exchanges ask listed firms to strictly follow official rules when issuing interim reports.</p>
<p>- China sets up a Qingdao Brewery Group with registered capital from state-owned shares in the Tsingtao Brewery Co Ltd.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS DAILY</p>
<p>- Ministry of Foreign Trade and Economic Cooperation says China to give more foreign donated funds to central and western regions.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ECONOMIC DAILY</p>
<p>- Editorial calls for mergers of small and inefficient cigarette makers.</p>
<p>- Unsold residential space in China reaches 66.24 million square metres by end of 1996, up nearly 30 percent from the previous year.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA BUSINESS DAILY</p>
<p>- Retail sales in Beijing hit 50.08 billion yuan in first half, up by inflation-adjusted 7.5 percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA DAILY</p>
<p>- A symposium on establishing a legal system for the socialist market economy says China's economy needs more laws, but they must be consistent and more practicable.</p>
<p>- China will stand by its decision to open the commercial sector to foreign investors, despite the competition they are expected to give to struggling state-owned businesses.</p>
<p>- Production of onshore oil and gas has risen steadily this year with intensified exploitation of China's western oil and gas fields.</p>
<p>- Ministry of Coal Industry says upgraded technology and market competition are expected to help the money-losing coal industry show a profit by the end of this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
