<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721014" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan defends seizure of S.Korea fishing boat.</title>
<headline>Japan defends seizure of S.Korea fishing boat.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto on Thursday defended Tokyo's move this week to seize a South Korean fishing boat in disputed waters.</p>
<p>&quot;If foreign fishing boats refuse to leave Japan's territorial waters despite warnings, it is natural that we should seize them,&quot; Hashimoto told reporters.</p>
<p>South Korea on Wednesday summoned Japan's ambassador to protest the seizure of a fishing boat by Japanese patrol vessels in disputed waters and demanded steps to ensure the incident would not be repeated.</p>
<p>The South Korean trawler, Taeyang No. 102, was operating in waters recently claimed by Japan, Seoul officials said. Japan last month held four South Korean fishing boats for similar reasons.</p>
<p>&quot;(South Korean) President Kim Young-sam and I had agreed to revise the bilateral fisheries agreement at an early date,&quot; Hashimoto said.</p>
<p>&quot;We share the view that the fisheries pact must be discussed at an early date separately from the territorial issue,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Japan in January expanded its territorial waters in accordance with a new maritime convention introduced by the United Nations in November 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;It was done in accordance with international rules,&quot; Hashimoto said.</p>
<p>Tokyo has told Seoul it would soon release the trawler and all 13 crew except the captain after an investigation.</p>
<p>Japan and South Korea have a troubled relationship stemming from Japan's 1910-45 colonial rule over the Korean peninsula. Frequent territorial disputes are fanned by ultra-nationalists on both sides.</p>
<p>Both countries claim sovereignty over barren outcrops of rock in the Sea of Japan midway between Japan and South Korea. The islands are called Takeshima in Japan and Tokdo in South Korea.</p>
<p>Japan has claimed the islands since 1905 when it signed an agreement with Korea that paved the way for colonisation. Seoul has stationed security police on the islands since 1954.</p>
<p>South Korea keeps a handful of permanent residents on the islands. Local historians say well-documented Korean claims to the islets date back to the year 512.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
