<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721045" id="root" date="1997-07-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: ASEAN recognises Ranariddh as Cambodian co-premier.</title>
<headline>ASEAN recognises Ranariddh as Cambodian co-premier.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) said on Thursday it still recognises Prince Norodom Ranariddh as co-premier of Cambodia despite his ouster at the weekend by rival Second Prime Minister Hun Sen.</p>
<p>&quot;ASEAN will continue to regard Ranariddh as co-premier of Cambodia,&quot; foreign ministers from the seven-member grouping said after a crisis meeting on Cambodia.  </p>
<p>The statement also confirmed earlier reports that Cambodia's admission into ASEAN -- which currently groups Indonesia, Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam -- would be delayed.</p>
<p>But Burma and Laos would be admitted as previously scheduled at ASEAN's annual meeting on July 21-29, the statement said.</p>
<p>It said that Indonesian Foreign Minister Ali Alatas and Philippines Foreign Minister Domingo Siazon would be sent to Beijing for talks with Cambodia's head of state, King Norodom Sihanouk, on ways to resolve the crisis.</p>
<p>At least 58 people were killed and up to 200 wounded in clashes in Phnom Penh between forces loyal to Hun Sen and those loyal to Ranardiddh last weekend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
