<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721458" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FTC concern on tobacco price-fixing seen unfounded.</title>
<headline>FTC concern on tobacco price-fixing seen unfounded.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal Trade Commission Chairman Robert Pitofsky's suggestion that the proposed tobacco settlement may allow cigarette companies to fix prices came as a surprise to Wall Street analysts, who said Friday that they saw no basis for such concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see how that's the case,&quot; Oppenheimer &amp; Co analyst Roy Burry said. &quot;Nothing I saw in the agreement said anything about prices.&quot;  </p>
<p>Pitofsky earlier Friday told a group of reporters in Washington that he believes the proposed settlement between the industry and the states attorneys general was written in such a way that it could permit cigarette companies to come together to determine how much an agreement was costing them.</p>
<p>He said the proposed settlement's antitrust exemption may then allow the companies to fix the amount they would add to the price of a pack of cigarettes, passing the cost of the pact along to consumers.  </p>
<p>&quot;The exemption is written in such a way that I believe -- maybe they didn't intend it this way -- it could cover price-fixing,&quot; Pitofsky said.</p>
<p>PaineWebber analyst Emanuel Goldman said he could not see any basis for that conclusion.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't see any price-fixing powers&quot; in the agreement, he said. &quot;It says absolutely nothing that I can find about how the prices will be determined.&quot;</p>
<p>Burry said Pitofsky may be simply floating an eye-catching theory in order to influence the debate in Congress, which would have to approve the pact.</p>
<p>Goldman said this was the first he had heard of the price-fixing issue.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what his agenda is,&quot; Goldman said, referring to Pitofsky.</p>
<p>The FTC chairman also said he thought the tobacco pact contained many good points, and that the FTC and other government agencies would have the opportunity to testify when the proposed settlement is reviewed by Congress.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
