<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721534" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed stands by U.S. TIPS as a policy tool - S.F. Fed.</title>
<headline>Fed stands by U.S. TIPS as a policy tool - S.F. Fed.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street has not been enthusiastic about the Treasury's inflation-linked securities, but the Federal Reserve sees the issues as a gauge of future inflation expectations and a valuable monetary policy tool.</p>
<p>&quot;An important role the bond markets... play (in monetary policy) is to sort of provide information,&quot; Glenn Rudebusch, a research officer at the San Francisco Fed, told Reuters.  </p>
<p>He said the Treasury's new Inflation Protected Securities, better known as TIPS, provide a more evident distinction between nominal and real interest rates, which in turn helps the Fed &quot;understand or gauge expectations of inflation.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the new financial instruments have helped to provide more information on the economy to the Fed.</p>
<p>&quot;Information about expectations is important, and using the real and nominal debt to get a better handle on those expectations is also important,&quot; Rudebusch said.  </p>
<p>The Treasury's first TIPS auction took place on January 29 with the sale of $7.0 billion in 10-year inflation-linked securities. The government re-opened the issue in April with the placement of $8.0 billion.</p>
<p>On July 9, the Treasury sold $8.0 billion in its first five-year TIPS sale. The government now has plans to launch a 30-year issue next year.</p>
<p>In an environment of falling inflation, the TIPS haven't been very popular among investors, and most auctions have been met with lukewarm reception from Wall Street.  </p>
<p>The return on the TIPS is calculated by combining the seasonally unadjusted Consumer Price Index (CPI) plus a money market premium.</p>
<p>Rudebusch said another aspect of interest rates that has become particularly important for the operation of the Fed's monetary policy is the term structure relationship of short- and long-term rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Long-term interest rates are formed on the expectation of future short-term interest rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;So to the extent that you can discern those expectations ... that helps you understand where markets view the future path of monetary policy and the economy,&quot; the San Fransciso Fed economist added.</p>
<p>Interest rates have been playing a larger role in monetary policy as informational indicators, mainly after the notion of tying policy and money aggregates weakened a decade ago.</p>
<p>&quot;In the postwar period, the ultimate objectives of the Federal Reserve -- namely full employment and stable prices -- have remained unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the Fed has modified its operational and intermediate objectives for monetary policy several times in response to changes in the economic environment,&quot; the San Francisco Fed economist said.</p>
<p>(( -- 212-859-1676 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
