<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721609" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-FERNANDEZ TO PLAY SUGIYAMA IN OPENING FED CUP SINGLES.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-FERNANDEZ TO PLAY SUGIYAMA IN OPENING FED CUP SINGLES.</headline>
<dateline>BROOKLINE, Massachusetts 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mary Joe Fernandez meets Ai Sugiyama in a rematch of a spirited Wimbledon encounter a year ago to launch the U.S.-Japan Fed Cup qualifying playoff Saturday at Longwood Cricket Club.</p>
<p>&quot;I won it but it was a real tough match,&quot; said the 13th-ranked Fernandez, recalling her difficult three-set match with Sugiyama in the fourth round of the 1996 Wimbledon championships.</p>
<p>In the second singles match Saturday, Olympic champion Lindsay Davenport, ranked eighth in the world and an impressive 12-2 in Fed Cup singles, will face Naoko Sawamatsu.</p>
<p>The singles competition resumes Sunday with Davenport against Sugiyama, and Fernandez facing Sawamatsu.</p>
<p>A doubles match will follow, with Davenport and Lisa Raymond opposing Naoko Kijimuta and Nana Miyagi.</p>
<p>The winner of the tie will join the eight-team competition to determine next year's team championship title.</p>
<p>The United States, winners of 15 Fed Cup titles since the start of the competition in 1963, lost to the Netherlands in the first round this year.</p>
<p>Last year, the U.S. team beat Japan 5-0, but captain Martina Navratilova says the Americans are taking the challenge seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a different team and they have a different team, so it's a whole new ballgame,&quot; she said. &quot;But that doesn't mean we're not confident.&quot;</p>
<p>Japanese captain Takeshi Koura is not just looking for a good showing. &quot;We plan to win,&quot; said Koura. &quot;Our experience in the big tournaments like Wimbledon has made our team more confident this year.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We know the Americans are very good, but we have two strong singles players who are very well prepared.&quot;</p>
<p>Sugiyama is ranked 25th in the world, and Sawamatsu 45th.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BROOKLINE, Massachusetts"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
