<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72178" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ford denies report that logo use changes planned.</title>
<headline>Ford denies report that logo use changes planned.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ford Motor Co public relations workers were busy Tuesday shooting down a published report that the U.S. No. 2 automaker is exploring de-emphasizing its familiar blue logo in its corporate advertising.</p>
<p>Ford spokesman Jim Bright said there are no plans to back away from the oval, which dates back to the early days of the 93-year-old automaker.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the oval is one of the strongest assets we have,&quot; said Bright, adding that consumer research consistently shows it has high recognition.</p>
<p>A story in the Detroit News Tuesday said a team of sales and marketing executives have spent the past several months trying to decide if the oval is still appropriate for representing the whole corporation.</p>
<p>Bright said the story may have confused corporate image issues with an ongoing study at the Ford division.  That study is looking into how the division's brand identity differs from that of the corporation. He said the study may result in some more image advertising, but no visual changes to the Ford division logo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
