<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721795" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: No sign of BOE intervention on stg yet - traders.</title>
<headline>No sign of BOE intervention on stg yet - traders.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sterling's surge above three marks for the first time in more than six years encountered no resistance from the Bank of England on Friday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The dealers here have been trawling for signs of the central banks all day but there has been no sign whatsoever,&quot; said one analyst at a major UK bank here.</p>
<p>An official at the Bank of England declined to comment on the issue.</p>
<p>Sterling climbed to 3.0010 marks, the strongest it has been since October 1990. It was at 2.9965/75 at 1500 GMT from 2.9566/76 late Thursday in Europe.</p>
<p>Cable climbed as high as $1.6986, its best showing since January 10. It was last at $1.6945/50 from $1.6882/92 Thursday. The pound's trade-weighted index rose to 104.9, the highest it has been since October 1990.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Bank of England will be wary of taking on sterling bulls too aggressively until there is a fundamental reason for the pound to reverse its gains.</p>
<p>&quot;A set piece battle to defend any particular level is futile given the market's current mood,&quot; said Mark Cliffe, chief international economist at HSBC Markets. &quot;You need weak data or a material change in policy before it becomes worthwhile.&quot;</p>
<p>Until then any sales of pounds by the Bank of England will be aimed at smoothing sterling volatility, he said. -- Swaha Pattanaik, London newsroom +44 171 542 6284</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
