<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721789" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK government water plan meets rush of replies.</title>
<headline>UK government water plan meets rush of replies.</headline>
<byline>Jo Winterbottom</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>British water and sewerage companies, already doused with a 1.65 billion pounds ($2.8 billion) share of a new tax on excess profits, have rushed to respond to the centre-left Labour government's plans to improve the heavily criticised industry.</p>
<p>Deputy prime minister John Prescott, who put forward the 10 point plan at a water summit on May 19 and gave companies until mid-June to reply, will announce the outcome of responses on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The response has been pretty much as we wanted,&quot; a spokesman for the Department of the Environment said, adding that the preference was for voluntary moves from companies rather than changes in regulation.</p>
<p>Results have already poured in.</p>
<p>Four companies -- Anglian, Northumbrian, Severn Trent and Thames -- have changed their tune and agreed to licence alterations covering compensation during droughts which they had previously rejected from industry regulator Ofwat.</p>
<p>They join North West Water, South West, Welsh and Wessex which had agreed licence alterations before the summit.</p>
<p>Yorkshire has said it will review the situation while Southern, alone of the ten, said it could not comment and did not issue a statement on its response to any of the issues raised.</p>
<p>Prescott might single out individual companies for comments good or bad on Tuesday, but is also expected to give an overall analysis of responses.</p>
<p>Since the summit, companies have also rushed to introduce free repairs for leaks from customers' pipes after the government said it expected this as part of its plan.</p>
<p>And charitable funds to help customers who cannot pay bills have sprung up, with many companies saying disconnections should be used only as a last resort or for those who will not pay even though they have the means.</p>
<p>The government's plan also called for mandatory targets for cutting leaks which Ofwat head Ian Byatt has said he will set annually.</p>
<p>Britain, traditionally seen as wet and windy, has just endured its driest period for two hundred years while the amount of water leaking out of company pipes has topped 800 million gallons a day and many customers have had curbs imposed on water use.</p>
<p>The Labour party, which swept to power in a landslide victory on May 1, has been fiercely critical of the water and sewerage companies, privatised by a previous Conservative administration, as they made hefty shareholder payouts and paid large executive salaries.</p>
<p>Its five billion pound &quot;windfall&quot; tax on excess profits of privatised utilities, announced in its first budget on July 2, was a central plank of the manifesto which brought it to power after eighteen years of Conservative rule.</p>
<p>Companies have also submitted drought contingency plans to the Environment Agency, another proposal from the 10 point plan, with all of these either agreed or in the process of being settled, the agency said on Friday.</p>
<p>Companies also showed willing to contribute to two reviews, one on pricing and one on using water from rivers, which the government proposed.</p>
<p>The pricing review will look at metering, which gained mixed responses although most companies force households with sprinklers, swimming pools or other thirsty appliances, to pay by this method.</p>
<p>The government has indicated that it is not in favour of compulsory metering, an avenue supported by Anglian, which operates in the very dry east of England and has a high percentage of metered customers.</p>
<p>More general points in the plan met with more general responses from companies, such as the need for water conservation and promoting efficient use of supplies.</p>
<p>Prescott's Hippo, the blue bag used to cut down water for flushing toilets, received wide recognition by companies along with a host of other conservation measures and many added free water efficiency audits for households, another request of the plan.</p>
<p>And companies were quick to detail the amount of information they published, whether in annual reports or through the media, on performance and quality targets.</p>
<p>Prescott had called for companies to publish performance details and information on investment along with resulting benefits to the environment.</p>
<p>The review into abstraction, the process by which companies use river water to top up supplies, will focus on the impact for the environment.</p>
<p>Finally, Prescott's suggestion that an Environmental Task Force could be set up, as part of its plans to cut youth unemployment using revenues from the five billion pound windfall tax, received a warm welcome from the water companies.</p>
<p>&quot;It could make a very positive contribution in improving the efficient use of water,&quot; said one company in its response.</p>
<p>($ = 0.592 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
