<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72172" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed inaction clears way for new Wall St milestones.</title>
<headline>Fed inaction clears way for new Wall St milestones.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Reserve's move to hold U.S. monetary policy steady cleared the way for stocks to set new milestones, calming, for now, jitters that a rate hike would crimp wobbly corporate profit growth.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going up,&quot; said David Shulman, chief equity strategist at Salomon Brothers. &quot;I can see a 6200 target before the election.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dow industrials shed 40 to 5853 late Tuesday after surging briefly on news that the Fed, as expected by a some on Wall Street, decided to leave rates unchanged.  </p>
<p>The long bond was up 12/32 to yield 6.99 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, analysts, economists and traders are trying to distill all the news and ramifications of the Fed's inaction. We had a knee-jerk rally and are consolidating to inflationary implications. It's a positive. The volatility is helping to keep excesses minimized,&quot; said Eugene Peroni, chief technical analyst with Janney, Montgomery Scott.</p>
<p>He said the market's technicals &quot;are still quite positive. I wouldn't be surprised to see a correction but the market has significant latitude for a two to three percent correction without disturbing its upward momentum.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Dow on Monday roared back from a 53-point deficit to end at a record closing high of 5894.74. The S&amp;P 500 last Friday set a record close of 687.02 and was off one to 685 late Tuesday. The tech-studded Nasdaq Composite rose two to 1214 late Tuesday, not too far from June 5's record finish of 1249.15.</p>
<p>Stocks have been buoyed over the past week by renewed interest in the high-technology sector, which helped Wall Street snap record after record in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Tech stocks have been acting strongly, especially semiconductors,&quot; Peroni said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It helps to create an inspiring tone when economically sensitive stocks are doing this well. It opens a favorable outlook for earnings and the Fed's postponement of an increase should help to bolster the earnings outlook potential.&quot;</p>
<p>Joseph Battipaglia, chief investment strategist at Gruntal &amp; Co, said, &quot;It's clear sailing from now to the middle of October before we start looking at third-quarter earnings. I think we'll get some good news on techs and the cyclicals will have a decent performance. Though we didn't have a rally to 6000 on the (Fed) news, once we start seeing earnings we should have a sustainable rally through the elections.&quot;  </p>
<p>When asked if Wall Street was merely seeing the Fed's inaction Tuesday as a delay of an inevitable tightening after the elections, he said, &quot;It's the boy who cried wolf. The Fed can tighten at any point in the cycle and is keying off core CPI, gold, the dollar, and the overall level of confidence in the economy. There's nothing to react to in a negative sense.&quot;</p>
<p>Salomon's Shulman said the falling dollar after the Fed's inaction pressured stocks and bonds. But he noted a weaker dollar would ultimately aid overseas profits for multinationals, boosting the bottom line for major U.S. corporations.  </p>
<p>He noted AT&amp;T Corp was the latest company to warn of an earnings shortfall. AT&amp;T was the most-active NYSE issue and slid 5-3/4 to 51-1/2, accounting for the bulk of the Dow's 21-point loss at the close.</p>
<p>&quot;We had some accidents and we'll probably have more preannouncements,&quot; Shulman said. &quot;The big issue is people are expecting a big acceleration in fourth-quarter earnings. The earnings bulls have conceded the third quarter (S&amp;P operating earnings are seen up a mere 6.1 percent). But I'm an earnings bear and I see the third quarter as weak, but I don't see the acceleration for the fourth quarter -- I see a profit squeeze.&quot;  </p>
<p>Shulman said the near-term outlook for stocks also hinges on the outcome of congressional elections, on whether Democrats reassert control over Congress, and on economic data that will sway monetary policy.</p>
<p>But, he noted, &quot;The path of least resistance is up.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk 212 859 1721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
