<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721741" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: European VGO stronger on European demand.</title>
<headline>European VGO stronger on European demand.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>European vaccum gas oil prices rose by the end of the week on stronger European demand with little supply seen, but the trans-Atlantic arb was virtually shut, traders said.</p>
<p>They said that low sulphur VGO cargoes were assessed in the $127/$129 region after a trade in the past two days at $129.90 fob for a 20-25,000 tonne cargo loading July 18-23 sold by a major to a Spanish refiner.</p>
<p>A cargo traded earlier this week at $124 fob and trders said three other European buyers were heard on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;On the VGO front, there is still European demand. We have seen a couple of deals this week. There's buying interest still from three players,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is fairly tight now, there's not too much avails around&quot;.</p>
<p>But traders said that the arbitrage to the United States was not workable at the moment.</p>
<p>&quot;The arb to the States is shut...The only way to make it work is if you discounted the backwardation...but I very much doubt it can be done,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>High sulphur VGO cargoes were largely quiet during the weak except for a small parcel sold at around $130 cif. --Haitham Haddadin, London newsroom, +44 171 542 8145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
