<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721833" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: ELAN CEO says firm to stay the course.</title>
<headline>ELAN CEO says firm to stay the course.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>ELAN Energy Inc Chief Executive Verne Johnson, whose company's stock was savaged by investors on Friday following a negative analyst's report on its prospects, said the firm planned to stick to its current strategy developing its vast reserves of heavy oil.</p>
<p>&quot;We think there's considerable value in our strategy and in our assets and we have the program in hand to create that value going forward and that hasn't changed,&quot; Johnson said in aa telephone interview.</p>
<p>The report, released late on Thursday by First Energy Capital Corp analyst Martin Molyneaux, recommended investors sell the stock based on a deepening price discount for Canadian heavy oil, flagging production volumes, high operating costs and second-quarter cash flow well below last year's figure.</p>
<p>He revised his 12-month target price to 6.60.</p>
<p>The assessment sent ELAN stock into a tailspin, dropping 1.25 to a new year low of 8.00 on turnover of over 3.3 million shares on Friday.</p>
<p>Johnson, who would not comment directly on the report's specifics, said the data expected to result in the poor second-quarter showing was made public last month at the Canadian Association of Petroleum Producers investment symposium.</p>
<p>&quot;I said at CAPP the second quarter was going to be a flat quarter on production and because price was down, the second quarter versus the first quarter, cash flow would be lower than expected,&quot; he said. &quot;Today, it got figured out, I guess.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite the lower-than-expected production levels, Johnson said ELAN had no plans to make an acquisition to beef up 1997 numbers.</p>
<p>&quot;We have, first of all, such a significant amount of potential in drilling to add production that we don't feel we have to do anything like that,&quot; But...we are always on the lookout for opportunities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He acknowledged last month that, with the poor second-quarter performance, ELAN was vulnerable as a takeover target, a key reason for the implementation of a poison pill at the time. ((Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
