<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721955" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Once bullish zloty may eye downside next week.</title>
<headline>Once bullish zloty may eye downside next week.</headline>
<byline>Wojciech Moskwa</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The zloty's enduring bullish sentiment has eroded over the last months and dealers said that the Polish unit -- at an all-time low on Friday -- may head lower next week unless propped up by the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;It is safer to hold long currency positions until this trend is reversed...as big floatations ended and foreigners are not likely to again buy Poland paper until after parliamentary polls in September,&quot; said Wojciech Trzepizur, dealer at BRE SA.</p>
<p>Dealers said inflows from the floatation of copper concern KGHM Polska Miedz SA already went through the market this week, which only briefly strengthened the zloty on Monday.</p>
<p>But some said the zloty, which ended the week at its lowest level ever against the currency basket, could be buoyed later in July when Bank Handlowy's longer-term investors, which hold 24-percent equity in the privatised bank, pay for their shares.</p>
<p>On Friday the zloty closed at 0.20 percent above the trading band centre, against last week's close at 0.76 percent and some 1.5 percent above parity a month ago.</p>
<p>It closed at 3.3245 to the dollar and 1.8885 to the mark.</p>
<p>Even the Thursday statement of Finance Minister Marek Belka that Poland was considering reducing the zloty's one percent per month crawling peg devaluation failed to stop the zloty's gradual decline against the basket.</p>
<p>Analysts said that the central bank, which controls the exchange rate policy, was not expected to agree to cut the devaluation rate because it could add to Poland's current account problems.</p>
<p>Dealers said next week more losses could be in store for the zloty as foreigners closed Polish treasuries positions, and that parity could be a key support level.</p>
<p>&quot;The critical level is parity, if the zloty slips below it the central bank may start selling currencies,&quot; said Rafal Kaminski, dealer at Pekao SA.</p>
<p>Dealers said however that if the zloty's fall was caused by large-scale foreign withdrawal the central bank may refrain from intervening during a withdrawal wave and only later pull the zloty back up above parity, in order to lower its costs.</p>
<p>Most said the zloty would probably drift between 0.5 to parity next week, but some expected the zloty to gain slightly if the central bank intervened and return into a band between 0.5 and one percent above parity.</p>
<p>The zloty, which has been driven upward by foreign investment and cross border trade inflows for several years, first showed a dent in its armour in late May when it tumbled two percent after the Czech crown's steep decline.</p>
<p>Since that time foreign portfolio investors have been monitoring Poland's external deficit even more closely, with some pulling out of zloty instruments altogether.</p>
<p>Some said that foreign investors may have been quicker to withdraw from Polish treasuries on Friday in order to close positions ahead of any potential economic problems caused by large-scale flooding in the south of Poland.</p>
<p>However, the government has ruled out changing the 1997 budget to allow more expenditures for the flood relief effort.</p>
<p>At next Monday's one billion zloty T-bill tender foreigners were again expected to again stay on the sidelines despite expectations of increasing yields, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally, all yields will rise and the longest should rise sharply,&quot; said Robert Gluch, dealer at ING Bank in Warsaw.</p>
<p>The benchmark 52-week T-bill yield was seen rising to 22.1 percent from this week's 21.86 after NBP-bill yields increased to by about 0.3 point to 22.50 percent this week.</p>
<p>The 26-week and 13-week T-bill yield should rise by about 0.1 to 0.15 point from the previous 21.71 and 21.13 percent.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
