<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="721978" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Mir crew sets up new links to Earth before repairs.</title>
<headline>Mir crew sets up new links to Earth before repairs.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The crew aboard crippled space station Mir spent most of Friday installing new communications equipment giving it better links to Earth before they undertake vital repairs next week, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;They spent most of the day installing the two Antares transmitters and receivers,&quot; NASA spokeswoman Kathleen Maliga said from Russian Mission Control outside Moscow. &quot;It expands the capability so you can have better voice transmission, telemetry (data transmission) and television.&quot;</p>
<p>The better links to Earth will aid the crew as they make final preparations with Mission Control to repair the Spektr module's energy-generating solar panels, damaged on June 25 after another Russian supply ship hit the ageing space station.</p>
<p>Mir, an 11-year-old orbital complex made up of different modules, lost up to half its electric power in the collision. Failure to beef up power supplies will threaten the future of the station.</p>
<p>The crew of two Russian cosmonauts and a British-American astronaut also spent part of Friday moving around equipment they unloaded earlier this week from the Progress, a cargo ship sent with repair equipment and other supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;They brought aboard all this equipment and they have to put it somewhere, so they are moving around some things and throwing away others,&quot; said a Russian Mission Control official.</p>
<p>When they have put their orbiting house in order, the cosmonauts will then make final preparations for repairs inside the Spektr module, which is now sealed off from the rest of the space station as it suffered a puncture in the accident.</p>
<p>During the operations, expected to take place in the early hours of July 18, one cosmonaut -- with a fellow cosmonaut nearby to give a hand -- will attempt to link 17 internal cables to three of the four solar panels attached like wings to Spektr.</p>
<p>It is expected to be a difficult task as the cosmonauts must work with their bulky spacesuits and gloves inside the cramped craft, a rarity in space travel, space officials say.</p>
<p>The crew plans to don their suits and practice the repairs elsewhere inside Mir next Tuesday, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's like preparations in the theatre,&quot; the Russian official said. &quot;They will have practices and just before the premiere, the cast will give a dress rehersal.&quot;</p>
<p>If the crew decides next week it needs more time to prepare, Mission Control has penciled in a back-up repair day of July 23, Maliga said.</p>
<p>On Saturday the crew plans to devote itself to repair planning and then to try and rest mostly, she added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
