<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722053" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AZERBAIJAN: Azerbaijan fears epidemics after floods.</title>
<headline>Azerbaijan fears epidemics after floods.</headline>
<byline>Nino Ivanishvili</byline>
<dateline>YEVLAX, Azerbaijan 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Floods have sent raw sewage flowing through dozens of towns and villages in central Azerbaijan, prompting fears of epidemics.</p>
<p>Waist-deep water covered most main streets of this town of 75,000 people on Friday, five days after rains subsided.</p>
<p>Raw human sewage was floating along the surface in many places. Residents used homemade rafts and boats to collect fresh drinking water provided by the local government.</p>
<p>&quot;We fear the sewage could contaminate drinking water. We badly need disinfection materials and drugs,&quot; said Kamil Muratov, the deputy administrative chief of Yevlax, 300 km (190 miles) west of the former Soviet republic's capital, Baku.</p>
<p>Azerbaijan has appealed for help from the United Nations to tackle the floods, which have killed 11 people, destroyed or damaged more than 7,000 homes, wrecked roads and bridges and wiped out several thousand hectares of wheat and cotton crops.</p>
<p>Officials said they were caught off guard by the freak rains which swept across usually arid desert and steppe regions.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first time we have faced a problem like this,&quot; said Muratov.</p>
<p>Many rural homes in the mostly Moslem country do not have indoor toilets, increasing the problems with sewage flows. The risk of epidemics is heightened by temperatures of up to 40 degrees Celsius (105 Fahrenheit).</p>
<p>Emergency workers and local residents frantically dug canals and tried to pump the standing water out of the town.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working non-stop,&quot; said Mamed, a fireman from the neighbouring town of Ter-ter.</p>
<p>The government has sent in 25 fire engines with special pumping equipment from places including Baku.</p>
<p>Most people in central Azerbaijan are poor and the area is a haven for some of the hundreds of thousands of destitute refugees who have fled the country's nearly decade-long conflict with Armenia over the disputed region of Nagorno-Karabakh.</p>
<p>Shovshet Mamedova, 67, looked in tears at what was left of her one-room first floor flat. The plywood floor and parts of the walls had been washed away.</p>
<p>&quot;I get a pension of 20,000 manants ($5) a month and I don't even have enough to eat,&quot; she said. &quot;Now on top of that I don't have a place to live.&quot;</p>
<p>The country's largest hydroelectric station at Mingechaur has shut down after being damaged by the rains, causing some power cuts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AZERB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YEVLAX, Azerbaijan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AZERBAIJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
