<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72207" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends weaker, trade buying holds.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends weaker, trade buying holds.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar closed an active session barely above the day's lows, where steady trade buying managed to hold the market, floor sources said.</p>
<p>Fund selling in May emerged once the contract broke an uptrend line at 11.15, triggering selling in other months, one dealer said. Trade short-covering and producer buying held the March contract at an uptrend line.</p>
<p>While last week's flurry of liquidation reduced open interest in October, the speculative long position remains high. Open interest stood at 24,128, off 1,919 in October, while open interest in the March contract stood at 67,745, up 215 lots.</p>
<p>March settled off 0.23 to 11.04, having ranged from 11.30 to 11.02. Spot October closed 0.13 weaker at 11.17, while the back months eased 0.23 to 0.14 on the day. Traders pegged support in March at 11.02 and cited stops below 11.00.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at a heavy 40,469 lots compared with Monday's official volume of 17,578 lots.</p>
<p>Market sources said a close near the day's lows points to weaker near-term prices. &quot;People are a little nervous because sugar appears awfully cheap compared to month ago,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is just no interest among the big end users.&quot;</p>
<p>--Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities Desk 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
