<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722124" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Cardoso seeks to build on Brazil reform victory.</title>
<headline>Cardoso seeks to build on Brazil reform victory.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian President Fernando Henrique Cardoso, seeking to build on a crucial reform victory in Congress earlier this week, urged lawmakers Friday to back the government in another important, upcoming vote in Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;I appeal to the lawmakers of Sergipe: don't abandon me, don't abandon the Brazilian people,&quot; the president was quoted by local newswire Invest News as saying during a visit to northeastern Sergipe state.  </p>
<p>&quot;Vote with us, vote with strength because we are going to do what Brazil needs to be done,&quot; Cardoso said.</p>
<p>The Brazilian government won a long-awaited vote in Congress Wednesday when the lower house defeated an opposition amendment which would have made a mockery of a civil service reform bill.</p>
<p>The amendment sought to prevent federal, state and municipal governments from firing workers found to be incompetent. The government killed the bill with just two votes to spare.  </p>
<p>But the Cardoso administration faces an even tougher battle to keep the civil service reform bill intact when the legislation is put to a second round of voting in the Chamber of Deputies, probably in August.</p>
<p>Although the government is considered likely to win the full vote on the bill itself, political observers say it could well fail to defeat another important opposition amendment.  </p>
<p>The amendment would strike down an article of the reform bill that would allow federal and local governments to fire large numbers of staff, including those with lifetime job guarantees, to bring spending on payrolls to under 60 percent of their receipts.</p>
<p>Officials say that article represents the thrust of the government's attempts to rein in spending on pay and pensions, which in some states accounts for 100 percent of receipts.  </p>
<p>But the amendment has the backing of powerful public sector lobbies who want to maintain lifetime job security for civil servants. Many lawmakers enjoy the support of civil service trade unions and others do not relish the idea of voting in favor of job cuts in the run-up to next year's elections.</p>
<p>In his speech Friday, Cardoso urged lawmakers not to give in to pressure from opponents of the reform.</p>
<p>&quot;There are times when we must be brave and not listen to the lobbies, the ones who are organized to defend their perks,&quot; Invest News quoted the president as saying.</p>
<p>(( -- Brasilia newsroom 5561 3141193))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
