<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72218" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper ends higher after stock drop boost.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper ends higher after stock drop boost.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper settled higher, drawing much needed strength from news of a larger-than-expected drop in LME red metal stocks Tuesday.</p>
<p>LME stocks fell 8,825 tonnes to 256,625 tonnes.</p>
<p>William O' Neill, senior futures strategist at Merrill Lynch, said the doom and gloom in the base metals over the past few days was absent, and the stock drop injected a good tone into the market.</p>
<p>Brokers said some fund buying in New York and London pushed LME three months contract back over the key $1,900 per tonne mark.</p>
<p>December COMEX copper settled 1.50 cents firmer at 89.15 cents per pound, traded 89.60 to 88.05 cents. Volume was estimated at 8,500 lots, compared to Monday's 4,701 lots.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve on Tuesday left interest rates unchanged at a policy meeting in Washington. &quot;The market closed before the rate announcement, but it might help the market tomorrow,&quot; O'Neill said.</p>
<p>Copper is a key metal used by industry which would have been hit by a rate hike. LME stocks in Long Beach, Calif. fell 1,225 tonnes to 55,950 tonnes. Brokers said good prices in the Far East was beginning to suck metal from the West Coast.</p>
<p>-- Huw Jones, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
