<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722255" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China dissident sues jail for rights violations.</title>
<headline>China dissident sues jail for rights violations.</headline>
<byline>Lynne O'Donnell</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prominent Chinese dissident Bao Ge said on Friday he was suing the labour camp where he was held for three years without trial.</p>
<p>He said the Shanghai Number One Labour Camp had violated his human rights and broken Chinese law by illegally confining him and restricting his right to write letters, receive visitors and vote.</p>
<p>He had not been permitted to appeal his sentence, nor to read books he had taken to the prison camp, including his Bible, Bao told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bao, 33, was released from three years of &quot;education through labour,&quot; a form of administrative detention that does not require a trial, on June 4, the eighth anniversary of China's 1989 crackdown on pro-democracy demonstrations centred on Beijing's Tiananmen Square.</p>
<p>Bao's suit, lodged on Friday with the Shanghai Xuhui District People's Court, charged the labour camp with threatening and searching his relatives when they visited him and of keeping records of their conversations, he said.</p>
<p>Letters he wrote were screened, he was not allowed to receive books sent by relatives or have pens and pencils, and was not permitted to leave the prison to visit a dying relative, all of which violated China's regulations concerning re-education through labour, he said.</p>
<p>Bao had been a member of the Shanghai-based Association for Human Rights, but was better known to the authorities as a campaigner for compensation from Tokyo for Chinese victims of Japanese war atrocities.</p>
<p>The issue of Japanese compensation is sensitive because Beijing signed away all such claims in the 1970s, a decision that still infuriates many Chinese.</p>
<p>Bao has frequently been jailed for his outspoken views, and sparked a diplomatic row when he and another dissident were detained during a visit to Shanghai by then French prime minister Edouard Balladur in April 1994.</p>
<p>Telephone lines to his home were cut in the days immediately after his June 4 release and members of his family said at the time they had been warned not to speak to the foreign press.</p>
<p>Bao's mother, Wang Yufen, said she was not allowed to visit her son during the last 18 months of his sentence.</p>
<p>Bao said his telephone was cut again from June 30 to July 3, coinciding with the July 1 return of the former British colony of Hong Kong to Chinese sovereignty.</p>
<p>Bao had written to Hong Kong's incoming chief executive Tung Chee-hwa asking that peaceful protests there at the time of the handover not be treated with a heavy hand.</p>
<p>Police had been following him in recent days, he said, and movements of his family members were being restricted.</p>
<p>He said he hoped his legal action did not result in the persecution of other political prisoners, including veteran democracy campaigner Wei Jingsheng, currently serving his second 14-year jail term for subversion.</p>
<p>China's small circle of active dissidents has dwindled in recent years, with most activists fleeing into exile or serving lengthy jail terms.</p>
<p>Beijing frequently comes under fire from Western governments and human rights watchdogs for its heavy-handed treatment of political dissidents.</p>
<p>China rejects such criticism of its human rights record as interference in its internal affairs, arguing that ensuring adequate food and clothing for its 1.2 billion people is more important than political freedoms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
