<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722211" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>AUSTRALIAN GOVT TO CONSIDER CAMBODIAN AID PROGRAMME</p>
<p>The Australian Government is considering its aid programme to Cambodia and is talking to other major aid donors about a co-ordinated approach.</p>
<p>Foreign Affairs Minister, Alexander Downer, says he welcomes the strong message sent by the ASEAN nations yesterday to delay Cambodia's membership of ASEAN.</p>
<p>Speaking in Cairns, Mr Downer says the Cambodian Ambassador will be called in and told by his Department that Australia insists the election in May goes ahead.</p>
<p>Mr Downer: &quot;What I am doing is getting the Department today to call in the Cambodian Ambassador, and explain to him that we are now considering our aid programme.&quot;</p>
<p>The Minister says given that the AID programme is under consideration, it is very important that Hun Sen ensures the Cambodian constitution is upheld; the Paris Peace Accords are implemented; and that elections take place in May of next year, as promised.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PRESSURE ON GOVERNMENT TO RELEASE WALLIS RESPONSE</p>
<p>The Federal Government is coming under further pressure to release its response to the Wallis report, when Parliament resumes late next month.</p>
<p>Three financial industry bodies have jointly written to the Federal Treasurer, Peter Costello, urging quick implementation of major recommendations of the financial systems enquiry.</p>
<p>The letter is co-signed by the Investment Managers' Association, the Investment Funds Association and the Life, Investment and Superannuation Association.</p>
<p>Some analysts question whether the Government has the political will to fully implement the reforms, and say lack of action so far is creating uncertainty among international investors.</p>
<p>But group spokesman, John Maroney, says that is not such a problem.</p>
<p>Mr Maroney says there is potential for a significantly better system, an the sooner the Government moves on it, the sooner everyone concerned is able to get on with job.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MELBOUURNE RALLY CONDEMNS ONE NATION PARTY; WIK PLAN</p>
<p>Victorian Aboriginal leaders have condemned Pauline Hanson's One Nation Party saying it will do nothing to make Australia a better place for its original inhabitants .</p>
<p>And the Federal Government has been singled out for pushing through its response to the High Court's Wik decision.</p>
<p>Around 1,000 people gathered on the steps of the Victorian Parliament at the midway point of a march to mark Naidoc Week.</p>
<p>They called on the Government to abandon its 10 point Wik plan, describing it as taking Aboriginal people back to the 1950s.</p>
<p>Melbourne Aboriginal leader, Richard Frankland, said until the Government had the courage to apologise for the Stolen Generation, and what he called &quot;attempted genocide&quot;, there can be no Australian nation.</p>
<p>His view was shared by Victorian ATSIC Commissioner, Geoff Clark.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>GEORGE SAYS LETTERS AIMED AT SETTING THE RECORD STRAIGHT</p>
<p>ACTU President, Jenny George, says mining union letters to the stock exchange about the Hunter Valley dispute were in response to misleading letters from mine owner Rio Tinto.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard has described the letters from the Construction, Forestry, Mining and Energy Union, as treachery.</p>
<p>Ms George says letters from Rio Tinto to the stock exchange had given the impression coal is being produced and moved from the mine and the dispute is almost over.</p>
<p>The union is striking over a new enterprise agreement and individual contracts, and Ms George says the dispute is far from over.</p>
<p>Jenny George: &quot;The issue that is causing the stumbling block and the resolution of this dispute is not John Mason's letters, but the calculated strategy of Rio Tinto to bludgeon people into submission, to bludgeon working people and to destroy, to try and set out to destroy the union movement.&quot;</p>
<p>- - --</p>
<p>NEW SOUTH WALES TREASURER TO FIGHT DEFAMATION ALLEGATION</p>
<p>The New South Wales Treasurer, Michael Egan, will defend an allegation he defamed Olympic chief John Coates during the controversy over the hotel bed tax.</p>
<p>Australian Olympic Committee President and senior Vice-President of SOCOG, John Coates, is suing Mr Egan for damages in the Supreme Court in Sydney.</p>
<p>Mr Coates has taken offence at the Treasurer's comments last month, that he was a director of a company which runs a big city hotel, and there was a conflict of interest.</p>
<p>Mr Coates denies any association with the control of any New South Wales hotel, and a spokesman for Mr Egan has confirmed the Treasurer will fight the legal action.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>QUEENSLAND PREMIER DISMAYED AT HIGH COURT RULING ON ERVIN</p>
<p>The Queensland Premier Rob Borbidge has expressed dismay at the High Court's decision to release U.S. activist, Lorenzo Ervin.</p>
<p>Mr Ervin was released from a Brisbane jail today, after the High Court set aside Senator Amanda Vanstone's decision to revoke Mr Ervin's Australian visa.</p>
<p>Rob Borbidge says it is not the first time he has disagreed with the High Court.</p>
<p>He says a person with Mr Ervin's criminal history clearly should not be allowed to stay in Australia.</p>
<p>Mr Borbidge: &quot;Obviously I'm very concerned at that decision. Without knowing the legal reasons behind it it's very hard to comment on. It is, I would think, a very disappointing decision from the High Court, but I guess, like a great many Australians, I'm getting used to disappointing decisions from the High Court.&quot;</p>
<p>Mr Borbidge says he believes there are appropriate rules in place, in respect of who can come in to Australia, and says Mr Ervin's background speaks for itself.</p>
<p>He is encouraging the Federal Government to investigate its legal options.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
