<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722283" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodian royalists seek to replace prince.</title>
<headline>Cambodian royalists seek to replace prince.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior member of Cambodia's ousted First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh's party said on Friday it was time to seek a replacement for Ranariddh because of political realities.</p>
<p>&quot;How can we organise a resistance? The situation is very different than previous years,&quot; Loy Sim Chheang, secretary general of Ranariddh's FUNCINPEC party and first vice president of the parliament, told reporters. &quot;We need to be flexible.&quot;  </p>
<p>Loy Sim Chheang said FUNCINPEC still existed and was preparing to ask Ranariddh to name a replacement as party president. The government was also taking steps to name a new first prime minister, he said.</p>
<p>He said royalists could no longer count on the type of regional support that enabled them to oppose Hun Sen's Hanoi-backed government in the 1980s.</p>
<p>Second Prime Minister Hun Sen's forces wrested power away from Ranariddh during fighting in Phnom Penh last weekend.</p>
<p>Ranariddh has accused Hun Sen of staging a coup, but Hun Sen has denied the charge and said he would keep Cambodia's coalition government intact, although without Ranariddh.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
