<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722244" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan keeps options open on Thai rescue plan.</title>
<headline>Japan keeps options open on Thai rescue plan.</headline>
<byline>Yoshiko Mori</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan on Friday kept its options open on an expected request from Thailand to support a multi-billion dollar financial rescue scheme, shying away from showing its cards before a bilateral meeting next week.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not aware of any particular rescue package for Thailand,&quot; an international monetary source told reporters on Friday. He also declined to comment about the possibility of Japan using a so-called Asian repo pact to assist Thailand.</p>
<p>Thai Finance Minister Thanong Bidaya arrives here next week for what he said on Thursday was a visit aimed mainly at building ties with his Japanese counterpart.</p>
<p>&quot;At first, we want to hear what their economic policies are, after their decision to float the baht and allowing it to fluctuate based on economic fundamentals,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Japanese Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka also said on Friday that Thailand had made no specific requests for help with its financial problems.</p>
<p>Thai officials, however, have said that the country would try to raise a total of $10 billion, consisting of $5 billion in loans from banks and $5 billion in bond issues, in order to replenish reserves that were severely depleted when it defended the baht against speculative attacks in May.</p>
<p>Thailand last week sent markets into a frenzy by announcing a de facto devaluation of its currency, sending the baht 15 to 20 percent lower with a surprise move to float the baht.</p>
<p>The baht fell to a record low of 29.75 to the dollar on Friday in line with the Philippine peso, which sank after Manila's central bank announced it would allow its currency to move in a wider range against the dollar.</p>
<p>Other Asian currencies were thrown into a tailspin by Manila's move, which dealers said did little to restore investors' fragile confidence in the region.</p>
<p>Many analysts say Japan has no alternative but to accept a big part of the burden to ease the Thai credit crunch and prevent a chain reaction from happening across the region.</p>
<p>However, a senior Bank of Japan official said on Friday that Thailand's currency crisis is not serious enough to warrant support from Tokyo.</p>
<p>In April of 1996, Japan agreed with the monetary authorities of Australia, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore and Thailand to establish bilateral repurchase agreements to provide liquidity in times of currency crises. South Korea joined the pact in January of this year.</p>
<p>The repo pact gives participants instant access to cash by selling their holdings of U.S. government securities to the pact's partners with a promise to buy them back later.</p>
<p>Asked if Japan would be willing to lend money to Thailand via the repo pact if Thailand made such a request, the source said this technically was possible, although the repo pact only offers short-term liquidity to any country.</p>
<p>On the possibility of the baht's woes spreading to the currencies of other emerging Asian economies, the source said that he was not worried about such a possibility because the fundamentals of those economies were basically sound.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
