<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722362" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Final round of talks begin on U.S. tax cut bill.</title>
<headline>Final round of talks begin on U.S. tax cut bill.</headline>
<byline>Tabassum Zakaria</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>House and Senate negotiators Friday began the final stretch toward the first major American tax cut in 16 years, expressing optimism they could craft a compromise bill President Clinton would sign.</p>
<p>&quot;I can safely say that no one sitting here today will get all that they want,&quot; said Sen. William Roth of Delaware, the Republican chairman of the group working out differences between House and Senate plans.</p>
<p>&quot;But when we're through -- when Congress passes this legislation and the president signs it -- Americans will get what they need: real tax relief,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The lawmakers will try to carve one final tax bill from the different versions passed by the House and Senate, with an eye to objections raised by the White House over provisions in both. They aimed to present the legislation to the full House and Senate for a vote before the August recess.</p>
<p>The tax bill would turn into law part of a five-year balanced budget agreement between congressional leaders and the White House that called for $85 billion in net tax cuts.</p>
<p>Clinton believed differences would be resolved, White House spokesman Mike McCurry said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the president's view is that the spirit of bipartisanship is holding on the (Capitol) Hill and that the likelihood of tax cut legislation and spending legislation that reflects the bipartisan balanced budget agreement is still quite likely,&quot; McCurry told reporters in Romania, where Clinton was travelling.</p>
<p>The May budget pact was designed to remedy stubborn deficits, but more recently signs emerged that the deficit is declining faster than expected because of a stronger economy.</p>
<p>That positive development led some Republicans to call for more tax cut legislation next year and some Democrats to question the need for a tax cut at all.</p>
<p>Sen. Daniel Patrick Moynihan, a New York Democrat, said, &quot;This is no time for tax cuts. The budget ... as a result of a spectacular combination of economic growth, low unemployment and low inflation -- is on the verge of balancing itself.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the Congressional Budget Office cut its estimate of the deficit for this fiscal year ending Sept. 30 to below $50 billion, down from its previous projection of $67 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The amount of tax relief compared to the overall federal budget is still very, very small,&quot; said Representative Bill Archer, a Texas Republican who is vice chairman of the tax conference. &quot;I hope that it will be only the first step and that we can come back year after year.&quot;</p>
<p>Archer and Roth were the chief architects of the respective tax bills passed by the House and Senate. The Senate version drew more bipartisan votes and less fire from the White House.</p>
<p>The issue of &quot;fairness&quot; has dominated the debate. Democrats say the Republican legislation gives too big a share of the tax cuts to the wealthy at the expense of low-income families. Republicans say their plans give the bulk of the tax cuts to the middle class and that Democrats want to give money back to families who do not pay income taxes.</p>
<p>Lawmakers stressed issues they saw as priorities.</p>
<p>Representative Charles Rangel, a New York Democrat, focused on education. &quot;It seems to me ... that it's going to take a lot of flexibility in this conference if we are going to overcome the objections the president has,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The White House has said the House and Senate legislation shortchanged the roughly $35 billion agreed upon in the budget agreement for higher education incentives.</p>
<p>Senate Budget Committee Chairman Pete Domenici, a New Mexico Republican, wanted to address the proposed transfer of the 4.3 cents per gallon gasoline tax from the general fund to the Highway Trust Fund. Spending that money only for transportation could over five years result in $36 billion cuts in other programmes such as education and health, he said.</p>
<p>House and Senate Republicans have said they wanted to change some airline tax proposals. A tug-of-war is likely over the ethanol subsidy due to expire at the end of 2000, with Archer wanting to end it, but others pushing to extend it.</p>
<p>Clinton will meet with Republican and Democratic congressional leaders Tuesday to discuss the status of the tax and spending cut legislation, McCurry said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
