<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722483" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MBS mart shivers as US 30-yr hovers near 6.50-pct.</title>
<headline>MBS mart shivers as US 30-yr hovers near 6.50-pct.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mortgage-backed securities were slightly firmer with discount coupons showing the greatest price appreciation, but participants continued to closely eye interest rate movements.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasury market price gains that sent yields close to the lowest levels since December 1996 have many mortgage market participants concerned about a possible wave of prepayments.</p>
<p>&quot;Convexity is a big concern. Everybody is concerned about prepayments,&quot; said Sally Runyon, a mortgage-backed analyst at Technical Data.  </p>
<p>&quot;There has been alot of swapping out of higher coupons into lower coupons&quot; due to prepayment concerns, Runyon said.</p>
<p>That coupon shift, an investor said, was already seen early in the week.</p>
<p>Late this session, discount coupons were as much as 8/32 firmer while higher coupons rose 1/32 to 3/32.</p>
<p>While the Treasury's long bond yield did not touch 6.50-percent, concerns about prepayments in 8-percent and 8.5-percent coupons were evident, said Runyon. In fact, Runyon noted, there may have been concerns about prepayments within 7.5-percent coupons.  </p>
<p>Among key issues, Government National Mortgage Association 7.5 percent 30-year bonds rose 5/32 to 101-13/32 bid to a bond equivalent yield of 7.32 percent. Comparable Federal National Mortgage Association securities rose 7/32 to 101-09/32 while Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corp. securities also rose 7/32, to 101-14/32.</p>
<p>Ten-year Treasury notes were up 7/32 at 102-29/32 to yield 6.22 percent and the 30-year Treasury bond rose 15/32 to 101-8/32 for a 6.53 percent yield.</p>
<p>Some market players suggested that a fall below the 6.50-percent rate on the Treasury's long bond was likely next week.</p>
<p>&quot;We see long rates easing down, stimulating mortgage originations and perhaps even a refinancing boomlet,&quot; according to market observers at Smith Barney Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a wait and see game, but I think the economy is strong enough to prevent a decline in the 30-year U.S. Treasury below 6.00-percent,&quot; said the investor.</p>
<p>But, one Midwest buysider said he was closely watching the market's reaction to prepayment talk more than the actual prepayments. That investor, who had downsized his mortgage allocation to 30 percent from 50 percent, said that he did not feel a move down in coupon offered enough relative value.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, participants said they heard that an adjustable-rate mortgage (ARM) bid list with Government National Mortgage Association collateral made its way through the market. And, some fixed income market players noted movement from mortgages into Treasuries, although mortgage banker sales were not evident this session.</p>
<p>Early in the day, an East Coast portfolio manager said, the June Producer Price Index appeared to have little affect on MBS. &quot;The PPI was pretty much as expected,&quot; he said. PPI was unchanged, while PPI excluding food and energy declined 0.1 percent.</p>
<p>((Aleksandrs Rozens 212-859-1668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
