<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72241" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tyson sees no sign of end to U.S. expansion.</title>
<headline>Tyson sees no sign of end to U.S. expansion.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>White House economic adviser Laura Tyson on Tuesday said she saw no signs on the horizon that the current U.S. economic expansion will end anytime soon.</p>
<p>Tyson was asked about the likelihood of a recession following a speech to the National Press Club. She said there was nothing in the economic indicators suggesting that would occur. &quot;I think that you cannot see anything in the current economic climate to suggest that this expansion will not be maintained,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>Tyson, who is head of President Clinton's National Economic Council, was also asked about the link between wage growth and inflation. She said there has been some pickup in the growth of wages during the past several months but she added that this did not appear to be stoking inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;There doesn't seem to be anything here that would fundamentally change the inflation picture,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Tyson, who spoke just prior to an expected announcement on interest rates from the Federal Reserve, was also questioned about the potential impact of an interest-rate rise on the economy.  </p>
<p>She stressed that, in keeping with a policy of the Clinton administration, she would not comment on Fed policy.</p>
<p>However, she said, &quot;Higher interest rates would clearly have some slowing effect on spending.&quot; On the other hand, she pointed out that other factors were at play that would help sustain growth.</p>
<p>Just before 1415 EDT, the Fed said in a statement that following a meeting of the Federal Open Market Committee, it had no announcement on policy, signaling that it was leaving interest rates steady.  </p>
<p>Tyson, who spoke with reporters about the outlook for growth for the rest of 1996 following the press club appearance, said the economy was likely to cool down in the second half of this year but that it would still grow at a healthy rate.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an expectation that the economy is going to slow down in the second half of this year,&quot; Tyson said.</p>
<p>She said this expectation was partly due to the fact that long-term interest had risen in the first half of the year. She added that there were already signs of a slackening, saying that the growth in industrial production and in exports has slowed.</p>
<p>But Tyson said the White House did not expect to change its forecast for all of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not see any reason right now to change our forecast,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The latest White House forecast, released in July, calls for gross domestic product growth of 2.6 percent in 1996, fourth-over-fourth quarter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
