<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722437" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Air Force officer resigns to avoid court martial.</title>
<headline>Air Force officer resigns to avoid court martial.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Air Force will allow an officer to resign and avoid a court-martial for fraternising with an enlisted woman who became his wife and lying about it, the Air Force announced Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Secretary of the Air Force Sheila E. Windnall today accepted Second Lt. William Kite's request to resign in lieu of trial by court-marital,&quot; the Air Force said in a statement. &quot;Lt. Kite will receive a general discharge under honourable conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>Kite violated military law when he began a relationship with former Master Sgt. Rhonda Kutzer, now his wife, when the two served together at Whiteman Air Force Base in Missouri.</p>
<p>Compounding the offence, the couple then tried to hide their relationship from superiors.</p>
<p>The Kite case came on the heels of the Air Force's general discharge of Lt. Kelly Flinn, the first woman B-52 bomber pilot.</p>
<p>Flinn accepted a discharge rather than face a court-martial on charges of adultery with the husband of another Air Force woman, refusing to obey an order to end the relationship and lying about it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
