<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72276" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOMC -- What are experts looking at?</title>
<headline>FOMC -- What are experts looking at?</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. experts covering the Federal Reserve, almost evenly divided regarding the decision the Federal Open Market Committee will announce later on Tuesday, are pondering recent signals from the Fed:</p>
<p>++ In a Reuters poll of 55 Fed watchers at U.S.-based primary dealers, banks and advisory firms, 31 said they expect at least a 25-basis-point increase in the 5.25-percent federal funds rate, including 17 who see a discount rate hike as well.</p>
<p>This would be the Fed's first rate move since January 31 and the first tightening since February 4, 1995.  </p>
<p>++ In his Humphrey-Hawkins testimony before Congress in July 18, Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan remarked:</p>
<p>-- &quot;The timing and extent of that (economic) downshift are uncertain.&quot;</p>
<p>-- &quot;Have we moved into an environment where inflation imbalances no longer threaten the stability and growth of our economy in ways they once did? The simple answer, in our judgment, is no.&quot;</p>
<p>-- &quot;If the economy grows so strongly as to strain available resources, history persuasively indicates imbalances will develop that will bring the expansion to a halt.&quot;  </p>
<p>-- &quot;I am confident that the FOMC would move to tighten reserve market conditions should the weight of incoming evidence persuasively suggest an oncoming intensification of inflation pressures.&quot;</p>
<p>-- &quot;We respond to evidence that those strains themselves are developing.&quot;</p>
<p>-- &quot;Price stability is an appropriate and desirable goal for policy.&quot;</p>
<p>++ The Beige Book, released on June 19, focuses on wage pressures and shows a marked acceleration of economic activity compared to the prior report released just five weeks earlier.  </p>
<p>++ Fed Governor Laurence Meyer addressed the National Association of Business Economists in Boston on September 8.</p>
<p>An embargoed version of his speech was made available before the September 6 release of the August employment report. But on September 8, the NABE distributed an addendum to Meyer's speech that emphasizes the Fed's readiness to respond to wage-related price pressures.</p>
<p>++ Minutes of the FOMC since the fourth quarter of 1993 show that every time an FOMC member dissented, the FOMC promptly followed with a move in the direction of the dissent.  </p>
<p>Minneapolis Fed President Gary Stern dissented in favor of a tightening at the July 2-3 FOMC meeting.</p>
<p>++ According to Fed sources, the &quot;opportunistic disinflation&quot; theory, whose name was coined by Meyer, was conceived by former Fed Vice Chairman Alan Blinder.</p>
<p>The sources said Blinder did not attract much support for his idea during his tenure -- notably because the theory does not account for what the Fed should do with inflation in times of rapid growth. Price stability remains the Fed's main goal and there is no indication the FOMC has abandoned the preemptive strike notion, they said.</p>
<p>++ According to a Fed source, eight out of 12 Fed banks have submitted requests for a discount rate hike -- which means Greenspan has the broad support of the entire Fed System for a aggressive move on both the fed funds and discount rate.</p>
<p>The Fed is also said to be nearing targeting core Consumer Price in a zero-to-two-percent range for its policy. The core CPI rose by 2.6 percent year-over-year in August.</p>
<p>-- Isabelle Clary, 212-859-1666</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
