<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722709" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Winterthur unaware of a Swiss takeover bid.</title>
<headline>Winterthur unaware of a Swiss takeover bid.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-06-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Winterthur chairman Peter Spaelti said he had heard nothing about any possible takeover offer for his company from Swiss Reinsurance or allied banking group Credit Suisse Group .</p>
<p>In an interview with Swiss radio DRS, Spaelti was answering a question about takeover speculation after Swiss Re acknowledged it held around five percent of Winterthur shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Naturally I do not know what Swiss Re or the CS Group think,&quot; Spaelti said.</p>
<p>&quot;But I have heard absolutely nothing about a move like this, a takeover offer for Winterthur from Swsis Re or CS,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Speculation about some kind of takeover or merger bid in the Swiss financial sector has swept repeatedly through the stock markets for the past two months.</p>
<p>The spotlight fell again on Winterthur after Swiss financier Martin Ebner made public a letter sent accidently to his BK Group by Winterthur. The letter shown to reporters said Swiss Re had reached the five percent cap on voting rights in Winterthur.</p>
<p>Swiss Re is seen by analysts and stock market traders as allied with CS Group because of several joint ventures and mutual share holdings, as well as the fact that new CS chief executive Lukas Muehlmann came from the same post at Swiss Re.</p>
<p>CS Group in turn was rumoured to be a potential buyer of Winterthur in April when a former Muehlemann colleague, Thomas Wellauer, was named CEO at Winterthur. He will take office on January 1, 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
