<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722850" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - July 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - July 11.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following business stories Friday:</p>
<p>* R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co, of RJR Nabisco, said it will retire the advertising image of Joe Camel.</p>
<p>* The Clinton administration will report to Congress on Friday that the North American Free Trade Agreement has so far generated modest benefits for the United States.</p>
<p>* Assets in stock, bond and money market mutual funds topped $4 trillion in June for the first time.</p>
<p>* The arrival of a heat wave lifted apparel sales and helped retailers report strong sales for June.</p>
<p>* Lower revenue from bond trading cut quarterly earnings at J.P. Morgan by 15 percent, but revenues rose.</p>
<p>* Compaq reported earnings that beat estimates and announced price cuts.</p>
<p>* The resignation of the Apple Computer CEO leaves an opening unlikely to attract many resumes.</p>
<p>* As New York State's utility industry braces for deregulation, a debate has begun over the role of the New York Power Authority.</p>
<p>* Some diet centers that had hoped prescription diet pills would provide a quick fix for their sagging sales are reconsidering their positions on dispensing the medications after a combination of two such drugs was linked to a heart ailment.</p>
<p>* Customers of Niagara Mohawk Power could have reduced rates by early next year as a result of an agreement that allows it to renegotiate its high-cost contracts for electricity with most of its independent power producers.</p>
<p>* Parts of tape recordings in a Texaco race discrimination case may have been erased.</p>
<p>* Palladium prices fell four percent after Russian exports resumed for the first time this year, ending an impasse that depleted stockpiles.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
