<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="722933" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures ease to session lows post-PPI.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures ease to session lows post-PPI.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures fell to session lows as traders and dealers took profits after U.S. producer prices for June met most market expectations, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers were good but so close to expectations that people just decided to take profits,&quot; one T-bond floor source said.</p>
<p>Locals on the Eurodollar futures floor were initially caught short after the numbers were released.  December shot to 94.09, while September T-bonds scaled above resistance at 114-06/32 to a daily high of 114-09/32.  </p>
<p>The U.S. June Producer Price Index (PPI) fell 0.1 percent for a record sixth consecutive monthly drop.  The previous record was set from August to December 1952.  The core rate rose 0.1 percent, as expected, while May's 0.3-percent decline in the overall and core rate was unrevised.</p>
<p>September T-bonds rallied to 114-05/32 in the first 10 minutes of pit trade ahead of the 0730 CDT/1230 GMT PPI numbers.  Traders said pit trade had been active on the upside before release of the PPI on speculation that the numbers would continue to show subdued price pressures in the latter part of the second quarter.  </p>
<p>Signs of low U.S. inflationary pressures have supported the September T-bond contract's rally off the nine-month low of 105-30/32 on April 11, 1996.</p>
<p>The 14.1-percent drop in U.S. June crude petroleum prices was the biggest decline since 15.4 percent in December 1993.</p>
<p>However, the market's rally was soon met with profit-taking, with four U.S. dealers each selling 1,000 September T-bonds.</p>
<p>The contract dipped below the pivot point of 113-25/32, and now faces support at 113-23/32, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;This market is technically tired,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's struggling to make any headway at all,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Support for December Eurodollars is at 94.055 and 94.02.</p>
<p>At 0803 CDT/1303 GMT, September T-bonds were off 02/32 at 113-26/32, 10-year T-notes were off 01/32 at 109-14/32, and December Eurodollars were 0.005 lower at 94.065. ((Chicago Derivatives desk 312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
