<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723069" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK analysts relaxed about retail price pressures.</title>
<headline>UK analysts relaxed about retail price pressures.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Winning</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sharply rising British retail sales volumes may not necessarily mean inflationary pressures are mounting, financial analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly sales are going up, but there is actually very little inflation within the retail sector,&quot; said Clive Vaughan, retail consultant at Verdict Research.</p>
<p>The recent rises in interest rates, the seemingly unstoppable appreciation of the pound, keen competition between retailers and low cost pressures mean there is plenty of room for sales growth without prices going through the roof.</p>
<p>&quot;In competitive markets, like retailing, there is not much room for manoeuvre to put prices up. Consumers are still pretty cautious,&quot; Vaughan added.</p>
<p>The Confederation of British Industry's June distributive trades survey, showing 58 percent of retailers reporting higher sales volumes over last year, certainly paints a healthy retail picture.</p>
<p>Official data showed sales leapt 1.1 percent in May, the biggest monthly jump in nine years.  But Vaughan saw no sign of inflation in key areas like clothing and electrical goods.</p>
<p>Inflation figures, released earlier this week, showed underlying RPI pushed up in June as bad weather sent seasonal food prices soaring.</p>
<p>But clothing and footwear prices fell 0.4 percent over the month while household goods prices edged lower too.</p>
<p>Huge windfall payments from the flotations of building societies mean more money in people's pockets but it is not being blown blindly on the high street.</p>
<p>&quot;Windfall gains are very much a one-off, you would expect them to be hitting June and July sales in a big way, but there is no reason that should cause inflation,&quot; Vaughan said.</p>
<p>&quot;Retailers are not going to try and stick their prices up for two months and then bring them down again.&quot;</p>
<p>Consumers were &quot;making damn sure they are not being ripped off&quot;, Vaughan added.</p>
<p>Durable goods, such as washing machines and stereo equipment, were likely to be the main focus of windfall gains spending.</p>
<p>The recent bumper results announced by Dixons, Britain's biggest electrical retailer, suggested windfall gains were increasing sales in this sector, analysts said.</p>
<p>But inflation? Maybe not.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment the signs are very encouraging,&quot; said Dharshini David, UK economist at HSBC Markets. &quot;The retail price index figures on Tuesday showed that for both household goods and clothing and footwear, which are key things to look at on the high street, price pressures there are very subdued.&quot;</p>
<p>She said both areas boasted annual price increases of less than one percent, far below what would be expected given the strength of demand.</p>
<p>The windfall gains had not altered consumer's search for value, she added. &quot;People are wandering out there with their windfalls but they are still looking for value for money.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumers are still carrying around a lot of debt... one thing they could do with these windfall gains is pay off some of those bills.&quot;</p>
<p>David said that cost pressures facing retailers were also very weak at the moment with producer prices low and wage costs moderate. Retailers' margins can be increased without hitting the consumer.</p>
<p>Producer prices, due out on Monday, are forecast to show output prices up just 1.1 percent in the year to June.</p>
<p>The fear of rising interest rates, which dragged the economy down into recession at the start of the decade following the &quot;boom&quot; years at the end of the 1980s, should also keep the consumer from being too spendthrift.</p>
<p>David Walton, UK economist at Goldman Sachs, said the 100 basis point rise in interest rates over the past nine months and the strength of sterling -- up more than 20 percent in less than a year -- would offset bubbling high street demand.</p>
<p>&quot;We have probably got in place a policy stance that can deliver slower growth overall in the economy and should limit any inflationary pressures that you might otherwise have had from retail sales.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
