<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723058" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BA board backs chief Ayling over strike.</title>
<headline>BA board backs chief Ayling over strike.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The board of directors of British Airways Plc threw its weight behind its chief executive Bob Ayling in his handling of a dispute with unions representing cabin crew, who have been on strike since Wednesday morning over pay and conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;Each member of the Board has expressed their full support for the chief executive and his management team in their efforts to secure the business efficiencies we need to safeguard the future of this company,&quot; BA chairman Sir Colin Marshall said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Hundreds of flights and thousands of passengers have been grounded by the cabin crew strike, which is expected to end early on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Full operations will be restored as soon as possible consistent with achieving the company's business plan and long-term objectives,&quot; Marshall said.</p>
<p>&quot;If management does not keep British Airways competitive, no one will have jobs,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Marshall, a former BA chief executive, said the BA board welcomed moves by the head of the main union involved in the talks, Bill Morris, to seek a compromise.</p>
<p>Earlier, BA and unions representing disgruntled staff offered to meet for talks over the weekend to head off further strikes. Catering staff added to the airline's woes last night by rejecting proposals in a separate dispute which may lead to separate strikes.  </p>
<p>BA regretted the problems caused to its passengers, employees and business partners.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a tragedy to see our continued success jeopardised,&quot; the BA statement said.</p>
<p>The airline, Europe's biggest, is seeking to save 42 million pounds in costs through a restructuring of its cabin crew's pay and conditions. It insists the other unions accept the deal it struck over five months with the small breakaway union, Cabin Crew 89.</p>
<p>&quot;We noted with regret that BASSA (the BA cabin crew's union arm) chose to walk out of the negotiations about cabin crew terms and conditions having taken part in the those talks between November 1996 and March 1997,&quot; Marshall said.</p>
<p>It repeated the &quot;pattern of non-cooperation&quot; BA has experienced with BASSA over many years, he added.</p>
<p>Morris at the Transport and General Workers Union (T&amp;G), the big union representing BASSA, has pledged to help the airline make its target savings, but he is not prepared to have new terms imposed on cabin crew.</p>
<p>Referring to the separate catering dispute, the BA board backed the management's decision to sell the catering unit at Heathrow airport -- the main source of union anger -- saying it was providing staff at the unit with &quot;fair and reasonable terms&quot; of transfer.</p>
<p>-- Paul Keller, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4086</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
