<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723007" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Montgomery Ward gets permission to pay severed workers.</title>
<headline>Montgomery Ward gets permission to pay severed workers.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Montgomery Ward &amp; Co Inc., seeking to repair a black eye it received after stopping severance payments to fired employees, was granted permission Friday by a bankruptcy court to restart the payments.</p>
<p>The retailer, which filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection on Monday, said in court documents that it had suffered &quot;substantial negative publicity&quot; over the halt in payments, which total $3.9 million to 380 former workers.</p>
<p>The 408-store retailer also stopped paying pension benefits of $51,000 a month to widows of non-executive retirees, it said in documents filed in Wilmington, Del.</p>
<p>After a hearing in Wilmington, Bankruptcy Judge Peter Walsh granted the company's request to resume the payments.</p>
<p>Montgomery Ward said it was prohibited from cutting the checks under bankruptcy law. While it intended to ask the court for permission to resume paying again at a later date, it said Friday it needed an order to begin right away.</p>
<p>&quot;In short, without the requested relief, the stability of the debtors would be undermined by the potential threat that otherwise loyal employees at all levels would seek other employment,&quot; the retailer said in documents.</p>
<p>The 408-store chain has eliminated 400 jobs at its corporate headquarters and closed three stores and two distribution centres this year. It plans to shut a third facility and a fourth store this summer.</p>
<p>The 125-year-old retailer filed for bankrutpcy protection after talks with lenders over a rescue package failed. Montgomery Ward employs about 50,000 workers. General Electric Co.'s GE Capital Services owns 58 percent of Montgomery Ward.</p>
<p>In Chapter 11 a company is protected from its creditors as it tries to work out a plan to pay its debts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
