<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723249" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Healthdyne says court denies Invacare motion.</title>
<headline>Healthdyne says court denies Invacare motion.</headline>
<dateline>MARIETTA, Ga.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Healthdyne Technologies Inc. said Friday an appeals court has denied hostile suitor Invacare Corp.'s motion for a review of a federal court ruling upholding the medical device maker's antitakeover provisions.</p>
<p>However, Healthdyne now faces another lawsuit by Respironics Inc. alleging unlawful use of its patented technology.</p>
<p>A federal judge in Atlanta last Thursday denied a request by Invacare, a medical equipment manufacturer, to overturn part of Healthdyne's shareholder rights plan that allows only continuing directors to nullify the &quot;poison pill&quot; provisions.</p>
<p>&quot;We are extremely pleased by the decision of the Court of Appeals,&quot; said Parker Petit, chairman of Healthdyne.</p>
<p>Petit said the company's litigation victory would have no effect on the continued exploration of possible alternatives to improve shareholder value.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the Court's interpretations of Georgia law, even if Invacare's nominees are elected at the July 30 shareholders meeting, they will not be able to redeem the rights under our shareholders rights plan,&quot; said Petit.</p>
<p>&quot;Given these facts, we call upon Invacare to tell our shareholders how Invacare will be in a position to buy their shares in the tender offer or to conduct its two-week so-called 'auction' of the company,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Invacare officials were not available to comment.</p>
<p>Invacare's bid, launched in January, is valued at about $200 million. The $15-a-share offer is scheduled to expire Aug. 1, unless extended.</p>
<p>Separately, Respironics said Friday that Healthdyne wilfully infringed the Pittsburgh-based company's patent on pioneering technology used in its portable Bipap medical device. One version of the device is used in ventilating a patient's lungs while another helps patients with sleep disorders.</p>
<p>The complaint, filed in a federal court in Pittsburgh, seeks injunctive relief and damages.</p>
<p>Officials of Healthdyne was not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>Marietta, Ga.-based Healthdyne's stock rose 17 cents to $17.875, while Invacare gained 25 cents to $24.25 early on Nasdaq. Respironics edged down 12.5 cents to $23.50, also on Nasdaq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARIETTA, Ga."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
