<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723321" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle calls mixed, feeders steady to up.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle calls mixed, feeders steady to up.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Early calls on CME live cattle futures ranged from 0.100 cent per lb higher to 0.100 lower while feeder cattle were expected steady to 0.200 cent per lb higher, livestock analysts said.</p>
<p>Some analysts look for carryover technical demand from Thursday's late rally. A stronger tone to fed cattle and outlooks for tighter cattle supplies ahead may also lend support.</p>
<p>Although early projections on next week's Cattle-on-Feed report point to larger-than-year-ago on-feed suppplies, the U.S. Cattle Inventory report is expected to show reduced total cattle numbers, they said.</p>
<p>Early analyst projections on the Cattle-on-Feed report ranged from 114 to 117 percent of a year ago for July 1 on-feed supplies in the seven major cattle feeding states with June placements ranging from 109 to 125.1 percent and June marketings ranging from 101 to 106.9 percent.</p>
<p>Estimates on total U.S. cattle supplies as of July 1 were ranging from 108.4 to 109.6 million head, 97 to 98 percent of last year.  </p>
<p>However, some analysts consider live cattle futures overbought on the late short covering rally Thursday. Packers have adequate live supplies to meet kill needs well into next week and boxed beef values continue to slip, they said.</p>
<p>Indications on feeder cattle futures pointed mostly up following another advance in the latest CME feeder cattle index and lower corn futures projections. The seasonal trend for feeders is also up, rising 14 of the last 15 years during July. Feeder supplies were seen very tight going into the fall and the upcoming U.S. Cattle Inventory report should confirm the tight feeder numbers, they said.</p>
<p>Early analyst estimates on the inventory report which will be released next Friday point to feeder cattle supplies  at 96.4 to 98 percent of last year as of July 1. Early estimates on the estimated 1997 calf crop are 97 to 98 percent.</p>
<p>The latest CME feeder cattle index was up $0.62 at $81.37 per cwt, a new high for the move and the highest level since April 15, 1994.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
