<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723357" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USDA to cut 1,320 more jobs, save $449 mln - Post.</title>
<headline>USDA to cut 1,320 more jobs, save $449 mln - Post.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Agriculture Department plans to cut about 1,320 administrative jobs over the next five years, generating estimated savings of up to $449 million, the Washington Post reported Friday.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman informed key deputies of the proposed job cuts in an internal memo Thursday, saying the move was intended to shift money into computer modernization and to protect basic services.</p>
<p>Between 500 and 600 administrative jobs would be lost at the department's Washington headquarters, the Post said.</p>
<p>The newspaper quoted sources as saying that Glickman also called department representatives in several states to explain his proposal.</p>
<p>The brunt of the cuts would come in the Farm Service Agency, which helps farmers qualify for and comply with programs; the Natural Resources Conservation Service, which provides technical assistance to farmers; and rural development agencies that provide housing, business and utilities service.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless we simplify our administrative overhead and reduce costs, we will not have credibility when we ask the Congress to appropriate funds for our programs and we will ultimately be unable to provide adequate services to our customers,&quot; the Post quoted the memo as saying.</p>
<p>Glickman's decision to cut overead positions comes in the midst of a broader downsizing at USDA, where about 11,000 workers were already scheduled to lose their jobs over the next four years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
