<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723319" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USDA wheat estimate to stir class jitters, spreads.</title>
<headline>USDA wheat estimate to stir class jitters, spreads.</headline>
<byline>Sam Nelson</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>USDA's forecast Friday for U.S. wheat production will stir the spreads between the Kansas City hard red winter, Chicago soft red winter and the Minneapolis spring wheat contracts, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue in wheat is class and reflects a spring wheat crop that doesn't have very good conditions so far,&quot; said John Zanutto, vice president for Merrill Lynch Futures. &quot;The markets will do some spreading.&quot;</p>
<p>USDA Friday said U.S. 1997 U.S. wheat production would total 2.431 billion bushels, within the range of analysts' average estimates for 2.433 billion.</p>
<p>But the U.S. winter wheat tally at 1.781 billion was above the average estimate for 1.687 billion and the USDA spring wheat tally at 569.265 million bushels was sharply below average expectations for 634 million. Also the durum wheat outlook released by USDA at 80.927 million was sharply below the average estimate for 106 million bushels.</p>
<p>Traders and analysts were expecting CBOT and KCBT wheat to open from three to five cents lower while MGE spring wheat futures could stage a rally as a result of the government's wheat production forecast. U.S. Midwest cash dealers posted scattered five cents protection on SRW wheat early Friday.  </p>
<p>Analysts and traders expressed little surprise at USDA's forecast for U.S. corn or soybean data in Friday's July supply/demand report.</p>
<p>Jack Scoville, vice president for Price Futures Group, did seen a potential hike from USDA's forecst for U.S. 1997-98 (Sep-Aug) soybean ending stocks if U.S. Midwest weather continues its nearly ideal pattern for crop production.</p>
<p>USDA pegged 1997-98 U.S. soybean ending stocks at 285 million bushels, within expectations for roughly 280 million to 300 million and, as expected, well above USDA's June forecast for 240 million bushels.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think most traders were looking for 300 (million) or more primarily on the increase in acreage (soybeans) in the last USDA report,&quot; Scoville said.</p>
<p>USDA in June said 1997 U.S. soybean acreage would total 70.9 million, sharply above analysts' average expectations for 68.4 million.</p>
<p>Scoville and Zanutto were the featured analysts Friday at a CBOT press briefing following release at 0730 CDT of the government's wheat production and supply/demand reports.</p>
<p>&quot;Next week's rain event or non-rain event will do more to the flat prices than any of these numbers,&quot; Zanutto said. &quot;The soy number (1997-98 soy carryover) is subject to change to more like 300 million to 320 million depending on weather.&quot;  </p>
<p>USDA boosted to 1.196 billion bushels its forecast for 1997-98 (Sept-Aug) carryover from the previous govenment tally of 909 million. That move was considered mildly bearish for the CBOT corn futures market.</p>
<p>&quot;On the whole, I was not surprised at all by the numbers (corn/soybean) and the next few weeks will determine where we go,&quot; Zanutto said.</p>
<p>But analysts and traders Friday bantered a lot about the government's wheat balance sheet and wheat price direction.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a possibility we'll go back to test contract lows,&quot; Scoville said, referring to another decline in CBOT and KCBT wheat futures markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed, we could test contract lows but I think the bear has had his day and will have to be extra careful in pressing those levels,&quot; Scoville added.</p>
<p>((Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
