<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723400" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Auctioneers eye vintage 90-year-old champagne find.</title>
<headline>Auctioneers eye vintage 90-year-old champagne find.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Schmelz</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Auction houses were queueing up on Friday for the right to sell off thousands bottles of 90-year-old champagne salvaged from the wreckage of a ship carrying victuals for the Russian tsar's army.</p>
<p>The first of what is thought to be 5,000 bottles of vintage champagne and stores of cognac and fine wine have been brought ashore after having lain on the Baltic seafloor since the ship carrying them was torpedoed in 1916 by a German submarine.</p>
<p>London and Paris auction houses have contacted the consortium which plans to salvage the wreck, in hope of selling the champange which some say could fetch as much as 10,000 crowns per bottle.</p>
<p>One French auction house wanted to sell the bottles at the Eiffel Tower, consortium member Claes Bergvall said.</p>
<p>The champagne, identified as a 1907 Heidsieck &amp; Co of Reims, France -- printed on the inside of its corks -- retained its original light gold colour and has a sweet taste believed to have been fashionable at the turn of the century.</p>
<p>A small glass given to this correspondent on Friday by the consortium in a central Stockholm wine cellar revealed that most of the bubbles had disappeared from the champagne, which was almost cloying compared to modern, fruity sparkling wines.</p>
<p>Experts have described the sweet taste and fine bubbles as &quot;gout americain&quot; (American taste).</p>
<p>Experts say the wine was kept in near ideal conditions for the past 80 years: complete darkness and plus one degree centigrade temperatures.</p>
<p>The two men who discovered the wreck are looking for sponsors to continue the costly and time-consuming salvaging operation of the Swedish ketch Jonkoping, which lies about 25 nautical miles from Rauma, Finland, where it was headed.</p>
<p>Divers will only be able to stay at the depth of the cargo, 62 meters (200 feet) down, for 20 minutes, said Bergvall, part of the two-man consortium which discovered the wreck.</p>
<p>Some of the green bottles, which smell like rotten fish and are covered with a build up of sediment, have been damaged and their bottoms are completely missing.</p>
<p>But the corks on most of the bottles which have been brought have prevented seepage and pop loudly in traditional style when opened.</p>
<p>The Jonkoping left the Swedish port of Gavle on October 28, 1916 after a storm that had lasted a week, bound for Finland and Petrograd (now St. Petersburg) to carry the cargo ordered by the Tsar's imperial army and the central bank of Finland.</p>
<p>The submarine, U-Boat 22, had a field day after the storm, sinking six other ships. Sweden was neutral during the war.</p>
<p>Luck and a string of coincidences led the two Swedes to find the wooden, two-masted ship.</p>
<p>Bergvall and his partner Peter Lindberg learned of the ship's fate in a book and searched through Sweden's well-kept national archives to find its location.</p>
<p>Bergvall, who sold and designed T-shirts before he discovered the ship, said he invested as much as 300,000 crowns before the first dive.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been lucky all the way,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>If luck holds out, some 40,000 litres of cognac stored in oak barrels will be in as good shape as the champagne.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that before shipping the barrels were covered in paraffin so they should hold well,&quot; Bergvall said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know the make of the cognac. But we can rest assured that's it's very high quality because the Russian army had very good taste -- very expensive taste anyway,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
