<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723550" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Slovak president calls for NATO, EU support.</title>
<headline>Slovak president calls for NATO, EU support.</headline>
<byline>Nigel Stephenson</byline>
<dateline>SALZBURG, Austria 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak President Michal Kovac urged NATO and the European Union on Friday not to turn their backs on his country and said membership of both was still his aim.</p>
<p>Slovakia, once mentioned as a leading candidate to be among the first new members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation and the EU, appears to have missed out on the first wave of expansion of both.</p>
<p>NATO, at its summit in Madrid this week, invited Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic to join. The European Commission agreed in principle on Thursday to recommend the EU open membership talks with six states but Slovakia was not among them.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope that the member countries of the European Union and NATO will not turn their backs on Slovakia and that they will even more intensively support the democratic forces in Slovakia which wish for Slovakia's integration,&quot; Kovac told Reuters in an interview at the Central and Eastern European Economic Summit in Salzburg.</p>
<p>Slovakia, which became a sovereign state after the former Czechoslovakia split in 1993, has come in for repeated Western criticism over the slow pace of democratic reform.</p>
<p>Kovac, an avowed political foe of Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar, blamed the three-party governing coalition for Slovakia's failure in the integration process and said real change was only possible after next year's parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>&quot;Real changes and many changes can only be expected after the parliamentary election,&quot; Kovac said.</p>
<p>Meciar, whose Movement for a Democratic Slovakia (HZDS) dominates the government, has said that NATO applied different criteria for membership eligibility for different countries.</p>
<p>Kovac said Slovaks had to understand it was necessary to take further steps to strengthen democracy and to put pressure on politicians to create the right conditions for integration.</p>
<p>&quot;I am convinced...they will make the right decision in the election and that by this they will be contributing to building up confidence again towards Slovakia which will enable Slovakia to get integrated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Western criticism of Slovakia intensified after a botched referendum in May on NATO membership and a proposal to introduce direct presidential elections.</p>
<p>The referendum was declared void after the Interior Ministry removed the presidential election question from the ballot at the last minute, insisting it was illegal.</p>
<p>Kovac said there was very little possibility the election issue would be resolved before his term in office ends early next year.</p>
<p>Under the present system, parliament chooses the president but, with the current deeply divided asembly, it is very unlikely any candidate would win the required number of votes. In that case, power passes temporarily to the prime minister.</p>
<p>&quot;It will depend on the coalition and first of all on the leader of the main political party whether he is going to support the draft amendment of the constitutional law or not.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if he believed there would be a change of government after the next election, he said polls showed the coalition had approximately 30 percent support and that this would not be enough after the election to put together an administration.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SALZBURG, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
