<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723508" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Germany's Genscher pans 3.0 pct deficit aims-paper.</title>
<headline>Germany's Genscher pans 3.0 pct deficit aims-paper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former German foreign affairs minister Hans-Dietrich Genscher, a signatory of the Maastricht Treaty, said on in an interview on Friday a strict reading of the monetary union deficit was at odds with the treaty itself.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who pretend that there is a 3.0 percent written in the Maastricht treaty are not respecting its terms,&quot; he was quoted as saying in an interview with daily Le Figaro.</p>
<p>&quot;The fathers of this treaty were people more competent in economics and finance than the politicians who claim the title of apostles of stability and want to change the treaty by reinterpreting it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>By establishing &quot;criteria that do not exist, (they) are sapping confidence in the stability of the future currency&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>Genscher also warned that &quot;a controlled delay (of EMU) would quickly lead to an uncontrollable collapse of the single market and thus of European integration adding that the Bundesbank was right in qualifying this discussion about the number behind the decimal point as a 'phantom debate'.&quot;</p>
<p>He criticised repeated German reprimands directed at other European Union members and said it was perfectly legitimate to add social aspects to the Maastricht monetary criteria, without calling it a &quot;scandal&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We started with the Italians, the Spanish and other people from the south, now it is the turn of the French to be used as scapegoats&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is how with an incredible irresponsibility we are playing a game of questioning one of the most precious assets gained from our post-war economic policy.</p>
<p>&quot;I am telling you that France will be part of EMU and that your new government will do everything to fulfil the terms of the treaty, but not those added afterwards by a few German politicians,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom 331 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
