<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723658" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - BTPs eye 137.05, but cracks appear.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - BTPs eye 137.05, but cracks appear.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian BTP futures traded on LIFFE appeared to be running out of steam on Friday, after the previous session saw a decline for the first time this month, traders in London said.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the September contract closed at 136.24, after opening at 136.40.</p>
<p>&quot;Momentum is slowing, short stochastics started turning in the last day or so,&quot; said Marc Ostwald, technical analyst at London Bond Broking Company. &quot;It's a violently overbought market.&quot;</p>
<p>September BTPs were up 0.23 at 136.47 by 0750 GMT.  </p>
<p>BTPs were heading for resistance from the contract high at 137.05 set on July 9, after overcoming initial resistance from a pivot point at 136.40 in early trade.</p>
<p>Technical analysts at an Italian bank also said further retracement could be on the cards, as the contract opened below an upsloping trend line at 136.35/40. However, they said the bear market was likely to be short-term.</p>
<p>&quot;The major trend is positive, buy dips,&quot; the Italian bank analysts said in a research note.</p>
<p>They cited resistance at 136.85, and a defeat of the contract high at 137.05 would target 137.85.  </p>
<p>On the downside, support was pegged at 135.98/95, lows set on July 8 and July 10.</p>
<p>&quot;If it falls off more, then the 135.33/35 lows will be the next support,&quot; said Ostwald.</p>
<p>At the short end, September Eurolira futures were unchanged at 93.31. Supports were at 93.29/28 and then 93.21/20. Resistances were at 93.35 and 93.45.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
