<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72371" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GDR REPORT - India wallows ahead of SBI issue.</title>
<headline>GDR REPORT - India wallows ahead of SBI issue.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian global depositary receipts (GDRs) wallowed in thin trade ahead of a new issue from State Bank of India, which is expected to be priced on October 3.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade is limited ahead of State Bank of India -- market talk is of the issue being priced at parity to the underlying stock,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>State Bank of India's underlying share closed up 0.60 rupees at 263.05, equating to around $7.30 per GDR, with each GDR equivalent to two underlying shares.</p>
<p>The James Capel Indian GDR Index fell 0.12, or 0.17 percent to 68.66 points, a premium of 12.65 percent over the local market after the Bombay Stock Exchange 30 share index rose 6.64 points, 0.20 percent, to 3,337.73.</p>
<p>Trading in Taiwanese equities was also thin, with the Capel Taiwan Index falling 0.06 points, or 0.07 percent, to 88.15 points for a premium of 2.71 percent over the local market.</p>
<p>The Taiwan Weighted Index had gained 23.87 points or 0.37 percent to end at 6,477.85.</p>
<p>The Capel Korea Index rose 1.01 points 1.53 percent to 66.86 points, a premium of 28.26 percent over the local market after te Korea Composite Index rose 8.71 points to provisionally close at 777.91.</p>
<p>Samsung GDRs followed the local market higher, adding $1.63 to $43.00/$45.00, after the underlying rose 1,300 won, or 2.21 percent, to 60,200 won, while KEPCO rose 56 cents to $19.00/$20.00 after the local stock put on 700 won, or 2.59 percent, to 27,700 won.</p>
<p>-- David Chance London newsroom 44 171 542 5887</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
