<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723724" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: C-C Amatil hit on Philippine peso woes.</title>
<headline>C-C Amatil hit on Philippine peso woes.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in beverage group Coca Cola Amatil Ltd were sold down further on Friday after taking a hammering 24 hours earlier. Brokers said the fresh falls are on the slump in the Philippines peso.</p>
<p>At 1.00 p.m. (0300 GMT), Coca Cola Amatil shares were 47 cents or 3.11 percent down at A$14.65 with 385,000 shares traded. A day earlier the group's shares fell seven percent on a downgrade by investment bank Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is a combination of the two (peso and downgrade), but I think people are wondering should they sell the stock further from here,&quot; one Sydney broker said.  </p>
<p>C-C Amatil increased its exposure to the Philippines when it acquired San Miguel Corp soft-drink business, while the Philipines largest brewer received a 25 percent stake in C-C Amatil to become the group's second largest shareholder.</p>
<p>The Australian beverage group is 33 percent owned by The Coca-Cola Co. C-C Amatil shares have now fallen almost 16 percent since the beginning of July.</p>
<p>The Philippine peso tumbled over 11 percent earlier after the country's central bank announced it would allow the peso-dollar rate to move in a wider range.</p>
<p>-- Kevin Morrison 61-2 9373-1813</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
