<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="723714" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia releases former U.S. Black Panther.</title>
<headline>Australia releases former U.S. Black Panther.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former U.S. Black Panther activist Lorenzo Ervin was released on Friday from a maximum security Australian jail where he had been held for the past three days pending his planned deportation.</p>
<p>Ervin was released after the Australian government reversed its cancellation of his visa. No reason was given for the government's decision.</p>
<p>Ervin was detained on Tuesday after the government ordered his deportation on grounds that he was not of good character, based on his conviction for hijacking an aircraft from the United States to Cuba in 1969.</p>
<p>The black human rights activist will on Monday attend an immigration department hearing to show cause why he should be allowed to stay in Australia.</p>
<p>On leaving jail, Ervin called on Australian Prime Minister John Howard to apologise for his treatment.</p>
<p>&quot;It is really a shame that a person cannot live down their political past,&quot; Ervin told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say Mr Howard owes me an apology,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Monday, Howard said he was shocked to hear Ervin had been allowed to enter Australia on July 4 and hoped he would be deported. On Tuesday, the country's acting immigration minister cancelled Ervin's visa and ordered him detained and deported.</p>
<p>The minister said Ervin was not of good character and had falisified his immigration documents -- a charge Ervin denies.</p>
<p>Ervin unsuccessfully sought two new visas and took legal action in Australia's High Court, saying he had been denied natural justice.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Australian government solicitor told the court that the decision to cancel Ervin's visa had been put aside.</p>
<p>Ervin's lawyer Terry Fisher said the &quot;backdown&quot; was a &quot;major victory for free speech&quot;.</p>
<p>Ervin was invited to Australia for a four-week speaking tour by anarchist group Angry People.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
