<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724043" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Ranariddh asks for U.N. intervention in Cambodia.</title>
<headline>Ranariddh asks for U.N. intervention in Cambodia.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Goodman</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodia's ousted first prime minister, Prince Norodom Ranariddh, urged the Security Council on Thursday not to recognise any government resulting from last weekend's coup and to freeze aid to Cambodia.</p>
<p>After meeting council President Peter Osvald of Sweden, he told reporters he also asked the council to appeal for mediation in the crisis by King Norodom Sihanouk, now in Beijing.</p>
<p>Ranariddh, Sihanouk's son, was ousted on Sunday by his co-prime minister, Hun Sen, after two days of fighting between their forces in Phnom Penh, the capital.</p>
<p>Sihanouk has already offered to mediate but has been turned down by Hun Sen.</p>
<p>Ranariddh said he had asked the council &quot;not to recognise any government issued from a coup d'etat and ... to do everything in the framework of the Paris peace accord.&quot;</p>
<p>That 1991 agreement ended years of civil war in Cambodia and launched a U.N. peacekeeping operation that resulted in elections in 1993.</p>
<p>The council &quot;should make a clear appeal to his majesty the king for his immediate mediation ... because the Paris peace accord says very clearly that the king has to resolve any difficulty and serious crisis in Cambodia,&quot; Ranariddh said, adding that mediation would also be in line with Cambodia's constitution.</p>
<p>Ranariddh said he had asked the council to &quot;freeze any assistance and aid to Cambodia unless Cambodia is back not only to normality but to the framework of the Paris peace accord, that is to say, to have a democratic, liberal state.&quot;</p>
<p>He delivered the same message during a meeting with General Assembly President Razali Ismail of Malaysia.</p>
<p>While Secretary-General Kofi Annan has criticised the coup, the Security Council has so far been silent, with members attempting to reach a common stand. Diplomats said the Chinese delegation was still awaiting instructions.</p>
<p>At a news conference before seeing the secretary-general, Ranariddh called for unspecified economic sanctions and challenged Hun Sen to hold free and fair elections.</p>
<p>He said he was &quot;planning to go back as early as possible to a controlled area (of Cambodia) out of reach of Hun Sen&quot; but said he would not be taken seriously if he disclosed where and when he would arrive.</p>
<p>Ranariddh said Hun Sen had staged the coup for four main reasons:</p>
<p>-- He feared the outcome of elections set for next May.</p>
<p>-- He was worried that a probe by FBI agents showed his bodyguards were responsible for a grenade attack on an opposition rally earlier this year.</p>
<p>-- He was concerned that the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency had discovered that about 600 tons of marijuana had been exported from Cambodia.</p>
<p>-- He opposed any trial of former Khmer Rouge leader Pol Pot by an international tribunal, something Ranariddh said he had been close to arranging.</p>
<p>&quot;My priority is diplomatic and political struggle and not a military one, because any civil war would mean necessarily more suffering, more destruction for my poor country, Cambodia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In an interview on television's CNN news channel, Ranariddh proposed &quot;free, fair and democratic elections ... controlled by the United Nations observers or by observers sent in by other countries&quot; to produce &quot;a new government with only one prime minister.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier, he welcomed a decision by the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN), meeting in Kuala Lumpur, to postpone Cambodia's membership and to continue recognising Ranariddh as co-premier.</p>
<p>Ranariddh said he had appealed to ASEAN to &quot;postpone, at least for the time being, the admission of the kingdom of Cambodia because the regime that will be set up after the coup is illegal and is outside the framework of the Paris peace agreement,&quot; of which ASEAN members were signatories.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
