<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724076" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - July 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - July 11.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- If Austria applies for NATO membership, Finland may have to reconsider its stance towards the alliance, President Martti Ahtisaari said in a televised interview.</p>
<p>- Finland's current division of powers between the president and the government is suitable, says opposition Centre Party leader Esko Aho rejecting the idea of reducing the powers of the president. @</p>
<p>- Total public spending, especially on education and pensions, rose by 38 billion markka in the past three years to 327 billion markka in 1996, despite simultaneous cuts of 20 billion markka.</p>
<p>- The death rate of Finns who have been treated in mental hospitals is four times higher than that of others, a social and health care study shows.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- An comparison by International Data Group showed Finland to be the world's second most highly developed information society after the United States. @</p>
<p>- Telecom equipment groups Ericsson and Nokia benefit from their mutual &quot;co-competition&quot; in world markets, and Finland will remain one of Ericsson's most important research and development centres, says Ericsson's Finnish subsidiary's newly appointed CEO Veli-Matti Mattila.</p>
<p>- Finnish diversified group Hackman's environmental technology unit Hardwaco will become profitable in a few years, says Hadwaco's managing director Lauri Prepula.</p>
<p>- Extra Sunday shopping days do not seem to have boosted retailers' profitability, and many shops have opted to stay closed on Sundays this summer, sector representives say. @</p>
<p>- State-owned power group IVO is trying to enter the higher-priced German electricity markets, deputy managing director Kalervo Nurmimaki says.</p>
<p>- Various options for cooperation between oil group Neste and IVO are still under study, ministry of trade and industry says.</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- Rainbow trout at northern Finland fish farms are showing up with a bacteria-related kidney disease. @</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- Thirty guests at a western Finland wedding down with food poisoning -- meat balls the suspected source.</p>
<p>-- Nora Hallberg, Helsinki Newsroom +358-9-680 50 292</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
