<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724065" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German share market rally seen rolling on.</title>
<headline>German share market rally seen rolling on.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German share market rally is likely to keep on rolling for the time being with investors pouring funds into equities because conditions remain ideal, dealers said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't think of any negative factors, we have the best of all possible scenarios for the share market,&quot; one Frankfurt share trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;My only slight fear is that people are piling into the stock market without really knowing what they are buying.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said the fundamental outlook for shares remained as positive as ever.  </p>
<p>The weak mark is helping exporters, interest rates are at historic lows and unlikely to rise anytime soon and Germany as well as the U.S. are on course for more inflation-free growth.</p>
<p>Share prices resumed their rise on Friday morning after a very short-lived dip on Thursday.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX index, which reflects electronic trade in 30 blue-chip shares, was up 40.49 points or 1.01 percent at 4,041.14 at 0810 GMT, 20 minutes before floor trade opened.</p>
<p>Dealers did not rule out that the index could test its all-time high of 4,067.51 on Friday and saw the DAX on course to reach 4,250 or 4,300.  </p>
<p>The DAX index tumbled about 1.6 percent in active bourse dealings on Thursday, hurt by the dollar falling more than a pfennig on comments from the Bundesbank that the U.S. currency's correction against the mark was now over.</p>
<p>The DAX ended down 63.48 points at 3,992.38 points, ending a streak of seven consecutive bourse sessions that ended with new record closing levels. The IBIS DAX, which reflects all-day computer dealings, pared some losses and ended down 26.32 points at 4,000.65.</p>
<p>But dealers dismissed Thursday's fall as a temporary blip.  </p>
<p>&quot;All in all, there's still no change in the fundamental environment. We're seeing a lot of liquidity pouring into the market.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. Dow Jones Industrial Average closed up 0.57 percent at 4,023.12 points overnight while the dollar was slightly firmer against the mark in early European trade. It was quoted at 1.7550 marks at 0830 GMT.</p>
<p>Banks were among the top performers, benefiting from bullish financial markets which should be reflected in their half-year earnings reports due to be published in the coming weeks, traders said.  </p>
<p>Deutsche Bank was up 1.10 marks at 104.10 marks, while Bayerische Vereinsbank rose 1.69 marks to 74.30.</p>
<p>Engineering groups Thyssen AG and Preussag AG were also up sharply after a newspaper report said they eventually plan to merge their shipbuilding businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;One hopes that should lead to synergy benefits,&quot; one dealer said. &quot;It may also lead to job cuts in the long term.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said they were waiting for a news conference at 1200 GMT by German Finance Minister Theo Waigel where details of the federal government's supplementary budget for 1997 and the 1998 budget will be announced.  </p>
<p>But traders said the market impact was likely to be minimal since many details have already been leaked.</p>
<p>The 1230 GMT U.S. producer price report for June is not expected to have much impact either since U.S. inflation is generally believed to be under control.</p>
<p>--David Crossland, Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
