<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724037" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - July 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - July 11.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Greek Cypriot press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ALITHIA</p>
<p>- United Nations envoy Diego Cordovez gives the two Cypriot leaders meeting in New York a six page document outlining their intentions on issues of procedure at the talks.</p>
<p>- Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash has broken the media blackout imposed by the United Nations and givien hardline comments to a Turkish Cypriot newspaper.</p>
<p>CYPRUS MAIL</p>
<p>- Media blackout holds in New York as talks continue between President Glafcos Clerides and Rauf Denktash.</p>
<p>- Parliament approves extra police jobs, but rejects a request from the finance ministry to extend the duty free rights of the Archbishop and bishops.</p>
<p>HARAVGHI</p>
<p>- Banks and employers are expected to give an answer to the mediation proposal made by the labour ministry yesterday for the renewal of collective working agreements.</p>
<p>PHILELEPHTHEROS</p>
<p>- The U.N. has prepared a document on the constitution of a federal Cyprus, which it plans to submit to the two sides during the course of the direct talks in New York.</p>
<p>- A crisis between doctors in the civil service and the government is fizzling out. The government urges doctors to submit counter-proposals to its suggestions on how to meet demands for better working conditions.</p>
<p>SIMERINI</p>
<p>- Cordovez gave a document on the constitutional aspects of the Cyprus issue to the two leaders yesterday.</p>
<p>- Denktash raises issues of sovereignty again. Turkish Cypriot media reports Denktash called on President Clerides to respect the &quot;sovereignty&quot; of the Turkish Cypriots and &quot;equal political rights&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
