<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724145" id="root" date="1997-07-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: White House, states show united front on tobacco.</title>
<headline>White House, states show united front on tobacco.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>White House officials said Thursday they were united in the fight against smoking with the state attorneys general who brokered a settlement with the tobacco industry but wanted more time to study the agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;We are united in a single cause to reduce smoking, especially by children,&quot; Bruce Reed, White House domestic policy adviser, said after a meeting on the proposed settlement.</p>
<p>Reed and Donna Shalala, secretary of health and human services, met at the White House with Mississippi Attorney General Mike Moore and Washington state Attorney General Christine Gregoire to review the $368.5 billion deal and discuss President Bill Clinton's concerns about it.</p>
<p>On Wednesday Clinton, in Madrid for a NATO summit, rejected as &quot;unreasonable&quot; a part of the proposed settlement that would restrict the government's hard-won powers to regulate the nicotine content of tobacco products.</p>
<p>Shalala declined to say what the administration would like changed in the agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;Other than what the president has already said on the (Food and Drug Administration) restrictions, we will not make any public comments on any other parts,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to finish our review,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Moore said the deal was &quot;very much alive&quot; despite the president's objections.</p>
<p>The FDA's jurisdiction over nicotine recently was upheld by a federal court, and health advocates were adamant that any settlement not dilute it.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can strengthen the language that we have proposed, that would be a good thing,&quot; Moore said. &quot;I think there is a little room, but not a whole lot of room, for tinkering with this agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said he was worried that any delays in implementing the agreement, which requires legislation approved by Congress, would mean more children would pick up a habit many would find difficult to kick as adults.</p>
<p>He said a decision Thursday by R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co. to replace its controversial Joe Camel advertising figure when it rolls out a new ad campaign this week was a good-faith gesture that showed the tobacco industry was serious about not marketing its products to children.</p>
<p>&quot;We think that shows good faith at a special time when we have this bill being prepared to go before Congress,&quot; Moore said. &quot;And we're all going to work together in this with the White House and make this thing happen.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton, who was traveling in Europe, also praised the tobacco company's decision.</p>
<p>&quot;As I said last year when we announced the Food and Drug Administration rule to protect youth from tobacco, we must put tobacco ads like Joe Camel out of our children's reach forever,&quot; he said in a written statement.</p>
<p>&quot;I am glad RJR has finally taken this step today, and I hope other companies will follow suit,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In the House of Representatives, Texas Democrat Lloyd Doggett said he was introducing legislation to rein in U.S. tobacco companies that aggressively promote tobacco overseas.</p>
<p>&quot;The world's children are the newest targets in Big Tobacco's continued addiction to making money at the expense of human lives,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Under the settlement proposal, tobacco companies would strengthen the health warnings on their packages and change their advertising practices.  Doggett would require the same of tobacco exports to other countries.</p>
<p>A number of congressional critics and public health experts have faulted the proposed settlement because it does not address tobacco exports.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
