<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724162" id="root" date="1997-07-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: TENNIS-VILOCA, MANTILLA IN ALL-SPANISH FINAL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-VILOCA, MANTILLA IN ALL-SPANISH FINAL.</headline>
<byline>Steve Keating</byline>
<dateline>GSTAAD, Switzerland 1997-07-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Juan Albert Viloca upset second seed Alex Corretja on Saturday to join Felix Manilla in an all-Spanish final to the Swiss Open.</p>
<p>Viloca, who claimed his first victory over a top 10 player when he beat number nine Marcelo Rios in the second round, produced an even more impressive performance against fellow Spaniard world number six Corretja, fighting back to record a 3-6 7-6 6-4 win to earn a place in his first career final.</p>
<p>Mantilla, the sixth seed, advanced to the final for the second consecutive year with a dominating 6-3 6-4 win over eighth seedWayne Ferreira of South Africa.</p>
<p>No matter what the outcome of Sunday's final it will mark the sixth time time in seven years that a Spaniard has won the Swiss title.</p>
<p>After easily winning the first set, Corretja, winner of two tournaments already this season and a finalist in two others, looked poised to finish off his compatriot when he went 5-4 up in the second and was serving for the match.</p>
<p>But the 24-year-old Viloca, ranked a career high 67, dug in and got the pivotal break he desperately needed, forcing the set to a tie-break which he won 7-5.</p>
<p>&quot;When Corretja was leading and serving for the match, I thought to myself it was going to be tough to comeback,&quot; said Viloca. &quot;But I kept fighting and the match turned around.</p>
<p>&quot;When I won the second set he started to get tired.&quot;</p>
<p>Viloca took control of the match when he broke Corretja and held serve to go 5-3 up in third.</p>
<p>Hampered by a nasty blister on the second finger of his right hand that required treatment after each of the last three games, Corretja never threatened a comeback as Viloca avenged an earlier defeat by him in his only other semifinal appearance, at Kitzbuehel a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Near the end of the match at 5-3 I came to the net and tried to hit a volley and caught my finger in the grip,&quot; said Corretja. &quot;But that wasn't what decided the match.</p>
<p>&quot;I've never lost a match this year when I had the advantage like I had.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess it had to happen sometime, I just hope it doesn't happen again.&quot;</p>
<p>Corretja's appearance in the final comes as no surprise to Mantilla, who is looking for back-to-back tournament wins after beating French Open champion Gustavo Kuerten in the final in Bologna.</p>
<p>&quot;We in the Spanish camp always knew he (Viloca) had a lot of potential,&quot; said Mantilla. &quot;It's going to be a tough match tomorrow.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GSTAAD, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
