<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724298" id="root" date="1997-07-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Explosions rock Havana hotels, bombs suspected.</title>
<headline>Explosions rock Havana hotels, bombs suspected.</headline>
<byline>Frances Kerry</byline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1997-07-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Loud explosions rocked two Havana hotels within minutes of each other on Saturday, injuring at least three people. Authorities suggested the blasts were caused by bombs.</p>
<p>The explosions took place at the Hotel Nacional and the nearby Hotel Capri in Havana's central Vedado district, shattering windows in the lobby areas.</p>
<p>A Danish tourist, Ole Madsen, and several hotel workers said at least three people were injured in the explosion at the Nacional, a Havana landmark that opened in 1930.</p>
<p>Asked by reporters what caused the explosions, Tourism Minister Osmany Cienfuegos, visiting the hotels shortly after the blasts, said: &quot;Obviously they are enemies of ours.&quot;</p>
<p>Cienfuegos said the explosion at the Capri was in a sofa and there were no injuries at that hotel.</p>
<p>At the nearby Hotel Nacional, at least four ambulances were seen speeding away after the explosion, although it was not clear if they were carrying wounded people.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the explosions, both of which hit the hotel lobbies, took place at about 11:25 a.m. local time (1525 GMT) and 11:30 a.m. local time (1530 GMT).</p>
<p>Madsen, who was sitting in the Hotel Nacional garden at the time of the explosion, said the blast appeared to have ripped through a row of telephone booths in the lobby.</p>
<p>He said that ground floor windows opening onto the back garden of the hotel were broken.</p>
<p>A security cordon of police and plain clothes security officials prevented reporters entering the Nacional, a luxury hotel owned and managed by the state Cuban firm Gran Caribe.</p>
<p>The atmosphere in the streets by the hotels right after the explosions was very tense, with plain clothes security officials trying to stop foreign cameramen filming the scene.</p>
<p>Deputy president Carlos Lage visited the Hotel Capri after the explosions, but declined to make any comment to reporters.</p>
<p>Many ground floor windows were shattered by the blast at the Capri, a highrise 1950s block owned and managed by Cuban state firm Horizontes.</p>
<p>&quot;We heard a very loud noise, like an earthquake,&quot; said Spanish tourist Carlos Alvarez, describing the explosion at the Capri. &quot;There was horrible confusion and hysteria in the lobby, everyone was crying,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Pascal Massiot, a Frenchman from Nantes, said he was convinced the explosion was a bomb. &quot;There were a lot of people in a state of shock,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>While police prevented reporters from entering the hotels, dozens of curious passers-by gathered in the streets to find out what had happened.</p>
<p>Saturday's explosions followed reports in U.S. news media that a small bomb exploded in the discotheque of Havana's Hotel Cohiba in mid-April, causing damage but no injuries.</p>
<p>President Fidel Castro's Communist government never confirmed or denied that report. The Spanish hotel chain Sol Melia that manages the Cohiba Hotel said there was an explosion at the disco that was caused by faulty gas piping.</p>
<p>If Saturday's explosions were caused by bombs, suspicion will likely fall on hardline exile opponents of Castro in Florida, some of whom have carried out attacks in the past.</p>
<p>In 1991, a Miami exile group claimed responsibility for a seaborne machine-gun attack on a hotel at the beach resort of Varadero.</p>
<p>Violence involving firearms or explosives is rare in Cuba, where the tourist industry is the leading source of hard currency amid the economic crisis the island was plunged into after the collapse of the Soviet Union.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
