<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724268" id="root" date="1997-07-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Moscow and Chechnya agree on some pipeline details.</title>
<headline>Moscow and Chechnya agree on some pipeline details.</headline>
<dateline>GROZNY, Russia 1997-07-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Work will begin in the next few days on mending a pipeline to carry Azeri oil across Russia's rebel region of Chechnya to the Black Sea, and Moscow will pay for the work, Interfax news agency said on Saturday.</p>
<p>It quoted Boris Berezovsky, deputy secretary of Russia's policy-making Security Council, as saying Chechen specialists would carry out the work although Russians could be brought in.</p>
<p>&quot;Work on restoring the Chechen part of the Baku-Novorossisk pipeline will be fully financed by the federal authorities,&quot; the agency quoted Berezovsky as saying in an interview in the Chechen regional capital Grozny.</p>
<p>He did not give an estimate for how much it would cost.</p>
<p>It quoted the president of the Chechen state oil company YUNKO, Khodzhakhmed Yarikhanov, as saying work would begin on the pipeline &quot;in the next few days&quot;.</p>
<p>It was not clear how long the work would take, nor when oil would begin to flow.</p>
<p>The pipeline, a key conduit for Azeri oil from Baku on the Caspian Sea to the Russian Black Sea port of Novorossisk, was damaged during Russia's war with Chechen rebels.</p>
<p>An outline agreement on the pipeline was signed in the Azeri capital Baku on Friday. Saturday's talks were to tackle some of the details.</p>
<p>The deal is significant because Chechnya has set itself up as a de facto independent entity since the war ended last August. The Kremlin regards Chechnya as one of 89 regions within the Russian Federation, although has adopted a pragmatic approach to several bilateral problems.</p>
<p>Officials said earlier the two delegations would also discuss agreements on Russian-Chechen banking and customs ties.</p>
<p>The pipeline deal, held up for months by bickering between the sides over details, is intended to clear the way for crude output from an $8 billion Western consortium developing off-shore Azeri Caspian Sea fields to reach world markets.</p>
<p>Few details of the agreement have been made public.</p>
<p>Radio Ekho Moskvy quoted a Chechen presidential aide on security, Akhmed Zakayev, as saying the agreement did not specify what tariffs Chechnya would get, but he said he did not expect any major further disputes.</p>
<p>&quot;All questions were removed yesterday in the first half of the day in Moscow, and in Baku (Friday evening) we talked over all the nuances,&quot; he said. &quot;On the whole, an agreement on all questions has been reached.&quot;</p>
<p>Chechen Interior Minister Kazbek Makhashev told Ekho Moskvy a supplementary agreement on tariffs and other details would take another 20 or 30 days.</p>
<p>He said Russian special forces would guard the pipeline.</p>
<p>But Yarikhanov told Interfax Chechen authorities would assume responsibility for the security of any Russian workers brought in to repair the pipeline.</p>
<p>Friday's agreement was signed by Russian Fuel and Energy Minister Boris Nemtsov, Yarikhanov and the president of Azeri state oil company SOCAR.</p>
<p>The consortium, led by British Petroleum Co, wants to begin using the route to transport its oil later this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AZERB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020043">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GROZNY, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
