<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72420" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius rupee strengthens on dollar and pound.</title>
<headline>Mauritius rupee strengthens on dollar and pound.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mauritian rupee strengthened against the dollar and pound on Tuesday, reflecting international trends, forex dealers said.</p>
<p>The rupee was quoted at a mean commercial rate of 20.5895 for one dollar from 20.6295 on Monday. Against the pound, the rupee traded at a mean of 32.0405 from 32.0808 on Monday.</p>
<p>Forex dealers said rupee strength reflected the dollar's softening overnight.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if commercial banks are currently getting short in their foreign currency reserves thereby, putting weakening pressure on the rupee, this was offset by the dollar's depreciation abroad,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The dealer attributed the forex shortage situation in banks to an absence of central bank intervention.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank last sold dollars to banks the previous Monday (September 16). In the meantime, the square position of banks has become one of shortage,&quot; the dealer added.</p>
<p>Commercial banks are also looking forward to the Mauritius Sugar Syndicate to put on tender sale pound sterling receipts from sugar exports, the country's largest hard currency earner in net value added terms.</p>
<p>The Syndicate is expected to sell an equivalent of 2 billion rupees or 25 percent of the sugar proceeds directly to banks during the financial year 1996/97. The remaining 75 percent are kept by the central bank for market interventions.</p>
<p>--Mike Chung, Port Louis ++230 212-6870.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
