<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72427" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Cardiology think-tank suffers Yeltsin media circus.</title>
<headline>Cardiology think-tank suffers Yeltsin media circus.</headline>
<byline>Alastair Macdonald</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cardiologists attending an international conference in Moscow on Tuesday have the world's most famous heart patient on their doorstep, but are still in the dark about what is wrong with him.</p>
<p>Yet they needed a clinical ruthlessness to fend off a frenzy of media badgering for their opinions on Russian President Boris Yeltsin's health and concentrate on their otherwise intimate symposion on &quot;The History of Cardiovascular Surgery&quot;.</p>
<p>Michael DeBakey, the pioneer of heart bypass surgery from Houston, needed all his 88 years of Texan charm to keep his cool. He will advise a council of doctors, due to meet on Wednesday, on the timing and other details of the planned operation on the 65-year-old Kremlin leader.</p>
<p>After a day of stonewall insistence that he had yet to see Yeltsin or his case details, DeBakey summed up his attitude to the media in one word: &quot;Toleration.&quot;</p>
<p>Bagrat Alekyan, a Moscow cardiologist and one of the organisers of the symposium, told reporters: &quot;It's just not serious, making all this fuss. We've got a sick person here.&quot;</p>
<p>Renat Akchurin, the leading Russian heart specialist and one-time pupil of DeBakey's who is expected to lead the surgical team, was even less diplomatic.</p>
<p>He accused stampeding camera crews following him on a trip to the coffee bar of breaching journalistic ethics.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, for all the good doctors' insistence that they keep their minds on their symposium, the thrill of a big and intriguing case bubbled in the backrooms.</p>
<p>German heart surgeon Hans Borst, a speaker at the long-planned conference, said he thought the experts would happily advise Yeltsin, who is in hospital preparing for the operation and has had two or three heart attacks.</p>
<p>&quot;Logically the Russians should use the expertise presented by a group of at least 12 foreigners who are very well versed in this type of surgery,&quot; Borst said. &quot;All of us are rather curious about what is going to be the next step.&quot;</p>
<p>Yeltsin, breaking a long tradition of secrecy about the health of top Kremlin leaders, said on September 5 he was ready to undergo surgery to resolve long-standing problems.</p>
<p>But his doctors have since expressed concern about whether he was fit enough for surgery.</p>
<p>Akchurin has said the operation might have to be postponed for up to eight weeks.</p>
<p>Possible help from Western advisers could include specialised post-operative care, especially if there were complications after surgery, Borst said. These could include pneumonia, lung infections and liver or kidney problems.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that he still has angina pectoris, heart pain on exercise, makes him a candidate to be operated on...but since the question is raised whether he should be operated on at all I wonder whether there are other snags which we do not know about yet,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Asked if Yeltsin could stay president without an operation, Borst said: &quot;If he has angina pectoris and it cannot be handled by drugs he cannot (stay in office), because he will drop out at the times he is most needed.&quot;</p>
<p>Russian communists, arguing that the president would not be able to carry out his duties fully if doctors did not operate, have said Yeltsin might have to step down.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, quoted by Interfax news agency after a 40-minute meeting with Yeltsin, said on Tuesday: &quot;This is out of the question now.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
