<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724333" id="root" date="1997-07-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan says unsurprised by China-Sao Tome break.</title>
<headline>Taiwan says unsurprised by China-Sao Tome break.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-07-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan said on Saturday it was not surprised by rival China's decision to suspend diplomatic ties with the tiny West African state of Sao Tome and Principe.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not surprised by the development,&quot; foreign ministry African affairs chief Timothy Yang told reporters, choosing his words carefully so as not to further agitate Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;What concerns us most is our diplomatic relations with Sao Tome. We will not interfere with Sao Tome's ties with other countries,&quot; Yang said.</p>
<p>Beijing's official Xinhua news agency said on Saturday that communist China has suspended ties with Sao Tome because the twin-island African nation had extended official ties to Taipei in May despite Beijing's strong protests.</p>
<p>Beijing has seen Taiwan as a rebel province not entitled to diplomatic ties since the two split in 1949 after a civil war. It refuses diplomatic ties to any state recognising Taiwan.</p>
<p>The suspension of ties was Beijing's latest tightening of the diplomatic screws on Sao Tome. Beijing halted development aid to the impoverished nation in May pending Sao Tome's decision of who it would recognise.</p>
<p>Sao Tome, like many other developing African and Caribbean states, has been a bit-player in a fierce diplomatic tug-of-war between Beijing and Taipei, with both sides making use of soft loans and other aid to woo potential allies to their side.</p>
<p>Beijing had been building Sao Tome's first national sports stadium and had several residential and engineering projects in the country, one of the world's poorest states.</p>
<p>Sao Tome officials have said their republic had won pledges of aid from Taiwan totalling $30 million over the next decade after deciding to formalise ties with Taipei.</p>
<p>Taiwan's exiled Republic of China is recognised by only 30 states, virtually all of them small, poor and heavily dependent on the Chinese Nationalist government's financial generosity.</p>
<p>Taipei severed ties with the Bahamas in May after learning the Caribbean nation was preparing to secure links with Beijing.</p>
<p>South Africa, Taiwan's biggest ally since South Korea made the switch to communist China in 1992, has said it would drop recognition of Taipei in favour of Beijing in 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
