<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724308" id="root" date="1997-07-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Three drug chiefs to vie for Mexican crown - reports.</title>
<headline>Three drug chiefs to vie for Mexican crown - reports.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three drug traffickers are vying to replace Amado Carrillo Fuentes, the long-reigning Mexican drug baron who died unexpectedly last week, news reports said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The death of Carrillo Fuentes of either complications from liposuction or an overdose of medicine slipped into his intravenous drip is causing a reshuffling of the drug trade, newspaper Reforma said.</p>
<p>Carrillo, 42, ran the Juarez Cartel, based in the northern border city of Ciudad Juarez, across the border from El Paso, Texas.</p>
<p>Citing Mexican government documents and sources, as well as statements from the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), Reforma said that among those aspiring to fill Carrillo's shoes are his brother, Vincente Carrillo Fuentes.</p>
<p>&quot;A natural successor, he knows of the latest negotiations with the capos of Peru and Colombia,&quot; Reforma said in a front page story.</p>
<p>News reports also named long-time drug dealer Ignacio Coronel, who has negotiated with nacro-traffickers in other Mexican states on behalf of Carrillo.</p>
<p>Juan Esparragoza, alias &quot;The Blue,&quot; who was in charge of handling business ties with the Colombian cartels, could also try to take over the role played by Carrillo, the paper said.</p>
<p>Nicknamed &quot;The Lord of the Skies,&quot; Carrillo used passenger jets to transport cocaine from South America to Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;The succession of 'The Lord of the Skies' implies a restructuring of organised crime in Mexico,&quot; Reforma said.</p>
<p>U.S. officials considered Carrillo the most important figure in the Mexican drug trade, shipping tons of cocaine a year to the United States from his base in northern Mexico.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
