<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724388" id="root" date="1997-07-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt state to sell 15 firms to their workers.</title>
<headline>Egypt state to sell 15 firms to their workers.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-07-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Officials in charge of Egypt's privatisation programme were quoted on Saturday as saying the state has decided to sell off 15 public firms to their workers and was considering getting banks to help finance the project.</p>
<p>Public Enterprise Minister Atef Obeid was quoted in the government-owned Ahram daily as saying the state was willing to sell the firms over a period of 10 to 20 years. The companies are in the transport and rice milling sectors, he added.</p>
<p>In past privatisations, the state has offered equity stakes to private or institutional investors, reserving a maximum 10 percent of its holdings for employee shareholder associations.</p>
<p>The employees can then buy the shares from the company over an extended time period.</p>
<p>Obeid's adviser, Mahmoud Salem, was quoted in the Akhbar al-Youm newspaper as saying the state was considering giving tax breaks to banks which offer loans to employees to encourage them to buy the stocks.</p>
<p>Analysts say the state is probably trying to appease the workers who have been quoted in the opposition press as saying that they feel cheated by the privatisation programme, the flagship of the Egypt's economic reforms, as it gives them minimal influence over the management of their companies.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +202 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
