<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724439" id="root" date="1997-07-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France Telecom says swap wld help alliance.</title>
<headline>France Telecom says swap wld help alliance.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chairman of France Telecom has said a share swap with Germany's Deutsche Telekom would bolster an alliance between the two operators but depends on the new French government's stance on privatisation.</p>
<p>France Telecom chairman Michel Bon said in an interview with the Journal du Dimanche newspaper released on Saturday that a share swap was topical because of Bonn's agreement last month to sell some of its remaining shares in Deutsche Telekom.</p>
<p>&quot;Such an exchange would reinforce our alliance with them (Deutsche Telekom),&quot; Bon said. &quot;But this operation depends on the government's decision on opening up France Telecom.&quot;</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom said last month it had entered negotiations with France Telecom over a possible share swap but the French operator immediately denied this, saying there were only informal but regular discussions.</p>
<p>Privatisations are a sensitive issue for France's new Socialist-led government, which has already run into fierce conservative opposition attack over its decision on Friday to scrap the sale of defence contractor Thomson-CSF.</p>
<p>The six-week-old government is now weighing whether to go ahead with the previous centre-right government's plans for a partial selloff of France Telecom. It has hinted this sale may go ahead if staff are consulted and agree first.</p>
<p>The planned sale of a minority 30 to 35 percent public stake worth around 50 billion francs was suspended after the left's upset victory in parliamentary elections on June 1.</p>
<p>Bon declined to comment in the interview on the merits of privatisation, saying this was a matter for the government.</p>
<p>He has previously been quoted as saying the suspension of the sale last month was a setback but not a catastrophe.</p>
<p>White-collar workers at France Telecom favour the selloff but the Communist-backed CGT union is firmly against any privatisations. The Communists are junior partners in Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin's government.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom said last month it had reached an agreement with the German government allowing Bonn to sell some of its remaining shares in the company to strategic investors.</p>
<p>Both countries' plans were drawn up to help shape up their finances for European monetary union starting in 1999.</p>
<p>An exchange of shares between France Telecom and Deutsche Telekom would build on a strategic alliance known as Atlas and bring the two groups closer together at a time when European operators are getting ready for full competition next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
