<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724420" id="root" date="1997-07-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Cyprus talks end; another round expected in August.</title>
<headline>Cyprus talks end; another round expected in August.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Goodman</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-07-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four days of talks between leaders of the Greek and Turkish Cypriot communities ended on Saturday and a U.N. source close to the negotiations said a second round was likely next month in Switzerland, subject to confirmation by the two sides.</p>
<p>The source described the U.N.-sponsored meetings between President Glafcos Clerides and Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash as &quot;very positive and very constructive.&quot;</p>
<p>But a Turkish Cypriot source painted a bleaker picture, saying there had been little change in basic positions, particularly over the issue of sovereignty, that for decades have deadlocked efforts to reunite the divided Mediterranean island as a bi-zonal, bi-communal federation.</p>
<p>One sign of this emerged on Friday when Denktash was said to have been angered by a report that the European Commission in Brussels had agreed in principle to open membership talks with six countries, including Cyprus.</p>
<p>The Turkish Cypriots strongly oppose any negotiations on membership by the Greek Cypriot-led government in Nicosia, which they do not recognise and say cannot speak for them.</p>
<p>Clerides, speaking to reporters on Friday, had characterisd the atmosphere of the talks as good and said they provided a good opportunity for exchanging views on issues that had long concerned both sides.</p>
<p>The meetings between Clerides and Denktash, at a rural resort called Troutbeck, 90 miles (145 km) north of New York city, were led by Secretary-General Kofi Annan's special adviser for Cyprus, former Ecuadorean Foreign Minister Diego Cordovez. He was not scheduled to make any public statement about the talks until Monday.</p>
<p>A U.N. spokeswoman would only confirm that &quot;the talks ended after lunch&quot; on Saturday.</p>
<p>Officials close to the talks said Cordovez, who earlier submitted proposals dealing with various aspects of the Cyprus problem, came up with an amended version on Saturday incorporating some of the two sides' observations. The Cypriot leaders will take this home for further study. It is to form the basis for discussion at the planned August session.</p>
<p>The U.N. source close to the negotiations said: &quot;The whole point of these talks was to get a process going. It is quite obvious now that this process is established.</p>
<p>The next round is expected to be held from August 11 to 16 at a location near Geneva, but the source said this had to be confirmed by the two sides.</p>
<p>Cyprus has been virtually partitioned since troops from Turkey took over the north of the island in 1974 in reaction to a coup in Nicosia backed by the junta then ruling Greece.</p>
<p>But the Greek and Turkish Cypriots have been estranged since 1963, when a government in which both participated split apart amid violence that led to the dispatch of U.N. peacekeepers still stationed on the island.</p>
<p>Adding urgency to resolving the long-festering Cyprus problem, in addition to negotiations next year on the controversial issue of European Union membership, is the Nicosia government's plan to deploy Russian-made S-300 air defence missile in 1998, which Turkey has vowed to prevent.</p>
<p>The Greek Cypriot-led administration is recognised internationally as the legitimate government of all of Cyprus while the Turkish Cypriots, who set up their own state in 1983 with Denktash as president, are recognised only by Ankara.</p>
<p>The Greek Cypriots, comprising about 80 percent of the island's population of some 800,000, envision a solution based on the devolution of power, granting each community a degree of autonomy while retaining as many elements as possible of a strong central government.</p>
<p>The Turkish Cypriots see a federation arising through the surrender of some powers by two independent sovereign entities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
