<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724521" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Thyssen, Krupp to detail steel plans Sept 3 - report.</title>
<headline>Thyssen, Krupp to detail steel plans Sept 3 - report.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-07-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>German steel and engineering companies Thyssen AG and the Krupp group plan to outline the details of their steel merger and begin wider cooperation talks next month, a newspaper reported on Monday.</p>
<p>The daily Berliner Zeitung newspaper said that following the success of talks about merging the two companies' steel operations, Thyssen had taken the initiative and suggested widening talks to explore other areas of cooperation.</p>
<p>Citing Thyssen spokesman Reiner Hochscheidt, the paper said details of the results of talks about a steel merger that began in March would be announced on September 3 and talks about broader cooperation would begin the same day.</p>
<p>Krupp shares were trading up 2.8 percent at 330 marks in early trading on the computerised IBIS system. There was still no price set for Thyssen shares by 0645 GMT.</p>
<p>Krupp launched an unprecedented hostile takeover bid for its larger rival Thyssen in March, but withdrew the offer under pressure from local politicians and the workforce after Thyssen agreed to begin talks about merging the steel businesses.</p>
<p>Thyssen made clear at the time that once the talks about a steel merger were concluded the two companies would also explore the possibility of cooperating in other areas.</p>
<p>The newsweekly Der Spiegel, in an advance release of a story that was published on Monday, said at the weekend senior management at Thyssen and Fried. Krupp AG Hoesch-Krupp had met for talks to discuss a merger of the two groups.</p>
<p>The magazine said the deal to combine their flat steel units would be approved in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>Thyssen chief executive Dieter Vogel and his counterpart at Krupp, Gerhard Cromme, have been involved in the talks with top executives at the two groups located in Germany's &quot;rust belt&quot; in the northern Ruhr River Valley, it added.</p>
<p>The talks are at such an advanced stage that Vogel officially notified the Thyssen supervisory board on July 17 of the discussions, it said.</p>
<p>Officials at both companies said at the weekend that it was well known that further cooperation talks would take place after the flat steel unit merger, which will create a new European steel giant even as it sheds about 8,000 jobs.</p>
<p>But the officials would not confirm whether leadership at the two companies are near agreement on a mega-merger.</p>
<p>A deal between Thyssen and Krupp could create Germany's fifth-largest industrial group. Thyssen reported sales of almost 39 billion marks in its 1996/97 business year and has a global workforce of about 124,000 people. Krupps had 1996 sales of over 24 billion marks and a workforce of 70,000.</p>
<p>The steel unit merger, which calls for Thyssen to take a 60 percent stake and Krupp a 40 percent stake, will create a group capable of producing around 15 million tonnes of steel a year, similar in size to France's Usinor-Sacilor or British Steel.</p>
<p>The new company, Thyssen Krupp Stahl AG, will concentrate on hot metal operations at Thyssen's main Duisburg steel works by shutting down three blast furnaces at Krupp's Dortmund plant and expanding rolling and processing work at Krupp Hoesch.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
