<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724661" id="root" date="1997-07-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CSR says housing recovery signs encouraging.</title>
<headline>CSR says housing recovery signs encouraging.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSR Ltd said on Monday that signs of improvement in the housing industry were encouraging but the recovery was patchy to date and tilted towards high rise apartments.</p>
<p>&quot;However, indications are that the traditional detached housing market is starting to improve and overall that should result in stronger demand for CSR's building materials,&quot; said chairman Alan Coates.</p>
<p>Coates said CSR had achieved some modest price increases in the past few months.  </p>
<p>However, the bulk of a planned profit improvement would come from cost reductions, productivity improvements and volume increases, he said.</p>
<p>Coates said CSR's new fibre cement plant was now producing a full range of products and would be profitable this year, its second year of operations.</p>
<p>Building materials had shown healthy margin increases since the start of the current financial year, he added.</p>
<p>Coates said the improvement in activity in construction materials was clearer, and demand was encouraging.  </p>
<p>Part of an expected profit improvement should come from modest price increases, but CSR would benefit mainly from reducing overheads and rationalising production facilities.</p>
<p>Results from Asian operations were expected to improve, and no new plants were planned in the immediate future.</p>
<p>&quot;The improvements achieved with construction materials in the first three months of this year, through lower overheads, reduced operating costs and better asset utilisation, have resulted in good margin gains,&quot; Coates said.</p>
<p>The contract mining forward order book had been increased by A$30 million, he added.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
