<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724632" id="root" date="1997-07-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Foreign presence in Brazil privatizations growing.</title>
<headline>Foreign presence in Brazil privatizations growing.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-07-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's National Development Bank (BNDES) estimates that foreign participation in the country's privatizations will grow to 40 percent in upcoming sales, a newspaper said.</p>
<p>The BNDES estimates the government will earn more than $85 billion from privatization over the next three years, of which $34 billion will derive from foreign investors, Jornal do Brasil said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The first companies to be privatized were less glamorous and often in a poor financial situation, but now there are two fundamental changes. The type of assets which are being sold strongly attract foreign investors and the stability of the economy has changed foreigners' impression of Brazil,&quot; Jornal do Brasil quoted BNDES Vice-President Jose Pio Borges as saying.</p>
<p>In 1991, when the privatization program began, foreign participation was less than five percent, but by 1996 foreigners were involved in 13 percent of investment in privatizations, Jornal do Brasil said.</p>
<p>This year, with the sale of mining giant CVRD, this share increased to 20 percent and only recently to 26 percent with the privatization of B Band cellular telephone services. ((-- Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
