<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72472" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech minister to offer Budvar selloff plan-agency.</title>
<headline>Czech minister to offer Budvar selloff plan-agency.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech Farm Minister Josef Lux will submit a plan to privatise the brewery Budvar n.p. before the end of 1996 now that trademark talks with Anheuser-Busch Cos collapsed, the CTK agency said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It quoted Lux as saying no definite plan for the selloff was ready yet, but there was little chance that A-B would take part in the Ceske Budejovice (Budweis) brewery, seen by many Czechs as a piece of national heritage.</p>
<p>Lux said it was the Czech side, not Anheuser-Busch, which ended the talks over the use of the &quot;Budweiser&quot; and &quot;Bud&quot; trademarks -- which is prohibiting the rivals from selling their lables in the other's key markets, CTK reported.</p>
<p>He said that the Czechs registered &quot;little positive attitude&quot; from A-B's side.</p>
<p>The Saint Louis-based brewer on Monday said it ended talks with Czech Budvar on settling the lengthy dispute.</p>
<p>The Czech government has been mulling the privatisation of Budvar with and without participation of A-B, but had held off taking any steps before the end of the trademark talks.</p>
<p>A-B said in a statement on Monday that it ended the talks because the company was successful in selling its beer under other trademark on the disputed markets.</p>
<p>&quot;It is no longer necessary for us to have a trademark settlement to develop our Budweiser business in Europe,&quot; A-B Chairman Jack Purnell said in a statement.</p>
<p>Anheuser-Busch said it sells its beer under the Budweiser name in 11 European countries and under the &quot;Bud&quot; name in nine other European countries. Both brands have virtually identical labels except for the name, it added.</p>
<p>The limitations had not had a significant impact on A-B's international growth, the U.S. brewer said.</p>
<p>-- Jan Lopatka, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
