<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724871" id="root" date="1997-07-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Stark -3 pct applies to all, sees France in EMU.</title>
<headline>Stark -3 pct applies to all, sees France in EMU.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior German finance official said the Maastricht Treaty's budget deficit limit of three percent applied to all states seeking to join monetary union but added he expected both France and Germany to qualify.</p>
<p>French Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn has already said France will not be able to reduce its budget deficit to 3.0 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) this year -- the ceiling set by Maastricht for nations seeking to join EMU.</p>
<p>The French government is waiting for an audit of public finances due on July 21 before taking further action.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no way I am going to give any advice here or voice expectations,&quot; Juergen Stark, state secretary to Finance Minister Theo Waigel, told Handelsblatt newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;The three percent target level applies to all member states that want to qualify.&quot; He predicted European economic and monetary union (EMU) to be launched as scheduled on January 1, 1999, the paper said.</p>
<p>Handelsblatt released the interview ahead of publication in Monday's editions.</p>
<p>Monetary union only made sense if at least two large EU states and several smaller ones joined from the start, Stark said, adding that Germany and France were likely to be among the large states to join.</p>
<p>He declined to comment on whether nations should be allowed to join even if their deficits are a fraction above 3.0 percent, Handelsblatt said.</p>
<p>Germany was bound by parliamentary decisions to interpret the convergence critieria strictly and could not use all the leeway provided by the Treaty, Stark said.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot and don't want to use the full scope for interpretation,&quot; Stark said according to Handelsblatt.</p>
<p>The government's supplementary budget for 1997 and its 1998 budget, approved last Friday, showed that Bonn was doing all in its power to cut its deficit to three percent in 1997 and reduce it below three percent in 1998.</p>
<p>Stark also ruled out the formation of an &quot;economic government&quot; during EMU as a counterweight to the European Central Bank (ECB) and said Germany would never endanger the independence of the ECB.</p>
<p>France has called for a political counterbalance to the ECB but has recently toned down its demands for an economic government, calling instead for an &quot;economic pillar&quot; as a basis for policy coordination in EMU.</p>
<p>Stark said EU cooperation on economic and fiscal policies was a matter for the Ecofin council of finance ministers, whose powers had been strengthened by the Maastricht Treaty.</p>
<p>Since not all 15 EU states would join EMU from the start, an &quot;informal club&quot; of euro zone members would emerge to discuss coordination, but this club could not be a formal arena for decision-making, Stark said.</p>
<p>&quot;Under no circumstances do we want the independence of the European Central Bank to be undermined or attacked in any way through a strengthened Ecofin council or through the new informal club,&quot; Stark said.</p>
<p>&quot;The German government will not accept this.&quot;</p>
<p>Separately, Waigel said on Saturday that the euro must be as stable as the mark or it will be of no interest to Germany.</p>
<p>Speaking at a local party meeting of his Christian Social Union (CSU), the Bavarian ally of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats, Waigel criticised the debate in Germany about a delay to EMU.</p>
<p>Bavarian premier Edmund Stoiber, a leading CSU member, has insisted on the strictest possible interpretation of the criteria and said a controlled delay of the project would be preferable to a soft currency.</p>
<p>He has argued that nations must not be allowed any leeway to let their deficits exceed three percent of GDP.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
