<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724888" id="root" date="1997-07-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algerian rebel son leads killing of family - papers.</title>
<headline>Algerian rebel son leads killing of family - papers.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The son of an anti-Islamist militant led a Moslem rebel group to attack his own family and kill 14 relatives, including his father and mother, near the Algerian capital, Algerian newspapers said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Between 15 and 20 suspected rebels slaughtered the 14 family members in Balili village at Bou Smail area, 40 km (25 miles) southwest of Algiers, said El Watan and Liberte newspapers.</p>
<p>They said the attack was led by one of the sons of the family and that the rebels killed the man's parents, brothers and sisters. Three children -- two boys aged three and 13 and a girl aged five -- were among those killed.</p>
<p>The father was a member of a pro-government force known as The Patriots grouping anti-Islamist armed civilians, the newspapers said. The raid took place late on Friday night.</p>
<p>Early the next day, rebels hit a passenger bus linking Algiers and Afir village, 90 km (60 miles) northeast of the Algerian capital, with a homemade mortar, killing seven people and wounding 11, said Liberte newspaper.</p>
<p>Seven among those wounded were in serious condition, the newspaper said, adding that the rebels were from a group holed up in Mizrana forest.</p>
<p>The killings were the latest attacks blamed on Moslem guerrillas in which Algerian media has reported more than 300 civilian deaths since Algeria's general election on June 5. Last week, a member of parliament told a meeting of the House that 1,000 people had been killed in that period.</p>
<p>About 60,000 people have died in Algeria's violence since early 1992 when the authorities cancelled the country's first multi-party parliamentary poll in which radical Islamists took a huge lead.</p>
<p>Security forces killed two guerrillas in a clash lasting several hours near Takhoukht village in Tizi-Ouzou province, 90 km (60 miles) east of Algiers, Liberte said.</p>
<p>The newspaper named gang leader Hacen Farid as one of those killed in the clash which erupted on Friday and ended early on Saturday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
