<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724816" id="root" date="1997-07-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Americans vote Australia number one holiday place.</title>
<headline>Americans vote Australia number one holiday place.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>If Americans could spend a vacation in any other country in the world and cost was not an issue, their clear favorite would be Australia, according to a poll released on Sunday.</p>
<p>Britain was their second choice and France their third in the survey conducted by Louis Harris and Associates, Inc.</p>
<p>But Australia came in number one on the list of preferred travel destinations among almost all demographic groups -- men, women, most age groups and regions.</p>
<p>Britain and Italy were the first and second choices among people 65 and over, while African-Americans' first preference was France.</p>
<p>Next in order of overall popularity after Australia, Britain and France came Germany, Italy, Canada, Ireland, Mexico, Switzerland and Israel.</p>
<p>The pollsters attributed the popularity of Australia as a travel destination to the marketing efforts of its tourist authorities as well as the appeal of the outback, the Great Barrier Reef, Australian movies and the friendly, outgoing, English-speaking people.</p>
<p>The survey was conducted by telephone within the United States between June 11-17 among a nationwide cross section of 1,026 adults and has a margin of error of plus or minus three percentage points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
