<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724978" id="root" date="1997-07-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: TENNIS-DUTCH DOUBLES PAIR SECURES FED CUP WIN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-DUTCH DOUBLES PAIR SECURES FED CUP WIN.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-07-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch doubles pair Miriam Oremans and Manon Bollegraf beat Jana Novotna and Eva Martincova of the Czech Republic to secure their country's place in the final of the Fed Cup on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Dutch pair won 6-4 7-6 in failing light after a nail-biting semi-final on the clay of Prague's Stvanice Stadium. </p>
<p>Oremans, who had already beaten Adriana Gresi in a dramatic three-set match to keep the Dutch level at 2-2, led her team's jubilant organge-clad supporters in a dance around the court after their victory.</p>
<p>World number two Novotna had earlier beaten Brenda Schultz-McCarthy, ranked 14, in straight sets.</p>
<p>The Dutch will face France, who beat Belgium 3-2 in Nice, in the final.</p>
<p>The Czechs had appeared to be on their way to victory when Gresi saved three match points at 4-5 in the third set. However, clearly in distress with severe cramp, she went on to squander her own match points and lost the third set 9-7.</p>
<p>Gresi replaced Sandra Kleinova, who played singles on Saturday but was forced to withdraw through illness.</p>
<p>Gresi had to leave the court for several minutes while Czech coach Hana Mandlikova and other team staff massaged her aching legs.</p>
<p>Novotna has been nursing a pulled stomach muscle since last month's Wimbledon final when she lost to Martina Hingis but said she was pleased with her performance against Schultz-McCarthy.</p>
<p>&quot;It was difficult but we both played great tennis,&quot; she said. She said she had become much more aggressive after the first set tie break.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
