<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724907" id="root" date="1997-07-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Commodities-India's castor oil take a spicy route.</title>
<headline>Commodities-India's castor oil take a spicy route.</headline>
<byline>Dev Varam</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-07-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>After pepper, it's castor oil.</p>
<p>Last week, India moved a step closer towards globalising its commodities trade by opening castor oil futures to foreign players, traders and analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>They said the government decision to permit global castor oil futures and the resumption of domestic futures in cotton and jute would help put India on the world commodities map.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very good move and will benefit India,&quot; said Dilip Thakkar, a director of the Bombay Oils and Oilseeds Exchange Ltd, which currently conducts the domestic castorseed futures.</p>
<p>Thakkar said the globalisation of futures trade in castor oil was in line with the economic reforms that India started in the early nineties.</p>
<p>The latest development comes at a time when hectic efforts are being made to launch a global pepper exchange in August.</p>
<p>&quot;The pepper people have made our task easy as procedures for setting up a clearing house of our own are the same,&quot; said Thakkar. &quot;We have the necessary infrastructure.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the governing body of the exchange would meet on Wednesday to discuss the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to complete all formalities within three months,&quot; Thakkar said, adding that global futures trading would begin from Diwali, the Hindu festival of lights in November.</p>
<p>Thakkar said once India set up the global exchange, other major players in the castor oil industry and trade such as Brazil and China could come and trade on it.</p>
<p>India is the world's largest producer of castorseed followed by Brazil and China. India's castorseed production in 1996/97 (November/October) has been estimated at 650,000 tonnes, down from 950,000 tonnes in the previous year.</p>
<p>Traders said the sharp fall in production in the current year was due to a drop in the area under castorseed cultivation as farmers switched to more remunerative crops like cotton and groundnut.</p>
<p>India's castor oil production in 1996/97 has been estimated at 260,000 tonnes, of which 90,000 tonnes is meant for domestic consumption and the remainder for export.</p>
<p>While traders in general welcomed the move to set up a global exchange for castor oil, some expressed fears about possible price manipulation by big foreign players.</p>
<p>&quot;Multinationals and other big foreign players can depress prices to buy castor oil at cheaper rates,&quot; said Jaggubhai Tanna, chairman of Jamnadas Madhavji International Ltd, a leading firm exporting castor oil.</p>
<p>&quot;In a depressed price situation, farmers will be the losers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tanna said the existing infrastructure was unable to cope with even the domestic futures trade in castorseed.</p>
<p>&quot;First we must set our own house in order,&quot; he said, adding that amendment of by-laws would be a drawn-out process.</p>
<p>Traders said most of the teething troubles could be overcome by following the pepper path.</p>
<p>In February this year, India announced the setting up of the country's first international exchange and clearing house for pepper in the southern city of Kochi.</p>
<p>The global exchange, run by the Indian Pepper and Spices Trade Association (IPSTA), is expected to start from August.</p>
<p>Traders said the decision to allow futures trading initially for three years and extend it after a review would deter market players from investing in infrastructure on a long-term basis.</p>
<p>They said resumption of cotton futures, suspended 30 years ago, would benefit farmers, brokers and yarn and textile mills, but it should be a permanent system.</p>
<p>Forward trading in cotton was banned in the 1960s in a bid to curb speculation and to stabilise prices.</p>
<p>Traders said they expect futures trading to take off by December or early next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
