<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="724913" id="root" date="1997-07-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian shares seen rebounding after correction.</title>
<headline>Indian shares seen rebounding after correction.</headline>
<byline>Ranjit Gangadharan</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-07-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Buoyant foreign fund inflows are expected to help volatile Indian shares rebound this week after a technical correction, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The present correction could continue further to 4,250 levels by Tuesday, before the market stages a strong recovery,&quot; said the brokerage Khandwala Securities Ltd.</p>
<p>The benchmark Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) index closed last week in negative territory for the first time since the week ended May 23. The 30-share BSE index closed 1.84 points lower at 4,321.98 after soaring to a 33-month high of 4,448.06.</p>
<p>Analysts said they saw no slow down in foreign portfolio funds pumping cash into Indian equities, which have been among the best performing emerging markets in 1997.</p>
<p>They expect foreign inflows of at least $310 million in July. Net foreign institutional investments were $57 million from July 1-9 -- against $362.9 million in June.</p>
<p>A booming Wall Street and falling gold prices attracted more money into shares, equity strategist Arun Kejriwal said.</p>
<p>&quot;Falling gold prices and the fear of holding on to gold is generating invisable funds,&quot; he said. &quot;Some of the windfall gains from U.S. markets are also coming to emerging markets.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the stock to look at this week was State Bank of India, which would come out of a three-week, no-delivery period when the company's books are closed for dividend payments.</p>
<p>Indications of a pick-up in economic activity was another crucial factor driving Indian shares higher, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Real non-food credit growth has picked up since April,&quot; NatWest Markets said in a report. &quot;After persistently falling for about 10 months, real credit has bottomed out...&quot;</p>
<p>It said the growth in non-food credit normally leads growth in manufacturing by about two months.</p>
<p>In the next few weeks, analysts expect the benchmark Bombay index to beat its peak of 4,643.31 set on September 12, 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;That's very possible,&quot; said R. Balakrishnan, president of brokerage Dil Vikas Finance Ltd. &quot;But I refuse to believe this is backed by fundamentally sound factors.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the upsurge was largely due to demand-supply mismatches caused by strong demand in some 100 odd stocks and the lack of sellers.</p>
<p>&quot;The market lacks depth,&quot; he said. &quot;You pump in $300-$400 million and this market booms.&quot;</p>
<p>Indian stock markets have risen about 60 percent since hitting a three-year low in December 1996. Net foreign portfolio inflows during this period have totalled $1.2 billion, figures released by the market regulator show.</p>
<p>Bharat Heavy Electricals Ltd, Glaxo, ITC and Reliance were some of the stocks that have more than doubled during this period, Balakrishnan said.</p>
<p>Shares of multinational firms preferred by foreign funds because of consistent returns and better quality of management have become expensive, with many trading at price-to-earnings multiples of 45 to 50, traders said.</p>
<p>Strategist Kejriwal said he was doubtful if this rally could be sustained.</p>
<p>&quot;First-half company results could be a bombshell,&quot; he said. &quot;We might see a correction phase ahead in October.&quot;</p>
<p>For the half year ending September 30, 1997, companies are expected to show flat growth though big cap firms would benefit from lower interest costs, analysts said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
