<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725082" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-ROCCA RECALLS HOW CLOSE HE CAME.</title>
<headline>GOLF-ROCCA RECALLS HOW CLOSE HE CAME.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>TROON, Scotland 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Costantino Rocca loves to recall the greatest moment in his career, the one that gave him a sniff of glory in 1995.</p>
<p>No-one who saw it will ever forget the burly Italian stretched out, face down, arms pounding the sacred turf in front of the 18th green at St Andrews.</p>
<p>Rocca had just holed a 50-foot putt down through the Valley of Sin that fronts the green, up the hill and straight into the hole to force a playoff for the British Open title.</p>
<p>His reaction established Rocca as an object of worldwide affection, almost as if the fluffed chip just moments before the putt had never happened.</p>
<p>Nor did the fact that he then lost the four-hole playoff to American John Daly diminish him in the eyes of all who saw his putt and his reaction to it.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the greatest moment in my career,&quot; he repeated at Loch Lomond last week.</p>
<p>His conqueror that day, Daly, withdrew last week from the Royal Troon Open starting on Thursday because of his continuing fight against alcohol addiction.</p>
<p>&quot;If he retired in '95, I win the Open,&quot; Rocca joked, quickly adding his sympathy for the plight of the American.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel sorry for him. He is a good friend and a nice guy. It is a life problem, but he will come back again,&quot; Rocca said.</p>
<p>This week Rocca, a former plastics factory worker, hopes to go one better than he did two years ago.</p>
<p>He feels he may be ready following a troublesome shoulder injury sustained at the European TPC event in Hamburg late in May.</p>
<p>He missed the cut there and again the following week, then pulled out of the U.S. Open before completing his next three tournaments.</p>
<p>He said he hurt his shoulder hitting out of high rough in Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;For the last five weeks I have not been able to hit the ball the way I want,&quot; he said at Loch Lomond.</p>
<p>&quot;Last week I couldn't turn backwards. This week I cannot turn forwards. Maybe next week.</p>
<p>&quot;But it is much better,&quot; he said after his third round of 65 on Friday -- and before his closing 75. &quot;I am feeling much better and have more confidence now.&quot;</p>
<p>Since that memorable day two years ago, Rocca has tasted the pleasure of winning three points as Europe regained the Ryder Cup at Oak Hill later in 1995 and winning the European Tour's flagship event, the British PGA, last year.</p>
<p>&quot;1995 was a fantastic year for me. I was swinging so good and playing so good,&quot; he said. &quot;I have more experience than I did in 1995. Maybe my game has improved.&quot;</p>
<p>For all his success, Rocca is still relatively unknown in his soccer-mad motherland.</p>
<p>&quot;They know my name but not my face. I am better known in Britain, America, Germany -- everywhere. In Italy it is all soccer,&quot; the man from Bergamo said. &quot;The reaction in 1995 was good because it was the first time the Open was shown. People watched it in bars and what I did gave it life.</p>
<p>&quot;It was good for one year, then it became the same as before.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't remember the last time I was asked for my autograph.</p>
<p>&quot;If I win the Open maybe I will get asked for it -- at least in Bergamo.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROON, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
