<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725198" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: FLOODS OVERSHADOW START OF POLISH-GERMAN SUMMIT.</title>
<headline>FLOODS OVERSHADOW START OF POLISH-GERMAN SUMMIT.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's president and prime minister left for Germany on Monday for a summit designed to launch a new phase in bilateral contacts but which was set to be partly concerned with Poland's current flood disaster.</p>
<p>The talks aim to initiate regular meetings of leaders of the neighbours which are drawing closer after European Union and NATO moves to clear the way for talks on Polish entry.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sides decided...to give expression to a new phase in Polish-German relations which will begin on the one hand out of the EU Amsterdam summit and on the other from the Madrid summit of NATO,&quot; Poland's ambassador to Germany Andrzej Byrt said.</p>
<p>He told Polish radio that President Aleksander Kwasniewski, Premier Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz, Foreign Minister Dariusz Rosati, Economy Minister Wieslaw Kaczmarek and possibly others would go for the one-day talks with their German counterparts.</p>
<p>The trip was long-planned but has been overshadowed by floods that swamped thousands of square kilometres of southern Poland including dozens of towns and cities during the past week, killing at least 35 people.</p>
<p>Poland is desperately trying to raise funds for reconstruction and is also appealing for fast relief aid, notably including water pumps which are in short supply.</p>
<p>Byrt paid tribute to Germany's government, states and individuals who have quickly offered financial and other aid, comparing it to the help extended to Poles after Warsaw's then-communist authorities declared martial law in 1981.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the action developing in the Federal Republic now recalls the dramatic action of help to Poles during martial law,&quot; Byrt said.</p>
<p>Since the 1989 fall of communism in Poland and German unification official ties between the former World War Two foes have grown close, reinforced by regional cross-border links.</p>
<p>Germany, eager to entrench political and economic stability east of its borders, has been a champion of Poland's drive to bind itself securely to Western European structures.</p>
<p>Analysts say the regular summits are modelled on similar German-French contacts -- the three countries are linked in an informal understanding called the Weimar Triangle.</p>
<p>Byrt said they would be an effective way to develop rules for the countries' mutual dealings and allow ministers to settle complex issues effectively.</p>
<p>&quot;These are meetings on the basis of which there will be very concrete propositions for cooperation,&quot; said Byrt.</p>
<p>On Monday the two countries were due to clinch an agreement on culture. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
