<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725252" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK natgas up in winter, Aug/Sep busy on tender result.</title>
<headline>UK natgas up in winter, Aug/Sep busy on tender result.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK spot natural gas prices ticked up on Monday with a large volume of trade done in the coming winter as well as some trades done in August and September, traders and brokers said.</p>
<p>Transco on Monday announced the results of its storage margins tender. Gas was awarded to 17 companies at an average price of 9.45 pence a therm for delivery in August and September.</p>
<p>Transco announced the lowest price, 8.95 pence a therm, but not the highest, and did not give any information about what volumes were awarded at different prices.</p>
<p>But the industry appeared broadly satisfied with the results of the tender. &quot;It's been interesting, steady, nobody's got any cheap gas,&quot; said a trader. &quot;It's been a reasonably mature and civilised tender. It wasn't all the doom and gloom that some people were talking about.&quot;</p>
<p>Another said prices may move as a result of the tender. &quot;Maybe now people have seen the tender's out of the way, we might see the market readjust. All this uncertainty that's been hanging over the market has now been resolved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>And a broker said that the reason for the trade in August and September on the spot market and possibly also on the futures market was that there was buying interest from some players who &quot;didn't get the volumes they wanted&quot; through the tender.</p>
<p>Otherwise, a broker said the fact that the winter traded with significant volume was &quot;the most exciting thing&quot; that happened on Monday. Nearly half the trades recorded were for gas in either Q4 or the Q4/Q1 strip, with other trades seen in October and the October gas year, both of which include parts of next winter.</p>
<p>The price rises in this period were not attributed to any changes in fundamentals. &quot;The winter's reasonably strong, it's picked up a little but that's because there's been a lot of trading around,&quot; said a trader. A seller at St Fergus added that the rises showed &quot;indications of renewed firmness in the winter.&quot;</p>
<p>The IPE saw 450 lots traded, the highest total for several weeks, with 250 lots of that concentrated in August and September, corresponding to the period of the storage tender gas becoming available. The balance, 200 lots, was traded in January and February, when the OTC market was at its busiest.</p>
<p>--Sebastian Alison, London Newsroom, +44 171 542 6412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
