<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725218" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bond market wrapup - late European trade.</title>
<headline>Bond market wrapup - late European trade.</headline>
<text>
<p>This is how major world bond markets looked at 1630 GMT on Monday.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - U.S. Treasury prices opened lower on profit-taking, analysts said. &quot;There's some more profit-taking following the profit-taking we saw late Friday,&quot; said Kim Rupert, senior economist at Standard &amp; Poor's MMS. &quot;It's nothing significant. The flows were very light.&quot;</p>
<p>Futures: September T-bonds at 114-2/32, down 2/32</p>
<p>	    September Eurodollars at 94.23, unchanged</p>
<p> Cash:    Long bond yield 6.54 percent.</p>
<p>GERMANY - Bunds ended afternoon trade weaker after the</p>
<p>relentless rise of the dollar against the mark put pressure on</p>
<p>the German debt market.</p>
<p>Futures: September Bunds on LIFFE at 102.58, down 0.41</p>
<p>	    September Euromarks at 96.77, down 0.07</p>
<p> Cash:    10-year Bund yield 5.58 percent.</p>
<p>BRITAIN - UK gilts ended 21/32 lower, surrendering all of Friday's gains, after gilts followed the Bund's lead lower and underperformed along the way, dealers said. Gilts on Friday closed some 20/32 higher at 114-27 after the Bank of England announced it would not be auctioning any new 10-year gilts in the third quarter.</p>
<p>Futures: September Long gilts on LIFFE at 114.15, down 0.68</p>
<p>	    September Eurosterling at 92.84, down 0.02</p>
<p> Cash:    10-year gilt yield 7.08 percent.</p>
<p>FRANCE - The French bond market was closed for the Bastille Day holiday. The market will reopen on Tuesday.</p>
<p>ITALY - Bonds and BTP futures slipped back to hold in negative territory in late afternoon trading reflecting profit taking after recent strong gains and the lower tone to other bond markets, dealers said.</p>
<p>Futures: September Long bond on LIFFE at 136.14, down 0.64</p>
<p>	    September Eurolira at 93.33, down 0.05</p>
<p> Cash:    10-year bond (BTP) yield 6.45 percent.</p>
<p>JAPAN - The key September 10-year Japanese government bond (JGB) futures contract ended a slow day firmer but off earlier highs, traders said. Noting that strong technical resistance had developed near 125.20, a trader with a bank's securities arm said that without any fresh factors, buying aggressive enough to lift the key contract over 125 was unlikely at this point. Futures: September JGB future on LIFFE compared with Tokyo close at 124.9, unchanged</p>
<p>	    September Euroyen at 99.31.</p>
<p> Cash:    10-year JGB yield 2.51 percent.</p>
<p>EUROBONDS - New issue business was light, with a holiday in France acting as a dampener after the weekend. Primary market activity was focused on Latam sovereigns, with Brazil setting a 150 million stg deal, while Argentina announced plans for a $750 million seven-year global offering. The 10-year Brazil bond was reoffered at a spread of 275 b.p. over gilts, in line with an outstanding Argentinian bond. Among other deals, a GMAC unit asked for 250 million marks until December 2003 and Eskom emerged with a six billion rand 30-year zero coupon deal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
