<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725296" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BT top execs to head for U.S. to eyeball MCI.</title>
<headline>BT top execs to head for U.S. to eyeball MCI.</headline>
<byline>Kirstin Ridley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Telecommunications said on Monday it was sending senior executives across the Atlantic for face-to-face talks with its prospective merger partner MCI, after the American telephone operator's surprise profit warning last week.</p>
<p>While BT tries to unravel the extent to which earnings might be damaged by MCI Communications Corp's gloomy forecast -- which stunned the market and sent BT's shares plunging on Friday -- institutional shareholders shake their heads in wonder.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a godawful mess,&quot; noted one leading institution which declined to be identified.</p>
<p>The $24 billion BT-MCI merger to create one of the world's biggest, global telecoms alliances called Concert Plc had been trumpeted as the largest and most cunningly strategic trans-Atlantic merger in history.</p>
<p>But the deal promptly ended its eight-month honeymoon last week after MCI, America's second biggest long-distance carrier, said it was finding it harder, more expensive and more time-consuming to enter U.S. local telephone markets. It was also looking at hefty losses.</p>
<p>Some analysts said MCI's comments were partly a political move designed to put pressure on U.S. telecom regulators to open up local markets more quickly.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, BT and MCI's chairman Bert Roberts, who will attend BT's annual general meeting in the Scottish capital of Edinburgh on Wednesday, are likely to face sustained grilling from shareholders.</p>
<p>BT, which says it was only told about the extent of MCI's likely losses last Wednesday, says gaining access to the U.S. market remains a vital part of its global strategy. But it will launch an investigation and send more executives to America after Wednesday's meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be face-to-face meetings,&quot; a BT company spokeswoman said. &quot;We need information and we need the line straight. That will happen, but I've got no names.&quot;</p>
<p>Blaming the stalling tactics of local monopoly telecom operators in America and a lack of regulatory control, MCI said it expected an additional $500 million losses this year relative to expectations and an extra $700 million-$1.0 billion in the year to December 1998.</p>
<p>As observers started dubbing the new Concert company &quot;Discord&quot; and joked about crossed telephone lines, experts predicted BT would be hunting for MCI management scalps to blame for keeping it in the dark for so long.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, BT investors are waiting to hear how much shareholder value has been wiped out and whether the terms of the merger will be renegotiated to take into account the drop in MCI's value.</p>
<p>&quot;In such circumstances you would expect the board of any company to first see how material such information was and if they felt such benefit as they had originally identified from the deal was sufficiently diminished by the news -- presumably they would see if they could change the terms,&quot; noted another institution.</p>
<p>BT's chief executive Sir Peter Bonfield and finance director Robert Brace, who over the last few months have never tired of talking of Concert's &quot;tremendous growth prospects&quot;, telephoned concerned institutions on Friday to bring them up to date.</p>
<p>The company, which has said it might re-negotiate the merger terms of 5.4 Concert shares per MCI share plus $6.0 cash, says it was surprised and disappointed at MCI's announcement.</p>
<p>One corporate banker, who declined to be named, said that MCI's profit warning called into question the quality of due diligence. But he warned against taking too short-term a perspective.</p>
<p>&quot;It was always going to take quite a long time for the benefits of MCI's local loop (market) entry strategy in the U.S. to really bear fruit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>If BT's investigation uncovers no further skeletons in MCI's cupboards, BT might be able to convince a wary market to accept an adjustment rather than a fundamental renegotiation of merger terms, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, I'm not sure this falls under the category of 'material adverse change' in the context of the deal. If it does, BT would obviously have a duty to shareholders to renegotiate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>If either BT or MCI wanted to abandon the current deal and no third party is involved, a termination fee of $150 million has to be paid plus expenses up to a total of $15 million.</p>
<p>But BZW notes that if the merger is not complete by October 31 -- assuming no delays winning final U.S. regulatory approval -- BT or MCI can terminate the merger without penalty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
