<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725247" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products flat to firmer.</title>
<headline>Med oil products flat to firmer.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were steady to stronger on Monday, traders said.</p>
<p>Gas oil differentials were firmer with scarce offers pushing diesel prices higher, but weaker futures markets left outright prices little changed.</p>
<p>Traders said buying for Greece at around cif high quotes +$3-$4 a tonne and Spain at cif high quotes +$2-+$3 a tonne found refinery offers scarce as the narrow differential to heating oil left refiners reluctant to boost production of the more expensive to produce diesel.  </p>
<p>Prompt 0.2 sulphur cargoes were offered around cif high quotes +$3.75 to +$4 cif Med, but traders said buyers were scarce at this level with second half avails looking cheaper after trade around cif high +$2.50 cif Med last week.</p>
<p>Naphtha continued to be buoyed by Asian interest with dealers saying north African grades made the most sensible option. Levels were holding despite weaker numbers in NWE around high fob quotes +$2-3 a tonne.</p>
<p>Bulls in the gasoline market continued to hold on to Nigerian shortages as a lifeline and prices were steady to narrowly firmer in thin talk.  </p>
<p>High sulphur fuel oil cargoes were talked steady to stronger, with two buyers, a refiner and a trader, heard looking for cargoes, and the latter said willing to pay $81 fob for a cargo.</p>
<p>&quot;Unlike the north (of Europe) the Med is definitely tight,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>However some traders said that the market was steady around the $88 mark for cif cargoes, adding that the bid at the higher fob number did not reflect the market and was done for pricing purposes.</p>
<p>&quot;They're pricing a cargo out of Mersin sold into Greece and they want to see the quotes higher,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>There was talk of a Mediterranean buyer picking up a low sulphur fuel oil cargo in northern Europe but price details were not immediately available.</p>
<p>Traders however said that judging from swaps at $92.50/$93.50 for July it could be around the $93.50 mark -- or the asking price of one a seller offering actively in the north late last week.</p>
<p>Some traders however said that low sulphur was a little weaker, arguing that a weaker IPE Brent later in the day brought the whole complex down.</p>
<p>--London newsroom, +44 171 542 8145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
