<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725321" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sterling seen falling as C/A gap to grow - poll.</title>
<headline>Sterling seen falling as C/A gap to grow - poll.</headline>
<byline>Pratima Desai</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sterling's recent rise against the mark was forecast to reverse as investors withdraw from British assets in the face of an unsustainable current account deficit, a Reuters survey said on Monday.</p>
<p>In the survey of economists, banks and research houses, carried out between July 7 and 9, the median of 21 forecasts sees sterling at 2.8300 marks by end-1997 from current six-year highs around 3.00 marks.</p>
<p>The picture of a weaker British pound continues until mid-1999 when the median of 13 forecasts shows sterling at 2.6000 marks. The range of mid-99 forecasts was 2.4000 marks to 2.8000 marks.</p>
<p>Britain's current account deficit is expected to mount steadily over two years, culminating in a shortfall of 2.7 billion sterling ($4.6 billion) in 1997 and nine billion in 1998, the median of 25 forecasts shows.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of domestic demand is sucking in imports...Exports are also taking a knock,&quot; said an analyst at Sakura Finance.</p>
<p>&quot;We have yet to see the full effect of sterling strength on the current account. Once this is seen, sterling will fall against the mark.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said international investors would need a very high premium to hold sterling assets once the current account deficit started accelerating as doubts about the stability of the economy grew.</p>
<p>&quot;In the late 1980s we had the same situation. Then the government raised rates to attract funds into the economy, which financed (the current account) deficit. This time sterling will bear the brunt,&quot; said Nick Stamenkovic, economist at DKB International.</p>
<p>Britain's National Institute of Economic and Social Research forecast the lowest current account deficit in 1998, of just 2.6 billion sterling. The highest forecast was from Stephen Lewis, chief economist at London Bond Broking, at 16.4 billion sterling.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a combination of the uncompetitive levels of sterling and the J-curve effect, as a fall in sterling boosts import prices,&quot; Lewis said.</p>
<p>J-curve theory describes the time lag between a deterioration in the trade balance as import costs rise, and recovery as export volumes benefit from a lower currency.</p>
<p>Forecasts for Britain's trade deficit for end-1997 ranged from 2.5 billion sterling to 16.8 billion sterling, with the median at 11.8 billion.</p>
<p>By end-1998, the trade deficit forecasts averaged 16.6 billion, with predictions ranging between 9.9 billion sterling and 33.5 billion sterling, the survey showed.</p>
<p>But sterling strength, while playing havoc with Britain's external balances, will initially keep a lid on factory gate prices.</p>
<p>The median of 17 forecasts for 1997 and 1998 saw core producer output prices up 0.7 percent in 1997 and up 1.8 percent in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Goods price inflation will be slower than service price inflation. Manufacturing prices will be held in check by competition from imports,&quot; said Lewis.</p>
<p>&quot;Next year as sterling eases, demand will ease, leaving little scope for manufacturers to recoup their profit margins.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said there would be downward pressure on core producer output prices from subdued wage inflation next year as pay deals would be based on good inflation data from this year. ($ = 0.591 British Pounds Sterling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
