<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725304" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Golden wedding couples to celebrate with UK queen.</title>
<headline>Golden wedding couples to celebrate with UK queen.</headline>
<byline>Jill Serjeant</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Buckingham Palace opens its gates on Tuesday for a unique garden party, celebrating not the achievements of the great and good but the triumph of love over adversity.</p>
<p>Four thousand couples who married in 1947 and stayed that way have been invited to join Queen Elizabeth and Prince Philip in a mass celebration of 50 years of marriage.</p>
<p>The Buckingham Palace garden party is one of the highlights of events marking the queen's 50th wedding anniversary, reflecting a gone but not quite forgotten golden era when the British royals were the nation's first family.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be a great day. It's going to be a big experience just to see the palace itself,&quot; said retired postman Joe Slann, who will be joining the queen and Prince Philip with his wife Edna.</p>
<p>&quot;People get married more than once nowadays, sometimes two or three times, so they never get to have a 50th wedding anniversary. They just have 10 years here and 10 years there,&quot; he added sadly.</p>
<p>Tickets, allotted by ballot after advertisements in newspapers around the world, were 10 times oversubscribed for the tea and strawberries event on the lush lawns of Buckingham Palace.</p>
<p>Garden parties have been held since the 1860s. The three that take place in London every summer are normally attended by about 8,000 people, many from government, the civil service and the armed forces. An individual may not apply.</p>
<p>This time married couples are travelling to London from the length and breadth of Britain as well as from former Commonwealth countries for a chance to shake hands with the queen and reminisce about the days when men and women kept their vows to love honour and obey &quot;until death do us part&quot;.</p>
<p>According to official statistics, only 10 percent of couples who married in Britain in 1947 have divorced. Of those married in the 1990s, 10 percent are expected to split up in the first five years and 41 percent by 50 years.</p>
<p>About 40 couples are travelling to London from Canada and a similar number from Australia and New Zealand. All have had to pay their own travel costs and accommodation.</p>
<p>&quot;They are absolutely excited. They are a delightful group. Some are former servicemen who moved to Canada,&quot; said a spokeswoman for the Canadian High Commission in London.</p>
<p>Only about 10 percent of the guests are likely to get a chance to speak to the queen on what is normally a formal occasion marked by hats and gloves for ladies and morning dress for gentlemen.</p>
<p>Few of the couples celebrated their wedding in the style of the then Princess Elizabeth and Prince Philip, who rode to Westminster Abbey on November 20, 1947, in a glass coach for a glittering ceremony that belied the austerity of the immediate post-war years.</p>
<p>Crowds slept all night on the streets then, just as they did for the ill-fated 1981 wedding of the queen's son Prince Charles to Princess Diana. That marriage's bitter collapse 15 years later buried with it much of the nation's respect for the monarchy.</p>
<p>The queen's remaining three children have also failed to inherit the secret of lasting relationships. Prince Andrew and Princess Anne divorced and Prince Edward, 33, has yet to marry. Anne has since remarried.</p>
<p>Incurable romantics Bill and Doreen Lewis are going to the garden party after celebrating their own golden wedding by revisiting the same church in Devon, south-west England, where they were married at the same time of day as the royal couple.</p>
<p>&quot;They are both special people in every sense of the word,&quot; said their daughter Sheila. &quot;They are the most loving parents and grandparents, giving each and every one of us more love and care than can be imagined.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
