<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725450" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Nervous Serb leaders slam tribunal, NATO raid.</title>
<headline>Nervous Serb leaders slam tribunal, NATO raid.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nationalist Serb leaders in Bosnia have sharply condemned a U.N. tribunal for sentencing the first Serb found guilty of war crimes.</p>
<p>But Western envoys vowed to press on with efforts to bring suspects to account for their deeds in wartime.</p>
<p>Dusan Tadic, convicted of murder, torture and ethnic cleansing, was jailed for 20 years by the U.N. tribunal in the Netherlands on Monday.</p>
<p>Bosnian Serb President Biljana Plavsic and Momcilo Krajisnik, the Serb member of the collective Bosnian presidency, both criticised the verdict as unjust.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a political sentence,&quot; he told reporters in the north Bosnian town of Banja Luka where he met Plavsic. &quot;We are very bitter that care was not taken to put this trial on a better political foundation.&quot;</p>
<p>The sentence was handed down only days after a NATO raid on two Serbs also wanted by the tribunal. The swoop shocked and angered the hardline nationalist leadership.</p>
<p>Russia, standing up for its Serb allies, told British Foreign Secretary Robin Cook that the NATO operation was &quot;counter-productive&quot; and that no more raids should be carried out.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't want operations of this kind to be repeated because this will not improve the situation on the ground,&quot; Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov said.</p>
<p>One suspect was arrested and another shot dead after he opened fire on British soldiers, who codenamed the raid &quot;Operation Tango&quot;.</p>
<p>During a visit to Moscow, Cook refused to pledge that the alliance-led Stabilisation Force (SFOR) in Bosnia would refrain from more arrests.</p>
<p>&quot;We have given no guarantees that it will not be repeated,&quot; Cook said.</p>
<p>He reassured Primakov that secrecy had prevented a number of allies being consulted.</p>
<p>British officials privately said that the furious Russian reaction could make NATO think twice before trying to seize former Bosnian Serb president Radovan Karadzic, who has been twice indicted by the tribunal.</p>
<p>Serb leaders, who expelled Moslems and Croats from their homes and led a brutal siege of the capital Sarajevo, fear tougher international action to hold more of them accountable for their deeds during the 1992-95 Bosnian war.</p>
<p>They are concerned that Western countries led by the United States may try to arrest Karadzic and his wartime army commander General Ratko Mladic .</p>
<p>Serb authorities have also complained bitterly over the introduction of sealed, or secret, indictments which were employed in last week's operation.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the High Representative to Bosnia, Carlos Westendorp, said sealed indictments should not make any Bosnian feel insecure.</p>
<p>&quot;It is written in the hearts of men what happened during the war,&quot; spokesman Duncan Bullivant told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Only those who know the actions they carried out should bring them into conflict with the tribunal should feel afraid, and frankly, we welcome them feeling afraid,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the hours between Tadic's court appearance and the funeral on Sunday for the war crimes suspect killed by NATO troops, an explosion rocked a Bosnian Serb hotel used by U.N. officials and international police monitors.</p>
<p>The blast in the hardline stronghold of Zvornik caused no injuries but prompted fears of a nationalist backlash against foreign personnel.</p>
<p>An SFOR senior officer, British Lieutenant-General Roddy Cordy-Simpson, met Bosnian Serb army commander General Pero Colic in Bijeljina to try to defuse tensions surrounding last week's raid.</p>
<p>SFOR said Colic pledged to ensure calm prevailed. After the talks, the Serb general described the NATO raid as an attack on the Serb nation.</p>
<p>Tadic, who had faced a maximum of life imprisonment, looked shaken when handed 11 jail terms, the longest of them 20 years. They will run concurrently, with a recommendation that he serve at least 10.</p>
<p>U.S. judge Gabrielle Kirk McDonald accused Tadic of sadistic brutality against Moslem neighbours driven from their homes during the Serb conquest of northern Bosnia in 1992.</p>
<p>Hundreds of Moslem men were beaten and tortured, some to death, in camps set up by forces under the sway of nationalist leaders like Karadzic.</p>
<p>The sentence was described as severe by defence lawyers, who argued Tadic was small fry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
