<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725443" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - July 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - July 14.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>A Polish-German summit meeting takes place in Bonn on Monday. In an interview with Rzeczpospolita German Chancellor Helmut Kohl said the process of ending the division of Europe and Germany started in Poland.</p>
<p>A PBS public opinion poll shows that two thirds of Polish families will save no money this year, though the percentage of Poles unable to save in the past two years has fallen by seven percent to 64 percent.</p>
<p>DZIENNIK PRAWA I GOSPODARKI</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Dariusz Rosati said in an interview that the good condition of the Polish economy is an extremely strong argument in negotiations on the country's entry into NATO and the European Union.</p>
<p>Unofficial sources say the supervisory board of Bank Pekao SA has approved the purchase of part of the upcoming share offer by large insurer PZU SA. Auditor Arthur Andersen is currently examining the insurer's financial condition.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>Oil-sector experts say that due to the stabile situation on world oil markets fuel prices in Poland should not increase this summer. They said competition between the large Plock and Gdansk refineries should also keep prices down.</p>
<p>ZYCIE</p>
<p>On Tuesday the government decides on the privatisation of PZU. The project written by firm president Jan Monkiewicz sees 50 to 60 percent of the insurer's shares going to investors and 25 to 30 percent remaining with the state treasury.</p>
<p>NOTE - Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
