<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725438" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKMENISTAN: Turkmens threaten controls on Caspian oilfields.</title>
<headline>Turkmens threaten controls on Caspian oilfields.</headline>
<dateline>ASHGABAT 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkmenistan threatened on Monday to take tougher measures to control areas of the Caspian Sea it claims as its territorial waters but where Azerbaijan and foreign oil firms are already preparing to pump oil ashore.</p>
<p>&quot;Recent negative developments could force Ashgabat to move towards strengthening frontier controls around all the aforementioned fields,&quot; a senior official at Turkmenistan's foreign ministry told Reuters. He gave no details of what it might do to tighten control over the oilfields.  </p>
<p>The official, who declined to be named, said Turkmenistan had made its position known to the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) last week.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Turkmenistan demanded that a $1 billion agreement between Azerbaijan's state oil company SOCAR and Russia's Rosneft and LUKoil companies to develop the Kyapaz field be anulled, arguing the field belongs to Turkmenistan.</p>
<p>Turkmenistan also claims a field named Azeri and part of the Chirag field, now under development by the a multinational consortium headed by British Petroleum Co Plc and Norway's Statoil.</p>
<p>The Caspian's legal status is the subject of intense diplomatic wrangling between the five states around its shores and oil majors who want to cash in on the reserves.</p>
<p>The dispute hinges on whether, under international law, the Caspian is a sea or a lake. On that depends how national frontiers are drawn.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AZERB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURKM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ASHGABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKMENISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
