<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725535" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia tells NATO to end swoops on war suspects.</title>
<headline>Russia tells NATO to end swoops on war suspects.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov said on Monday he wanted to see no repeat of last week's swoops by NATO peacekeepers on suspected war criminals in the former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>Primakov, whose ministry last week condemned what it called &quot;cowboy raids&quot;, told a news conference after talks with visiting British Foreign Secretary Robin Cook that Moscow believed such operations were counter-productive. He also complained Moscow was not notified about the swoops on two Bosnian Serbs.  </p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't want operations of this kind to be repeated because this will not help to improve the situation,&quot; Primakov said.</p>
<p>But Cook later told British reporters that the British government reserved the right to mount similar swoops if asked to do so by the International Criminal Tribunal on the Former Yugoslavia or by the NATO-led peace Stabilisation Force (SFOR).</p>
<p>&quot;We have given no guarantees that it will not be repeated,&quot; Cook said. But he added that no repeat of the controversial operation was being contemplated.</p>
<p>British troops in the SFOR in Bosnia shot dead Simo Drljaca, former police chief in the town of Prijedor, last Thursday after he tried to avoid arrest by firing on them. They also arrested the director of Prijedor hospital, Milan Kovacevic, wanted for complicity in genocide against Bosnian Moslems and Croats, and extradited him to The Hague to face trial.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
