<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725658" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil Eletrobras can use Light shares for payouts.</title>
<headline>Brazil Eletrobras can use Light shares for payouts.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's federal power holding Eletrobras has been authorized to pay its 1996 dividends, worth 619 million reais, with shares in privatized power firm Light Servicos de Eletricidade SA, Brazil's National Development Bank (BNDES) said in a statement.</p>
<p>A special shareholders assembly will be held in July at which Eletrobras shareholders can opt to receive their dividends either in Light shares or in cash, the BNDES said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This operation shows the intention of promoting the privatization of Eletrobras without any disadvantage to the minority shareholder,&quot; the BNDES said in the statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The payment in shares also aims to free Eletrobras from the obligation of mobilizing large amounts of money to pay the dividends so it can spend the money on its expansion and modernization investments instead,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The Light shares used in the dividend payments will have a value equivalent to the average price of Light shares in the three trading sessions preceding the shareholders assembly, minus a discount of 10 percent.</p>
<p>The shares are part of a block of shares worth 1.7 billion reais which were left over from the privatization of Light in May last year and were due to be sold off in a global offer later this year.</p>
<p>The BNDES said even if all Eletrobras shareholders opted for Light shares, there would still be more than one billion reais worth of Light shares to be sold in the global offer.</p>
<p>((--Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
