<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725687" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Time ripe for Argentine debt buy-back - analysts.</title>
<headline>Time ripe for Argentine debt buy-back - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Adam</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina is in a good position to benefit from liquid international markets with a debt buy-back, but it should take care not to satiate the appetite for Argentine bonds needed in the short term, analysts said Monday.</p>
<p>Economy Minister Roque Fernandez recently sowed great expectation in the market when he said &quot;the conditions are right&quot; for an Argentine debt buy-back.  </p>
<p>His declaration pushed share and bond prices up, which ironically removed some of the financial interest for carrying out the operation in the short term, although the Economy Ministry has already analyzed a dozen proposals for the buy-back from international banks.</p>
<p>Analysts said they favored a buy-back, as long as it extended the length of Argentina's debt portfolio and cut the country's servicing costs.</p>
<p>One of the great advantages of such an operation would be to free part of the $15 billion in U.S. Treasury bonds which guarantee par and discount Brady bonds.  </p>
<p>This benefit would not apply if the floating-rate bonds -- which have no guarantee -- were bought back.  But these bonds could well be targeted, as they come due relatively soon.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is super-liquid, and it wants a buy-back.  The fact that Brazil and Mexico have already done it adds to the pressure,&quot; said Jose Rutman, economist for consultants Broda y Asociados.</p>
<p>Brazil and Mexico staged successful buy-backs in 1997 and 1996 respectively, receiving a warm welcome from world markets.  </p>
<p>&quot;This can be done so long as the market stays extremely liquid.  But things are so liquid that only one bad piece of external news, like a strong rise in U.S. interest rates, or domestic news, could make the operation more complicated,&quot; Rutman added.</p>
<p>Analysts sounded a note of caution, stressing that the government should make sure that any buy-back does not get in the way of any other debt issues necessary for its short-term financing needs.  </p>
<p>&quot;Insofar as as they can get better interest rates and extend debt terms, carrying out a debt buy-back in the short term would be justified,&quot; said Aldo Abra, economist at Proeco.</p>
<p>&quot;The thing is that a buy-back aimed at modifying the debt profile should not complicate debt issues for short-term financing,&quot; Abram said.</p>
<p>Argentina's active presence in international debt markets is marked by its need to finance its budget deficit and pay interest on its public debt.</p>
<p>It also went to the markets to assemble a trust fund to overcome the financial crisis of 1995.</p>
<p>The government is considering the creation of another trust fund to subsidize job creation and also plans to feed the market with shares in the now state-owned National Mortgage Bank, worth about $2.5 billion.</p>
<p>The average term of Argentina's debt is about four years, with maturing debt building up from $11.14 bilion in 1997 to $11.36 billion in 1998 and $20 billion from 2001, according to data from consultants Melconian y Santangelo.</p>
<p>Argentina's $100 billion in public debt -- equivalent to 32 percent of gross domestic product -- is rated BB by Standard And Poor's and Duff And Phelps, and B1 by Moody's.</p>
<p>((--Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
