<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725669" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Close ally of Colombia's Samper gets poll boost.</title>
<headline>Close ally of Colombia's Samper gets poll boost.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian former interior minister Horacio Serpa, an ally of President Ernesto Samper, is a formidable candidate to succeed him in elections next year, according to a poll published on Monday.</p>
<p>The poll in Semana, Colombia's leading news magazine, showed Serpa in a virtual tie with former chief prosecutor Alfonso Valdivieso, a popular anti-drug and corruption fighter, if run-off elections were held this month.</p>
<p>The nationwide poll showed that none of the 10 likely or already declared candidates for the presidency would obtain the necessary 50 percent of the votes, if the first round were held next Sunday.</p>
<p>But a second round between the top two contenders, Serpa and Valdivieso, would end in a virtual photo-finish.</p>
<p>The survey, conducted by the respected Napoleon Franci y Cia polling firm, was the first to show Serpa, Samper's right-hand man until he stepped down in May, posing a serious challenge to Valdivieso.</p>
<p>Valdivieso, who spearheaded an independent probe into charges that Samper financed his 1994 campaign with drug money, also resigned in May and is running as an independent.</p>
<p>Serpa, an outspoken critic of the United States, is running as a so-called &quot;pre-candidate&quot; of the ruling Liberal Party and is expected to win the party's full backing.</p>
<p>According to the poll, Serpa would win a commanding 30 percent of the vote in the first round of the May 1998 presidential election, followed by Valdivieso with 22 percent.</p>
<p>Valdivieso would win 39 percent in the second round, which will be held if necessary on June 21, followed by Serpa with 38 percent of the vote. Given the survey's margin of error of 1.23 percent, the result would be a &quot;technical tie,&quot; Semana said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
