<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725865" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo naphtha rises for fifth successive day.</title>
<headline>Tokyo naphtha rises for fifth successive day.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo naphtha prices rose for the fifth consecutive business day on Monday, buoyed by Friday's overseas crude gains, market participants said.</p>
<p>Higher prices in Tokyo were believed to have made the arbitrage from Europe economically feasible, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;With cheaper freights and the current east-west spreads, the arbitrage window is likely to have reopened,&quot; one trader said. However, traders mostly kept to the sidelines, trying to figure out which way the market is heading after naphtha spreads suddenly turned into backwardation last week.  </p>
<p>Near-term naphtha spreads moved into backwardation for the first time in three months last Thursday following a flurry of buying of prompt cargoes by a Thai petrochemical company.</p>
<p>The possible resumption of the east-west arbitrage may push spreads back into contango, threatening the Asian markets with surplus cargoes, traders said.</p>
<p>Open-spec naphtha for second-half September was assessed at $205.50/206.50 per tonne.</p>
<p>It was sold at $205.00 on Friday by a Japanese trading house to a Japanese refiner.</p>
<p>--Tokyo Energy Desk +81-3-3432-8837</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
