<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725816" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia's AMFB plans to expand.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's AMFB plans to expand.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arab-Malaysian Finance Bhd (AMFB) said on Monday it plans to open more branches and offer new services after being accorded a Tier-1 finance house by the central Bank Negara.</p>
<p>&quot;We will want to do more of course but we will select the areas where we want to be. We cannot say exactly how many, but the more the better,&quot; AMFB chairman Azman Hashim told Reuters in a phone interview.</p>
<p>The company currently has 93 branches and is a market leader in second-hand car financing.</p>
<p>The Tier-1 status will also allow AMFB to open new branches without having to get prior approval from Bank Negara, unlike finance houses which do not have the Tier-1 status.</p>
<p>Under Malaysia's two-tier system, a finance house qualifies as a Tier-1 firm if it has shareholders' funds of at least 300 million ringgit. Funds must be doubled by end-1998, while minimum paid-up capital must reach at least 600 million by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Finance houses must also meet stringent requirements set by the central bank on capital adequacy, asset quality, management efficiency, earnings performance and liquidity performance.</p>
<p>AMFB said in a statement that Tier-1 status will allow it to provide services such as factoring, remittance service, and issuing of negotiable instruments of deposit up to five times the capital funds.</p>
<p>The status will also allow it to grant unsecured business loans up to a maximum of 500,000 ringgit and participating in venture capital financing and special funds established by the central bank.</p>
<p>For the year ended March 31, 1997, AMFB announced net profit of 251.67 million ringgit, a 39.2 percent jump over 180.69 million the previous year.</p>
<p>Azman declined to give an earnings growth forecast for the current year. &quot;We are still expecting continuous growth but I can't tell you how many percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Azman said he was confident that AMFB's &quot;bread and butter&quot; business of financing second-hand car loans remains healthy.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't think car sales are slowing. In any case, most of our business are in the second-hand car business and that's still strong,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
