<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725822" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai baht plunges, spurs intervention, stocks fall.</title>
<headline>Thai baht plunges, spurs intervention, stocks fall.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Charles</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jittery regional currencies drove Thailand's newly floated baht to a record low against the dollar on Monday, spurring central bank intervention and causing shivers in the local bourse.</p>
<p>For the first time since announcing a surprise, de facto devaluation on July 2, the Bank of Thailand intervened in the market to stem the baht's steep fall against the dollar.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Rerngchai Marakanond confirmed market talk of an intervention and said the bank had sold dollars to help stabilise the Thai currency.</p>
<p>&quot;We intervened in the market, but in a very small way,&quot; Rerngchai told reporters. &quot;This caused the tumbling baht to stabilise in the afternoon.&quot;</p>
<p>The baht fell sharply to a record low of 30.80 to the dollar in morning trade on a spillover effect of speculative attacks on other regional currencies, dealers said. It recovered ground late to trade around 29.25/29.75 bid/ask offshore and 29.90/30.00 in domestic markets.</p>
<p>Rergnchai said he thought the currency market had been jolted by regional currencies and said it should stabilise in the next day or two.</p>
<p>The central bank's deputy governor, Chaiyawat Wibulsawasdi, said the Bank of Thailand decided the baht had fallen low enough when it dived over 30 baht to the dollar.</p>
<p>When it announced a change to a managed float from its 13-year-old regime of pegging the baht to a basket of currencies, the Bank of Thailand said it would intervene as required to keep the baht at an appropriate level.</p>
<p>Chaiyawat said the currency had dropped 15 percent, in terms of the average daily interbank rate, since the float was implemented on July 2.</p>
<p>But the central bank's determination to stick to its policy of &quot;managing&quot; the float failed to convince equities punters.</p>
<p>The bourse, which lost more than four percent of its value last week, dropped 2.65 percent on Monday in thin dealings as investors unloaded large capitalised stocks on fears the baht would lose more ground, brokers and analysts said.</p>
<p>The Stock Exchange of Thailand's key index ended down 16.64 at 611.91 points in thin turnover of 3.4 billion baht.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors believe that the baht isn't yet stable and will slip further from today,&quot; said one broker. &quot;They think it's risky to hold baht at present.&quot;</p>
<p>Several major Thai companies face huge exchange losses this year, analysts said. At 30 baht per dollar Siam Cement Plc, the country's largest conglomerate, faces exchange losses of 9.9 billion baht on its unhedged foreign loans.</p>
<p>&quot;Every bit the baht goes down makes a lot of these companies lose more and more,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>Analysts said they needed to see more concrete signs that the Thai economy -- growing at its slowest pace in a decade -- was on the road to recovery before the stock market would pick up.</p>
<p>A finance ministry official said on Monday Thailand would not rule out seeking financial assistance from the International Monetary Fund to help solve its economic problems.</p>
<p>Analysts said any such borrowing would be accompanied by painful conditions but it was necessary for Thailand to have a credit life-line.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
