<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725929" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: O.J. Simpson's house sold to bank at auction.</title>
<headline>O.J. Simpson's house sold to bank at auction.</headline>
<byline>Dan Whitcomb</byline>
<dateline>NORWALK, Calif. 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>O.J. Simpson's luxury mansion was sold off at a bargain auction price of $2.6 million on Monday, but the families of Simpson's slain ex-wife and her friend will not see any of the money.</p>
<p>Patrick Dobiesz placed the winning bid on behalf of Hawthorne Savings and Loan, which owns the mortgage on the property. He handed over certified checks in the amount of $2,631,259 to the auctioneer after the two-minute public sale on the steps of the courthouse here.</p>
<p>Asked by reporters why the bank bought a property it already owned, he said it would sell the house for a profit.</p>
<p>&quot;I assume the value of the property was far greater than they bid for it, so it was a price the bank was willing to pay,&quot; he said, adding he had been authorised to bid higher, but declined to say what his limit had been.</p>
<p>At the public auction in suburban Norwalk, bidding began at $1,875,000. The final bid was $100,000 more than the amount owed the bank by Simpson, who had defaulted on his mortgage payments.</p>
<p>Simpson was not present at the auction, and it was not immediately known how soon he would have to vacate the house he has lived in for 20 years.</p>
<p>Local KCAL television caught up with him on a local golf course, where he said people had come up to his door recently and offered him $3 million for the house.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a pretty good deal for someone,&quot; the former football star said. &quot;I'd accepted a while ago that the house is gone. I haven't made any payments in quite a while.&quot;</p>
<p>Simpson, who earlier said he and his murdered ex-wife Nicole Brown Simpson had put their handprints in the wet concrete when it was rebuilt, added: &quot;I love the house. My kids were born there. We had some great times there and now I've got to find someplace else to have some great times. You move on.&quot;</p>
<p>He told the TV station that his children, Sydney, 11, and Justin, 8, wanted to move to the Bahamas, but Simpson himself has said he wants to stay in the Brentwood area, where the children attend schools.</p>
<p>The June 1994 killings took place at Nicole Brown Simpson's condominium, but police found a trail of blood spots at the Rockingham estate two miles (3.2 km) away and a bloody glove that matched one found at the murder scene.</p>
<p>Hawthorne Savings recently foreclosed on the house at 360 North Rockingham Ave. in the exclusive Brentwood neighbourhood when he failed to make mortgage payments for several months.</p>
<p>However, the proceeds will not go toward satisfying the $33.5 million damage award against the ex-football star for the wrongful death of his ex-wife and her friend. The bank has first claim to the money, followed by Simpson's lawyers, who are still owed a considerable amount from Simpson's trials.</p>
<p>Simpson was acquitted of murder, but a civil court jury awarded the damages to Simpson's children and the family of Ronald Goldman for the deaths of his ex-wife and Goldman.</p>
<p>Peter Gelblum, a lawyer for Goldman's father Fred, was at the auction and told reporters: &quot;I'm a little surprised how low it went for.&quot;</p>
<p>The 6,000-square-foot (560-sq.-metre) house, which Simpson bought in 1977, has five bedrooms, six bathrooms, a tennis court, a waterfall, an Olympic-sized swimming pool and a guest house once occupied by Kato Kaelin, an important witness in Simpson's criminal trial.</p>
<p>The contents of the home were not part of Monday's sale. They will be auctioned off later this year to help pay some of the damages awarded by the civil jury.</p>
<p>According to court documents, the property had been appraised at between $4 million and $6 million.</p>
<p>Simpson has continued to maintain his innocence, even after being found liable for the deaths. &quot;No. Did not do it. Don't feel I could ever hurt anybody. I think I've spent my life being a good guy,&quot; he told CNN in an interview, part of which was aired on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORWALK, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
