<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72596" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HAITI: Unpaid workers demonstrate in Haiti streets.</title>
<headline>Unpaid workers demonstrate in Haiti streets.</headline>
<dateline>PORT-AU-PRINCE, Haiti 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of municipal workers carried coffins through the streets of the capital on Tuesday in an angry demonstration at not being paid for months.</p>
<p>Garbage collectors, cemetery workers and city hall employees ran past the Ministry of Interior and Defence, banging the coffins with branches and shouting &quot;We will burn you,&quot; in reference to Haitian President Rene Preval.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day the protesters blocked the gates of the National Palace. Preval had to leave through the rear exit for a scheduled appointment.</p>
<p>Radio Metropole reported there was a dead body in one of the coffins carried by the demonstrators. One coffin was filled with garbage, which angry workers attempted to throw into government buildings.</p>
<p>&quot;We need our country clean, but school is starting and I cannot send my children to school. Now we will leave the streets dirty,&quot; said city worker Fritzer Metise, one of the demonstrators.</p>
<p>Due to a lack of funds, the Haitian government is using a cash-only economic plan in which debts must be met with incoming revenue. Haiti maintains $140 million in federal cash reserves to appear stable to foreign investors.</p>
<p>Port-au-Prince Mayor Emmanuel Charlemagne, who supports the strike, said the workers who cleaned the streets and maintained the cemetery were frustrated but had continued their work despite the lack of pay because they felt it was vital to the city's operation.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyday I have called the palace to get a response but no officials have responded,&quot; said Charlemagne. &quot;Next we will send the bodies to the palace.&quot;</p>
<p>Other frustrated civil service workers have been striking throughout the country recently. A week ago, 43 nurses at Port-au-Prince's General Hospital who had not been paid for a year held a strike and demonstrated at government buildings.</p>
<p>The workers have threatened further unrest pending layoffs expected under a civil service reform package recommended by international economists. Ninety-three percent of the Haitian government budget is spent on salaries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT-AU-PRINCE, Haiti"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HAITI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
