<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="725932" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TWA crash probers go on test flight.</title>
<headline>TWA crash probers go on test flight.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the latest effort to solve the mystery of the TWA Flight 800 disaster, investigators took a Boeing 747 on a test flight on Monday to replicate conditions on board the doomed plane, officials said.</p>
<p>The test flight from New York's John F. Kennedy International Airport was one of several flights and experiments planned for this week, the first anniversary of the crash that killed all 230 people on board.</p>
<p>Investigators know an explosion in the plane's near-empty center fuel tank caused it to disintegrate off Long Island on July 17 last year, but they have not determined why.</p>
<p>The plane broke up in mid-air without warning just minutes after taking off from New York on a journey to Paris. FBI officials say there is no evidence a criminal act such as a bomb or a missile destroyed the plane, but they are not ready to declare that a mechanical fault caused the crash.</p>
<p>During the test flight on Monday, the Evergreen cargo carrier's Boeing 747 was loaded with the same kind of fuel carried by the ill-fated TWA passenger jet. Like the TWA plane almost a year ago, the plane stood on the runway for two hours with its air-conditioning system running before taking off.</p>
<p>National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) officials said there was no predetermined length of time for the test, part of which was an attempt to replicate the conditions on board before it exploded.</p>
<p>The results of the test and experiments would be determined after scientific analysis.</p>
<p>The NTSB said the plane used for the flight was loaded with more than 150 sensors to monitor temperatures in the fuel tank as the plane reached the altitude at which the explosion occurred.</p>
<p>Investigators also will try to understand how possible movement of the tank might have affected the build-up of vapors. The test would help investigators determine how explosive the mix of fuel and air fumes were in the nearly empty center fuel tank and how much energy might have been needed to trigger the blast.</p>
<p>Officials said there were potential dangers for the nine to 11 experts who were on the test flight, but they would take precautions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
