<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72600" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAMAICA: Jamaica elections director under a cloud.</title>
<headline>Jamaica elections director under a cloud.</headline>
<dateline>KINGSTON, Jamaica 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jamaica's director of elections was put on leave on Tuesday after he traded accusations with the Electoral Advisory Committee over alleged mismanagement and financial irregularities.</p>
<p>The dispute between the director, Major Winston Sutherland, and the EAC surfaced last weekend with local press reports citing copies of letters in which Sutherland criticised the EAC.</p>
<p>Sutherland said EAC members were preoccupied with a new computer-based voter registration system at the expense of training electoral officials to perform their jobs better, and wrote that he had been &quot;pressured, disrespected and intimidated.&quot;</p>
<p>However, EAC chairman William Chin See said Sutherland had been sent on leave so the committee could investigate certain financial irregularities. The EAC said Sutherland had spent $77,000 on a training course at an up-scale resort, when the total budget for training stood at $14,285.</p>
<p>In addition, Sutherland had appointed 10 regional administrators when no such posts existed, Chin See said.</p>
<p>The problems are the latest in a series of controversies that have plagued Jamaica's attempt to clean up the electoral system, which has been tainted by evidence of ballot box stuffing and other irregularies for nearly two decades.</p>
<p>The ruling Peoples National Party's first attempt to appoint an independant EAC chairman failed three years ago, when a Jamaica Labour Party supporter and businessman, Peter Thwaites, was named. He resigned within months, saying EAC members were attempting to dictate policy.</p>
<p>Sutherland was named to oversee the reform and the controversial implementation of a computerised voter registration system.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINGSTON, Jamaica"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAMAICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
