<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726022" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: United Airlines, flight attendants reach pact.</title>
<headline>United Airlines, flight attendants reach pact.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Flight attendants at United Airlines said Monday they reached a tentative contract agreement with the nation's largest airline.</p>
<p>The union declined to provide terms of the tentative pact, but union spokeswoman Jill Gallagher said, &quot;We did meet our primary goals of getting raises, retirement and respect.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;From an economic standpoint, it maintains the United flight attendants' position in the industry,&quot; said Association of Flight Attendants International President Pat Friend.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said that United's flight attendants are among the highest paid in the industry.</p>
<p>In Chicago, United said the new contract would run through the year 2006.</p>
<p>Negotiators for the Association of Flight Attendants said the tentative agreement was reached Saturday after a 25-hour final bargaining session. The pact requires approval by the airline's 22,000 flight attendants based in 20 cities in the United States, Europe, Asia and South America.</p>
<p>The union and the airline have been in talks since March 1996.</p>
<p>The agreement with the flight attendants follows United's recent contract agreements with the pilots and machinists unions.</p>
<p>Friend declined to comment on how the flight attendants' pact compares to those reached with the machinists and pilots, but she said negotiators felt they were &quot;comparable.&quot;</p>
<p>The pilots' recent agreement calls for two wage increases of 5 percent. In the year 2000, the pact also restores wage rates to levels that existed before July 1994, when certain United employees agreed to wage reductions in exchange for a majority-ownership stake in the company.</p>
<p>The flight attendants did not take part in the 1994 employee stock ownership plan. United is owned by UAL Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
