<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726315" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Argentina's Fernandez sees no debt buyback for now.</title>
<headline>Argentina's Fernandez sees no debt buyback for now.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine Economy Minister Roque Fernandez said Monday that Argentina would consider repurchasing its Brady bonds, but conditions were not right at present.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless we are fully convinced that it is good for us, we are not considering any possbility of doing a buyback,&quot; Fernandez told reports. &quot;At the present time we don't think there are enough benefits to doing that sort of operation.&quot;  </p>
<p>Last week, Fernandez had said that conditions were right to implement such a swap, and following his statement, the emerging debt market bid the country's Brady bonds higher.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Brazil implemented a Brady debt swap, in which the government issued 30 year global bonds to replace its costly Brady paper, extend its debt profile and release the U.S. Treasury collateral supporting the issue.</p>
<p>But Fernandez, visiting the United States to meet with Wall Street investors and U.S. officials, said the ministry would not make a decsion unless it saw significant benefits.  </p>
<p>Fernandez said Argentina would consider taking out a bridge loan facility when it privatized state mortgage lender Banco Hipotecario Nacional, but that borrowing would only be to finance public works included in the 1997-1998 budgets.</p>
<p>&quot;This has to be related to public works already included in the budget at the national or provincial level,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Argentine minister also said he did not think recent currency instability in Asia would spill over to the Latin American markets, and that Brazil's burgeoning current account deficit would not negatively affect Argentina.  </p>
<p>&quot;We believe the sitaution in Brazil can be managed and is being managed by the Brazilian authorities,&quot; he said. &quot;We don't expect any fundamental modification in the policies of Brazil that will jeopordize the economy of Argentina.&quot;</p>
<p>Brazil on Monday said its current account deficit over the 12 months to June widened to 4.19 percent of gross domestic product, and the Brazilian central bank said it expected the gap to grow to about 4.5 percent of GDP by year end.</p>
<p>Fernandez reiterated forecasts that the Argentina's unemployment rate would show a decline of 1.0 percentage point to 16.3 percent when the final jobs data is released July 18, and that the jobless rate would drop another percentage point by year end.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the reduction in unemployment is from new jobs being created,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He estimated that if Argentine growth continued at the same pace, and the government won approval of new labor legislation before Congress, then the country could reduce unemployment to 5.0 to 6.0 percent by 2000.</p>
<p>(( George Lerner, Emerging Markets Desk, 212-859-1671))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
