<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726520" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Nvid says significantly downsizing through sale.</title>
<headline>Nvid says significantly downsizing through sale.</headline>
<dateline>SARASOTA, Fla. 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>NVID and Aqua Bio Technologies, in a joint statement, said they intend to sell their Huron, Ohio manufacturing subsidiary, Aquionics, to a Florida based company headed and partly owned by two former Aqua Bionics employees.</p>
<p>Terms of the sale were not made public.  NVID said in a statement that this move represents a significant downsizing of its operations in order to reduce overhead costs.</p>
<p>NVID, a residential and commercial ionization equipment maker, is currently running under a new management team and plans to move its headquarters to Clearwater, Fla.  </p>
<p>Nvid also said the company as well as past and present officers were subpeoned or have been requested to produce information in connection with an ongoing law enforcement investigation being conducted by the United States Attorney's office in Tampa, Fla.</p>
<p>The company said it believed this investigation is focused upon the misappropriation or misuse of funds belonging to the company by certain former officers.  However, the scope of the investigation and the matters that it may include cannot be determined.  Similarly, the outcome or impact this investigation may have on the company is presently unknown.  </p>
<p>NVID says the SEC has also instituted a lawsuit against the company and two of its former officers, Matthew Klenovic and Robert Bunte.  This case is presently pending in the United States District Court in the Middle District of Florida.</p>
<p>The court has issued a preliminary injunction against the company, Klenovic, Bunte and Aqua Bio technologies national technical director, Andrew Arata. The court initially froze their assets, the company said in its statement.</p>
<p>However, on June 19, the court lifted the asset freeze on the company and Andrew Arata, said Michael Redden, the president of Aqua Bio Technologies. The freeze on Klenovic and Bunte's assets remain in place.  </p>
<p>Redden told Reuters that both Klenovic or Bunte resigned their positions and are not involved in the operations of the company nor have they sought, in any way, to influence the activities of the company.</p>
<p>NVID did say both Klenovic and Bunte still own substantial shares of the company and in the absence of action by the company or by the Court could influence activities of the company at a future date.</p>
<p>Aquionics is a manufacturer of water treatment and purification systems through the use of copper and silver ionization.  Aqua Bio Technologies functions as the marketing arm for NVID.  Both Aquionics and Aqua Bio Technologies are wholly-owned subsidiaries of NVID.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARASOTA, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
