<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726685" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - July 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - July 14.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for REUTERS by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi. Tel:3326806, 3326813, 3326849 Fax:+91-11-3351006 E-mail: biznis@giasdl01.vsnl.net.in</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>The Times Of India</p>
<p>MOB RANSACKS CONGRESS PARTY LEADER'S HOME</p>
<p>A mob of about 600 people shouting pro-Shiv Sena party slogans Sunday attacked the official homes of two Congress party leaders in Bombay. Both the leaders, Chhagan Bhujbal and Madhukarrao Pichhad, were at home but escaped the attack. The police arrested 10 people including four women. The leaders said the attacks were aimed at silencing them on the police firing in Bombay Friday in which 10 people were killed. Opposition parties have called for a state-wide general strike and blockade in Maharashtra state on Monday. Sporadic violence was reported from different parts of the state for the third day on Sunday after a statue of a leader of the untouchables, B.R. Ambedkar, was desecrated by unidentified people.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>FINANCE FIRMS BARRED FROM RAISING OVERSEAS LOANS</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry barred the non-banking finance companies (NBFCs) from raising overseas loans for domestic rupee lending and leasing. A ministry official said no NBFC had been given permission in the last few months to raise such funds. The clampdown is considered bad for NBFCs who had earlier used the external commercial borrowing route to raise cheap funds. Ministry officials said the bar was temporary. In 1996 the Finance Ministry allowed a large number of NBFCs to raise external commercial borrowings as part of its financial sector reforms. About $600 million was then picked up from this window.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>JAPAN RATES INDIA AT NUMBER TWO</p>
<p>Japan has rated India second in the list of most promising countries for Japanese foreign direct investment over the next 10 years. The conclusion was drawn after a study by the Export-Import Bank of Japan towards the end of 1996. In 1984 India stood eighth in the list. Apart from the size of its domestic market, India's plus points are its local management, wage costs and the capital market, the study said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>FLEX INDUSTRIES TO RAISE $100MLN OVERSEAS DEBT</p>
<p>Flex Industries Ltd is trying to raise $100 million in foreign debt with a 10-year tenure. This is to realign the company's debt structure and replace expensive domestic debt with cheaper foreign debt. Flex now has a total debt liability of six billion rupees. This includes both domestic and overseas borrowings. The company's annual interest outgo is estimated to be around 720 million rupees to 750 million rupees. Flex Industries now has an equity base of 240 million rupees and a net worth of 3.4 billion.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>$150 MLN YANKEE BOND ISSUE PLANNED</p>
<p>The Industrial Credit and Investment Corporation (ICICI) plans to tap the Yankee bond market to raise $150 million. The offering will have a maturity of 10 years. ICICI has approached Standard and Poor's and Moody's for rating. It had earlier raised $100 million. ICICI is now raising a 10-year paper without any bullet payment. So far the ICICI was depending on multilateral agencies like the Asian Development Bank and the World Bank to raise long term loans for on-lending to the infrastructure sector.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>POWER PROJECTS WORTH 12.5 BLN RUPEES SET FOR APPROVAL</p>
<p>The Foreign Investment Promotion Board has recommended for final approval six power projects that involve foreign direct investments worth about 12.5 billion rupees. The proposals will now have to be approved by the Industry Ministry. Among the projects are one by Air Liquide of France which plans to invest 150 million rupees as equity investment for a 12 mw bagasse-based co-generation power project being set up by Delhi-based SBEC Systems. South Korea's Hyundai will invest 1.07 billion rupees in the 200 mw diesel-based Basin Bridge power project in Tamil Nadu.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>RESERVE BANK CUTS GOLD BOND RATES</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank (RBI) Saturday cut the price of gold bonds at its open market counter purchase window by about 260 rupees. The bank cut the buy offer to 3,665.60 rupees from 3,928.36 rupees. This is the sharpest ever cut by the RBI. The RBI is attempting to buy back the gold bonds it issued in 1993 as the outflow of gold will be reduced when the bonds mature in March 1998, said Dinesh Prakash, a bullion merchant. He said RBI was attempting to capitalise on a current panic in the bullion market due to the worldwide crash in gold prices and buy the bonds with cash.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>DRAFT MONEY LAUNDERING BILL READY</p>
<p>White collar crimes such as over-invoicing, under-invoicing, illegal siphoning of funds from public companies and, the misuse of advance licensing scheme for exporters will be covered by the new money laundering prevention bill. The draft of the bill will be submitted to the Finance Ministry this week. But the five-member committee which prepared the draft is still considering the exclusion of systematic income tax violations from the purview of the act. The draft money laundering prevention will be a complementary legislation to the proposed foreign exchange management act. These two acts together will replace the foreign exchange regulation act.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Line</p>
<p>SEBI TRIPS GOVERNMENT PROPOSAL</p>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) has rejected a government proposal to divest shares of state-run Videsh Sanchar Nigam Ltd (VSNL) to retail investors by reducing the market lot to 10. A task force set up by the government is now considering the dematerialisation of a part of the VSNL holding to woo retail investors. The average market price of a VSNL share is 1,000 rupees. The company felt the offer would be more attractive to retail investors if the market lot was reduced to 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
