<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726605" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: FOCUS - Portugal inflation firmly on track for EMU.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Portugal inflation firmly on track for EMU.</headline>
<byline>Sergio Goncalves</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portugal's inflation fell in June, taking the country closer to monetary union and offering the chance of another interest-rate cut sooner than many expected, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>The National Statistics Institute announced the consumer price index (CPI) fell 0.3 percent compared with May, pulling the year-on-year rise back to 1.8 percent from 2.1 percent the previous month.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good number, better than even the most optimistic forecasts,&quot; said economist Martim Amaral Neto of Banco Essi.</p>
<p>The drop in the CPI, after a surprising 0.7 rise in May, showed inflation was firmly on a downward path again and that the government target of a 12-month average of 2.5 percent by December should be easily achieved, analysts said.</p>
<p>The June decline took the rolling average -- the government's benchmark rate -- to 2.9 percent in June. Analysts say the government's target should leave Portugal comfortably within the limits for European economic and monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;The next few months may see some volatility in the year-on-year rate, but average inflation should fall to 2.7 percent in June and 2.5 percent in August,&quot; said Pedro Braz Teixeira of Banco Santander de Negocios Portugal (BSNP)</p>
<p>&quot;The average inflation rate at the end of the year should be 2.2 percent,&quot; said Nuno Godinho of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Food and beverages, accounting for nearly 45 percent of the basket of products making up the CPI, led the decline, with meat prices dropping 3.7 percent.</p>
<p>However, analysts said that just as important as the decline in the headline CPI figure was the progress being made in reducing rises in non-tradable goods -- basically wages -- which climbed just 4.1 percent year-on-year in June, the lowest such increase since 1974.</p>
<p>Some analysts said that if the non-tradable goods sector continued to perform favourably, then the Bank of Portugal might surprise the markets again with a rate cut during the summer.</p>
<p>The Bank cut 0.30 percent off its key rates on Friday in a move clearly anticipating the good inflation figures. The size of the move led many analysts to predict it would take no further action before the autumn.</p>
<p>&quot;The year-on-year rate of increase in non-tradable goods is going to decline gradually moving towards the current level of wage rises which stands at 3.6 percent,&quot; said Braz Teixeira.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that somebody is going to get a surprise (on their forecasts) for Bank of Portugal rate cuts because there is room for one and the CPI figure proves it,&quot; Godinho said.</p>
<p>Another analyst with a foreign bank said that the inflation figured showed that the Bank of Portugal ought to follow any move by Spain and, possibly, even anticipate future cuts by its neighbour.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be during the summer,&quot; said the analyst who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Short-term interest rates in Portugal remain above those of Spain even though many analysts see Portugal as even better placed to join the single currency in 1999.</p>
<p>The Bank of Portugal's repo rate stands at 5.70 percent against the Spanish central bank's 5.25 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The tendency is going to be for a convergence with Spain and the yield curve is going to steepen quite significant, I have no doubts about that,&quot; said Godinho, referring to the differential between short and longer term interest rates.</p>
<p>The difference in yields between the two year and the 10 year Portuguese bonds stands at 105 basis points, compared with a differential of 125 in Spain.</p>
<p>--Lisbon bureau 3511-3150035</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
