<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726756" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian lawmakers vote to elect president.</title>
<headline>Indian lawmakers vote to elect president.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of an electoral college began voting on Monday to choose India's tenth president in a virtual one-horse race that was expected to pick K.R. Narayanan, currently the vice-president.</p>
<p>Officials said elected lawmakers of the federal parliament and state legislatures were voting in a secret ballot across the nation through a system of proportional representation.</p>
<p>The electoral college has 4,848 members. Counting of votes and the announcement of the result are scheduled for July 17.</p>
<p>The new president, scheduled to assume office for a five-year term later this month, will take charge three weeks before the 50th anniversary of India's independence from Britain on August 15.</p>
<p>Traditionally seen as a rubber-stamp job, the post of the president, India's constitutional head, has been seen as crucial following the emergence of coalition politics in which the president plays a key role in government formation.</p>
<p>President Shankar Dayal Sharma's five-year term expires on July 25. Though eligible for a second term, Sharma did not seek re-election.</p>
<p>If elected, Narayanan would become India's first low-caste president emerging from a traditional Hindu social hierarchy.</p>
<p>Narayanan, a former diplomat who was born in a poor family, was being contested by former chief election commissioner T.N. Seshan, but his victory was considered assured after three leading political groups pledged their support to him.</p>
<p>The 76-year-old Narayanan has received backing from Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral's United Front coalition, the Congress party and the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP).</p>
<p>The main support for Seshan is from the regional Hindu Shiv Sena party.</p>
<p>During his five-year term until 1996 as chief election commissioner, Seshan targeted politicians and bureaucrats in a campaign to clean up electoral politics.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
