<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72680" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia crudes firmer, MidEast trade picks up.</title>
<headline>Asia crudes firmer, MidEast trade picks up.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices in Asia were firmer on Tuesday on an outright basis while MidEast premiums edged higher.</p>
<p>The Brent/Dubai for November was assessed at $2.01/$2.06, one cent down on the day-earlier levels.</p>
<p>Dubai intermonth paper levels were steady with November/December and December/January around 39 cents.</p>
<p>Paper Tapis continued to firm, with October assessed at $22.45 to $22.60, up about 25 cents on paper levels on Monday.</p>
<p>Brent futures found support from the London gas oil futures pit.  </p>
<p>In early London dealings on Tuesday November Brent rose 14 cents to $22.40, breaking through light resistance at $22.30 to $22.40.</p>
<p>In wet trading, November Murban deals were said done between 20 cents and 22 cents per barrel premium to ADNOC, with Lower Zakum traded between 33 and 35 cents. The buyers were all majors, traders said.</p>
<p>The premiums were higher than recent deals of 19.5 cents.</p>
<p>Two cargos of Umm Shaif were traded between 31 and 35 cents premium, both to a U.S. major.  </p>
<p>A Qatar Land cargo changed hands at the official price plus two cents between a Japanese trader and a South Korean refiner.</p>
<p>In regional grades, a 220,000-barrel cargo of Bontang Mix was sold by a major to China at ICP less 12 cents, while 270,000 barrels of the grade traded to a U.S. major at ICP less 15/20 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>An October Cossack was said traded to a Japanese buyer at APPI Tapis quotes less 20 cents.</p>
<p>--Singapore, N. Fullick (+65 870 3081), Tokyo, Miho Yoshikawa, (+813 5473 3706)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
