<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726914" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Enron Oil says Q2 net hurt by property sales.</title>
<headline>Enron Oil says Q2 net hurt by property sales.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Enron Oil &amp; Gas Co said Monday its second-quarter net income, discretionary cash flow, and net operating revenues were lower than second-quarter 1996 primarily due to lower gains and proceeds from property sales and other marketing net income.</p>
<p>Enron Oil, a U.S. oil and gas company which is majority owned by Enron Corp, reported second quarter net income of $0.16 per share, or $24.6 million, against net income of $0.30 per share, or $47.6 million in the same period a year earlier.  </p>
<p>Discretionary cash flow was $123.9 million in the quarter, down from $176.5 million in the year ago quarter.</p>
<p>Enron Oil said it is on schedule to meet its 1997 targeted volume growth.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very pleased with the results of our program in North America during the first half of this year and excited about our prospects as we enter the second half,&quot; said Enron Oil chairman and chief executive Forrest Hoglund. &quot;We are excited about our 1997 drilling success complemented with tactical acquisitions, primarily in South Texas.  </p>
<p>&quot;These increases demonstrate (Enron Oil) is on schedule to meet its 1997 targeted volume growth.&quot;</p>
<p>The company said total North America equivalent production increased over nine percent in the first half of the year compared to a year ago.</p>
<p>Total North America wellhead natural gas delivered volumes averaged 781 million cubic feet per day, up 12 percent from the second quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>North America wellhead crude oil and condensate volumes increased 24 percent to an average 13.6 thousand barrels per day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
