<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726919" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BMC West sees Q2 EPS below analysts' views.</title>
<headline>BMC West sees Q2 EPS below analysts' views.</headline>
<dateline>BOISE, Idaho 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>BMC West Corp said Monday that its second quarter results will be lower than analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>It said earnings per share are anticipated to be in the range of $0.28-$0.30 -- less than analysts' earlier consensus estimates on First Call of $0.35.</p>
<p>The building materials distributor also said that sales for the quarter ended June 30 are expected to be below BMC West's internal projections and prior year sales.  </p>
<p>&quot;Sales have been slow, particularly in the state of Texas, due primarily to the effect of unusually harsh weather conditions on construction during the quarter,&quot; said Ellis C. Goebel, the company's vice president and treasurer.</p>
<p>He said that in addition, overall building permit activity in the 10 western states in which we have operations has been down, slowing the demand for building materials.</p>
<p>The company expects to release its results for the second quarter on July 29, he said.</p>
<p>BMC West currently operates 53 building materials centers in 10 Western states -- Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, Oregon, Texas, Utah and Washington.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOISE, Idaho"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
