<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="726987" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - BAA shares aim for 750p target.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - BAA shares aim for 750p target.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>		    DAY'S RANGE * SUPPORT * RESTNCE* MA-50 * MA-200</p>
<p> BAA		   580-590  *   545   *   600  *  549  *  518</p>
<p>---------------- VIEWS FROM THE MARKET - July 14 --------------</p>
<p>+ Chart breakout from a long-term consolidation pattern by shares in BAA implies they can go up to 750p over the medium-term, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>+ Underlying volatility in the share price may produce large price swings near-term, but the price-relative chart of BAA and its 50- and 200-day moving averages indicate the overall uptrend will win through, they added.</p>
<p>Shares in airports management group BAA are on a rising trend that should see them go up to 750p medium-term, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>The share price has swung wildly after breaking above previous resistance at 545p-550p in June so that its historic 10 day volatility has shot up to 51 percent from a low of 11 percent. But this has not undermined the longer-term trend.</p>
<p>&quot;A longer look at the price and relative (charts) encourages me to believe that BAA has much more potential than the 600p target I gave (originally),&quot; said Richard Lake, technical analyst at Brewin Dolphin &amp; Co.</p>
<p>&quot;With upward breaks in both price and relative a medium-term target of 750p looks quite possible,&quot; Lake added.</p>
<p>A price-relativity chart -- of the share price divided by the All-Share index -- shows the share price has been gradually trending higher since May although a clear chart breakout has not occurred. By 0920 GMT, BAA shares were down 1-1/2p to 585p.</p>
<p>Since 1994, the shares had been shuffling sideways between 420p and 550p but started to venture higher in November 1996 and by making a series of higher lows and breaking out of a bullish ascending triangle pattern in June this year and which can be observed on a weekly chart of the share price.</p>
<p>An indication of a higher share price had been given in February when BAA's 50-day moving average had crossed above the 200 day average. Both averages are now following the share price up and despite near-term volatility that trend should take the shares higher, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Pradip Mishra, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7954</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
