<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727095" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk MPs resign from Ciller's conservatives.</title>
<headline>Turk MPs resign from Ciller's conservatives.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two MPs resigned from Tansu Ciller's True Path Party on Monday, the latest in a string of resignations which have sapped the party's parliamentary strength and helped the new secularist government into power.</p>
<p>Dogan Gures, a career army officer who served as Turkey's chief of general staff for four years before becoming an MP in 1995, submitted his resignation early on Monday morning, state-run Anatolian news agency said.</p>
<p>Later Mahmut Yilbas, deputy for the eastern province of Van, also resigned from the party.</p>
<p>Gures said in his letter of resignation, quoted by the agency, he had tried to persuade the pro-Western True Path to enter into coalition with other secularist parties and break its alliance with the Islam-based Welfare Party.</p>
<p>Turkey's new secularist government won a vote of confidence on Saturday, two weeks after the collapse of a coalition between the country's first Islamist prime minister, Necmettin Erbakan, and Ciller's party.</p>
<p>The number of True Path deputies has shrunk from 135 after the last election in 1995 to 96 on Monday as a result of a series of resignations and defections. The latest MPs to quit have not said whether they will join another party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
