<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727274" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain mourns slain Basque politician.</title>
<headline>Spain mourns slain Basque politician.</headline>
<dateline>ERMUA, Spain 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain came to a virtual standstill on Monday as the nation paid its last respects to a young politician kidnapped and brutally murdered by Basque separatist guerrillas.</p>
<p>As a funeral began in Miguel Angel Blanco's home town of Ermua, millions of people stopped work at noon to observe 10 minutes of silence. Traffic came to a halt all over the country as motorists stood solemnly outside their cars.  </p>
<p>Workers streamed out of office buildings and stood in silent groups in a salute to Blanco.</p>
<p>Thousands of people in the northern Basque town of Ermua, where Blanco was a well-liked town councillor for the ruling Popular Party, lined the streets outside the packed chapel where Spanish Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar and Crown Prince Felipe joined family members and friends for the funeral.</p>
<p>Blanco was killed after ETA rebels kidnapped him and demanded the government move about 500 ETA inmates to the Basque region before 4 p.m. on Saturday. He was found bound and bleeding with two gunshot wounds in his head shortly after the deadline on Saturday and died some 12 hours later.</p>
<p>His kidnap and killing provoked a huge outcry from ordinary Spaniards, who took to the streets in historic numbers over the weekend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ERMUA, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
