<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727210" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: ETA may answer condemnation with more violence.</title>
<headline>ETA may answer condemnation with more violence.</headline>
<byline>Marjorie Olster</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Facing unprecedented condemnation and the threat of a government crackdown, the Basque guerrilla group ETA is likely to respond the way it has in the past -- with more violence, experts say.</p>
<p>The kidnap and slaying of a young Basque town councillor produced the strongest backlash against the separatist rebels in memory, sending hundreds of thousands of ordinary citizens into the streets to vent their anger.</p>
<p>Spain's central government and the nationalist leaders of the Basque regional government vowed to deepen the isolation of ETA and its political wing Herri Batasuna.</p>
<p>&quot;This will only intensify the conflict, politically and militarily,&quot; Basque political analyst Ramon Zallo said.</p>
<p>The killing of 29-year-old Miguel Angel Blanco -- who was laid to rest on Monday in his home town of Ermua -- was a turning point in public opinion.</p>
<p>In the past, Basques whispered their disenchantment with the ETA in private. Now they are screaming it. Cries of &quot;Sons of bitches!&quot; and &quot;Murderers!&quot; rang out at mass demonstrations in recent days.</p>
<p>Basques, once intimidated by ETA, have set fire to several of its political offices, and there have been clashes between ETA supporters and opponents.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a certain fear of low-intensity but widespread civil confrontation,&quot; said Charles Powell, a political analyst at Madrid's Ortega y Gasset Institute.</p>
<p>In official circles, the latest killing was seen as a sign of ETA's weakness and desperation. A wave of bombings and killings this year had failed to wring any concessions from the centre-right government.</p>
<p>The killing was seen as a revenge attack for the success of security forces in freeing prison official Jose Antonio Ortega Lara, who was held by the rebels for a year and half. He was found nine days before Blanco was kidnapped.</p>
<p>ETA's choice of a low-level, unpaid official from the ruling party showed it was not capable of penetrating the security shield surrounding more prominent figures or of staging a high-profile attack in Madrid during last week's NATO summit, analysts said.</p>
<p>Zallo, who supported the radical camp in the 1960s, said ETA is trying to prove it still poses a military threat despite the fact it has failed to win concessions on the political front.</p>
<p>The government has not budged on one of the group's key demands -- to transfer about 500 inmates scattered around the country to prisons in the Basque country.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem of ETA is political, not military. It is losing influence in the Basque country,&quot; said Zallo.</p>
<p>ETA, which stands for Basque Homeland and Freedom, launched a violent campaign for an independent homeland 29 years ago under dictator Francisco Franco, who repressed any expression of Basque nationalism.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar threatened on Monday to toughen the government stance. But too harsh a crackdown could backfire.</p>
<p>The government must avoid any repressive measures that would give the Basque public reason to sympathise with ETA's claim that they are authoritarian, Powell said. Such measures could also incite the rebels to escalate violence. &quot;We may be pushing (ETA) into a corner,&quot; Powell said.</p>
<p>However, some observers said ETA may choose to lie low for a while until the public furore subsides.</p>
<p>The Basque nationalists, who control the regional government and give the central government a majority in parliament, have long wavered between rejecting Herri Batasuna and trying to bring it into the democratic fold.</p>
<p>Zallo said the decision of Basque leaders on Sunday to cease all cooperation with Herri Batasuna removes an avenue of peaceful dialogue. The government in Madrid refuses to talk to ETA unless it first renounces violence.</p>
<p>Though Basque nationalists share ETA's goal of an independent state, they reject violence. ETA's support has waned since the Franco years and Herri Batasuna now has about 12 percent of popular support in the Basque region.</p>
<p>Herri Batasuna, backed by youth groups and a pro-ETA trade union, is very well organised and able to mount a mass demonstration or a general strike with substantial support.</p>
<p>Officials estimate the hard core of ETA, those who actually participate in bombings or kidnappings, is only 50 to 100 people organised into six to eight commando cells. It enjoys the support of a much wider network of collaborators and financiers both in Spain and in southern France.</p>
<p>ETA is financed primarily by the collection of a &quot;revolutionary tax&quot; from Basque businessmen under threat of reprisal. It also demands ransoms in some kidnapping cases.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
