<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727450" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Inovax buys drug maker Ponco for A$95 mln.</title>
<headline>Inovax buys drug maker Ponco for A$95 mln.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Inovax Ltd said on Monday that it had acquired the Indonesian holding company Circa International Ltd and its drug manufacturing unit PT Ponco Indonesia for A$94.6 million and the assumption of liabilities.  </p>
<p>Inovax said the liabilities amounted to about A$20 million.</p>
<p>The company said that in a related move it had received a letter of intent from Bakrie Securities, which was acting on behalf of the privately-owned Bakrie Group and other independent investors, to invest a total of about A$60.8 million of new equity in Inovax. It did not specify a time frame.</p>
<p>It said the investment by Bakrie would be priced at about the Inovax share price on June 28, when the commitment was received. Bakrie controls Bakrie and Brothers.  </p>
<p>Inovax had a market capitalisation of A$36.78 million based on its trading price of A$1.10 on Monday afternoon, which was up 10 cents from Friday's close.</p>
<p>Ponco, which has a manufacturing facility in West Java, was expected to have sales of about A$38 million this year, Inovax said.</p>
<p>It said Ponco was ranked among the top ten domestic Indonesian ethical drug manufacturers and was expanding its manufacturing capability with a new cephalosporin (anti-infective) facility and a new sterile facility for injectable and ophthalmic products.  </p>
<p>These were scheduled for completion in 1998, and should add significantly to Ponco's revenues, Inovax said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
