<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727499" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dlr confined in tight range vs yen by late Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Dlr confined in tight range vs yen by late Tokyo.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>0612 GMT	    TRADED HIGH/LOW AS OF 0600 GMT</p>
<p> USD/JPY     113.65/75		114.13-113.63</p>
<p> USD/DEM     1.7780/90		1.7835-1.7777</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The dollar was confined in a tight range against the yen by late Tokyo on Monday as trading energy ebbed after having fallen on exporter sales and interbank dealers in early morning trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>Tokyo traders expect the undertone of the mark to remain weak and were waiting to see moves by European traders in overseas trade for clues to mark's future direction.  </p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/mark could rise to 1.8 marks eventually,&quot; a trust bank dealer said. But traders said they are reluctant to sell marks further in Tokyo as they are not confident enough to forecast the mark's future moves after dollar/mark surged to its highest level in almost in six years in New York on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar/mark rate jumped on Friday but I just don't know how to react to the current level of dollar/mark,&quot; a dealer at a European bank said.</p>
<p>He added that it is possible that German monetary authorities will eventually talk up the mark again, and that speculation also put pressure on dollar/mark.  </p>
<p>On Thursday, Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer said that the dollar's correction from early-1995 lows against the mark had come to an end and that the mark's strength in the run-up to monetary union was important.</p>
<p>In late Tokyo, some profit-taking by overseas traders pushed the dollar down below 1.78 marks, but the greenback remained in a narrow range for the most of Asian trade amid a lack of fresh market-moving factors, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing new came out from Bank of Japan (BOJ) branch managers' meeting this morning either,&quot; a dealer at a long-term credit bank said.  </p>
<p>BOJ Governor Yasuo Matsushita said in an opening speech at the start of the BOJ branch managers' meeting that Japan's economy is continuing on a gradual recovery trend supported by firm production and incomes, despite the lingering impact of a rise in the consumption tax.</p>
<p>A European bank dealer in Singapore said the upside for dollar/yen looked slow due to exporter selling interest and heaviness in the mark/yen cross. He said a break below 63.70 in mark/yen could trigger option-related stop loss sales.</p>
<p>The German currency stood near 63.88/91 yen at 0655 GMT, compared with 64.15 yen in late New York on Friday.  </p>
<p>Traders said weakness in several Asian currencies was providing psychological support to the Japanese currency for its safe-haven status.</p>
<p>But dealers said dollar's topside against the yen may be capped ahead of the release of trade data both in Japan and United States later this week. Japan's customs-cleared trade balance data for June will be released on Thursday, followed by U.S. international trade data on Friday.</p>
<p>Some traders said they were cautious about selling dollars aggressively as they await Tuesday's news conference by senior Ministry of Finance (MOF) official Eisuke Sakakibara.  </p>
<p>Sakakibara is to take over the post of vice finance minister for international affairs after the cabinet, as expected, approves his promotion on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Outgoing vice finance minister for international affairs, Takatoshi Kato, incoming Vice Finance Minister Takeshi Komura and outgoing vice finance minister Tadashi Ogawa are also scheduled to hold news briefings on Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at around 113.98/03 yen and 1.7768/78 marks in New York on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom +65-8703080</p>
<p>-- Yoko Nishikawa, Tokyo +81-3-3432-8584</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
