<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727548" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai c.bank confirms intervention to help baht.</title>
<headline>Thai c.bank confirms intervention to help baht.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Thailand governor Rerngchai Marakanond on Monday confirmed market talk and said the central bank had intervened by selling dollars to help stem the baht's fall against the U.S. currency.</p>
<p>&quot;We intervened in the market, but in a very small way. This caused the baht to stabilise in the afternoon,&quot; Rerngchai told reporters.  </p>
<p>Rerngchai also said the central bank planned to keep the two-tier foreign exchange market and its current strict capital controls to prevent any further attack on the baht.</p>
<p>Rerngchai was speaking after meeting Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh, former finance minister Amnuay Viravan and senior officials from the government's think-tank, the National Economic and Social Development Board (NESDB).</p>
<p>The governor said the foreign exchange market, which has been jolted by the crisis in other regional currencies, was expected to return to normal in the next one to two days.  </p>
<p>&quot;The baht is at very low level and will stay at around 30 baht for some time. But the market should calm down in the next one to two days,&quot; Rerngchai said.</p>
<p>The baht fell sharply to new record low of 30.80 to the dollar on Monday morning on a spillover effect of speculative attacks on other regional currencies, dealers said.</p>
<p>The baht recovered ground in the afternoon, to trade at around 29.85/30.00 in mid-afternoon in the onshore market compared with 30.30/30.75 in early dealings.</p>
<p>The baht was also buoyed by the central bank deputy governor Chaiyawat Wilbulsawasdi's statement earlier that the baht had fallen to a level that was low enough and the bank would take action to stabilise the currency and stop wild fluctuations.</p>
<p>NESDB's secretary general Wirat Wattanasirtham said preliminary figures showed Thailand's gross domestic product would grow at a mere 4.6 percent this year if the baht were to fall by 10 percent.</p>
<p>He said the current account deficit would be at about 5.0-5.5 percent of GDP if the baht dropped 10 percent.</p>
<p>The Bank of Thailand said on Monday the baht had fallen about 15 percent since it switched to a managed float on July 2 from the previous system of pegging it to a basket of currencies.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
