<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727552" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL overnight interbank rate steady at 10 pct.</title>
<headline>KL overnight interbank rate steady at 10 pct.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The overnight interbank rate was steady at 10 percent on Monday after trading as high as 15 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said a few banks, which are also agent banks of Bank Negara, were seen lending overnight money at 9/10 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot tell if they are lending for Negara,&quot; said a dealer with Malaysian bank.</p>
<p>Earlier, a large agent bank of Bank Negara was also seen lending on the one-month.</p>
<p>The one-month rate was at 15/17 percent, against 15/20 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>One-week money was at 27 percent, against 25 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers said activities in the money market were mainly centred on the one-week and one-month. &quot;Nobody dares to take beyond one-month because it is too expensive,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market remained short of ringgit funds following Bank Negara's buying of the currency last week to defend the ringgit from a speculative attack.</p>
<p>Although the actual size of the intervention was not known, dealers estimated that between 2.5 billion and 5.0 billion ringgit went out of the system.</p>
<p>Dealers said there was confusion over where rates are heading after Bank Negara appeared to be allowing the ringgit to weaken against the dollar on Monday.</p>
<p>The ringgit plunged to a 16-month low of 2.55 a dollar early on Monday, from 2.5042/52 at the end of Kuala Lumpur trading on Friday, as speculators sold down the Malaysian unit.</p>
<p>Around 0800 GMT, ringgit was at 2.5435/45 to a dollar.</p>
<p>Interest rate futures on the Malaysia Monetary Exchange fell to reflect future expectations of firmer rates.</p>
<p>At 0800 GMT, the three-month Kuala Lumpur Interbank Offered Rate (KLIBOR) September contract was down four points to 92.26, or an implied yield of 7.74 percent.</p>
<p>The December contract fell two to 92.53, or 7.47 percent.</p>
<p>-- Syed Azman (603-201 4813) .</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
