<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727512" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian rupiah recovers at close, swaps lower.</title>
<headline>Indonesian rupiah recovers at close, swaps lower.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rupiah recovered against the dollar and swap rates fell in late trading after being jolted earlier on regional currency volatility, dealers said.</p>
<p>One U.S. bank dealer said the market seemd to quiet down, with the Indonesian currency seen recovering from a morning assault, while swaps also dropped across the board.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah was at 2,445.0/50.0 at 0915 GMT. The rupiah fell to an intra-day low of 2,469.0 from an opening of 2,453.0 before it bounced back to 2,445 and settled at 2,455 at midday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's volatile day. You are either making or lost a lot of money with this jumpy market,&quot; the U.S. bank dealer said.  </p>
<p>The dealer said swap premiums fell sharply from early high levels as the currency was driven into turbulence.</p>
<p>One-month swap fell later to 20.0/25.0 from 28.0 points, two to 41.0/51.0 from 55.0/60.0, three to 60.0 from 80.0 and six to 115.0 from 140.0 points.</p>
<p>The U.S. bank dealer said state banks were seen initiating another wave of dollar selling in late afternoon which saw some follow-through from offshore operators.</p>
<p>&quot;They also launched broad swap selling with the rupiah flush in the money market,&quot; he said, adding that overnight rates nose-dived to four percent from 20 percent.  </p>
<p>The dealer said this suggested the central bank was comfortable and had no plan to squeeze the market or take other action.</p>
<p>One Japanese bank dealer said he could not predict where the rupiah rates were heading in the very short-term because the regional environment was still so uncertain.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no clear trend in the market. We are too much exposed to the region,&quot; one Japanese bank dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;But I think the present levels in the spot and swap markets could not hold on for long. They are not at equilibrium levels,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the situation is short-lived and will be subject to a correction once things settle down,&quot; he said, adding the current spot and swap levels were in equilibrium.</p>
<p>The central bank offered repurchase of one-week papers at 13.75 percent which helped banks with SBI certificates.</p>
<p>The bank also offered seven-day bilateral papers (SBIs) at seven percent, two-week at 8.25 percent, one-month at 10.25 percent, three- and six-month at 10.50 and 11.25 percent and one-year at 12.0 percent.</p>
<p>The Japanese bank dealer said there was also no indication of a dollar tightening in the overnight market.  </p>
<p>&quot;Dollars are abundant in the market. Overnight rates are hovering at around 5.75/6.00 percent which are quite normal.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said the market did not react to a statement by State Secretary Murdiono who said a wider dollar-rupiah intervention band was to strengthen the Indonesian economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Our economic fundamentals are strong. The decision to widen the intervention band will make the economy even stronger,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;What we decided on Friday is a precautionary step. We are aware of attacks from everyhwere, but any speculation on the rupiah will fail,&quot; Murdiono said.  </p>
<p>Bank Indonesia, the central bank, surprised the market on Friday by widening the dollar-rupiah band to 12 percent from eight percent following recent de facto devaluations of the Philippine peso and the Thai baht.</p>
<p>Currency dealers said the rupiah was not a direct target of fund managers but was affected by the attacks on the Malaysian ringgit and the Philippine peso.</p>
<p>Kobus van der Waht, regional treasury economist at Standard Chartered Bank in Singapore, told Reuters Financial Television that Friday's surprise move had certainly given a signal.  </p>
<p>&quot;Bank Indonesia doesn't want to be part, or doesn't want to be in the same trap as happened in Thailand and to an extent in the Phillippines over recent weeks or months,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Thereby basically taking pre-emptive action (on band) and saying the past policy of depreciation is very much intact.</p>
<p>&quot;Decision making is over to the market and there is not going to be a situation where a specific level is defended at the cost of losing very valuable reserves,&quot; van der Waht said.</p>
<p>He said the market will not run away and investors, speculators and participants generally were giving Bank Indonesia the benefit of the doubt.  </p>
<p>&quot;They have been ahead of the curve in the past following a very prudent depreciation policy over many years and I thnk that is now giving them a big favour,&quot; van der Waht said.</p>
<p>He said there could be some rupiah weakening as one could expect in a nervous environment but not a run-away situation.</p>
<p>Bank Indonesia raised its intervention band by one point to 2,375/2,679 and the conversion band to 2,433/2,481 on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
