<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727621" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thailand ought to invest more in India - report.</title>
<headline>Thailand ought to invest more in India - report.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai businessmen ought to invest more in India as a means to widen the market for Thai products, a report issued by Bangkok Bank Plc said on Monday.</p>
<p>The report said recent Indian governments had been welcoming foreign investment with open arms but Thailand's investment in India was still minimal.</p>
<p>It said the latest statistics showed that Thai investment in India during the first 11 months last year slipped to 765.22 million rupees. In 1995 the amount was worth about 19.7 billion rupees.</p>
<p>Of the total investment by Thailand in India, 55 percent was in the telecommunications sector, 25 percent in real estate, 16 percent in fisheries and the remaining four percent in other areas, the report said.</p>
<p>It said there were several advantages foreign investors would gain from investing in India. These included access for Thai traders to penetrate the market in the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) with over 1,200 million consumers of which India is its leading member.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
