<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727616" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia's rupiah feels regional heat.</title>
<headline>Indonesia's rupiah feels regional heat.</headline>
<byline>Mantik Kusjanto</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah was on a roller-coaster against the dollar on Monday morning, rattled by continued speculative attacks on other regional currencies.</p>
<p>Currency dealers said the rupiah was not a direct target of fund managers but was affected by the attacks on the Malaysian ringgit and the Philippine peso.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah weakened to an intra-day low of 2,469.0 per dollar on Monday morning from an opening of 2,453.0 before it recovered to 2,445.0 and settled at 2,455.0 around midday.</p>
<p>&quot;For the rupiah, the issue is definitely the spillover from the peso and the ringgit,&quot; Edwin Png, country treasurer of Bank of America, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not because of the fundamentals of the rupiah,&quot; he said, adding that fund managers were taking advantage of Southeast Asian currency movements.</p>
<p>&quot;They want to buy it up as high as possible. But the rupiah situation is not that bad because the central bank only widened the band last week,&quot; Png said.</p>
<p>Bank Indonesia, the central bank, surprised the market on Friday by widening the dollar-rupiah band to 12 percent from eight percent following recent de facto devaluations of the Philippine peso and the Thai baht.</p>
<p>The move helped the rupiah strengthen briefly to 2,410.0 on Friday but it gave up ground to close at 2,438.0 a dollar in Jakarta as speculators maintained their assault on regional currencies.</p>
<p>Friday's widening was the eighth since 1992. The bank widened its band to 2,374-2,678 rupiah to the dollar.</p>
<p>Since 1992, Bank Indonesia has widened the intervention band in steps to give more room for price fluctuations to absorb external and internal shocks.</p>
<p>&quot;They are smart to do that. Fortunately, they didn't let it float like the peso and just widened the band,&quot; Png said, adding a float could have a wider impact on the rupiah.</p>
<p>However, economists remained comfortable with the rupiah's levels.</p>
<p>Daragh Maher, an economist at ING Barings, said earlier any effect on the rupiah due to a spillover from other currencies would be short-lived.</p>
<p>He said stable economic growth, the long-term nature of the country's foreign debt and controllable short-term private debt were among the factors helping to shield the rupiah from speculation.</p>
<p>Png said the top side of the dollar was expected to be at the 2,470 level because of overseas selling interest.</p>
<p>&quot;If you take the depreciation, it's very small compared to other currencies,&quot; he said. He added the turbulence could last for a couple of weeks but was confident of Bank Indonesia's ability to handle the situation.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the central bank is very well prepared compared to other central banks. They are more controlled in the sense that for the past 12 months the rupiah was always under attack.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The market is somehow already used to that. The central bank is already used to that, unlike others,&quot; Png said.</p>
<p>&quot;Somehow the economy is not really out of hand. I think they are doing a good job so far to control the economy and also the currency movement.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
