<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72771" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Henderson cash call seen boosting growth.</title>
<headline>Henderson cash call seen boosting growth.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Genevieve</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Henderson Land Development Ltd has capitalised on its record high share price to raise fresh funds and Monday's HK$3.5 billion share placement should boost earnings growth at the company, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The 55 million share placement at HK$64.00 per share was generally seen as an &quot;opportunistic&quot; placement after Henderson Land shares hit an all-time high of HK$66.50 on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think basically Henderson Land is taking advantage of the bullish outlook for its fundamentals in coming years,&quot; said Edward Chan, research director at NAVA SC Securities.</p>
<p>He raised his fiscal 1997 net profit forecast for the company by 1.4 percent to HK$11.05 billion and his fiscal 1998 forecast by 1.7 percent to HK$12.37 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Henderson Land's return on capital is about 25 percent, and if they have more new capital, I assume they would have better income,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Desmond Cheung, analyst at Vickers Ballas, agreed. &quot;The cost of capital for this HK$3.5 billion will be around six percent. The return on its investment is generally over 20 percent, therefore this should be beneficial to its earnings,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Henderson Land shares had gained 8.6 percent as of Monday's close since the company reported fiscal 1996 earnings on September 11 of HK$8.36 billion compared to HK$7.03 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a need for more capital to maintain that growth in earnings,&quot; said Martin Tacon, analyst at HSBC James Capel.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the desire and need to raise cash for long-term growth is always there and the timing depends on the market. I tend to say Henderson makes very good decisions in raising finance. I think their timing is good this time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said Henderson had taken advantage of an appetite for its shares in the market to raise fresh funds and the dilution impact of the placement would be minimal.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very much oportunistic. They did not really need the money,&quot; said Andrew Taylor, analyst at Asia Equity, adding that Henderson Land shares were trading around net asset value of between HK$64 and HK$66.</p>
<p>However, analysts said other developers wanting to take advantage of market buoyancy to raise cash may not find it as easy as Henderson Land.</p>
<p>&quot;To raise cash in this kind of interest rate environment needs orchestration,&quot; said Franklin Lam, director of research at HG Asia.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think investors will look for some guarantee that the aftermarket will be good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chan said property sales and profit growth at other developers may not be as good as Henderson Land's. &quot;I think the response may not be so overwhelming,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said Henderson Land shares were likely to come under short-term pressure following the placement.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, they ended HK$2.25 lower at HK$64.00.</p>
<p>&quot;Whenever there is a placement, one always feels that the company is making a statement in terms of the valuation of the stock. Henderson has had a good run and it is an indication that the company feels that at these levels the stock could be fairly valued,&quot; said Tacon.</p>
<p>However, analysts saw more upside later for the shares.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the current price level is quite demanding but with the return from property sales, the stock should reach over HK$70 in the next 12 months,&quot; said Cheung.</p>
<p>Lam said the market's appetite for property stocks was strong despite an expected rise in interest rates in the United States. &quot;That bodes well for developer stocks going into the next quarter or so and I do expect more upside for developers stocks between now and the end of the year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
