<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="727841" id="root" date="1997-07-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FEATURE - Dutch linguists plug into call centre market.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Dutch linguists plug into call centre market.</headline>
<byline>Keiron Henderson</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-07-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dutch look set for success in an ultra-modern industry because of skills perfected during their country's centuries-old trading history.</p>
<p>Call centres, where highly-trained staff deal with consumer telephone queries from around the world, are booming business in the Netherlands because of Dutch language skills and professional flexibility, say industry specialists.</p>
<p>Business consultant and accountancy firm KPMG sees call centre staff numbers rising to 100,000-125,000 by the year 2000, exploding from 25,000 now, as businesses pursue the benefits of marketing by telephone.</p>
<p>Typically, call centre staff field queries -- potentially from anywhere in the world -- about a company's products or services, solve problems for a client via help desks and offer services such as banking or hotel or flight reservations.</p>
<p>&quot;Somebody in America can call Amsterdam and book a room at a hotel in Philadelphia and not know they're talking to a Dutch person,&quot; said Gerard Burgering, whose TeleworX phone personnel recruitment business is struggling to keep up with demand.</p>
<p>LANGUAGE SKILLS DECISIVE</p>
<p>The Netherlands is not alone as an attractive site for call centres -- Glasgow in Scotland and Dublin in Ireland have cheap rents and other facilities -- but the deciding factor can be language skills.</p>
<p>&quot;The Netherlands is profiled as a country that provides most of the major languages in one area. We have a lot of people, not only Dutch people, but foreigners living in the country or passing through, that can be available for call centres,&quot; said Raimond Nicodem, electronic commerce chief at KPMG.</p>
<p>&quot;Land and other facilities in those countries are cheaper, but they're limited in terms of their actual foreign language populations. If you talk about smaller call centres that are not multi-lingual then Dublin is a real competitor with Amsterdam,&quot; Nicodem said.</p>
<p>Traditional call centres have been around for years, but are changing rapidly to become more efficient marketing tools as the telephone is used ever more closely with computer data bases.</p>
<p>&quot;Data base marketing is the issue,&quot; said Burgering. &quot;The use of the telephone and the integration of data and the Internet is very important in reaching the market now.&quot;</p>
<p>Nicodem says call centres are a separate business channel, outside of branch networks, for a wide range of businesses who want to get closer to individual customers and target their specific needs.</p>
<p>&quot;Information from people on the phones can be logged and collated, you can aggregate a lot more data and provide a truer image of your customer base,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not a whole lot of difference anymore in terms of quality between some types of consumer product, so the really competitive edge is not so much in product quality. It's the type of service and the quality of service that will distinguish companies from each other,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Burgering and Nicodem say call centre staff need to be highly educated and have strong communications skills as they collect and store data from calls.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to communicate over the telephone, listen actively, register information and follow up. It's not just picking up the phone and answering questions and putting the phone down,&quot; said Burgering.</p>
<p>DEMAND EXCEEDS STAFF SUPPLY</p>
<p>One potential block to the expansion of call centres in the Netherlands is that staff cannot be attracted quickly enough to meet exploding industry demand.</p>
<p>Burgering said he had already advertised in Belgian and German newspapers and the Internet, aiming to draw in staff, as potential employees had in the past been put off by talk of poor pay and conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;Conditions and pay are improving. The big companies do it very well and professionally but...because the market is exploding at the moment, some companies have hired people without really training them. Some companies gave telemarketing a bad reputation,&quot; said Burgering.</p>
<p>&quot;The thing is to convince employees that it's a good profession, a start for a commercial job. You learn how to communicate, administrate and work in dedicated teams,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Language skills in the Netherlands are not likely to be in short supply as the average Dutch schoolchild is proficient in English by his or her teens and has had years of schooling in German and/or French.</p>
<p>&quot;The culture has been multilingual for centuries,&quot; said Nicodem. &quot;I think that part of the success of the Netherlands in this type of industry is that it's service-minded and multi-lingual,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>For Burgering the Dutch have another strength. &quot;The Dutch are very good at it because of the open Dutch culture. People are always wheeling and dealing with other countries all over the world,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
