<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="728101" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Atlantic Energy proposes limited rate cut.</title>
<headline>Atlantic Energy proposes limited rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>NEWARK, N.J. 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Atlantic Energy Inc said Tuesday it proposed a five percent rate reduction as a first step toward a restructured electric utility industry.</p>
<p>The proposal was included in the filing its Atlantic Electric subsidary made with the New Jersey Board of Public Utilities in response to the board's proposal for electric industry restructuring.</p>
<p>The two-phase rate cut, based on 1996 rates, includes a reduction of about one percent when regulatory approval is received for the Atlantic Energy and Delmarva Power and Light Co merger.  </p>
<p>Another estimated four percent reduction would begin in the year 2001, related to other reductions in operating costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We view these projected rate reductions as a reasonable first step toward a restructured electric utility industry,&quot; said Jerry Jacobs, chief executive of Atlantic Energy.</p>
<p>&quot;In a few years, people will look back and evaluate the quality of decisions regulators, utilities and legislators made.  They will not judge how fast the industry was redesigned,&quot; Jacobs said.  &quot;They will ask if consumers and New Jersey are better off.&quot;  </p>
<p>The company said its filing accepts the board's proposal to phase-in customer choice of power suppliers beginning with 10 percent of supplies in October 1998.</p>
<p>Jacobs emphasized the need for full recovery of transitional -- or stranded -- costs, that is those costs incurred to comply with regulatory mandates.</p>
<p>Atlantic Electric's filing estimated its transitional costs are estimated to be about $1.3 billion, with $965 million or 75 percent is attributable to non-utility generation contracts.  </p>
<p>The utility said these contracts are the result of both federal and state public policy to stimulate the growth of non-utility generators -- or NUGs -- as mandated by the 1978 Public Utilities Regulatory Policy Act.</p>
<p>&quot;If Atlantic could buy the power we have to take from the NUGs in the open market, Atlantic's customers would save millions of dollars over the life of the contracts,&quot; Jacobs noted.</p>
<p>While negotiations with some of the company's NUGs have resulted in savings, the contracts are still substantially over market, Jacobs said.  </p>
<p>He stressed that Atlantic is committed to continue working with the NUGs to renegotiate these over-market contracts and to try to solve this problem.</p>
<p>&quot;If there ever was a time to challenge the NUG owners to come to the table and negotiate a reduction of these contracts, it is now when the BPU is working to restructure New Jersey's entire electric utility industry,&quot; Jacobs stressed.  &quot;Atlantic would like to join the NUGs in a search for the proverbial 'win-win' situation and pass these savings along to our customers.&quot;</p>
<p>The filing says &quot;we are going to attempt to renegotiate the NUG contracts to lower costs,&quot; Senior Vice President for External Affairs Henry Levari told Reuters.</p>
<p>However, he continued, the company would still prefer to buy out these contracts and securitize the buy-out costs.</p>
<p>He noted Atlantic Electric's projected rate reductions do not include any of the benefits securitization would produce, pointing out legislation is needed before costs can be securitized in New Jersey.</p>
<p>Levari said Atlantic Electric has already placed its generating facilities in a separate subsidiary which its filing proposes would be deregulated.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWARK, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
