<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="728211" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: OLYMPICS-SYDNEY BED TAX ROW PUT TO REST.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-SYDNEY BED TAX ROW PUT TO REST.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A row between Sydney hotels and the New South Wales state government over a planned city bed tax was put to rest on Tuesday, allowing organisers of the 2000 Olympic Games to get back to signing up major sponsors.</p>
<p>Games chiefs were forced to put A$600 million (US$440 million) worth of sponsorship deals on hold last month after hoteliers protesting against the new 10 percent accommodation levy refused to guarantee them rooms.</p>
<p>Under a compromise deal announced on Tuesday, Sydney city hotels promised to make 80 percent of their beds available for Olympic needs in return for a phasing-in of the tax.</p>
<p>&quot;This agreement overcomes a significant problem which had arisen in our preparations for the Games. We can now proceed with confidence,&quot; Sydney Organising Committee for the Olympic Games (SOCOG) president Michael Knight said.</p>
<p>Despite the deal, the bed tax headache will not immediately disappear for either the NSW government or SOCOG.</p>
<p>SOCOG vice-president John Coates, a lawyer who heads the Australian Olympic Committee, last week launched a defamation action against NSW state treasurer Michael Egan for having suggested that Coates's opposition to the tax might be motivated by his business links with a company which runs a city hotel.</p>
<p>Under the compromise, SOCOG itself sacrificed some A$6 million it had been due to charge as commission for providing clients with hotels. The organising body agreed to cut its own commission on rooms from 10 to five percent.</p>
<p>In return it is able to go ahead with major sponsorship deals which the row had threatened.</p>
<p>SOCOG officials had said they would have to renegoiate the deals at much lower rates because sponsors could not be guaranteed a room if there were no cooperation from the hotels.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we've had a few difficult months, SOCOG is now in a better position to sign up accommodation than we were at the beginning of the dispute over bed tax between the government and the industry,&quot; Knight, who is also the NSW Olympics minister, said in a statement.</p>
<p>The SOCOG concession on its own commission was one element in a compromise deal between the hotel industry and the New South Wales government, which is underwriting the cost of staging the Games. Hoteliers said the deal would save them a total of A$40 million.</p>
<p>In announcing changes to the bed tax legislation, state premier Bob Carr said the hotel levy would be reduced from 10 percent to five percent at the start of the phasing-in period in September, 1997.</p>
<p>But he said the reduction would apply only for hotels which sign agreements with SOCOG before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Cruise ships berthing in Sydney during the Olympics will be exempt. In addition, serviced apartments will be exempt from the bed tax for stays of 28 days or longer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
