<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="728330" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Guinness, GrandMet get new LVMH proposal.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Guinness, GrandMet get new LVMH proposal.</headline>
<byline>Tim Farrand</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>British companies Guinness Plc and Grand Metropolitan Plc said on Tuesday that Bernard Arnault the French entrepreneur who controls conglomerate LVMH had outlined a new proposal to both companies in talks held last Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a joint statement they pledged to look closely at the so-called Northolt proposal, named after the former military airbase on the outskirts of London where Arnault met the chairmen of Guinness and GrandMet aboard his private jet. More talks were held between respective company finance directors today.</p>
<p>The joint statement said Arnault proposed breaking up Moet Hennessy with the champagne business becoming wholly owned by LVMH and Hennessy, the cognac business, being sold for shares in UDV, the name given to the proposed merger of spirits brands owned by Guinness and GrandMet.</p>
<p>Arnault, who is the biggest shareholder in Guinness with a 14.2 percent stake, has rigorously opposed the planned 24 billion pound($40.5 billion) merger of GrandMet and Guinness, to be called GMG Brands, since it was announced in May.</p>
<p>The 42 year old Breton has also built up a 6.2 percent shareholding in GrandMet over the last few weeks. He argues that a three way drinks merger including Moet Hennessy, Guinness and GrandMet would add more value for all shareholders.</p>
<p>Guinness owns 34 percent of Moet Hennessy, the holding company for all of LVMH's wine and spirits activities and the two companies operate joint ventures worldwide.</p>
<p>LVMH is the world's leading cognac producer, with Hennessy the industry leader. It also owns Pellisson, a producer of brandy under the Raynal and Three Barrels labels and Hine a specialist in older quality cognacs.</p>
<p>Its champagne brands include Dom Perignon, Moet and Chandon.</p>
<p>The new plan was greeted more favourably by Guinness and GrandMet although it was still too early to say whether any agreement can be reached, said a spokesman acting for both companies.</p>
<p>&quot;His original proposal was to break up GMG Brands altogether. Sell off Pillsbury (GrandMet's U.S. based foods business), Burger King, and Guinness brewing and then merge all three drinks businesses with him having a controlling stake in it. That was on the table two weeks ago,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But there are &quot;elements of the new outline proposals which would not be in the best interests of GrandMet's and Guinness' shareholders,&quot; he said, although he declined to give details of those elements.</p>
<p>Analysts said the main sticking point is likely to centre on the split of value between GMG Brands and LVMH shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;They will have to work out the value of the Guinness shareholding in Moet Hennessy and how much Arnault should get of UDV in return for the cognac business,&quot; said one analyst who chose not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;In broad terms Moet Henessy makes 300 million pounds a year operating profit, so 200 of that goes to LVMH because it owns 66 percent. UDV has operating profit of 1.2 billion. So if you fold Hennessy into UDV that might be worth 10 percent of profits,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, an LVMH spokewoman said the French group was still working on the hypothesis of a three-way marriage between the three companies, following newspaper reports that said LVMH could swap its cognac for champagne with Guinness.</p>
<p>($ = 0.592 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
