<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="728415" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION - All Blacks hit training hard in S.A..</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION - All Blacks hit training hard in S.A..</headline>
<text>
<p>PRETORIA, July 14 - A vigorous training session kicked off a tough week for the All Blacks as they started preparing for Sunday's (NZ time) rugby test against the Springboks at Johannesburg, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>The physical, high-tempo two-hour session was just what coach John Hart was looking for to set the rhythm and intensity for the rest of the week leading to the tri-series opener at Ellis Park.</p>
<p>Though Hart hadn't planned for such a start to the week, he let the session take it its course, and later described it as satisfying.  </p>
<p>Hart expects the Springboks, coming off the final test win over the British Lions after losing the three-match series, to spring a ferocious forward game in an attempt to catch his team by surprise.</p>
<p>Captain Sean Fitzpatrick led today's training session and their non-stop back-breaking work on scrummaging confirmed a fierce forward battle in the making on Sunday.</p>
<p>Hart will name his team here tomorrow and said he had a fully fit squad to pick from.  </p>
<p>It appears that Andrew Mehrtens will return to first five-eighth after missing the last three tests, against Argentina (twice) and Australia, and Alama Ieremia will replace Lee Stensness at second five-eighth.</p>
<p>Mehrtens has made a full recovery from the nagging hamstring problem, which enabled Carlos Spencer to play his first three tests in succession.</p>
<p>Ieremia has also overcome a broken collar-bone.</p>
<p>His physical presence in the backline and ability to smash through defences give him the edge over Stensness for opponents like South Africa.  </p>
<p>No other changes are expected.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
