<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="728587" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Budapest milling wheat limit-up on quality worries.</title>
<headline>Budapest milling wheat limit-up on quality worries.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most milling wheat futures prices on the Budapest Commodity Exchange (BCE) went limit-up on Tuesday on fears that rainy weather forecast for the weekend could affect the crop's quality, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rainy weather could lower the quality of the wheat crop and it could also delay harvesting,&quot; said Janos Szolyka of Swap brokerage.</p>
<p>Milling wheat futures rose the daily allowed 400 forints per tonne for all positions except December which rose 380 forints.</p>
<p>Szolyka added that lower or steady feed wheat prices underlined the market's consensus that while the wheat crop would certainly be well above last year's, the quality of it was uncertain.</p>
<p>He also said that for the last two weeks Budapest grains prices started to move independently from Chicago prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Local prices no longer follow Chicago prices strictly, the market looks at European and domestic conditions instead,&quot; Szolyka said, adding that with the Czech and Polish floods export outlooks were improving.</p>
<p>Hungarian national railways MAV Rt said earlier today it would hire 500 rail carriages from Romania to handle grains exports considerably above last year's 300,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;We could export as much as 800,000 tonnes of wheat by the end of October, when export licences expire,&quot; said Istvan Bobak, MAV deputy general director in charge of logistics.</p>
<p>He added MAV also concluded agreements on the use of Croat, Slovenian and Italian rolling stock, should those be needed.</p>
<p>So far MAV has received indications of wheat exports towards Poland, the former Soviet Union, Bulgaria, Romania and Turkey, but no contracts have been signed yet, Bobak added.</p>
<p>Elswhere on the market, dormant maize futures rose 50 to 100 forints per tonne due to a technical correction and feed barley futures moved mixed in relatively low volume.</p>
<p>Total grains turnover jumped to 1,320 lots or 594.5 million forints from 556 lots or 242.51 million forints on Monday.</p>
<p>Milling wheat accounted for more than half of the turnover in volume terms with 763 lots.</p>
<p>(Lot size=20,000 kgs $=191.97 Hungarian forints)</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
