<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="728529" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: UN troops prepare to leave Croatia Serb enclave.</title>
<headline>UN troops prepare to leave Croatia Serb enclave.</headline>
<byline>Zoran Radosavljevic</byline>
<dateline>KLISA, Croatia 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations bade farewell on Tuesday to more than 2,000 peacekeepers who will leave the last Serb enclave in Croatia this summer, beginning the final handover of authority for the region to Zagreb.</p>
<p>Soldiers from Pakistan, Jordan and Argentina lined up in the rain at a UN base in Eastern Slavonia as representatives of the United Nations and the Croatian government gave speeches.</p>
<p>They then marched out of the parade ground, to the tune of Pakistani military pipers, in their national groups.</p>
<p>The parade came a day after the Security Council approved a plan for their withdrawal in New York, providing for all military personnel to leave Eastern Slavonia by October 15, with civilians staying until January.</p>
<p>In 1991 the enclave was the scene of the first episode of brutal killing, ethnic cleansing and devastation in former Yugoslavia. Rebel Serbs living there, backed by the Yugoslav National Army, rose up after Croatia seceded from the Yugoslav federation, flattening the region's capital Vukovar and expelling thousands of Croats.</p>
<p>A UN transitional administration with 5,000 troops has run the enclave since January 1996, as called for in peace accords that ended the war, to prevent a resumption of fighting. Led by U.S. general Jacques Klein, it has managed to pave the way for the enclave's return to Croatian rule.</p>
<p>After demilitarising the region, overseeing the first local post-war election and reintegrating local companies with Croatia, the UN will now try to speed up the return of refugees, spokesman Philip Arnold told Reuters.</p>
<p>Altogether 2,000 troops, including Jordanian and Pakistani battalions and an Argentinian reconnaissance unit, will have left fertile, oil-rich Eastern Slavonia by late August.</p>
<p>&quot;Today half of our troops are going home but the next two months are most critical for the UNTAES mandate,&quot; Klein said.</p>
<p>&quot;All electoral bodies must be functional and serve the people of the region...and a rule of law must prevail.</p>
<p>&quot;All Croatian citizens in the region must be fully protected regardless of their nationality. People must start returning and rebuilding their homes and their lives. We urge a comprehensive programme of national reconciliation to heal the wounds of the war. There is a future for all in Croatia.&quot;</p>
<p>He then wished the soldiers a safe journey and good luck. The troops will not leave immediately but will now prepare for their departure.</p>
<p>In the second phase of the pullout, another 2,000 troops are due to withdraw in autumn, leaving only some 700 soldiers to guard UN facilities, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The Security Council has left the door open in a resolution for the military to remain until the mandate ends on January 15, 1998, depending on Croatia's ability &quot;to reassure the Serb population and successfully complete peaceful integration&quot; as it takes back the enclave.</p>
<p>Croatia has been pressing for a quicker pace of reintegration and accused Serbs of lacking good will.</p>
<p>But another U.N. official said the success of the handover of authority would be vulnerable long after U.N. troops left next year. &quot;Overwhelmingly, it will depend on the energy and the good will of the Croatian government,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to work together with the (UN) on the full implentation of the mission to make it beneficial to all citizens.&quot; said Prime Minister Zlatko Matesa in his speech.</p>
<p>Zagreb is keen to return thousands of displaced Croatians to the region. In turn, thousands of Serb refugees will seek to go back to their own homes in other former rebel Serb enclaves elsewhere in Croatia, recaptured by the Croatian army in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KLISA, Croatia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
