<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="728659" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech telecoms affected by flooding.</title>
<headline>Czech telecoms affected by flooding.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech telephone operator SPT Telecom a.s. said on Tuesday that a maximum of 100,000 fixed lines had been interrupted by massive flooding in the eastern part of the country.</p>
<p>SPT said in a statement that it was still too early to &quot;calculate any financial sums&quot; as a result of the flooding, but that the lines affected represent only three percent of SPT's total number of lines in operation.</p>
<p>The worst flooding this century has indundated the eastern part of the Czech Republic for over a week, caused damage put at 100 billion crowns and killed at least 39 people.</p>
<p>The flood wave interrupted rail and road connection in the affected regions as well as gas, power as well as telephone links.</p>
<p>The Czech parliament has approved an issuance of up to five billion in flood bonds and release another up to five billion from privatisation proceeds for flood relief.</p>
<p>In June 1995, the Czech government chose a joint bid from the TelSource consortium formed by Koninklijke PTT Nederland and Swiss Telecom, from among five global telecom bids for a 27 percent stake, and effective operating control of the firm.</p>
<p>The group -- split between 51 percent for the Dutch PTT, and 49 percent for Swiss Telecom -- paid $1.32 billion for the shares, plus an additional $131 million in training services and technology.</p>
<p>SPT shares traded up 72 crowns to 3,552 at the daily price fixing on the Prague Stock Exchange on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Alan Crosby, Prague Newsroom, 420-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
