<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72884" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Attorneys open arguments in Gerulaitis death case.</title>
<headline>Attorneys open arguments in Gerulaitis death case.</headline>
<dateline>RIVERHEAD, N.Y. 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The trial of a pool mechanic charged in the gas poisoning of tennis star Vitas Gerulaitis began Tuesday with his attorney blaming the maker of a pool heating system and describing his client as a &quot;scapegoat.&quot;</p>
<p>Prosecutors have alleged that mechanic Bartholomew Torpey and his employer, East End Pools and Courts Inc., improperly rigged an exhaust pipe in the basement of a Southampton, Long Island, pool cottage where Gerulaitis slept.</p>
<p>Gerulaitis, 40, was found dead Sept. 18, 1994, on the exclusive estate of developer friend Martin Raynes. Torpey was accused of failing to install the correct length of pipe from a pool heating system, trapping carbon monoxide gas near the room where Gerulaitis rested.</p>
<p>Torpey was indicted on charges of criminally negligent homicide and the pool company was charged with second degree manslaughter.</p>
<p>In opening arguments Tuesday in Torpey's trial in Suffolk County Court, attorney David Clayton charged that prosecutors, by allowing a key expert witness from manufacturer Teledyne Lars to testify before a grand jury, had given the expert immunity from prosecution.</p>
<p>&quot;In this case the District Attorney and the city let the big people take a hike and went after the smallest people on the face of the earth he could find,&quot; Clayton told the jury. He described Torpey as the &quot;fall guy&quot; and a &quot;scapegoat&quot;.</p>
<p>Clayton blamed Teledyne Lars and the expert witness, James Cosmano, whom he said was the last person in the pool cottage to work on the heater three days before Gerulaitis' death.</p>
<p>Gerulaitis, who retired from the tennis circuit in 1984 but later returned to the game as a broadcaster, won 27 singles and nine doubles championships, including the 1977 Australian Open. He won millions of dollars but his career declined rapidly as he was treated for drug abuse.</p>
<p>During his opening arguments, Assistant District Attorney Edward Helig slammed his hand down on the defence table and said, &quot;the buck stops at this table right here. They're the people who did it, the people responsible for it.&quot;</p>
<p>He told the jury that Torpey was not educated enough and did not care enough to make sure the pipe extended outside of the door.</p>
<p>&quot;When you see one item, the photograph of how this defendant installed and vented this heater, you don't need to be an expert to see the photograph and know and say 'that's wrong',&quot; Helig said. &quot;He just didn't care enough, didn't take the time to find out how to vent this thing.&quot;</p>
<p>Gerulaitis' mother Aldona Gerulaitis has filed a $63 million civil lawsuit in Manhattan Supreme Court, citing nine defendants, including Torpey, the pool company and Raynes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIVERHEAD, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
