<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="728804" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks slump again on Brazil fallout.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks slump again on Brazil fallout.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks sank once more below the 4,700-point barrier at mid-afternoon trade on Tuesday after a partial earlier recovery fizzled out due to a spillover from plunging markets in Brazil, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Share prices recovered a little as day-trippers stepped in, rather than investors,&quot; a floor trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;When the market failed to recover as they hoped, they sold again. We're down on profit-taking, and dealers are concerned over the sharp fall in Brazil.&quot;</p>
<p>The leading IPC share index was down 85.27 points, or 1.79 percent, at 4,691.80..  </p>
<p>The IPC had pared losses to reach some 4,720 points after the Finance Ministry announced stronger-then-expected industrial output figures, dealers said.</p>
<p>In Brazil, the Sao Paulo bourse (Bovespa) had meanwhile plummeted 782 points to 11,916. Dealers said the falling Bovespa had sapped confidence and triggered losses on equity markets across Latin America.</p>
<p>Dealers noted that trading volume was nonetheless thin at 59.4 million shares and suggested investors were not bailing out of Mexico.</p>
<p>(( --Martin Roberts, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7907))  </p>
<p>Similarly, the telecom company's ADRs dropped to 49-3/4 in late trade before recovering a bit to end down 2-3/16 at 50-13/16.</p>
<p>Dealers said the decline on the Brazilian market overshadowed gains on Wall Street, where the Dow Jones ended up about 53 points at an unofficial record of 7,976.</p>
<p>On the broad market in Mexico, declining issues outnumbered gainers by 85 to 16, out of a total of 113 stocks that changed hands.</p>
<p>(( --Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7907))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
