<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="728849" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: FEATURE-Brazil's rebel lawmaker to go undercover.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Brazil's rebel lawmaker to go undercover.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Brazilian congressman who kidnapped a U.S. ambassador, wrote a best-seller while working as a night watchman in exile and sported what may be the world's smallest swimming trunks feels another change in life coming on.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm over-exposed,&quot; said Fernando Gabeira, the lone Green Party lawmaker in Brasilia, who has a knack of hogging the headlines. &quot;I'm going to go low-profile for a bit.&quot;</p>
<p>It is hard to imagine Gabeira undercover. For nearly 20 years he has campaigned against destruction of the Amazon rainforest and he once shut down a nuclear power station.</p>
<p>Last year he was being threatened with drug charges by outraged colleagues in Congress for importing a sackful of hemp seeds, a non-narcotic strain of cannabis he says could be a cash crop for Brazil's arid northeast. Then he defied Brazil's dominant car culture, cycling to work along the capital's monumental esplanades to protest urban pollution.</p>
<p>Gabeira, who may the only Brazilian politician to defend legalisation of drugs as a way to tackle inner city violence, also took part in a campaign of civil disobedience by marijuana-smokers and sympathisers on Ipanema Beach in Rio.</p>
<p>Physically, too, Gabeira stands out. His hair is shorter and grayer than in the 1970s, when he challenged Brazil's conservative attitudes towards bisexuality by wearing a tiny, crochet codpiece to the beach. But he still looks more like a fashion writer than a politician, standing out in an otherwise staid Congress with his high-buttoned jackets, colourful shirts and diamond earstud.</p>
<p>MORE MEDIA INTEREST IN HIS BEHAVIOUR THAN HIS POLICIES</p>
<p>&quot;The media is more interested in my behaviour than my policies,&quot; Gabeira grumbled in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>In the heady days of the late 1960s, however, when students led marches against military rule and found themselves up against an increasingly repressive regime, Gabeira's profile could not be low enough.</p>
<p>He was one of a group of intellectuals turned guerrillas who in 1969 snatched U.S. Ambassador Charles Elbrick as he was being driven through Rio and traded his life for the release of 15 revolutionaries from jail. Secret police tracked the kidnappers down and a leader of the group, a veteran member of Brazil's tiny armed resistance, was kicked to death in a cell.</p>
<p>Gabeira was tortured. His lover was crippled. But Gabeira eventually walked free and into exile when another group of guerrillas staged a copycat kidnapping of Germany's ambassador and included him in the list of prisoners they wanted freed.</p>
<p>Gabeira ended up in Sweden where he worked as a train driver, a gardener in a cemetery and a night watchman in a hotel. While there he wrote &quot;O Que E Isso, Companheiro?&quot; (&quot;What Do You Mean, Comrade?&quot;), a best-selling account of his trasformation from intellectual into armed rebel and a wistful lament about what might have been had the guerrillas persuaded the masses to forget about soccer and demand freedom.</p>
<p>It also remains one of only a few Brazilian books to deal with the barely healed scars of the 1964-85 dictatorship. A film based on the book was released in May to good reviews at home and abroad.</p>
<p>UNDER FIRE FROM FELLOW LEFT-WINGERS</p>
<p>Gabeira was back in the headlines, and back under fire. Angry members of Brazil's hard left raged about its portrayal of a torturer as a man racked with guilt while the guerrillas appeared either naive or coldblooded.</p>
<p>&quot;So little is known about the period, what people did, how they died, that the film has been taken as absolute truth, which it isn't,&quot; Gabeira said.</p>
<p>Other former members of his gang said the film glorified Gabeira and exaggerated his contribution to the kidnapping. &quot;Don't talk to me about Gabeira. Find somebody who's got something nice to say about him,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>But the public flocked to see the film, which is faster paced than the rather dense book, captures all the furtive passion of young rebels in love and is set against the stunning backdrop of Rio's mountains and bays.</p>
<p>Gabeira said the critical reception given the film by Brazil's left was typical. &quot;The trouble with the left is they have not yet understood they must change. They haven't even analysed the falling of the Berlin Wall,&quot; he said. &quot;Until they take in the Tony Blair effect they won't win any elections.&quot;</p>
<p>Blair was elected Britain's prime minister in May, ending 18 years of Conservative Party rule, after he moved his Labour Party closer to the centre of the road.</p>
<p>LEFT-WING PARTIES SEEN AS REACTIONARY DIE-HARDS</p>
<p>Although he considers himself &quot;part of the family,&quot; Gabeira sees Brazil's half-dozen left-wing parties as reactionary die-hards, unswerving in their opposition to all the government's reforms from privatisation to education.</p>
<p>He believes Brazil is making progress, albeit slowly, after decades lost to the struggle for democracy and the chaos of rampant inflation. &quot;Change in Brazil happens very slowly and you have to be very astute to see it,&quot; he said, attributing growing demands for social improvements to the rising numbers of Brazilians who travel abroad.</p>
<p>Like most people in Brasilia, he thinks social democratic President Fernando Henrique Cardoso, riding high on an anti-inflation plan, will win another term next year, having recently rewritten the constitution to allow his re-election.</p>
<p>Gabeira said he would not be running for Congress again next year. &quot;I don't want to become a professional politician,&quot; he said, prefering instead a return to his first profession, journalism, and a spell covering Europe's resurgent left.</p>
<p>&quot;In 2002 (when Brazil holds elections again) the country might be ripe for the kind of the change happening elsewhere,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
