<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729015" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Indian rewarded for drive to save Taj Mahal.</title>
<headline>Indian rewarded for drive to save Taj Mahal.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Indian lawyer who fought to preserve the Taj Mahal monument from environmental degradation was bestowed the Ramon Magsaysay Award for public service on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Mahesh Chander Mehta, 50, was recognised for his 13-year campaign to protect the Indian environment from the harmful effects of industry, the award foundation said.</p>
<p>The foundation especially cited the environmental crusader for securing Supreme Court judgments that led to the closure of coal-based industries whose emissions, it said, were eating into the soft marble of India's most famous shrine.</p>
<p>The Magsaysay award was established in 1958 in honour of a popular Philippine president who died in an air crash in 1957.</p>
<p>Mehta is the 34th Indian to win a Magsaysay award, giving India the distinction of having the highest number of Magsaysay laureates among 20 Asian countries from which prize winners have been selected, the foundation said.</p>
<p>Winners of the award's five categories each receive a cash prize of $50,000 and a gold medallion in ceremonies in Manila on August 31 to mark the anniversary of Magsaysay's birth.</p>
<p>The foundation last week named Thailand's former prime minister Anand Panyarachun as winner of the prize for government service for his campaign to strengthen democracy and stamp out corruption in Thailand.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
