<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729012" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: HK consults Beijing on illegal child immigrants.</title>
<headline>HK consults Beijing on illegal child immigrants.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Lau</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong will begin talks on Wednesday with Beijing to discuss a crisis over a growing number of illegal child immigrants from China.</p>
<p>Immigration Director Regina Ip was due to fly to Beijing on Tuesday to meet a director of China's Public Security Ministry, Xu Ganlu, who is in charge of entry and exit issues, an immigration department spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Ip would discuss ways to tackle the problem of thousands of young illegal immigrants who ultimately have residency rights in Hong Kong but who sneaked in, avoiding slow legal channels.</p>
<p>A senior Hong Kong Security Branch official said Ip would ask China to raise a daily quota for mainland child immigrants into Hong Kong to 90 from 66, to speed up the process.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to see whether this is acceptable to the mainland,&quot; the official, Raymond Fan, told reporters. Hong Kong's new constitution, the Basic Law, effective since China took back the former British colony on July 1, allows mainland-born children the right of abode if they have a parent with legal residency rights in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Last week Hong Kong passed a tough law to deport child illegals, fearing there would be an even bigger influx if a lenient precedent was set and they were allowed to stay without applying legally, a process which can take years in China.</p>
<p>Hong Kong operates a daily quota allowing 150 mainland Chinese migrants -- including 66 children -- into the territory.</p>
<p>More than 400 illegal children have applied for legal aid to fight the law. Some 50 applications have been approved, clearing the way for the families to face the government in court.</p>
<p>An estimated 66,000 children of &quot;separated families&quot; are waiting in China to join parents in this capitalist enclave. Families often resort to smuggling the children in or face demands for bribes by Chinese officials who handle their papers.</p>
<p>On Monday, as hundreds of children queued for legal aid to fight deportation, China threw its support behind Hong Kong.</p>
<p>A Chinese Public Security spokesman was quoted by the South China Morning Post newspaper on Tuesday as saying the requirement for children to get prior endorsement of their right of abode status before coming to Hong Kong was in line with the Basic Law.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a reasonable method that effectively protects the rights enjoyed by the applicants under the law and maintains normal exit and entry at the border,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;This requirement will be conducive to the correct implementation of right of abode under the Basic Law.&quot;</p>
<p>Social activists and lawyers have blasted the law, rammed through the China-appointed rubber stamp provisional legislature in one sitting last week, as unconstitutional. Over 100 lawyers have offered to help the children free of charge.</p>
<p>Political analyst Andy Ho said the government had set a dangerous precedent and painted itself into a corner.</p>
<p>&quot;They (lawyers) fear other measures could well be instituted in future to strip residents of other legal rights, supposedly enshrined in the Basic Law,&quot; Ho said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
