<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729017" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indocement up on share sale report.</title>
<headline>Indocement up on share sale report.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian PT Indocement Tunggal Prakarsa made strong gains in late trading on Tuesday following reports that the cement giant planned to sell its 50.1 percent stake in noodle maker PT Indofood Sukses Makmur.</p>
<p>Indocement was up 250 rupiah to 4,800 rupiah, with some 14 million shares traded near the close.</p>
<p>&quot;The reports have finally confirmed recent market talk that Indocement was expected to divest its stake in Indofood,&quot; one broker with a foreign brokerage firm said.  </p>
<p>Indofood, however, ended down 100 rupiah to 5,450 rupiah in thin trading of only 76,000 shares.</p>
<p>The proposed move is expected to be effected by the distribution of 724.34 million Indofood shares representing 39.56 percent of Indofood share capital to shareholders of Indocement in the form of a special dividend, Indocement said.</p>
<p>There will also be a sale of 193.10 million Indofood shares representing a 10.54 percent stake to private companies held by Indonesia's Sampoerna family, Indocement said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Food-based QAF Limited said in a statement on Tuesday it had agreed to acquire a majority stake in Indofood.  </p>
<p>Indocement, Indofood and QAF are controlled by Indonesia's largest conglomerate the Salim Group.</p>
<p>Indocement said the Salim Group would retain control of Indofood after its spinoff through a majority shareholding in QAF. -- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
