<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729083" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chase, Citicorp earnings rose in quarter.</title>
<headline>Chase, Citicorp earnings rose in quarter.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowski</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chase Manhattan Corp. and Citicorp, the nation's two largest banks, on Tuesday reported earnings gains for the second quarter despite some weakness in credit card and consumer banking operations.</p>
<p>Mellon Bank Corp., based in Pittsburgh, also said its earnings rose, up 6 percent. But Banc One Corp. of Ohio, the nation's eighth-largest bank, and No. 9 Wells Fargo &amp; Co. of California both said earnings fell, hurt by one-time costs related to acquisitions.</p>
<p>The results met or slightly exceeded expectations on Wall Street, as did earnings reported by Nationsbank, First Chicago NBD Corp. and other big banks on Monday.</p>
<p>Chase, which took over the No. 1 spot from Citicorp when it acquired Chemical Bank last year, said net income rose to $925 million, or $2 a share, in the quarter ended on June 30, compared with $856 million, or $1.83 a share, a year earlier.</p>
<p>Chase, based in New York, cited strength in its corporate business worldwide and a rise in revenue from trading for its own account, partly offset by weakness in credit cards and other consumer banking businesses, where earnings declined.</p>
<p>Excluding restructuring costs from the Chemical merger, Chase earnings were $969 million, or $2.11 a share, which was above the $2.07 a share forecast by analysts, according to First Call, which tracks Wall Street estimates.</p>
<p>Chase delivered a &quot;positive surprise,&quot; said analyst Robert Albertson at Goldman, Sachs &amp; Co. Chase stock rose $1 to $103 in late trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Citicorp, also based in New York, said earnings rose to $1.02 billion in the quarter from $952 million a year earlier, while earnings per share increased to $2.10 from $1.86.</p>
<p>The results were a penny above analysts' forecast of $2.09 a share, according to First Call, but Citicorp stock fell $2.125 to $126.375 on the NYSE as investors wondered whether the bank's days of rapid growth were over.</p>
<p>Several analysts said Citicorp's domestic credit card business did poorly in the quarter, but George Salem at Gerard Klauer Mattison said the company's problems appeared more widespread.</p>
<p>&quot;Citicorp is not doing well, period,&quot; he said. &quot;Where's the growth? I think this is a turning point for Citicorp. They have a real challenge ahead of them.&quot;</p>
<p>Earnings in Citicorp's consumer businesses, which include its retail branches, credit cards and its private bank, fell 3 percent for the second consecutive quarter. Earnings in its other main business, corporate banking, rose 5 percent.</p>
<p>Chairman John Reed cited &quot;challenges&quot; in the credit card business and said &quot;the highly competitive marketplace is a permanent reality,&quot; adding that Citicorp would focus on service and cutting costs to bolster results in the card and retail businesses.</p>
<p>Wells Fargo, based in San Francisco, said net income fell to $228 million, or $2.49 a share, in the quarter, from $363 million, or $3.61 a share, a year earlier.</p>
<p>The results were close to forecasts of $2.52 a share after the bank said last week that earnings would suffer because of troubles integrating First Interstate, which it acquired last year for about $11 billion in stock.</p>
<p>&quot;The results were not much worse than they warned. They were basically in the range,&quot; Stephen Biggar at S&amp;P Equity Group said.</p>
<p>Wells stock rose $1.50 to $267 on the NYSE, recovering some of its 6.6 percent drop after its earnings warning last Wednesday.</p>
<p>One analyst said the troubles were because it was not a friendly merger. &quot;I have a feeling it has a lot to with the the fact it was a hostile merger. A lot of top managers left Interstate when the deal closed. At this stage, you have to wonder if it would have gone a lot more smoothly had they stuck around,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Banc One said net income fell to $16 million, or 2 cents a share, from $395 million, or 66 cents a share, a year earlier. The latest quarter included a $467 million pretax charge related to its acquisitions of Liberty Bancorp Inc. in Oklahoma and First USA Inc. completed during the quarter.</p>
<p>Excluding the charge and previously announced accounting adjustments, Banc One said earnings fell to $391.6 million in the quarter from $395.2 million. Banc One stock fell 25 cents to $48.69 on the NYSE.</p>
<p>Mellon Bank, the No. 23 bank, said net income rose to $190 million, or 72 cents a share, in the quarter, from $179 million, or 63 cents a share, a year earlier. The results came in a penny above forecasts.</p>
<p>Mellon also said it would buy back up to 6 million more shares, or 2.4 percent of its stock, and the shares added $1.125 to $48.31 on the NYSE.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
