<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729251" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX Hub natgas ends mixed, Aug. gains on heat.</title>
<headline>NYMEX Hub natgas ends mixed, Aug. gains on heat.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures ended mixed Tuesday in a moderate session, with near record power demand in the East lifting front months, while some deferreds finished slightly lower, sources said.</p>
<p>August climbed 1.1 cents to close at $2.162 per million British thermal units. September settled one cent higher at $2.156. Other deferreds ended narrowly mixed.</p>
<p>&quot;We struggled to move higher on the heat, but the weather is supposed to moderate soon and the market looks like it's running out of steam,&quot; said one Midwest trader, adding much of the buying seemed to be short covering, not new length.</p>
<p>Many remained wary of the latest move up, with new supply coming on stream and another sizeable stock build expected in this week's AGA inventory report.</p>
<p>Early injection estimates for Wednesday's report range from 78 bcf to 101 bcf. For the same week last year, stocks gained 94 bcf.</p>
<p>Chart traders agreed the sharp decline Monday in August open interest indicated yesterday's rally was mostly short covering, likely triggered by the spot contract's move above resistance in the $2.15 area. They pegged August resistance along the down trendline in the $2.23 area. Support was seen at last week's $2.051 low, with psychological buying at $2.</p>
<p>In the cash Tuesday, Gulf Coast gas firmed three cents to the high-teens. Midcon pipes were four cents higher at about $2.10. New York city gate gas jumped more than a nickel to the low-to-mid $2.50s on near-record power demand in the area.</p>
<p>Temperatures over much of the nation are expected to remain above-normal for most of the week, but more seasonal weather is expected for the eastern half of the nation later this week and next.</p>
<p>The NYMEX Henry Hub 12-month strip rose one-half cent to $2.223. NYMEX said 34,699 contracts traded, up from Monday's revised tally of 26,967.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, August finished one cent higher at $2.06, while deferreds ended up by 0.9 to 1.9 cents. The East/West spread widened by 0.1 cent to 10.2 cents (NYMEX premium). KCBT said 315 lots traded, up from Monday's total of 177.</p>
<p>((--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
