<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729200" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: McDonald's Q2 seen up only 7 pct - analysts.</title>
<headline>McDonald's Q2 seen up only 7 pct - analysts.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Heavy competition in the U.S. fast-food market and an unsuccessful marketing campaign took a bite out of McDonald's Corp second quarter earnings, which are expected to rise only about seven percent, analysts said.</p>
<p>That compares with 13.5 percent earnings growth in the 1996 second quarter.</p>
<p>The First Call consensus of analysts' earnings estimates for the second quarter is $0.63 a share, compared with $0.59 earned a year ago. According to First Call, results are expected to be released on July 17.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think they'll manage to get close to that number,&quot; Natwest Securities analyst Damon Brundage said of the $0.63 consensus.</p>
<p>Analysts said they estimated McDonald's U.S. same-store sales declined between two and four percent in the second quarter. While April U.S. same-store sales were bolstered by the Teeny Beanie Baby promotion for Happy Meals, May and June same-store sales declined.</p>
<p>McDonald's does not comment on monthly same-store sales. But Jack Greenberg, chairman of the McDonald's USA unit, told reporters last week that May and June results were below the company's targets.</p>
<p>Year-to-date, he added, the company was on track.</p>
<p>In the middle of the second quarter, McDonald's canceled its Campaign 55 price promotion for lunch and dinner. Under that campaign, featured hamburgers were priced at 55 cents when customers also bought french fries and a drink.</p>
<p>Last week, McDonald's named a new lineup for its top U.S. management, which included Greenberg assuming the title of president of the domestic unit. McDonald's said the management changes were aimed at decentralizing its U.S. business and moving decision-making closer to the restaurant level.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
