<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729473" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. touts economic benefits of NATO expansion.</title>
<headline>U.S. touts economic benefits of NATO expansion.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration on Tuesday touted the economic benefits of NATO enlargement, saying that it would promote economic reform and investment in Eastern Europe and help spur U.S. exports.</p>
<p>&quot;The security and economic dimension really mesh and go hand-in-hand,&quot; U.S. Undersecretary of State for Economic Affairs Stuart Eizenstat told reporters.</p>
<p>The North Atlantic Treaty Organisation last week invited three former Soviet bloc states -- Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic -- to join the military alliance.</p>
<p>Lawmakers in the U.S. Senate, which must ratify the expansion, have raised questions about the planned enlargement, including whether it is necessary and how much it will cost. A Senate vote is not expected until next year.</p>
<p>State Department officials, who declined to be named, said it was too early to say how much opposition NATO expansion would run into in the Senate.</p>
<p>But they said it was not too early for the administration to start making the case for the move, and Tuesday's briefing on the economic benefits of a larger NATO was part of that.</p>
<p>Eizenstat said central European countries had the fastest growing economies in Europe, with a big appetite for consumer durable goods and huge infrastructure needs, especially in telecommunications and environmental clean-up.</p>
<p>He acknowledged that NATO expansion would also provide U.S. defence contractors with added sales oppurtunities, but he played down the economic significance of that.</p>
<p>&quot;We've encouraged them (the prospective new NATO members) not to make big-ticket purchases like fighter aircraft,&quot; because that could overburden their economies and their budgets, Eizenstat said.</p>
<p>He also said he would like to see the United States do more to help central European countries by lowering import tariffs.</p>
<p>But he admitted that would likely require legislation and that there were no plans to do that now.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
