<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729421" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Versace's style traveled far and wide.</title>
<headline>Versace's style traveled far and wide.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Wulfhorst</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gianni Versace's style is everywhere.</p>
<p>Princess Diana wears Versace. So does Monacco's Princess Caroline. So does Carolyn Bessette Kennedy, the closest thing America has to royalty of its own.</p>
<p>Versace, who was shot to death in Miami Beach on Tuesday, said last month he was drawing inspiration of late from four fashion muses -- Princess Diana, Madonna, Courtney Love and Bessette Kennedy.</p>
<p>&quot;They all have both chic and shock,&quot; he wrote in a piece for The New York Times magazine, adding words of praise for American women's sense of fashion.</p>
<p>&quot;American women are the most free,&quot; the Italian designer wrote. &quot;They use fashion and let fashion use them.&quot;</p>
<p>Even those who couldn't tell a Versace from a Valentino can see his brash and sexy signature everywhere.</p>
<p>Actress Courtney Love wore a white Versace gown, with an attention-grabbing plunging neckline, to the most recent Academy Awards ceremony.</p>
<p>One of this summer's hottest movie stars, Will Smith, sports a white Versace suit on the cover of Essence magazine. And Versace helped design an eight-page spread in the April issue of Vogue for Absolut Vodka.</p>
<p>Singer Elton John had his outrageous suits custom-made by Versace, and New York socialite and businesswoman Ivana Trump was a regular customer.</p>
<p>&quot;I just really adored him,&quot; Trump said on Tuesday. &quot;What set him apart was that his style was always young. He was very much young and jazzy and a little bit kinky at times, which is fine.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You get a little giggle out, and that was the difference from other designers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Versace's fashion shows are the ultimate 'see-and-be-seen' events, regularly attended by pop culture trend-setters such as the Artist Formerly Known as Prince and actor Leonardo DiCaprio.</p>
<p>Just last week, a London fashion critic crowned the exuberant designer &quot;the king of frock 'n' roll&quot; after seeing his latest Paris collection.</p>
<p>In New York on Tuesday, the posh Versace boutique on Madison Avenue closed its iron gates minutes after news of the shooting.</p>
<p>Outside, businesswoman Carole Rome said she had hoped to buy a Versace dress for a wedding this weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;You feel special in this type of clothing. It makes a woman feel special,&quot; she said. &quot;It's worthwhile because it's clothing that makes a statement.&quot;</p>
<p>Versace was reportedly weighing a bid to take his company public. He had more than 100 boutiques worldwide, while the younger Versus line designed by his sister Donatella had more than 500 boutiques from New York to London to Tokyo.</p>
<p>&quot;He achieved so much. Now was the time to start enjoying the money,&quot; said fashion reporter Elsa Klensch on CNN. &quot;That's what makes this so sad.&quot;</p>
<p>Known for his exuberant use of colour and innovative use of avante-garde fabrics, Versace's most recent collection featured dresses of embroidered silk and fine metal mesh and shoulder pads used decoratively under thin shoulder straps.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr. Versace wrote the book on making fashion fun,&quot; a critic wrote in The New York Times.</p>
<p>Born in Calabria in 1946, Versace produced his first signature collection in 1978. He introduced his first menswear collection soon after.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
