<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72963" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Secrecy over sick Klestil alarms politicians.</title>
<headline>Secrecy over sick Klestil alarms politicians.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secrecy over the illness of Austrian President Thomas Klestil, unconscious in hospital for three days over the weekend, raised alarm among politicians on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Senior conservative politician Andreas Kohl said it was unacceptable that physicians had not informed government leaders that Klestil's health had deteriorated over the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;This must never happen again,&quot; said Kohl, chief whip of the junior coalition partner, the rightist People's Party.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to have new guidelines...Doctors cannot remain silent,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Social Democrat Chancellor Franz Vranitzky, who began his first full day as acting head of state on Tuesday, said he knew nothing of the grave developments in the president's state of health until the early hours of Monday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;I was only told that night that the president was not doing as well as one had hoped,&quot; Vranitzky told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I should have been told earlier.&quot;</p>
<p>But the chancellor was swift to defend the doctors at Vienna General Hospital, saying they had probably more on their minds trying to determine the nature of Klestil's illness.</p>
<p>Chief physician Wolfgang Graninger said the president's condition was stable on Tuesday and he was fully conscious.</p>
<p>Klestil, 63, who separated from his wife in 1994 after revealing he was having an affair, was admitted to hospital on September 13 and transferred to intensive care last Friday.</p>
<p>Doctors said Klestil was suffering from an aggressive and atypical form of pneumonia but they were still investigating the nature of his lung inflammation. They said no cancer was found and the illness was not life-threatening.</p>
<p>News that Klestil had regained consciousness after spending three days sedated and on an artificial respirator came as a surprise to the media and opened a debate over the right of voters to be kept informed of the health of politicians running the country.</p>
<p>Undue secrecy over the state of health of a nation's leaders was not good for democracy, newspapers said. The respected daily Der Standard said that when leaders were ill their office should issue daily bulletins on their state of health.</p>
<p>&quot;Anything else leads to wild rumours and to crowds of journalists hanging around hospitals trying to get hold of any authentic report,&quot; the paper said in a commentary.</p>
<p>&quot;Secretiveness...reminds one more of a communist system than a democratic one, although a sick Boris Yeltsin in the middle of his presidential campaign is understandably a lot more problematic than an Austrian president half way through his term of office&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Under the constitution, the chancellor assumes the duties of president for 20 days, after which responsibilities pass, in turn, to the three presidents of parliament.</p>
<p>One of the presidents, Wilhelm Brauneder, belongs to the far-right Freedom Party but political sources said a fresh presidential election would probably be called before he could temporarily adopt the head of state's mantle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
