<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729642" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU Commission agrees six-country invitation list.</title>
<headline>EU Commission agrees six-country invitation list.</headline>
<byline>Janet McEvoy</byline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG, France 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission agreed on Tuesday that Poland, the Czech Republic, Hungary, Slovenia and Estonia should be invited to take part in talks on the EU's first expansion into eastern Europe.</p>
<p>They will join Cyprus, whose membership talks have been on hold for some time.</p>
<p>The long-awaited &quot;Agenda 2000&quot; policy document setting out plans for the EU's most ambitious expansion to date dashed the hopes of Latvia, Lithuania, Slovakia, Romania and Bulgaria that they would gain EU membership in the short term.</p>
<p>The document, detailing policy changes which the EU will have to make for the next century to get ready to welcome new members, was adopted without detailed discussion by the executive, ahead of formal presentation to the European Parliament on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The 20 Commissioners had resolved deep differences last week over how many countries to recommend.</p>
<p>Their fight foreshadows six months of frantic horsetrading between EU governments, which have the final say at their Luxembourg summit in December and are expected to bring all their national interests to bear in deciding just how big the EU's first foray behind the former Iron Curtain is to be.</p>
<p>The document, obtained by Reuters ahead of the decision, tells all 10 eastern European applicants they have to do more work on their economies before they cross the threshold.</p>
<p>But it comes down in favour of the five who have set up functioning market economies.</p>
<p>&quot;No candidate country today fulfils entirely the two economic conditions (set by EU leaders) but some should be able to do so in a few years,&quot; the document says.</p>
<p>In Warsaw, Poland welcomed the decision as an acknowledgement of the effort Poles had made towards membership.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel like an enterprise that has received the approval of its auditors,&quot; Jaroslaw Pietras, Deputy Minister in Poland's committee overseeing its membership drive said.</p>
<p>But in Bucharest the Romanian government implicitly criticised the decision to leave it out, saying any enlargement in waves would be &quot;artificial and discriminatory&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe an enlargement strategy of waves should be avoided. This would create new demarcations which would divide the candidate states in an artificial and discriminatory way,&quot; a government statement said.</p>
<p>Slovakia was ruled out, not because it had not progressed economically, but because, after years of communism, it was judged the only one not to have carried out the necessary political reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;A single candidate country does not fulfil the political criteria,&quot; the report says.</p>
<p>Turkey, whose EU application has been shunned on human rights grounds, was offered a consolation prize in the form of deeper links going beyond its existing customs union.</p>
<p>Under the plan, Ankara would receive assistance in areas ranging from agriculture to telecommunications.</p>
<p>In Ankara, Turkey said the decision not to invite it for EU membership talks was a mistake.</p>
<p>&quot;This decision is a mistake. It is not just and it is not objective,&quot; Foreign Minister Ismail Cen told a private news channel.</p>
<p>The EU document also maps out a formidable challenge for the current 15-member EU, including, as soon as possible after the year 2000, a new inter-governmental conference to overhaul the bloc's decision-making procedures for the influx of new members.</p>
<p>The EU's June 16-17 Amsterdam summit failed to agree on how to revise the way decisions are taken ahead of enlargement, but said a new overhaul would be necessary if the bloc extended to more than 20 members.</p>
<p>A radical reform of the EU's Common Agricultural Policy is also prescribed in the document, with drastic cuts of 10 percent in EU guaranteed prices for milk and 20 percent for cereals.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
