<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72976" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Polish president proposes anti-crime convention.</title>
<headline>Polish president proposes anti-crime convention.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's president submitted a draft convention to the General Assembly on Tuesday designed to counter what he called the &quot;seemingly unstoppable manifestation&quot; of transnational organised crime and terrorism.</p>
<p>&quot;I am convinced that only a world-wide effort under U.N. auspices has any prospect of stopping the crimes which threaten democratic freedoms and democracy itself,&quot; President Aleksander Kwasniewski said in a speech to the 185-nation U.N. body.</p>
<p>He noted that he had personally witnessed the &quot;terrorist attempt during the Olympic Games in Atlanta last July&quot; -- a still-unsolved bombing that killed one person and wounded more than 100.</p>
<p>&quot;I have received reports that my own country and the whole region face a steep increase in traffic of drugs, white slavery, trade in child sex, money laundering. Organised crime is a world-wide phenomenon,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The international community is faced with the growing threat arising from seemingly unstoppable manifestations of transnational organised crime.&quot;</p>
<p>Poland therefore believed the time had come to make a concerted international attempt to agree on a comprehensive legal instrument designed to enhance inter-state cooperation and facilitate the work of law enforcement agencies in fighting transnational organised crime.</p>
<p>Kwasniewski said the draft convention dealt with illicit traffic in drugs, arms and explosives, motor vehicles and cultural objects, stealing and smuggling of nuclear materials, money laundering, traffic in persons, counterfeiting and corruption of public officials.</p>
<p>The proposed convention, which he urged U.N. members to discuss and improve on, calls for states either to punish offenders or extradite them. It also asks states to introduce criminal liability of persons who derive profits from organised crime, wherever this liability is not clear.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
