<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="72986" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: PLO protests to U.N. over Jerusalem tunnel entrance.</title>
<headline>PLO protests to U.N. over Jerusalem tunnel entrance.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Palestine Liberation Organisation (PLO) called on the Security Council on Tuesday to reverse Israel's action in opening an entrance to a tunnel in the Old City of Jerusalem, saying it endangered the al-Aqsa Mosque and other Islamic structures.</p>
<p>In virtually identical letters to the president of the Security Council and Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali, PLO U.N. observer Nasser al-Kidwa said the tunnel was opened on Monday evening &quot;under the protection of army units&quot; and &quot;extends for approximately 500 yards (metres), parallel to the Western Wall of al-Aqsa Mosque.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the &quot;opening of this entrance and any use of the tunnel endanger the security and integrity of al-Aqsa Mosque and the foundations of the Islamic structures existing above the tunnel.&quot;</p>
<p>Al-Kidwa said Security Council resolutions had declared that all Israeli measures and actions aimed at changing the status of Jerusalem were invalid and called on Israel to rescind them.</p>
<p>&quot;The above-mentioned Israeli action is obviously another measure aimed at the Judaization of the city, creating yet additional facts with regard to the Holy City's status.&quot;</p>
<p>He called on the Security Council to &quot;take the necessary steps to address this issue and to have the Israeli action reversed.&quot;</p>
<p>Israel's Tourism Ministry said the tunnel, leading to archaeological sites near Jerusalem's Temple Mount, sacred to both Judaism and Islam, takes visitors on a journey through 2,500 years of history, including the time of Jesus. It would more than quadruple the number of tourists able to visit the site, the ministry added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
