<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729818" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Finolex seen to ride cable boom.</title>
<headline>India Finolex seen to ride cable boom.</headline>
<byline>Clarence Fernandez</byline>
<dateline>PUNE, India 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's oldest cable manufacturer, Finolex Cables Ltd, plans to double its turnover by 2001 on the back of a boom in the country's cable market fuelled by demands to boost telephone density.</p>
<p>&quot;Today the DoT (Department of Telecommunications) demand for cable is going up by about 25 percent every year,&quot; group chairman Pralhad Chhabria told Reuters at his headquarters in the western city of Pune.</p>
<p>&quot;Telephone density is only about 10 million telephones in the whole country, so there is no doubt the DoT demand for cable will continue for many more years. We do not foresee the demand will go down,&quot; Chhabria said.</p>
<p>This did not include projected demand from private telephone service providers, he said.</p>
<p>Finolex's 31-year head start on the rest of the country's private cable manufacturers would keep it ahead of the competition, Chhabria said.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year we did over five billion rupees in turnover,&quot; Chhabria said. &quot;We would like to be 10-billion-plus by 2001, and then we can expand in that area further.&quot;</p>
<p>Finolex plans to consolidate its lead by concentrating on two new products -- television cable, which used to be entirely imported, and specialised cable for LAN (Local Area Networks) computer configurations, Chhabria said.</p>
<p>&quot;One is television cable which we are going to produce on a mass scale in our new plant at Urse, 16 kilometres from the Pune plant,&quot; Chhabria said.</p>
<p>&quot;The next one is also the LAN cable, of which we are going to produce very, very large quantities because now every company, every office needs a computer, where the network is very essential,&quot; Chhabria said.</p>
<p>&quot;So these are the two areas where gradually we will build up a huge business.&quot;</p>
<p>Chhabria said Finolex's business strategy until the year 2002 would focus on the manufacture of basic varieties of cable.</p>
<p>&quot;We are planning to produce the maximum of the bread-and-butter cable, the general cable, which India needs and in which we are the only brand today,&quot; Chhabria said. &quot;We are expanding that area much faster than we planned earlier.&quot;</p>
<p>Capacity at the firm's first plant in Pune has been doubled to meet projected demand, Chhabria said. A new plant at Urse has an installed capacity to manufacture 6.5 million core kilometres of jelly-filled telephone cables a year.</p>
<p>Next year will see the opening of a third factory, in the resort state of Goa.</p>
<p>&quot;This Goa factory will produce high voltage power cable -- that is, 11 KV to 66 KV -- in the first phase, and there we are again going to put the light duty cable -- our building wire, automobile cable, and the general cable,&quot; Chhabria said.</p>
<p>Money to fund this expansion would be raised from overseas markets through external commercial borrowings (ECBs), Chhabria said. The group intends to raise $30 million in this manner in the financial year 1997/98 (April-March) alone.</p>
<p>Finolex Cables' net profit fell 12 percent to 4.84 billion rupees in financial year 1996/97, compared with 5.5 billion rupees the previous year.</p>
<p>--Bombay newsroom =91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PUNE, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
