<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="729801" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India PM sees no threat to ruling coalition.</title>
<headline>India PM sees no threat to ruling coalition.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral said on Tuesday he was sure of a solution to the crisis in his ruling United Front coalition, stemming from the planned withdrawal of a regional party.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure we would be able to sort it out in the next meeting of the steering committee (of the United Front),&quot; Gujral told Asian News International in a videotaped interview. &quot;I am absolutely certain we will be able to bridge the difficulties.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he had already spoken to two leaders of the Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam (DMK) after the southern-based party issued a statement on Monday saying it planned to withdraw its four ministers from the government, but that it would continue to support the coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not see any possibility or any probability or any chance of a strain on the government,&quot; he said. &quot;...I am sure that wisdom has prevailed already that we must accommodate each others' point of view.&quot;</p>
<p>The DMK had said on Monday that the coalition had compromised on its dignity by allowing some of its partners to force their own agenda in the coalition.</p>
<p>It did not explain the differences, which party leaders said were targeted at the Communist Party of India-Marxist (CPI-M), which had insisted on the removal from the coalition of a breakaway group of Gujral's Janata Dal party.</p>
<p>The DMK accounts for less than 20 of the United Front's 178 lawmakers in India's 545-seat lower house of federal parliament. The coalition's survival depends on vital support from the Congress party's 140 members.</p>
<p>The DMK's salvo was the latest in a chain reaction stemming from a split on July 5 in Gujral's Janata Dal party, whose then leader Laloo Prasad Yadav formed a breakaway Rashtriya Janata Dal but stayed on in the 15-party alliance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
