<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730141" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-BA hurt by strike, changes to go on.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-BA hurt by strike, changes to go on.</headline>
<byline>Paul Keller</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways Plc admitted on Tuesday that an ambitious restructuring programme was damaging staff morale but chief executive Bob Ayling vowed to press ahead with the changes, which last week sparked a costly strike by cabin crew.</p>
<p>Ayling told the shareholders' annual meeting that the 72-hour strike had cost the company &quot;tens of millions of pounds&quot; as well as lost bookings for the future.</p>
<p>He urged the cabin crew union involved in the dispute, to adopt a &quot;constructive approach&quot; to new talks due to be held later this week.</p>
<p>Separately, BA chairman Sir Colin Marshall told the meeting he was hopeful of securing BA's proposed grand alliance with American Airlines, despite protracted regulatory delays.</p>
<p>The alliance, unveiled just over a year ago, has been held up by regulatory authorities in the UK, Europe and the U.S. over concerns that it will dominate the North Atlantic market.</p>
<p>Ayling and Marshall said they were confident that concerns about making room for competition at London Heathrow, the main sticking point, could be overcome in time for the next summer season, starting in April.</p>
<p>&quot;Approval for our alliance hangs on the problem of achieving greater access to a congested Heathrow for our transatlantic competitors,&quot; Marshall said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in continuing dialogue with the respective authorities and hopeful of a satisfactory outcome.&quot;</p>
<p>More immediately, BA has trouble closer to home. It still has to resolve its staff disputes.</p>
<p>Last week's strike forced BA to run a skeleton service of flights and prompted passengers to book seats on rival airlines. The conflict centred on new pay and conditions which the BASSA cabin crew union said were being imposed on its 9,000 members without consultation.</p>
<p>A cabin crew union spokesman, responding to Ayling's call, said the union was prepared to co-operate as it now appeared negotiations were possible.</p>
<p>&quot;This has been a deeply damaging dispute which we must all now put behind us. The unions have always been ready to be constructive,&quot; Andrew Murray of the BASSA's parent, the Transport and General Workers' Union told Reuters.</p>
<p>BA says it expects to resume talks once management has seen proposals promised by BASSA on how to achieve 42 million pounds ($70.9 million) of savings from its members.</p>
<p>With new talks promised in what has been dubbed the 'pause for peace', the shareholders meeting went ahead peacefully with a conspicuous absence of union protests.</p>
<p>However, several employees and other private shareholders voiced concerns that Ayling's restructuring programme to cut a billion pounds from annual costs threatened to destroy staff morale.</p>
<p>One shareholder, also a BA employee, was applauded  when he said morale was &quot;at an all-time low&quot;.</p>
<p>Ayling said he recognised that the changes were upsetting for many employees, who were &quot;understandably fearful of change&quot;. But change was necessary to keep the airline competitive and he believed morale would improve once the changes were in place, he said.</p>
<p>As part of the cost-cutting drive, employees were being asked to accept pay re-structurings, businesses were being hived off, including its in-house catering operation and some of its 60,000 employees worldwide would continue to be offered voluntary redundancy.</p>
<p>But he said there were already enough volunteers for the 5,000 redundancies being sought, &quot;so there is no question of compulsory redundancies.&quot;</p>
<p>Ayling also welcomed the decision by the main ground staff union representing some 9,000 workers to drop the threat of a strike and instead accept the company's offer for further talks on the sale of its catering business at London Heathrow airport.</p>
<p>On other issues, a sore point for many of the 1,500 small shareholders who attended the meeting remained BA's 60 million pound project to change its corporate image, launched last month, with a new logo and ethnic art replacing the heraldic crest on the tailfin.</p>
<p>Both BA chairman Sir Colin Marshall and Ayling said the changes reflected BA's growing international customer base and denied there were any plans to drop the word 'British' from the company's name. ($ = 0.592 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
