<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73015" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: New Greek cabinet no surprise on economic policy.</title>
<headline>New Greek cabinet no surprise on economic policy.</headline>
<byline>George Georgiopoulos</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's new socialist cabinet, unveiled on Tuesday with Yannos Papandoniou's appointment as economic &quot;czar&quot; heading both the finance and national economy ministries, came as no surprise, economic analysts said.</p>
<p>Papandoniou, national economy minister since October 1993, was reappointed by Prime Minister Costas Simitis, who scored a convincing national election win on Sunday. But he now takes direct charge of taxation and the 1997 budget, due in November.</p>
<p>&quot;The cabinet announcements came out on the expected side,&quot; Alexander Devletoglou, Managing Director of N. Devletoglou Securities, said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that Papandoniou stays at the national economy ministry is positive. He was clear cut on economic and monetary policy during the campaign and it stays intact,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Papandoniou, a rising star in the socialist party, is credited with the part flotation of state telecommunications group OTE and has promised similar attempts to part-privatise other concerns, such as the state petroleum corporation.</p>
<p>He is best known for being in charge when Greece's inflation rate fell to single digits for the first time in 20 years. It is now 8.5 percent annually and he has vowed to cut it to under 8.0 percent by year-end.</p>
<p>Sticking with proven hands, Simitis elevated Papandoniou in effect to his economic &quot;czar&quot;, giving him the finance ministry as well.</p>
<p>&quot;There was always a belief that there should be one minister heading finance and national economy for better coordination,&quot; said John Marcopoulos, Managing Director at Sigma Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's reaction should be positive. It didn't look forward to unpleasant surprises. The stock market showed composure on Tuesday. I expect we will see faster action on many pending agendas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One unsettling note for some was the reappointment of Vasso Papandreou as development minister. She upset foreign investors and provoked the anger of some Western governments by revoking an awarded casino licence and demanding other deals be renegotiated.</p>
<p>Simitis who won his gamble on early polls on Sunday against the opposition conservatives produced a cabinet mix of old-guard socialists and younger generation reformers.</p>
<p>Socialist officials said Simitis had abandoned early plans for a radical &quot;new-look&quot; government.</p>
<p>He opted to shuffle key ministers among top posts instead and retained his two defeated rivals in the race to replace late party president Andreas Papandreou at the helm of the party.</p>
<p>Akis Tsohatzopoulos will take over from Gerassimos Arsenis as defence minister. Arsenis will replace George Papandreou as education minister.</p>
<p>Papandreou, son of party founder Andreas will join outspoken Theodore Pangalos as his deputy foreign minister.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me more of the same, as if the elections didn't take place. As far as economic policy is concerned there shouldn't be any worries -- it will stay the same,&quot; analyst Emmanuel Varsos of Investment Analysis told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
