<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730350" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Viag sees 97 earnings stable, slightly up.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Viag sees 97 earnings stable, slightly up.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT, Germany 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>German diversified utility Viag AG on Tuesday forecast a rise in group sales in full-year 1997 and said that it expected earnings to remain stable or rise slightly during the year.</p>
<p>Viag's management board chairman Georg Obermeier said at the group's annual shareholders meeting that a hike in group dividends was a possibility, without making any concrete forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;Viewed in the longer-term, naturally 12 marks cannot be the last word,&quot; Obermeier said, adding that the potential for higher pay-outs to shareholders was there.</p>
<p>He said Viag's chemical unit SKW Trostberg and its aluminium unit VAW Aluminium AG performed particularly well in the first half of 1997 and that Viag's business in the first half of the year was as expected, matching the previous year.</p>
<p>There were no major problem areas in the group's holdings, but Obermeier admitted that there were weak points in certain units.</p>
<p>These included its stake in Computer 2000's U.S. computer group AmeriQuest, which Obermeier said was a &quot;flop&quot; and which Viag would dispose of once the group had been whittled down to a form which would be able to survive on its own.</p>
<p>However, Obermeier defended Viag's majority holding in Computer 2000, saying that the unit had a great position in the European computer business.</p>
<p>The group said problems at its Gerresheimer Glas unit would have only a limited impact on the group's earnings.</p>
<p>Obermeier said that Viag would not be seeking to raise capital for the foreseeable future and he went on to say that he still expected profits of between 60 million and 80 million marks ($33.6 million and $44.8 million) at the group's Computer 2000 unit in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see a capital raise for the foreseeable future,&quot; Obermeier said, despite the group's planned investment of 7.5 billion marks in the next ten years. This would come from the group's high levels of cash-flow at around 4.5 billion marks.</p>
<p>Obermeier said the group was targeting a 20 percent return on sales and a 10 percent return on capital employed (ROC) in its energy business by the year 2000.</p>
<p>He said Viag would seek a 10 percent return on sales and a 12 percent ROC in its chemicals business.</p>
<p>Viag was seeking a six percent return on sales and a 12 percent ROC in its packaging business and returns of two percent on packaging sales and six percent ROC in its logistics unit in the same period.</p>
<p>Obermeier went on to detail start-up losses in its telecommunications joint-venture, which would reach between 3.6 and 3.7 billion marks by 2001.</p>
<p>Viag would pick up around 45 percent of these costs, with the remainder falling to its telecoms partners British Telecom and Telenor. The telecoms business should become profitable in the year 2001.</p>
<p>Obermeier said that had the group used the International Accounting Standard (IAS) accountancy method to work out its figures for 1996, Viag's group net profit would have been around 200 million marks higher than the 1.06 billion marks reported.</p>
<p>Viag reported its figures according to German accounting law. The group would have benefited by around 200 million marks from tax write-offs had it used the IAS system, Obermeier said. --Clifford Coonan, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.784 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
