<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730303" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Saudi billionaire prince eyeing Lebanon deals.</title>
<headline>Saudi billionaire prince eyeing Lebanon deals.</headline>
<byline>Michael Georgy</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mega-investor Saudi Prince al-Waleed bin Talal is eyeing Lebanon, where he plans to ride the reconstruction boom with hundreds of millions of dollars invested in tourism and banking.</p>
<p>&quot;The prince is looking at mainly tourism and banking in Lebanon,&quot; a source close to the prince who requested anonymity told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebanon used to be the biggest tourism market in the Middle East and now with the reconstruction the prince thinks tourism will be hot again,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Prince al-Waleed, who has a huge international portfolio of investments ranging from computers to theme parks, this year became a major partner in Beirut finance house Lebanon Invest after buying an undisclosed number of shares.</p>
<p>The source would not put a price tag on Prince al-Waleed's investment plan in Lebanon, but said it ran into the hundreds of millions of dollars.</p>
<p>&quot;We think this is the right cycle for Lebanon and the country has high potential,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lebanon, still recovering from a devastating 1975-90 civil war, has mounted a multi-billion dollar drive to rebuild the country's infrastructure and Beirut, once the region's banking and financial capital.</p>
<p>Prince al-Waleed's plan to invest here is good news for the Lebanese government which is trying to restore investor confidence and is hoping to lure tourists with summer festivals.</p>
<p>Some market watchers were optimistic that his interest in Lebanon would boost prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;For sure this is good news. What is interesting is what kind of direct investments he will pursue. That's the key question,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>But one broker was cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be dangerous for the market to have one man holding hundreds of millions of dollars in investments,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The source close to Prince al-Waleed said he was interested in Lebanon's congested banking sector. But he added that there were no negotiations underway with specific banks.</p>
<p>One market watcher said the prince would probably be on the prowl for small banks which are struggling to boost their capital.</p>
<p>&quot;It is likely that he will look to buy small banks which are having trouble meeting the obligation to raise their capital,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said Waleed is in the final stages of negotiations with real estate firm Solidere, Lebanon's biggest company, to buy property to build a $100 million Four Seasons hotel in the city centre.</p>
<p>The prince said last month that he had forged a partnership with a Lebanese businessman to open a Planet Hollywoood restaurant in Beirut.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
