<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730414" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FIS leader took party to heights, then banishment.</title>
<headline>FIS leader took party to heights, then banishment.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Abassi Madani, leader of the Islamic Salvation Front (FIS) who was freed from jail on Tuesday, showed the world a benign face of fundamentalism while leading a party that plunged Algeria into turmoil.</p>
<p>His opponents say that behind the facade lay dictatorial political ambitions, &quot;a wolf in sheep's clothing&quot;.</p>
<p>Small, stocky and bearded, Madani, now 66, took one of the Arab world's biggest Moslem fundamentalist parties into conflict with the Algerian state.</p>
<p>The affable tone he adopted with journalists and foreigners vanished after street unrest sparked by a FIS strike in 1991 to demand changes in the election law he said favoured the old ruling National Liberation Front (FLN).</p>
<p>As unrest worsened, army tanks deployed near Kouba mosque, one of two mosques used alternately during Friday prayers by the FIS leaders to inspire their militants.</p>
<p>&quot;If the army does not withdraw we will be obliged to call a Jihad (Holy Struggle),&quot; he told 20,000 emotional supporters at Friday prayers after a night of gunfire and clashes.</p>
<p>Two days later, he was arrested along with his fiery deputy Ali Belhadj who remains in jail.</p>
<p>A former university lecturer in educational psychology, Madani headed the FIS during its 30-month life from registration after reforms to end a one-party state to its banning by a court in March 1992.</p>
<p>With Madani offering the voice of dialogue and democracy and Belhadj providing the fire and denouncing democracy, the FIS swept Algeria's first multi-party regional elections in June 1990.</p>
<p>It took control of more than half the country's townhalls and regions and its opponents said it used local authority funds and facilities ruthlessly to advance its cause.</p>
<p>Its victory shook North Africa, southern Europe and conservative Arab kingdoms, fearing the emergence of a new Iran.</p>
<p>&quot;Our victory is not only the first stone in construction of an Islamic state but repentance of this part of humanity...,&quot; Madani said.</p>
<p>But ahead of the first multi-party general election due on June 27, 1991 Madani called the general strike which was seen as a turning point in the showdown with the authorities.</p>
<p>Many diplomats saw the strike call as his biggest error.</p>
<p>Dissidents who later quit the FIS said he went ahead despite being in a minority in the FIS policy-making Madjlis Echoura.</p>
<p>But even in military jail in Blida, 50 km (30 miles) from Algiers, where he was detained before being tried in 1992, Madani kept his grip on the party.</p>
<p>Despite an internal power struggle, the party proclaimed him supreme leader and during the runup to the rescheduled general election empty chairs behind symbolic prison bars appeared at each FIS rally to recall his absence.</p>
<p>The party's provisional leader Abdelkader Hachani took the FIS to a huge lead in a first round of the rescheduled election in December 1991 and Madani's name echoed in fundamentalist areas.</p>
<p>But with more detentions and with the party driven underground after unrest following the January 1992 cancellation of the poll, mention of the FIS and leaders became something only to whisper.</p>
<p>Amid the worsening violence in 1994, President Liamine Zeroual removed Madani and Belhadj from their cells into a luxury state villa to prod them for dialogue to end the strife. The talks finally broke down and the authorities said the leaders were still sticking to their hardline Islamist demands.</p>
<p>The government then disclosed a letter it said Belhadj sent to the guerrillas urging them to step up attacks. The letter, found on the body of Armed Islamic Group (GIA) chief Cherif Gousmi, baffled analysts over the FIS leaders' ties to radical rebels.</p>
<p>FIS members have said several times that Madani suffered various illnesses during his detention. He is married and has at least three sons.</p>
<p>Two sons, Salim, aged 30, and Ikbal, 26, were each jailed in Germany last month for respectively two years eight months and two years four months after being found guilty of belonging to a criminal organisation and forging official documents.</p>
<p>Madani was born in Sidi Okba, near Biskra in east Algeria, on February 28, 1931. He did his studies in England and although he speaks both English and French, he will only use Arabic in public.</p>
<p>Arrested by the French at the start of the independence war in 1954 for implication in an attack against Radio Algiers, he was sentenced to 10 years in prison.</p>
<p>He was freed in March 1962 at the time of the ceasefire between France and the FLN which was to rule a socialist-centred state for nearly three decades.</p>
<p>He quit the party in the 1970s, denouncing the socialist ideology, and started to build clandestine support for his Islamic ideals. He was detained in 1982 for several years for espousing the creation of an Islamic state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
