<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730696" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia dlr hits fresh low for fourth day in row.</title>
<headline>Australia dlr hits fresh low for fourth day in row.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian dollar support crumbled under sustained offshore pressure at the midsession to see the currency make a fresh 18-month low for the fourth consecutive session.</p>
<p>The main driving force remained the looming risk of a Reserve Bank rate cut, which would be the fifth in the cycle, although traders said technicals are now more than bearish enough to give speculators an incentive to sell.</p>
<p>Commodity prices were also subdued despite a steadying in the Commodity Research Bureau index and made it hard for dealers to find a single reason for holding the currency.  </p>
<p>By 12.30 pm (0230 GMT) the beleagured dollar had shrunk to US$0.7347/52, another 18-month low, from an early US$0.7360/65 and US$0.7375/80 late here Monday.</p>
<p>That was down almost a cent from Friday's local finish of US$0.7445/50 and below two key support levels at US$0.7410 and US$0.7380 which analysts had expected to hold somewhat longer than a couple of days.</p>
<p>Traders said exporter and Asian bank bids were offering temporary assistance but, with US$0.7350 now creaking under the weight of offers, most thought it only a matter of time before last year's US$0.7305 trough was revisited.  </p>
<p>The area around 73 cents was also an important Fibonacci level being a 50 percent retracement of the entire uptrend from its US$0.6420 trough in October 1993 to the US$0.8210 high seen so briefly in December 1996.</p>
<p>Breaching this would thus be very significant from a technical viewpoint and could entail a further retreat to the next major targets of US$0.7100, which would be a 62 percent retracement of the uptrend, and the 1995 low point of US$0.7070.</p>
<p>Analysts reckoned it would require a break back above the US$0.7650/80 resistance area established in late May/early June to reverse the bear trend -- a rally of three cents from here.  </p>
<p>Such a recovery was not beyond the scope of imagination but would require the market to be misplaced in its expectations of another RBA rate cut.</p>
<p>A run of weak employment data has seen the 90-day bank bill future for September almost fully price in a 50 basis point easing in the cash rate to 5.0 percent. Most analysts believe the bank is only waiting on confirmation of the extremely benign inflation enviroment from data next week before delivering.</p>
<p>Today's partial figures on prices suggested there was little danger of an upside shock from the quarterly consumer price report, which is due on July 23.  </p>
<p>Manufacturing input prices for May rose 0.5 percent on the month but were 2.9 percent lower on the year, reinforcing the subdued message seen in the output price figures released on Monday which showed annual growth of just 0.8 percent.</p>
<p>The Bureau of Statistics said the decline in the dollar had led to a 0.1 percent increase in import prices for May and the 2.6 percent fall in annual terms was the smallest since March 1996. Analysts said this was a precursor of upward pressure to come if the dollar remained at these levels or fell further, although they felt it would take a run of monthly gains to make the depreciation a real concern for the RBA.  </p>
<p>Analysts remain confident the quarterly consumer price data will show both headline and underlying inflation falling further and many expect annual growth in the latter to reach 1.7 percent, its lowest level since the series began in the early 1970s.</p>
<p>On the crosses the local currency edged up on the yen to 85.11/21 from 83.70/80 but remains essentially range bound along with US$/yen. The dollar remained firm on the mark, one of the few major currencies in the world weaker than itself, and was steady at 56.5 in trade weighted terms.</p>
<p>-- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
