<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730681" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia cuts military aid to Cambodia.</title>
<headline>Australia cuts military aid to Cambodia.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Foreign Minister Alexander Downer said on Tuesday Canberra would halt its A$2 million annual military aid to Cambodia in protest at Second Prime Minister Hun Sen's military takeover.</p>
<p>But cabinet had decided that general humanitarian and development aid, worth another A$32 million a year, would continue, Downer told reporters.  </p>
<p>&quot;At this stage, the government is continuing aid projects for humanitarian reasons,&quot; Downer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has made clear its view that Hun Sen's overthrow of his coalition partner and first prime minister Prince (Norodom) Ranariddh by military action was completely unacceptable,&quot; said Downer, who met Cambodian ambassador Vun Chheang earlier on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Australia's military aid to the impoverished southeast Asian state funds communIcations and language training and maintenance of navy vessels.</p>
<p>Downer repeated Australia's call for a return to constitutional rule in Cambodia and for free and fair elections on schedule in 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
