<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73066" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German debt and futures firm, await FOMC meeting.</title>
<headline>German debt and futures firm, await FOMC meeting.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Bunds and futures were firmer in late dealings as the market traded in strong volumes while awaiting the outcome of the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting in the U.S.</p>
<p>At 1450 GMT, DTB December Bund futures were up 27 basis points at 98.13 as trading volumes in Frankfurt neared 60,000 contracts for the session.</p>
<p>Traders said the German market has already priced in the U.S. Federal Reserve raising short-term interest rates by about 25 basis points, with a hike of 50 basis points putting pressure on the spread against U.S. debt, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The worst-case scenario of a 50 basis point hike should result in a T-note/Bund spread in the vicinity of 90 basis points, while the more likely scenario of 25 basis points is expected to have little impact,&quot; MMS International said.</p>
<p>No rate cut in the U.S., which MMS favours, should push the spread back to about 70 basis points. At 1410 GMT, the U.S.-German spread was inching out to 76 basis points.</p>
<p>The German market found some support from two state reports showing a drop in September consumer prices month-on-month. Baden-Wuerttemberg said its prices fell 0.2 percent, while North Rhine-Westphalia said prices fell 0.1 percent.  </p>
<p>On a technical basis, December Bund futures were expected to find support at 98.00 and 97.92 while resistance was evident at 98.26 and 98.36.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
