<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730653" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ debt market refuses to toe line after CPI data.</title>
<headline>NZ debt market refuses to toe line after CPI data.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>------------- (Snapshot at close) -------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close</p>
<p>FUTURES					  PHYSICAL YIELD (PCT)</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS (SEP) 92.85 (PREV 92.90)  90-DAYS  7.57 (PREV 7.47)</p>
<p>3-YR BONDS   (SEP) 93.18 (PREV 93.24)  02/01    6.78 (PREV 6.70)</p>
<p>10-YR BONDS  (SEP) 93.19 (PREV 93.22)  11/06    6.79 (PREV 6.73)</p>
<p>OVERNIGHT CASH  8.00 PCT  (PREV 7.60)  US 5-YR  6.16 (PREV 6.12)</p>
<p>NZD/USD    0.6650/57 (PREV 0.6669/76)  US 10-YR 6.25 (PREV 6.22)</p>
<p>TWI 65.80  (PREV 65.81)		    US 30-YR 6.56 (PREV 6.53)</p>
<p>RBNZ MCI  NZ/MCI 765.70 (PREV 758.94) Reuters NZ MCI -59 vs -66</p>
<p>---------------------------(JULY 15)----------------------------  </p>
<p>New Zealand bank bills closed higher on Tuesday after the debt market was disappointed by inflation data, but monetary conditions remained easier than desired by the Reserve Bank.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market is taunting the bank despite the accuracy of the RB's forecast of the state of the economy and the bank could now be justified in waving its big stick.</p>
<p>The Monetary Conditions Index closed nine basis points in interest rate terms easier than the extremity of the RB's desired level.  </p>
<p>HSBC's Stefan Dunatov said the RB was now unlikely to amend its 50 b.p. band around the September quarter MCI target of 825.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result we expect the RBNZ to continue resisting moves by the market to push the MCI lower than around 70 BP were it has spoken on the last two occasions.&quot;</p>
<p>The market had eased conditions ahead of today's inflation data, hoping the numbers would suprise on the downside.</p>
<p>In the event, underlying inflation was 0.3 percent in the June quarter for an annual rate of 1.49 percent -- precisely on the bank's and the consensus forecasts.</p>
<p>But some in the market remain unbowed.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market doesn't believe the RB. It is pre-empting a further easing,&quot; said one dealer, who added that he doubted the RB wanted to take stern action as inflation was heading to the lower end of the RB's 0-3 percent target and the economy remained weak.</p>
<p>The New Zealand dollar softened in the afternoon as it has most afternoons recently and that put more pressure on the bank bills to reverse the easing.</p>
<p>One dealer said the RB would have greater confidence in its forecasts and that may embolden it to act.  </p>
<p>&quot;Their model is right. Inflation came in as expected and, armed with that, it can say 'we know what's best for the economy and you better get back inside that 50 point range or we are going to beat you about the head'. And I think they will,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There was a big divergence between the physical 90-day bills at 7.57 percent and the September futures at 92.85 percent and something would have to give, he added.  </p>
<p>Longer bond yields rose about six basis points to 6.79 percent. The global market was also turning bearish with U.S. treasuries soft, Australian 10 year futures seen near their peaks and European rates also flagging.</p>
<p>&quot;They are all showing patterns of puffing. Maybe we are in for a period of consolidation,&quot; said an Auckland bond dealer.</p>
<p>-- Simon Louisson, Wellington newsroom +64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
