<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73075" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures tagged Bund futures on Tuesday during a lacklustre session with little domestic news to spark interest ahead of the outcome of the Federal Reserve's monetary policy meeting today.</p>
<p>Traders said there was a spurt of activity early in the morning wiping out most of Monday's losses, one French brokerage was a notably buyer, then the contract settled into a range with speculation as to the chances of a Fed rate rise the main focus.</p>
<p>&quot;It's really half and half,&quot; said a trader at a French brokerage. &quot;Twenty-five basis points is in the market, but half say they might do nothing before the (presidential) election.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said overall the French market was long on bonds ahead of the FOMC outcome and that some had closed out short positions today. &quot;The domestics are definitely long of paper,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another Matif trader lamented the lack of volatility, especially given expectations for a lively autumn which many had said would be peppered with social unrest and budget worries.</p>
<p>&quot;September has turned out to be a complete non-event. There were two weeks of panic in August but there was no-one around to trade it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A call for a vote of confidence on economic policy by Prime Minister Juppe failed to ruffle many feathers in the market.  </p>
<p>Ciaran O'Hagan, bond analyst at JP Morgan in Paris, said a successful vote, which was highly likely, could actually be positive for the markets as it would remove any uncertainty.</p>
<p>&quot;He's telling them to put up or shut up,&quot; said Nick Parsons, foreign exchange strategist at Banque Paribas, referring to critics of the government's economic policies within the ruling coalition. Analysts said the outcome of the vote was a foregone conclusion, given that the ruling coalition holds four-fifths of the seats in the 577-member assembly.</p>
<p>One trader, however, said that although a win was guaranteed it could still potentially be negative for the market.  </p>
<p>Speculation about the next CADES issue continued on Tuesday, though there were few fresh angles. An issue of up to 18 billion francs, made up of a new 2005 bond and one of the 2002 or 2007 bonds remained the consensus view.</p>
<p>Sources said the spread over French government for CADES bonds could well be lower than the seven basis point spread when the fund first sold bonds in May, given that the paper was trading well in the secondary market.</p>
<p>Most primary dealers were quoting the spreads for the 2002 and 2007 CADES bonds below seven basis points on Tuesday with some putting the 2002 bond at six basis points over OATs.  </p>
<p>Banking sources also said the state French railway company, SNCF, had launched a tender for a domestic franc issue on Wednesday morning. They said it wanted to sell between 1.5 billion and 2 billion francs of TEC 10 variable rate bonds maturing in 2007.</p>
<p>The franc started weakly, slipping as slow as 3.3903 per mark early in the day, but climbed steadily to reach 3.3834 per mark, close to Monday's high of 3.3810.</p>
<p>-- David Clarke, Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
