<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730784" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam raises alarm over state budget.</title>
<headline>Vietnam raises alarm over state budget.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Edwards</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam, facing its first economic slowdown since reforms were launched in 1986, said on Tuesday that drastic measures were needed to help resolve unexpected problems affecting the state budget.</p>
<p>But it was vague about what those problems were.</p>
<p>Media reports of a weekend meeting of senior Finance Ministry and other officials said revenues had been hit hard this year by changes in import-export and incentive policies.</p>
<p>The English-language Vietnam News quoted Deputy Prime Minister Phan Van Khai as telling the meeting that falling consumer demand had affected industrial growth, while aid disbursement had been slow and foreign investment had fallen.</p>
<p>&quot;Deputy Prime Minister Phan Van Khai told senior finance officials...that it was an urgent task to 'deploy drastic measures' to fulfill planned targets for 1997 already fixed by the National Assembly at its spring session,&quot; the paper said.</p>
<p>But economists in both Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City said that while the signs were worrying, the absence of information which might indicate the extent of the problem meant it was difficult to assess the extent of Vietnam's economic woes.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be worried about the budget in terms of revenue collection,&quot; said a senior Western analyst. &quot;If the state-owned enterprises are in trouble, tax payments would drop. The problem is we don't have very accurate information on state enterprises.&quot;</p>
<p>Under Communist Party policy Vietnam's state industry occupies a leading role in the economy, despite sector-wide problems of inefficiency, low profitability, shortages of investment capital and weak management know-how.</p>
<p>Falling revenue is seen as one of three alarm trip-wires which would indicate serious problems. The others are an increase in the transfer of arrears from state firms to state banks or to state power firms in the form of unpaid utility bills.</p>
<p>But the sector is not the only one which is facing difficulties. The domestic banking industry has run aground in recent months over problems with bad debts from scandal-ridden local companies and, consequently, the issuing of new credit.</p>
<p>As with the state sector, the absence of details indicating the extent of the problem has left analysts in the dark over whether Vietnam's economy is undergoing a cyclical downturn or facing a more fundamental structural crisis.</p>
<p>Khai was quoted by the official Vietnam News Agency on Monday as saying first-half revenue to the state budget stood at only 41.4 percent of the National Assembly's 1997 target. A government ban on imports of non-essential goods -- aimed at tackling a ballooning trade deficit -- was cited as the main cause.</p>
<p>Vietnam News said the meeting had decided that while government spending would be cut in the second half of this year, some $290 million in working capital would have to be found for profit-making state-owned businesses.</p>
<p>The move drew criticism from economists.</p>
<p>&quot;What you see is a command economy, and in a command economy the government does everything,&quot; said a prominent Ho Chi Minh City analyst. &quot;But unfortunately it does not do it in the right way.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
