<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730840" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila's Napocor says no power rate hike in July.</title>
<headline>Manila's Napocor says no power rate hike in July.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The state-run National Power Corp (Napocor) said on Tuesday it would not raise its rates in July despite the possibility of fuel price increases due to the weaker peso.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no power rate increase for July and that's definite. We have enough financial resources to ride through the current aberration in the foreign exchange market. We are hedged, of course,&quot; Napocor president Guido Delgado told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Napocor is the country's biggest power generation firm. In the main island of Luzon, Napocor charges a basic rate of 1.7953 pesos per kilowatt-hour (kwh).</p>
<p>Oil refiners are expected to raise prices of petroleum products as a peso depreciation would result in higher landed cost of crude and higher exchange rate.</p>
<p>&quot;We should be able to use our current inventory to buy our fuel needs. We have enough dollars,&quot; Delgado said.</p>
<p>Delgado said the rainy season also allows Napocor to maximise the use of hydroelectric power plants.</p>
<p>Delgado, however, said the company may feel &quot;a slight negative impact&quot; on its net income due to higher interest expense. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>He said Napocor's power rates in the succeeding months will depend on the peso-dollar rate and fuel prices in the international market.</p>
<p>&quot;If the peso settles between 27 and 28, assuming there will be no change in fuel prices, there's even a possibility that there will be no power rate increase since we have enough cushion for that level in our 1997 budget,&quot; Delgado said.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (63 2) 8418939 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
