<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730860" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: IFC invests $41 million in Saigon Hilton Hotel.</title>
<headline>IFC invests $41 million in Saigon Hilton Hotel.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The World Bank's private sector financing arm said on Tuesday it would make loans totalling $41 million to partially finance construction of a new international-standard hotel in Ho Chi Minh City, the Saigon Hilton.</p>
<p>The International Finance Corporation (IFC) said in a statement that its financing would help meet demand created by increased business travel and tourism to Vietnam and be a model for similar projects.</p>
<p>&quot;IFC has been devoting significant resources to the tourism sector in Vietnam because it is a major growth industry as well as a significant foreign exchange earner and employment generator,&quot; said Javed Hamid, director of the IFC's Asia I Department.</p>
<p>The same thinking was behind the IFC's investment in Hanoi's five-star Sofitel Metropole Hotel in 1994.</p>
<p>That investment has drawn criticism because the hugely successful hotel is a joint venture between French partners and a Vietnamese state-owned firm. Critics say the IFC should be backing projects considered too risky for other investors and which also encourage private sector development.</p>
<p>The Ho Chi Minh City hotel -- which will cost a total of $81.5 million -- will be owned by Societe d'Economie Mixte Hotel Pointe des Blagueurs, a joint venture between state-owned SaigonTourist and two foreign investors.</p>
<p>The foreign partners are Feal International SA, a French firm specialising in hotel construction and renovation, and Hilton International Co.</p>
<p>Although the latest venture includes a state-owned partner, it could be said that the IFC is investing where others would hesitate.</p>
<p>A hotel glut in Ho Chi Minh City has pushed occupancy rates lower every year since 1993, hitting industry profits. According to the official daily Vietnam News, the average occupancy rate was 41 percent in the first five months of this year.</p>
<p>The IFC said its financing would consist of a $9.5-million loan for its own account, a subordinated loan of $3.55 million and a syndicated loan of $28 million for the project participants.</p>
<p>Credit Agricole Indosuez acted as co-arranger of the financing with IFC and as lead manager of the syndicated loan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
