<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730896" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Chinese yuan ends down at intraday low vs dollar.</title>
<headline>Chinese yuan ends down at intraday low vs dollar.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chinese yuan closed down at an intraday low of 8.2930 on Tuesday from Monday's 8.2910 against the U.S. dollar in Shanghai due to speculative selling in the last few minutes of trading, traders said.</p>
<p>The weighted average price on Monday was 8.2910.</p>
<p>Dealers said speculative selling in the last five minutes depressed the local currency with the market already having digested the foreign trade surplus figures announced on Monday.</p>
<p>The yuan opened higher at an intraday high of 8.2900 and fell steadily to move around 8.2910 for most of the session before slipping to the low right before the close.  </p>
<p>Trading was active with most business done at 8.2915, traders said.</p>
<p>China on Monday posted a trade surplus of $17.77 billion in the first half of 1997, against a surplus of $876 million in the same 1996 period.</p>
<p>One dealer said the strong foreign trade surplus was the reason the yuan opened at the key 8.2900 resistance level.</p>
<p>&quot;But the heavy surplus had been expected by the market,&quot; he said. &quot;So with profit-taking after the yuan opened at the key level, there was no momentum for further rises.&quot;  </p>
<p>A second dealer said the yuan closed down mainly due to speculative selling in the last five minutes of trading.</p>
<p>&quot;The yuan lost too much late in trading on Tuesday and a rebound is expected on Wednesday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected the yuan to move around 8.2920 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The yuan closed little changed at 7.2723 from 7.2730 against 100 Japanese yen and lower at an intraday low of 1.0708 from 1.0701 against the Hong Kong dollar.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai Newsroom (8621) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
