<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="730940" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Coup kills tourism in Cambodia.</title>
<headline>Coup kills tourism in Cambodia.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>ANGKOR WAT, Cambodia 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bloody coup and the onset of the rainy season have left Cambodia's magnificent 12th century ruins at Angkor Wat high and dry for tourists.</p>
<p>Never since Cambodia started down what seemed the road to lasting peace in 1991 have the monuments in the sprawling Angkor temple complex been so unvisited.</p>
<p>Angkor Wat can now be enjoyed without distraction except for pestering vendors and the occasional rumble of distant artillery.</p>
<p>&quot;Hey mister, please buy one of my Angkor Wat T-shirts, I really need the money,&quot; said a boy outside the temple who learned his English from the U.N. peacekeepers, aid workers and tourists who jump-started Cambodia's post-war economy.</p>
<p>But the peacekeepers have gone home and two days of fighting in Phnom Penh over the weekend of July 5-6 have driven many aid workers, foreign businessmen and tourists out of the country.</p>
<p>Hotels and restaurants in the nearby town of Siem Reap are virtually deserted, with journalists and a few aid workers providing most of the custom.</p>
<p>&quot;We have 95 rooms and at this time during the rainy season we would normally have about 30 rented, but now we have only seven guests and they are all reporters.&quot; said 24-year-old Sar Sopheap, cashier at Siem Reap's Tar Prohm hotel.</p>
<p>&quot;The tour agencies have cancelled all their groups for July and August. I hope that business improves by the dry season in October or we may have to close.&quot;</p>
<p>The French proprietor of the town's Only One restaurant apologises profusely for slow service to the few journalists who show up for evening meals.</p>
<p>His Cambodian staff refuse to work after dark because the situation is so unsettled around Siem Reap.</p>
<p>In truth the town seems peaceful and firmly under the control of troops loyal to Hun Sen, who ousted Cambodia's First Prime Minister, Prince Norodom Ranariddh, in the coup.</p>
<p>Fighting heard in the distance moves farther from the town every day and in no way threatens Siem Reap or the temple complexes at Angkor.</p>
<p>But for the moment Angkor remains sadly neglected as journalists, out of duty, and a few tourists, out of curiosity, monitor desultory fighting that has now moved 60 km (35 miles) west of Siem Reap.</p>
<p>For several days a Welsh backpacker and his French girlfriend pushed right up to the front line, hitching rides on motorbikes and tanks and occasionally walking.</p>
<p>The intrepid pair were full of curiosity about how reporters, TV cameramen and still photographers went about the business of war reporting.</p>
<p>For their part, the journalists expressed some interest in who the young couple were and why they were so keen to follow the troops and guns streaming west along Route 6.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess you could call us freelance tourists,&quot; the Welshman explained.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANGKOR WAT, Cambodia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
