<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731014" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PRESS DIGEST - Israel - July 15.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Israel - July 15.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>HAARETZ</p>
<p>- One dead and 66 wounded in bridge collapse at opening of Maccabiah games.</p>
<p>- Palestinian police detained on their way to attack at Jewish settlement.</p>
<p>- Two civilians dead after Israeli army fired on village in south Lebanon.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Neeman will recommend immediate budget cut of 600 million shekels.</p>
<p>- Two IsraAir pilots suspended after leaving cockpit during flight.</p>
<p>- 1,1770 young women victims of systematic sexual exploitation in Israel.</p>
<p>JERUSALEM POST</p>
<p>- Prime Minister warns of &quot;strong action&quot; on Hebron.</p>
<p>- Merrill Lynch purchases 12.5 percent stake in Bezeq.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu, Neeman, Frenkel to discuss budget today.</p>
<p>YEDIOTH AHRONOTH</p>
<p>- Disgrace at Maccabiah opening.</p>
<p>MAARIV</p>
<p>- Effort to resuscitate casualties at bridge tragedy.</p>
<p>GLOBES</p>
<p>- Full competition in the credit card market: all the banks will issue all the cards.</p>
<p>- Strike at Bezeq after sale of 12.4 percent of shares to Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu backs immediate 600 million shekel cut in 1997 budget and additional cut in 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
