<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731113" id="root" date="1997-07-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Philippine, Thai wheat buyers in currency funk.</title>
<headline>Philippine, Thai wheat buyers in currency funk.</headline>
<byline>Rene Pastor</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine and Thai wheat buyers moaned on Tuesday at the savage increase in their costs brought about by the devaluations of the peso and the baht and said they will have to raise the prices of their products.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to cost us more, I would say 15 percent on average,&quot; Kamthorn Tatiyakavee, vice-chairman of Thai President Foods, told Reuters in an interview when asked about the recent devaluation of the Thai baht.</p>
<p>&quot;At this moment, most of us are thinking the baht will go down to 32 (baht to the U.S. dollar) or something,&quot; he said on the sidelines of a conference in Singapore organised by the U.S. wheat industry.</p>
<p>Ricardo Pinca, director of corporate affairs at General Milling Corp, told the conference that the fall of the peso will force Philippine flour millers to slow their wheat buying, most of it from the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Our cost is now 20 percent more than it was five days ago. In the next few months, there will be a slowdown of wheat importations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The baht and the peso were effectively devalued within a few days of each other after being pounded by heavy speculative selling.</p>
<p>The Philippines is the second biggest buyer of wheat in Southeast Asia, consuming nearly two million tonnes in 1996, while Thailand's consumption has grown steadily to 693,000 tonnes last year from 528,000 tonnes in 1993.</p>
<p>Malaysia, where the ringgit has also come under attack, may escape what happened to Thailand and the Philippines.</p>
<p>&quot;The Malaysian flour price is fixed by the government,&quot; said Neoh Soon Bin, managing director of the Soon Soon Group of Companies. &quot;I don't think the government is going to change the flour price,&quot; he said in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>Both Kamthorn and Pinca said flour millers in the two nations will have no choice but to raise their prices.</p>
<p>&quot;People must face higher costs after the baht was floated. There is no choice,&quot; Kamthorn said.</p>
<p>A request by the Philippine government for food distributors to hold down any rise to only 10 percent will be very difficult to meet, one senior Philippine flour miller said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's highly inflationary,&quot; one senior Philippine flour miller said. &quot;Some 80 percent of our final product is derived from wheat. It will be difficult for us to follow the government on this.&quot;</p>
<p>Farm House, Thailand's major bakery company, said the price of wheat flour it had bought from mills will rise by 10 percent from next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The price could rise further if the baht keeps falling. Our industry depends a lot on import content -- wheat and milk,&quot; said a senior Farm House official.</p>
<p>&quot;The public will also be hit as we don't know how long we can shoulder the extra cost. Due to change in life style, bread and confectionery is increasingly popular,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Demand for wheat products will not probably ease soon in Thailand or the Philippines.</p>
<p>Industry officials in Bangkok said demand for wheat will probably rise to at least 750,000 tonnes in 1998.</p>
<p>Kamthorn and Pinca said strong growth in wheat consumption could also be seen in the fast food industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at the growth of the fast food industry to boost consumption,&quot; Pinca said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
