<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731252" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FULL TEXT - Apple reports Q3 loss.</title>
<headline>FULL TEXT - Apple reports Q3 loss.</headline>
<dateline>CUPERTINO, Calif. 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Apple Computer Inc Wednesday reported a smaller than expected third quarter loss of $56 million or $0.44 a share versus a loss of $32 milion or $0.26 a share in the year-ago quarter. The following is a copy of the company's results.</p>
<p>------------------ NEWS RELEASE ---------------</p>
<p>CUPERTINO, Calif., July 16 /PRNewswire/ -- Apple Computer, Inc. (Nasdaq: AAPL) today announced financial results for the Company's fiscal 1997 third quarter ended June 27, 1997. Revenues for the quarter were $1.7 billion, compared to $1.6 billion in the quarter ended March 28, 1997 and $2.2 billion in the quarter ended June 28, 1996.  International sales accounted for 53 percent of total revenues in the current quarter.</p>
<p>Gross margins for the quarter were 20.0 percent, compared to 18.9 percent in the March quarter and 18.5 percent in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>The Company recorded a net loss for the quarter of $56 million, or $(.44) per share, compared to a net loss of $708 million, or $(5.64) per share in the March quarter and a net loss of $32 million, or $(.26) per share, in the year-ago quarter.  The Company's loss from operations was $60 million, representing a significant sequential improvement from the loss from operations of $186 million, exclusive of charges for restructuring and the write-off of in-process research and development, for the March quarter.  The Company's loss from operations in the year-ago quarter was $116 million.</p>
<p>Operating expenses for the current quarter were $408 million, down $81 million from the March quarter, exclusive of charges for restructuring and the write-off of in-process research and development; and down $111 million from the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;The Company continues to progress with its restructuring initiatives, as is evidenced by the significant sequential decrease in operating expenses,&quot; said Apple CFO Fred D. Anderson.  &quot;As anticipated, we experienced sequential revenue growth, largely on the strength of our high-end Macintosh products and robust education market sales.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Our financial goals are to continue to reduce operating expenses and to return the Company to profitability,&quot; said Anderson.  &quot;Though we do not expect to return to profitability in our fourth fiscal quarter, Apple's management team is focused sharply on that objective.  We are encouraged by our customers' and developers' positive responses to our product lineup and operating system roadmap.  We eagerly await the expected launch of Mac OS 8 later this month, which we believe will provide our customers with a significantly improved user experience, enhanced performance and stability, and outstanding multimedia and Internet integration.&quot;</p>
<p>Except for the historical information contained herein, the statements in this press release are forward-looking statements that involve risks and uncertainties.  Potential risks and uncertainties include, without limitation, continued competitive pressures in the marketplace; the effect competitive factors and the Company's reaction to them may have on consumer and business buying decisions with respect to the Company's products; the consequences competitive factors and buying decisions may have on current inventory valuations; the Company's ability to successfully recruit a qualified chief executive officer; the Company's ability to successfully integrate the products and technologies acquired from NeXT Software; the ability of the Company to make timely delivery of successful technological innovations to the marketplace; the ability of the Company to successfully resolve its quality issues; the effect of any future losses on the Company's needs for liquidity; the effect of business restructuring on the future performance of the Company, especially the performance of the Company'semploye es and the need for any  future restructuring, and the effect that it might have on the performance of the Company.  More information on potential factors that could affect the Company's financial results is included in the Company's public reports filed with the SEC, including the Company's Form 10-K for the 1996 fiscal year, the Company's Form 10-Q for the second fiscal quarter, and the Company's Form 10-Q for the third fiscal quarter, to be filed with the SEC.</p>
<p>Apple Computer, Inc., a recognized innovator in the information industry and leader in multimedia technologies, creates powerful solutions based on easy-to-use personal computers, servers, peripherals, software, handheld computers and Internet content.  Headquartered in Cupertino, California, Apple develops, manufactures, licenses and markets solutions, products, technologies and services for business, education, consumer, entertainment, scientific and engineering and government customers in more than 140 countries.</p>
<p>NOTE:  Apple, the Apple logo, and Macintosh are registered trademarks of Apple Computer, Inc.  Additional company and product names may be trademarks or registered trademarks of the individual companies and are respectfully acknowledged.  </p>
<p>				     APPLE COMPUTER, INC.</p>
<p>		  CONSOLIDATED STATEMENTS OF OPERATIONS</p>
<p>		   (Dollars in millions, except per share amounts)</p>
<p>					THREE MONTHS ENDED	  NINE MONTHS ENDED</p>
<p>				     June 27,    June 28,     June 27,	June 28,</p>
<p>					 1997	  1996	  1997	     1996</p>
<p>    Net sales		     $1,737	$2,179	$5,467	   $7,512</p>
<p>Costs and expenses:</p>
<p>    Cost of sales		  1,389	 1,776	 4,419	    7,055</p>
<p>    Research and development     101	   155	   391		458</p>
<p>Selling, general and</p>
<p>     administrative		  307	   364	 1,027	    1,209</p>
<p>In-process research and</p>
<p>     development			--	    --	   375		 --</p>
<p>    Restructuring costs	     --	    --	   155		207</p>
<p>					 1,797	 2,295	 6,367	    8,929</p>
<p>    Operating loss		   (60)	 (116)	 (900)	  (1,417)</p>
<p>Interest and other income,</p>
<p>     net				   4	    65	    16		 82</p>
<p>Loss before benefit from</p>
<p>     income taxes		    (56)	  (51)	 (884)	  (1,335)</p>
<p>    Benefit from income taxes     --	   (19)	   --	     (494)</p>
<p>    Net loss			  $(56)	 $(32)	$(884)	  $ (841)</p>
<p>    Loss per common share     $(0.44)     $(0.26)     $(7.04)	  $(6.81)</p>
<p>Cash dividends paid per</p>
<p>     common share		 $   --	$   --	$   --	   $ 0.12</p>
<p>Common shares used in</p>
<p>the calculations of loss</p>
<p>per share</p>
<p>     (in thousands)	    126,500	123,735    125,547	  123,463</p>
<p>				     APPLE COMPUTER, INC.</p>
<p>				 CONSOLIDATED BALANCE SHEETS</p>
<p>						ASSETS</p>
<p>					  (In millions)</p>
<p>							     June 27,	  September 27,</p>
<p>								 1997		  1996</p>
<p>							    (Unaudited)</p>
<p>Current assets:</p>
<p>    Cash and cash equivalents			 $1,018		$1,552</p>
<p>    Short-term investments				 212		   193</p>
<p>    Accounts receivable, net of allowance     for doubtful  accounts of $100</p>
<p>     ($91 at September 27, 1996)		     1,207		 1,496</p>
<p>Inventories:</p>
<p>     Purchased parts					 175		   213</p>
<p>     Work in process					  23		    43</p>
<p>     Finished goods					  336		   406</p>
<p>								   534		   662</p>
<p>    Deferred tax assets				    307		   342</p>
<p>    Other current assets				   215		   270</p>
<p>	Total current assets			     3,493		 4,515</p>
<p>Property, plant, and equipment:</p>
<p>    Land and buildings				     460		   480</p>
<p>    Machinery and equipment				525		   544</p>
<p>    Office furniture and equipment		     121		   136</p>
<p>    Leasehold improvements				 180		   188</p>
<p>								 1,286		 1,348</p>
<p>    Accumulated depreciation and amortization     (746)		 (750)</p>
<p>    Net property, plant, and equipment		 540		   598</p>
<p>    Other assets					     308		   251</p>
<p>								$4,341		$5,364</p>
<p>				     APPLE COMPUTER, INC.</p>
<p>			 CONSOLIDATED BALANCE SHEETS (Continued)</p>
<p>			   LIABILITIES AND SHAREHOLDERS' EQUITY</p>
<p>				    (Dollars in millions)</p>
<p>								June 27,	September 27,</p>
<p>								  1997		1996</p>
<p>Current liabilities:</p>
<p>    Notes payable to banks				$127		$186</p>
<p>    Accounts payable					 812		 791</p>
<p>    Accrued compensation and employee benefits     115		 120</p>
<p>    Accrued marketing and distribution		 269		 257</p>
<p>    Accrued warranty and related			 139		 181</p>
<p>    Accrued restructuring costs			  167		 117</p>
<p>    Other current liabilities			    281		 351</p>
<p>    Total current liabilities			  1,910	     2,003</p>
<p>    Long-term debt					   951		 949</p>
<p>    Deferred tax liabilities			     284		 354</p>
<p>Shareholders' equity:</p>
<p>Common stock, no par value; 320,000,000</p>
<p>shares authorized; 126,559,143 shares</p>
<p>issued and outstanding at June 27, 1997</p>
<p>     (124,496,972 shares at September 27, 1996)    476		 439</p>
<p>    Retained earnings					750	     1,634</p>
<p>    Other							(30)		(15)</p>
<p>    Total shareholders' equity			 1,196	     2,058</p>
<p>								$4,341	    $5,364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CUPERTINO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
