<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731332" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Calif. regulators approve MCI-British Telecom deal.</title>
<headline>Calif. regulators approve MCI-British Telecom deal.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>California regulators Wednesday approved the proposed $20 billion merger of MCI Communications Corp and British Telecommunications Plc.</p>
<p>The five-member commission voted unanimously at a meeting here to approve the merger as being in the public interest. However, the commission reserved the right to reopen the review if the final Federal Communications Commission order on the merger, expected later this year, does not contain appropriate competition safeguards.  </p>
<p>The commission's six-month review focused on the change in control of MCI's California subsidiaries that will take place as a result of the merger.</p>
<p>&quot;This is one British invasion we welcome with open arms,&quot; Commissioner Jessie Knight said. &quot;Mergers of this scope have enormous potential to positively impact telecommunications competition,&quot; he said, adding that the merger may mean as much to competition in the '90s as the breakup of AT&amp;T did in the 1980s.</p>
<p>MCI operates five telecommunications carriers in California while British Telecom has no business in the state.  </p>
<p>Knight said the proposed merger would enhance MCI's competitive position with British Telecom's expertise and financial resources.</p>
<p>&quot;This enhancement will likely increase competition in the local telecommunications market, which furthers the policies of the California Public Utilities Commission (CPUC) to promote competition.&quot;</p>
<p>Knight also said the affiliation of MCI's and BT's cellular and paging services would improve services on a global scale, making California businesses better able to compete internationally.  </p>
<p>MCI surprised investors on both sides of the Atlantic earlier this week when it said it expected to post significantly higher losses than forecast because of problems breaking into local U.S. phone markets.</p>
<p>The company said regulatory restraints and foot-dragging by local monopoly telephone companies were preventing it from breaking into these markets.</p>
<p>BT Chairman Iain Vallance called for calm on Wednesday ahead of a thorough review of MCI's strategy.  </p>
<p>Shareholders of both companies have approved the merger as has the European Commission and U.S. Justice Department, each with conditions to prevent an anti competitive behavior.</p>
<p>The approval by the FCC and some states is still required.</p>
<p>In their application for CPUC approval, British Telecom and MCI said they would spend at least $20 million on infrastructure investments in California local networks.</p>
<p>The CPUC said its review of the price paid for MCI's shares &quot;leads us to conclude that it is fair and reasonable considering the value to both BT and MCI shareholders.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We find that efficiencies and operating cost savings will accrue because MCI will still operate as a separate holding company, these savings will accrue primarily in terms of the broader base for financing with the resultant corporate flexibility which it brings,&quot; the CPUC decision said.</p>
<p>Access to more financing was likely to lead to better service conditions for MCI's California rate-payers, the CPUC said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
