<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731489" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-CONFIDENCE FACTOR VITAL FOR LEHMAN.</title>
<headline>GOLF-CONFIDENCE FACTOR VITAL FOR LEHMAN.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>TROON, Scotland 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Titleholder Tom Lehman deems himself a late bloomer who had to learn to trust his golf game to become a winner.</p>
<p>The 38-year-old American who burst into golf's big-time with his superb victory at Royal Lytham last year has developed into one of the strong men of golf.</p>
<p>It was not always so, he admitted on Wednesday on the eve of the start of his title defence over the windy links of Royal Troon.</p>
<p>&quot;It took me a long time to actually start trusting my golf game and believing in myself,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Historically up until 1990 or 1991 I would get ahead and just collapse. I couldn't ever finish off a victory, whether it was an Open or a mini-tour event.&quot;</p>
<p>In recent years he has learned how to do so. Not only does he come here as champion, he comes in hot on the heels of an impressive five-stroke triumph over a strong field at the Loch Lomond world invitational last Saturday.</p>
<p>Yet it was only seven years ago that Lehman came close to quitting the game. Three poor years on the U.S. Tour from 1983 to 1985 sent him scampering to play in Asia and Africa in 1986.</p>
<p>When he returned to the United States to play the satellite tour, it still took him until 1991 to earn his way back on to the full Tour in 1992.</p>
<p>He recalled a shot on the final hole of the Tour school when he needed a birdie to make the cut to have two more rounds in the six-round event to earn his Tour card.</p>
<p>&quot;I hit an eight-iron to about two feet and made birdie to make the cut. It was the biggest shot I ever had to hit and I made a birdie,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>It was in 1990 that he almost quit. The Minnesotan was offered a position as golf coach at the University of Minnesota and was close to taking it -- until he realised he would be spending the harsh winters renting out skis instead of coaching, or playing, golf.</p>
<p>He and his wife Melissa decided he would try &quot;just one more year&quot; on the mini-tour -- and it paid off.</p>
<p>The years of 1992 and 1993 were profitable with six top-10 finishes and just over $1 million in prize money, then in 1994 he really broke through by finishing second in the Masters.</p>
<p>He won the Memorial Tournament that year for his first Tour victory and the Colonial Invitational in 1995, then last year he finished third in the U.S. Open before coming to win at Royal Lytham.</p>
<p>He added the prestigious Tour Championship by six shots, headed the U.S. money list and was named the PGA Player of the Year.</p>
<p>He was third again in last month's U.S. Open.</p>
<p>Lehman is grateful for the respect accorded him for his victory last year and admits he is keen to be remembered as much for the kind of person he is as for how good a player he is.</p>
<p>&quot;Being respected, liked and supported, that means a great deal to me,&quot; he said. &quot;I definitely wouldn't want to be the kind of person about whom people say 'The guy was a great golfer but what a jerk!'</p>
<p>&quot;That doesn't appeal to me at all.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROON, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
