<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731484" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-WATSON'S LIKING FOR LINKS TOOK TIME.</title>
<headline>GOLF-WATSON'S LIKING FOR LINKS TOOK TIME.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>TROON, Scotland 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>When Tom Watson won his second British Open title in a scintillating shootout with Jack Nicklaus at Turnberry in 1977 it was not enough to turn him into a fan of links golf.</p>
<p>Though Turnberry provided Watson with &quot;maybe the most satisfying victory I've ever had&quot;, it took a far less successful Open at Royal Lytham in 1979 to change his outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;I played miserably there. I made the cut but I struggled the whole week,&quot; the five-times champion recalled on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Until that time I didn't like links golf. I didn't like the bumps and the bounces and the so-called 'bad breaks'. I liked target golf. I liked hitting the ball through the air and stopping it. That's the way I learned when I was a youngster.&quot;</p>
<p>Having made the cut he shot 76-81 to finish joint 26th. &quot;I said to myself, 'I didn't play well but I think I understand a little bit more about the game,'&quot; said the American.</p>
<p>One hole in particular, he said, helped to sway him. &quot;It was the par-five seventh. One day I played driver, three-wood, five iron, the very next day I played driver, nine iron because the wind switched.&quot;</p>
<p>Of the previous Open at the Royal and Ancient he said: &quot;I didn't like St Andrews, the bumps and the shots it required you to make.</p>
<p>&quot;But I thought more about it in '79 and I said, 'This is not just a game of targets and through the air and yardages. This is a game of shot-making values'.&quot;</p>
<p>Of his 1977 Turnberry success he said: &quot;I played golf more through the air there. Here at Troon, you have to play a little more on the ground, like St Andrews.</p>
<p>&quot;It requires some skills you don't normally see pros using.&quot;</p>
<p>The 47-year-old Watson, who ended a nine-year drought on the U.S. Tour by winning the Memorial Tournament last year, said his present game &quot;is not particularly good.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is not as good as I would like it right now. It is not in the state that it has been when I have won tournaments.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he had made a couple of recent changes which he was happy with &quot;but I wish I had a couple more days of practice with it before I put it to the test.&quot;</p>
<p>Watson's five wins put him second on the all-time list with three other players, one behind Englishman Harry Vardon who won six between 1898 and 1914.</p>
<p>Asked what one more victory would mean to him, Watson replied: &quot;Move over Harry!&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROON, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
