<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731538" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-CARDINALS WAIVE VALENZUELA.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-CARDINALS WAIVE VALENZUELA.</headline>
<dateline>CINCINNATI, Ohio 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Less than 24 hours after Fernando Valenzuela admitted he didn't know what was wrong with his pitching, the St. Louis Cardinals on Tuesday waived the Mexican left-hander, possibly ending his career.</p>
<p>The 36-year-old Valenzuela leads the major leagues with 12 losses and has just two wins in 19 appearances. He has an earned run average of 4.96 and has allowed 106 hits in 89 innings, walking 46. He began the year with San Diego but was acquired by the Cardinals in June.</p>
<p>On Monday, Valenzuela lasted just 2 2/3 innings, allowing three runs and two hits. But he walked six and threw only 30 of 67 pitches for strikes in a 4-2 loss to the Cincinnati Reds.</p>
<p>&quot;Six walks in 2 2/3 is really too many,&quot; Valenzuela said after the game. &quot;I think something is wrong. My arm felt real good, that is why I can't understand it. I didn't have control, especially on my screwball.</p>
<p>The portly left-hander was a pleasant surprise last season for the Padres, who won the National League Western Division title. He went 13-8 with a 3.62 ERA in 33 games, including 31 starts.</p>
<p>Valenzuela has compiled a 173-153 record with Los Angeles, California, Baltimore, Philadelphia, San Diego and St. Louis during a 16-year career. He became the darling of baseball and a special favourite of the Dodgers' Mexican fans in 1981 when he won the N.L. Rookie of the Year and the Cy Young Award. He pitched a no-hitter for the Dodgers in 1990.</p>
<p>To fill Valenzuela's roster spot, the Cardinals promoted pitcher Eric Ludwick from Louisville of the American Association (AAA). Ludwick was 6-8 with four saves and a 2.96 ERA as both a starter and a reliever with the Redbirds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CINCINNATI, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
