<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731548" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: CYCLING-GERMANY HAILS ULLRICH AS NEW TOUR GIANT.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-GERMANY HAILS ULLRICH AS NEW TOUR GIANT.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany woke up on Wednesday with a new hero in Jan Ullrich, whose boyish, freckled face was on the front page of almost every newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;Ullrich, the Tour giant&quot;, read the headline of popular daily Bild a day after the 23-year-old from Rostock took control in the world's greatest cycle race.</p>
<p>The Germans, used to winning in many sports from football to tennis, have always loved the Tour de France and up until now followed it with passion but frustration.</p>
<p>Not only have they never seen one of their riders win the race but the last German to have taken the yellow jersey was Klaus-Peter Thaler, who wore it for just two days in 1978.</p>
<p>Local commentators were becoming somewhat tired of having to cite his name as well as Dietrich Thurau's or Rudi Altig's.</p>
<p>Thurau, who rode with the coveted jersey on his back for 15 days in 1977, and Altig, who had his moments of glory in the 1960s and now works on the race for television, are two of few Germans to have shone in cycling.</p>
<p>Others did well, such as Erik Zabel, who won the points classification's green jersey last year and looks set to win it again after taking three stages already so far this year.</p>
<p>But winning mass sprints was just not enough for a country so familiar with sporting honours.</p>
<p>Then Ullrich came along, signalling his class with a promising second place in 1996 before bursting into the limelight this year with two days of brilliant, seemingly effortless riding up the awesome slopes of the Pyrenees.</p>
<p>Germany had something to celebrate in the 1996 Tour with the victory of Dane Bjarne Riis, who rides alongside Ullrich in the German Deutsche Telekom stable.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom's white and pink jersey soon became one of the favourite outfits of Germans on their Sunday rides on the country's numerous cycle tracks along the Rhine or elsewhere.</p>
<p>&quot;Ullrich in yellow at last,&quot; was one of the other headlines in Bild, which used two full inside pages to greet Germany's latest sports phenomenon.</p>
<p>Riis, meanwhile, has said he would be happy to concentrate on helping his team mate keep the yellow jersey until the traditional finale on the Champs-Elysees.</p>
<p>Several newspapers told the story of Ullrich's childhood in what was then East Germany and how his life brutally changed when the Berlin Wall collapsed in 1989. He was 14.</p>
<p>Ullrich was described as a hard worker and a top athlete willing to cover 35,000 kilometres every year in his bid to emulate his idol, five times Tour winner Miguel Indurain of Spain.</p>
<p>Germans also learned that his trademark golden earring was given to him by his girlfriend Gabi, with whom he fell in love at first sight.</p>
<p>Ullrich is on the way to star status,  other big name Germans such as Boris Becker, Juergen Klinsmann and Steffi Graf are well aware it comes at a price.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
