<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731500" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-PRICE MUST OVERCOME LOSS OF FRIEND AT TROON.</title>
<headline>GOLF-PRICE MUST OVERCOME LOSS OF FRIEND AT TROON.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>TROON, Scotland 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nick Price will be battling to overcome the loss of a former caddy and close friend when he bids for his second British Open title at Royal Troon this week.</p>
<p>The Zimbabwean's former caddy Jeff &quot;Squeaky&quot; Medlen, who carried Price's clubs when he won at Turnberry in 1994, lost a two-year battle against leukaemia last month.</p>
<p>The day after Price finished 19th at the U.S. Open, Price journeyed to his friend's home in Columbus, Ohio to see his friend for the last time.</p>
<p>Within hours of the visit, Medlen died.</p>
<p>He had been released from hospital four days earlier when it became clear to the doctors they could do nothing more to help him.</p>
<p>&quot;He went home to die,&quot; Price said this week about Medlen, whose high-pitched voice earned him his nickname.</p>
<p>&quot;For me the worst thing was that I never felt he wasn't coming back. I didn't care if he never carried my bag again just as long as he lived.&quot;</p>
<p>Now Price has to sort out his emotions if he is to mount a serious challenge for the event he almost won when it was played at Troon in 1982.</p>
<p>He led by three shots with six holes to play but then squandered four shots to hand American Tom Watson the title.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a great week for me,&quot; Price recalled on Tuesday. &quot;The fact that I didn't win was hard to stomach for a couple of days but I think I learned from that experience.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe I would be the player or the person I am now had I won then.&quot;</p>
<p>Price says his game is bubbling just under the surface, competent in all areas but just lacking that bit of brilliance in any one area to make him win again.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing I would like to have done in the last four or five weeks is win a tournament. I have come close but I just have not had the final punch in my game to get through,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have not done anything exceptionally well. That's what you need to do. You need to have most of your game pretty solid and one department outstanding.&quot;</p>
<p>Price said he did not feel that world number one Tiger Woods was a strong favourite despite his impressive Masters victory in April and his rapid rise to the top of the game.</p>
<p>&quot;Tiger is learning more about his game every day,&quot; Price said.</p>
<p>&quot;Every time he goes out there as a professional he is learning something else about himself. When you play pro golf day in, day out against 120 or 140 players who can really play, you learn more and more about yourself and the game.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROON, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
