<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731706" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MCI denies profit warning a political move.</title>
<headline>MCI denies profit warning a political move.</headline>
<dateline>EDINBURGH 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>MCI Communications Corp denied on Wednesday that a surprise profit warning last week was a political move to force U.S. regulators to open up domestic markets more quickly.</p>
<p>MCI said last Thursday it expected to post significantly higher than forecast losses because of problems breaking into local U.S. markets.</p>
<p>The statement rocked a planned $20 billion merger with British Telecommunications Plc.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have been a whole lot easier to have gone out and placed an advertisement -- and less painful,&quot; an MCI spokeswoman said after an annual meeting of BT shareholders in Edinburgh.</p>
<p>MCI says regulatory restraints and footdragging by local monopoly telecom companies are preventing it from breaking into the $100 billion U.S. local markets.</p>
<p>Some analysts say MCI might be exaggerating the estimated investment needed and losses expected from its local business.</p>
<p>Other analysts believe the bearish MCI forecast may point to problems with MCI core long-distance business.</p>
<p>Salomon Brothers says that BT knew about MCI's plans for breaking into local markets and backed its efforts to dramatically highlight the footdragging by local operators.</p>
<p>BT backs MCI's call for effective action by regulators but has said it plans a thorough review of MCI's strategy following the U.S. group's surprise statement.</p>
<p>Few analysts think the merger, which will be the largest trans-Atlantic deal in history if passed by U.S. regulators, is likely to fall apart but BT may decide to renegotiate the terms.</p>
<p>MCI shareholders have been keen to point out that not all the news from BT has been good. BT has been hit by a 500 million stg windfall tax on the earnings.</p>
<p>BT's contributions to its pension fund also have to be raised considerably after tax changes, MCI shareholders have said.</p>
<p>MCI chairman Bert Roberts will be returning to Washington on Wednesday or Thursday but Jerry Taylor, the company's chief executive who also attended the meeting in Edinburgh, is likely to stay in Europe for the time being, the MCI spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 4017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EDINBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
