<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731780" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa's Old Mutual sees rate cut by Christmas.</title>
<headline>S.Africa's Old Mutual sees rate cut by Christmas.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africans can look forward to the first of two or three interest rate cuts before Christmas, Old Mutual Asset Managers economist Johan Els said on Wedensday.</p>
<p>Els was more conservative than most other economists interviewed by Reuters this week about how soon to expect the first reduction from the central South African Reserve Bank's (SARB) current 17 percent key Bank rate.</p>
<p>The bank rate last moved in November last year, when it was increased by 100 basis points.</p>
<p>Most economists said on Tuesday they expected the first 100 basis-point cut in September, with one saying a cut in August was possible and another saying it might not be before October.</p>
<p>While some predicted a four percentage-point cuts by the end of 1998, Els said he expected the rate to drop by two or three percentage points.</p>
<p>&quot;The (first) cut may come late in the year and only once the Reserve Bank is convinced that the economic fundamentals are in place to support lower interest rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reserve Bank governor Chris Stals reiterated in an interview with Reuters Financial Television last week that he would not cut rates until there was clear evidence that the growth in money supply and private credit extension was coming down.</p>
<p>Els said he expected credit creation to drop from 16.6 percent in May to between 10 and 12 percent by December.</p>
<p>&quot;Private sector credit creation will be a key number with the balance of payments figure. One can expect Dr Stals to be extremely wary of signalling too early a cut in rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Els said it was too early to celebrate the limited outflow of funds after the government's relaxation of foreign exchange controls on individuals from July 1.</p>
<p>Individuals were given the opportunity to invest up to 200,000 rand abroad, but economists estimate the outflow since July 1 at around only a million rand a day.</p>
<p>&quot;While there has been a negligible outflow of funds since the easing of exchange control, economists would want to wait for a few months at least to see if this trend is maintained.</p>
<p>&quot;By the end of Septmber we should have a clearer picture,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Els said Old Mutual, the country's biggest investment institution, expected economic growth of two percent in 1997, down from 3.1 percent last year.</p>
<p>He said the rand, which weakened to around 4.55 against the dollar after last week's fall in the gold price, could weaken further for a 1997 average of 4.60 to the dollar.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom +27 21 252238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
