<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="731863" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnia aid conference set for July 23-24.</title>
<headline>Bosnia aid conference set for July 23-24.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The World Bank said on Tuesday an international conference to raise funds for Bosnia's peacetime reconstruction will be held on July 23-24 after a six-month delay caused by political bickering.</p>
<p>&quot;The donors' conference has been agreed for July 23 and 24 in Brussels,&quot; Saumya Mitra, from the World Bank's office in Sarajevo, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Invitations in the name of the World Bank and the European Commission will be going out today to Bosnian authorities and the donors,&quot; Mitra said.</p>
<p>The conference was originally scheduled for January but had to be postponed several times because of disputes between leaders from the country's Serb and Moslem-Croat territories.</p>
<p>Western officials said major powers decided to drop one of the conditions for the aid conference to avoid further delays.</p>
<p>Donor countries had previously demanded that Bosnia clinch a stand-by agreement with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) as a precondition for holding the conference.</p>
<p>But rival Serb and Moslem-Croat federation representatives could not agree on the design of an interim currency, which has held up the $100 million IMF deal.</p>
<p>The design of the currency is a politically sensitive issue in Bosnia, which was devastated by a 3-1/2 year war. Serb leaders have insisted on the use of nationalist symbols in the design which Bosnian Moslem officials find offensive.</p>
<p>The adoption last month of a package of economic legislation, including laws on a central bank, state budget, debt service and customs regulations, helped clear the way for the conference, Mitra said.</p>
<p>The World Bank hoped to win pledges from organisations and more than 30 donor governments for $1.4 billion in aid in 1997, he said.</p>
<p>The conference was expected to focus on raising funds for the restoration of the country's power and water networks and for the construction of housing for refugees.</p>
<p>Some foreign experts, who asked not to be named, said it was unclear whether the conference would manage to reach the 1.4 billion target.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether the donors will really come up with that is not very unlikely. The mood among the donors is not the best,&quot; said one Western official, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Donor governments, facing their own economic troubles at home, might be reluctant to offer significant aid as long as Bosnia's inter-ethnic government remained virtually paralysed by political quarrels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
