<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732031" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks pull back from &quot;samba effect&quot;.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks pull back from &quot;samba effect&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks rebounded sharply at the close Wednesday from a heady dive during the prior session.</p>
<p>Dealers and analysts said buyers returned to the market to hunt bargains as fears subsided of contagion from a possible devaluation and fire sale in Brazilian financial markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday's slide was due to Brazil rather than domestic fundamentals, and that means things look better in the long run,&quot; said Roberto Garcia, a fund manager at the Vector brokerage.</p>
<p>Final closing prices showed the blue-chip IPC share index was up 93.08 points, or 1.98 percent, at 4,787.43.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's rebound was more than just technically grounded, it shows a return of market confidence,&quot; said Hector Jimenez, an analyst with the Inverlat brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;We reacted in tandem with other markets, a sort of domino effect,&quot; Jimenez added, referring to rallies in New York and Brazil. &quot;Bancomer and Telmex hauled us up.</p>
<p>The Bovespa index of most active stocks traded in Sao Paulo ended up up 8.81 percent at 12,641 points. The Dow Jones, meanwhile, soared 63.17 points to a record close of 8,038.88.</p>
<p>Dealers said brisk trading volume of 114 million shares underpinned the strong presence of buyers in the market.</p>
<p>Financial firm Bancomer climbed 33 centavos (4 centavos) to 4.38 pesos (56 cents) and telecommunications company Telefonos de Mexico (Telmex) ended up 35 centavos (4.5 cents) at 20.65 pesos ($2.62). The two stocks together accounted for almost 30 percent of all shares traded during the session. Telmex American Depositary Receipts rose 1-7/16 to end at 52-1/4.</p>
<p>Garcia said some brokers began to position themselves ahead of second-quarter earnings reports expected in the coming days.</p>
<p>&quot;Players with liquidity on their hands took advantage of the slide to pick up bargains. All we have on the horizon now are Q2 earnings,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They are stepping into food, beverages, tobacco, construction and transportation,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Beverage firm Fondo Economico Mexicano was near the head of the prominent gainers' list after rising 4.30 pesos (55 cents) to 53.00 pesos ($6.73) in brisk trade. Construction firm Tribasa also traded strongly and advanced 1.30 pesos (16 cents) to 24.60 pesos ($3.12).</p>
<p>On the broad market, gainers outpaced sliders by 85 to 21, out of a total of 124 stocks that changed hands.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
