<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732139" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Banacci Q2 results forecast short of Q1.</title>
<headline>Banacci Q2 results forecast short of Q1.</headline>
<byline>Henry Tricks</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grupo Financiero Banamex Accival (Banacci) is expected to report a profit of about 51 centavos per share in the second quarter, slightly short of the first quarter's, according to a Reuter survey of banking analysts.</p>
<p>Net of revaluation surplus, the earnings are expected to be 25 centavos per share -- a figure not normally reported by Banacci but one that analysts say more accurately reflects its results.  </p>
<p>Its total income including revaluation surplus is expected to be about 880 million pesos, which compares with 971 million pesos in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Comparisons with Q2 1996 are invalid because Mexico introduced radical new accounting rules in January.</p>
<p>This Q2 result, analysts said, is expected to include deferred tax credits as it did in the previous quarter which may disguise lingering weakness in the bank's earnings statement, analysts said.  </p>
<p>They also said the results of the banking group, which owns Mexico's biggest bank Banamex, are expected to be tarnished by further deterioration of its mortgage portfolio.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of earnings they're likely to be pretty good...but more due to good trading income,&quot; said Susana Ornelas, bank analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in Mexico. &quot;In terms of asset quality, I think we're going to see an important deterioration.&quot;  In the first quarter, Banamex's past-due mortgage loans rose much more sharply than those of its closest rival Bancomer, and some analysts expect the weakness persisted in the second quarter.  </p>
<p>Carlos Gomez, bank analyst at Paribas Capital Markets in New York, said he expects Banamex past-due loans grew by four percent, with all new bad loans coming in the mortgage sector.</p>
<p>Overall asset quality, he predicted, would be pretty much in line with Q1's, with past-due loans at 20.6 percent of total loans.  Reserve coverage was likely to hover around 60 percent.</p>
<p>He also expected net interest income to decline because of lower inflation.  Under Mexico's new accounting rules, inflation on past-due mortgages is registered as interest income, he said.  </p>
<p>According to Brent Erensel, banking specialist at UBS Securities in New York, declining interest rates in the quarter were expected to improve the bank's cost of funding, as well as boost trading gains because of the growth in Mexican equity and fixed-income markets.</p>
<p>But he said loan demand at Banamex was still not expected to have grown.  Credit growth in Mexico has been stifled since the 1994-1995 economic crisis.</p>
<p>A table with analysts projections for the second quarter of 1997 follows. All figures are in pesos:  </p>
<p>1) Including revaluation surplus:</p>
<p>				     EPS		Total Profit</p>
<p>    UBS Securities	     0.50		890 million</p>
<p>    Paribas			0.52		877 million</p>
<p>2) Excluding revaluation surplus:</p>
<p>    Credit Lyonnais	    0.15		N/A</p>
<p>    Probursa		     0.28		495 million</p>
<p>    Deutsche Morgan Grenfell 0.32		545 million</p>
<p>    Merrill Lynch		0.12		N/A</p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9569))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
