<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732149" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Distribution key hurdle in Brazilian insurance.</title>
<headline>Distribution key hurdle in Brazilian insurance.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Vowinkel</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign insurers entering the Brazilian market will find distribution, rather than state regulation, to be their biggest problem, the head of one of Brazil's leading insurers said.</p>
<p>Brazil has been attracting a great deal of interest from foreign insurers in the last year or so as deregulation and economic growth have improved the prospects for the insurance market, said Itau Seguros president director Luiz de Campos Salles, a speaker at an insurance conference here.</p>
<p>Indeed, Campos Salles said he expects total premium volume in Brazil to at least double in the next 10 years as the country's insurance consumption expands.</p>
<p>Insurance penetration, or premiums as a percentage of the country's gross domestic product, is likely to double to 4-5 percent from a current two percent, he said.</p>
<p>But the distribution problem is so serious, he said, he was not particularly concerned about foreign competition.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not very preoccupied with the foreign competition,&quot; Campos Salles told Reuters in an interview after his presentation Tuesday at an International Insurance Society Conference here.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm more preoccupied with the Brazilian competition, with some of my more clever competitors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign companies, when they begin bringing distribution know-how, that is the time when I will be disturbed. Until then, I'm not really disturbed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The reason distribution is such a problem is that Brazil is still a poor country despite recent economic gains and brokers have far fewer prospects per square mile in Brazil than they do in the United States, he said.</p>
<p>Therefore, Brazilian insurers must pay brokers commission rates of as much as 30 percent compared with about seven percent in Europe.</p>
<p>Although Brazil's overall population is probably greater than in other developed countries, &quot;the density of possible targets is much, much smaller,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Because a Brazilian broker makes far fewer sales than his counterparts in more developed countries, the &quot;companies have to pay for his survival a much higher commission,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he said, other new distribution methods, such as direct, affinity and worksite marketing are only just now being introduced in Brazil.</p>
<p>Direct marketing and worksite marketing have potential for success in Brazil, he said.</p>
<p>But, he said, he was not optimistic about the prospects for affinity marketing, which involves the sale of insurance through associations, such as the AARP.</p>
<p>Affinity groups are simply not part of the Brazilian culture the way they are in the United States, Campos Salles said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think, for Brazil, that is a long time away from any success,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However, he said he believes worksite marketing will be very important and said Itau Seguros plans to begin selling auto and homeowners insurance through that channel.</p>
<p>Although foreign insurers have expertise in some of these new distribution methods, he said he believes the trick is understanding the culture.</p>
<p>&quot;To know what to distribute, how, the least inefficient way of doing it, to whom, that is where the foreign companies need a tremendous amount of local help,&quot; Campos Salles said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
