<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732285" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thailand not seeking IMF loans, officials say.</title>
<headline>Thailand not seeking IMF loans, officials say.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Thailand and finance ministry officials said on Wednesday that Thailand has not considered seeking loans from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to help ease its liquidity and economic problems.</p>
<p>Central bank spokeswoman Duangmanee Wongprateep said Thailand had not asked for financial assistance from an IMF team now visiting the country. The team is in Thailand to help assess government measures for bailing out cash-strapped or troubled financial institutions.</p>
<p>&quot;In theory, (an IMF loan) is an option open to us but we have not moved to consider seeking one from them,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>Central bank officials said a separate IMF team has visited Thailand to provide technical advice on how to implement the baht's managed float policy. The baht was floated on July 2.</p>
<p>Thailand let its baht depreciate sharply early this month after the currency faced speculative pressure for several weeks.</p>
<p>Finance ministry sources said an IMF loan was still not required despite Thailand's current economic downturn, the worst in over a decade.</p>
<p>&quot;No move has been made (on borrowing from the IMF). Such a need would arise if our foreign reserves were greatly depleted but it is premature to say our reserves have plunged because of central bank intervention (to defend the baht),&quot; a finance ministry official said.</p>
<p>He said some of the forward baht/dollar positions taken by the Bank of Thailand in May in defence of the baht had still not matured, making it difficult to determine how much foreign exchange the central bank would use in its intervention.</p>
<p>&quot;Borrowing from the IMF would subject Thailand to certain austerity conditions and we should consider them first,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However, analysts said that while Thailand may not need IMF financial assistance it could benefit from loans by the agency because these would be viewed by the financial market as a stamp of approval of the country's economic adjustment policies.</p>
<p>The Thai stock market rallied sharply on Wednesday as regional funds moved into the bourse on hopes that the IMF may be preparing to step in and help the economy.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Thanong Bidaya and Bank of Thailand Governor Rerngchai Marakanond go to Tokyo on Wednesday night for talks with their Japanese counterparts on the country's economic situation.</p>
<p>Japan appears to have linked financial aid for Thailand's ailing economy to IMF involvement in its economic management.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662)-6520642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
