<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732281" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan to withdraw Cambodia rescue planes.</title>
<headline>Japan to withdraw Cambodia rescue planes.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan on Thursday will withdraw the three Self-Defence Force planes that were sent to Thailand in preparation for a possible evacuation of Japanese nationals from Cambodia, government officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;I will issue the instructions tonight and the planes will leave for Japan on Thursday morning,&quot; Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto told reporters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, government spokesman Seiroku Kajiyama told a news conference that a decision on whether to withdraw the planes would depend on meetings between Japanese and Cambodian officials.</p>
<p>Japanese ambassador to Cambodia Shohei Naito met Second Prime Minister Hun Sen on Wednesday to convey Japan's position and to determine whether the situation in Cambodia was under control. Japan's special envoy to Cambodia Yukio Imagawa also met King Norodom Sihanouk, now in Beijing, for a similar purpose.</p>
<p>Three C-130 Hercules transport planes left for Thailand last Saturday, in the first dispatch of a military aircraft since the end of World War Two on an overseas mission other than a training flight.</p>
<p>But Cambodian Vice Information Minister Khieu Kannariddh had said Cambodia would not allow the Japanese planes into the country, as the situation had largely returned to normal.</p>
<p>Kajiyama said almost all Japanese nationals who wished to leave Cambodia have already left.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
