<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732327" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar signs oil, gas deals with ARCO.</title>
<headline>Qatar signs oil, gas deals with ARCO.</headline>
<dateline>DOHA 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar on Wednesday signed two oil and gas agreements with a consortium led by Atlantic Richfield Company (ARCO) of the United States.</p>
<p>The first agreement is a 25-year exploration and production sharing contract for marine block 11, located northeast of the Qatari mainland.</p>
<p>The second accord allows the consortium to develop and produce natural gas from a part of the mammoth North Field -- the world's largest single concentration of gas -- and market it in the Gulf.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreements represent a new era of exploration and production of oil and gas in our country,&quot; Qatari Minister of Energy and Industry Abdullah bin Hamad al-Attiyah told reporters after the signing.</p>
<p>Other members of the consortium are Gulfstream Resources Ltd of Cyprus -- a subsidiary of Gulfstream Resources Canada Ltd, British Gas Plc's British Gas Exploration and Production Ltd, and the German firms Wintershall AG -- a subsidiary of BASF AG -- and Preussag Energie GmbH.</p>
<p>Qatar aims to boost oil production capacity to over 900,000 barrels per day bpd) and gas sales to around 25 million tonnes a year by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Under the exploration and production sharing agreement, the consortium will be required to conduct a new 2-dimensional (2-D) seismic and gravity survey over a minimum of 2,000 sq km and reprocess the existing 2-D seismic data of at least 500 sq km.</p>
<p>The consortium will also conduct a comprehensive multidisciplinary geological study and drill a minimum of two exploration wells during the first four years of the contract period.</p>
<p>Under the second agreement, the consortium will produce and market gas in the Gulf region in return for a share in the gas output. Condensates and other liquids will be marketed separately.</p>
<p>The already operates Qatar's offshore Al-Rayyan field which currently produces 32,000 bpd of crude oil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
