<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732324" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: New head of Egypt exchange wants easy investing.</title>
<headline>New head of Egypt exchange wants easy investing.</headline>
<byline>Miral Fahmy</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO, Egypt</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Easy access, easy exit&quot; is the motto of the new chairman of the Egyptian stock exchange, Canadian-educated former fund manager Sherif Raafat.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to make investing in the market simple, easy and we have to change the system, the infrastructure. We need more disclosure, education and bright young people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The recent appointment of 51-year-old Raafat marked a major change. The government had for decades filled the post with state-sector cronies, often with little knowledge of market operations.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a signal that the government is moving in the right direction -- it is hiring people who are pure professionals and not politicians or bureaucrats. They're hiring people on credentials and not on loyalty,&quot; said Shireen AlKady, vice chairman at market analysts Prime Investments.</p>
<p>Books about emerging markets and their more established counterparts litter Raafat's spacious office at the Cairo exchange.</p>
<p>He said his immediate aim is to increase market transparency and update the infrastructure to make investing easier.</p>
<p>&quot;I was at a conference recently where they said the best part about Egypt is that it has a history of 4,000 years but the bad side is that it has a bureaucracy that is also just as old,&quot; Raafat said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we build it on a good basis then we will succeed. But if we cut corners, then we'll end up like a lot of other emerging markets that never made it.&quot;</p>
<p>Although the exchange has an automatic matching system and a clearing house, brokers say transactions take days and much effort to process.</p>
<p>Timely corporate information is not readily available and the few trading rules are not strictly enforced.</p>
<p>Hardy local and foreign investors have so far taken these matters largely in their stride but Raafat says these factors are hampering market growth.</p>
<p>&quot;If an investor is willing to put $20 million in the market knowing that it will take him six months to get in and six months to get out, then he might double or even triple that amount if it only takes him a few days,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We must have more liquidity, and rules and penalties. We don't want to regulate to the extent that we stifle the market but we have to put some principles in place.&quot;</p>
<p>Raafat has yet to execute his many ideas but he already has a reputation among traders as a revolutionary.</p>
<p>He says anything that will ease trading and is in the interest of the investor is good -- and that applies not only to the bourse but to the privatisation programme, the flagship of the government's economic policy.</p>
<p>He believes the government must give up more majority stakes in state firms to attract the institutional investors necessary to give the exchange more depth.</p>
<p>&quot;Why are we encouraging the weak hands, the small investors, and cutting off the strong hands like the institutions who will stay and develop the bourse?&quot; he said. &quot;We must give them priority and increase liquidity.&quot;</p>
<p>The state must also improve its offering format from local newspaper advertisements and increase the public's access to such offerings by establishing mini-brokerages in the state-owned banks and their branches, Raafat added.</p>
<p>His long-term goals include weaning the exchange from the government's share offerings and making it a forum where private-sector firms raise capital. He also sees it as a tool to channel direct foreign investment into the country.</p>
<p>Brokers say that the lack of fresh issues was one of the main reasons the all-share index of the exchange fell to five-month lows in early July.</p>
<p>&quot;Egypt is a signatory to the WTO (World Trade Organisation treaty) and private-sector firms used to being protected by tariffs will have to improve and they could use the bourse (stock exchange) to raise capital,&quot; Raafat said.</p>
<p>&quot;If someone wants to set up a factory, then he can raise some money through the bourse. This will contribute in some way to increasing the country's GDP.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO, Egypt"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
