<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732491" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Louisiana judge declare mistrial in breast implant trial.</title>
<headline>Louisiana judge declare mistrial in breast implant trial.</headline>
<byline>Jua Nyla Hutcheson</byline>
<dateline>NEW ORLEANS 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A state judge Wednesday declared a mistrial in the first-ever class action silicone breast implant case to go to trial against Dow Chemical Co.</p>
<p>New Orleans District Court Judge Yada Magee ended the trial on the grounds of &quot;prejudicial misconduct,&quot; primarily gestures and non-verbal communications, made by plaintiffs' counsel.</p>
<p>A few hours later, after another hearing, Magee said she would reconsider the mistrial ruling overnight and issue a decision Friday morning, said Dawn Barrios, one of the plaintiffs' attorneys.</p>
<p>The jury in the three-month-long trial will not be dismissed until Monday to give plaintiffs time to appeal the decision, Magee said in a separate order before deciding to reconsider.</p>
<p>Barrios said the written reasons for the mistrial appeared to target Houston attorney Tom Pirtle. But in the hearing, she said, defence attorneys complained about all plaintiffs attorneys.</p>
<p>In the mistrial order, Magee wrote, &quot;In this instance ... the court does recognise that plaintiffs' counsel is 'very engaging.' It cannot be transcribed in a record, but the court is aware that he has a pleasant disposition and a charismatic personality ... Plaintiff nor their counsel should be penalised by his natural charisma.&quot;</p>
<p>But, she said the &quot;effect of plaintiffs' counsel conduct does prejudice the defendant.&quot;</p>
<p>The lawsuit initially covered an estimated 14,000 women who received silicone breast implants, 1,700 of whom recieved implants manufactured by now-bankrupt Dow Corning Inc.</p>
<p>The case was pared down to focus on damages claimed against Dow Chemical by eight class representatives, with the remainder of the case concerning Dow-Corning implant recipients transferred to a Michigan federal court at the urging of Dow Chemical.</p>
<p>The Louisiana lawsuit alleges that Dow Chemical, owner of 50 percent of Dow Corning, is liable for health problems stemming from the implants because it allegedly tested silicone compounds in its laboratories for Dow Corning, which was dismissed from the case because of bankruptcy proceedings.</p>
<p>The case against Bristol-Myers Squibb Co., another manufacturer, will be tried later.,</p>
<p>Magee split the trial into four phases. In the current phase, the jury was to determine if Dow Chemical bears some reponsibility for testing and safety.</p>
<p>Dow Chemical maintains there is no scientific proof that silicone implants cause medical problems and that even if they do, Dow Chemical bears no responsibility for them.</p>
<p>An estimated 1 million American woman have received breast implants, about 80 percent of them for cosmetic reasons. Several thousand say they suffered serious immune system and connective tissue disorders after the implants leaked or ruptured.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW ORLEANS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
