<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732579" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton picks Shelton as top U.S. military officer.</title>
<headline>Clinton picks Shelton as top U.S. military officer.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton has chosen Army Gen. Henry Shelton to be the next chairman of the U.S. Joint Chiefs of Staff, a U.S. official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The official, who asked not to be identified, said Clinton was expected to announce the nomination of Shelton, a 34-year veteran who now heads the U.S. Special Operations Command, to become the top U.S. military officer on Thursday morning.  </p>
<p>Defence Secretary William Cohen on Wednesday gave Clinton his formal recommendation that Shelton replace Army Gen. John Shalikashvili as the top U.S. military officer and accompanied him to the White House for an interview with the president, U.S. officials said.</p>
<p>Cohen's first choice, Air Force Gen. Joseph Ralston, withdrew from consideration last month after disclosure of an adulterous affair more than 10 years ago when he was separated from his wife. Ralston is vice chairman of the joint chiefs.</p>
<p>Shelton, a 34-year veteran who commanded the U.S. military operation in Haiti three years ago, now heads the U.S. Special Operations Command, an elite group of 47,000 Army, Navy and Air Force troops.</p>
<p>A native of Tarboro, North Carolina, Shelton did not attend the elite U.S. Military Academy at West Point. He holds a degree in textile engineering from North Carolina State University and a master's degree from Auburn University in Alabama.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
