<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732512" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USDA aide sees good US soy, cotton sales to China.</title>
<headline>USDA aide sees good US soy, cotton sales to China.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. soybean and cotton sales to China should continue at their recent healthy pace, but prospects for U.S. wheat and corn are not so promising, a U.S. Agriculture Department aide said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not expect to see us exporting a lot of corn or wheat to China this year,&quot; said Scott Reynolds, USDA's agricultural trade officer in Shanghai. &quot;But that doesn't mean (U.S. bulk commodity sales are) completely out because cotton and soybeans and soybean meal are doing very well.&quot;  </p>
<p>U.S. cotton exports to China totaled slightly more than 1.5 million bales in the first 11 months of 1996-97, down from about 1.75 million for the same period in 1995-96 but still strong.</p>
<p>The big success story this year has been U.S. soybeans, soymeal and soyoil sales to China.</p>
<p>The U.S. has exported more than 1.5 million tonnes of soybeans, 565,500 tonnes of soymeal and 337,600 tonnes of soyoil so far in 1996-97, compared to 263,500 tonnes of soybeans, no soymeal and 135,500 tonnes of soyoil in same period in 1995-96.  </p>
<p>Fueling that demand is Chinese hog and poultry production, which has grown rapidly in recent years in response to rising incomes. To a lesser degree, imported soybean and soymeal is also going into Chinese fish farm production, he said.</p>
<p>Forecasts for China to harvest large wheat and corn crops for a second consecutive year have reduced its need for imports of those commodiites, Reynolds said.</p>
<p>In addition, China still refuses to accept U.S. wheat from the Pacific Northwest because of its concerns with a fungus known as TCK smut sometimes present in that crop, he said.  </p>
<p>Last year, China's refusal to accept any wheat shipments that might contain TCK smut led to the cancellation of U.S. wheat sales totaling more than 1 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The U.S. has long maintained that China's objections are not based on sound science and that TCK smut poses no threat to human health or to China's own wheat crop.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, China chose to strictly enforce its zero tolerance standard for TCK smut last year despite a 1992 pledge to do away with all food and plant safety standards not based on sound science.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure,&quot; Reynolds said, when asked if the Chinese had, in effect, a continuing ban on all U.S. wheat imports.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese buy when they wish to buy and it's not always easy to predict that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But in years like the current one when the Chinese have a large crop, &quot;their import demand will be less,&quot; Reynolds said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that they will be able to meet their needs in wheat (this year) with very small or (zero) imports from the United States,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Washington newsroom, ((202-898-8300))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100138">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
