<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732653" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS --up 1/2 after inflation data.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS --up 1/2 after inflation data.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bond prices gained at least 1/2 point Wednesday mainly on the strength of a favorable inflation report, market participants said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was pretty active, there was a lot of secondary trading,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Treasury prices outpaced the gains in muncipals, after the Labor Department said consumer prices in June rose just 0.1 percent overall, versus expectations for a 0.2 percent rise.</p>
<p>The figure was another piece of reassuring news for investors counting on inflation to remain tame, and offered more validation for the Federal Reserve's decision to hold interest rates steady.</p>
<p>The government long bond rallied throughout the day, breaking through the 6.50 percent yield barrier late in the session on price gains of nearly a full point.</p>
<p>In new issue news, Merrill Lynch &amp; Co. said it postponed until next week a $162 million Hawaii Housing Finance and Development Corp refunding deal expected today.</p>
<p>Goldman Sachs &amp; Co said it repriced United Nations Development Corp's $162 million issue, lowering yields. .</p>
<p>Bear Stearns &amp; Co. said it repriced $38 million Methodist Health Systems, Tenn., bonds, cutting yields and lowering the par amount from $47 million.</p>
<p>On the competitive side, Raymond James &amp; Associates won the largest deal, a $41 million Texas Public Facilities Authority deal, and reoffered the 2015 maturity at 5.25 percent. The 2017 was not formally reoffered. </p>
<p>September municipal bond futures closed up 29/32 to 120-13/32, while September Treasury bond futures gained 24/32 to 114-22/32. The MOB spread widened to 183 ticks from 178 at the close on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In the secondary market, bids on Bexar County, Texas, MBIA 5-1/4s of 2027 were down one basis point to 5.52 percent.</p>
<p>Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority FGIC 5.0s of 2027 were down four basis points to 5.35 percent.</p>
<p>Municipal bond sales for Thursday were expected to total $422 million in 22 sales, according to Reuters Municipal Bond Information Group.</p>
<p>Negotiated offerings total $133 million in eight sales, with a $32 million Colorado Regional Transportation District offering through George K. Baum &amp; Co. topping the list.</p>
<p>On the competitive side, 14 sales totaling $290 million are scheduled. A $200 million Florida Department of Transportation offering at 1100 EDT is the largest.</p>
<p>--Steven Dickson, 212-859-1652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
