<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732603" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMF welcomes Indian growth, seeks structural change.</title>
<headline>IMF welcomes Indian growth, seeks structural change.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund welcomed India's strong economic growth on Wednesday, but said the authorities should press on with fiscal consolidation and structural reform.</p>
<p>A statement on the Indian economy released two weeks after the IMF board considered its annual economic review said Indian GDP growth had averaged seven percent a year over the last three years.</p>
<p>&quot;The continuation of strong economic growth without major signs of an acceleration in inflation...was welcome evidence of the continuing robust supply response to the structual reforms initiated in the early 1990s,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Directors reiterated that to sustain high growth, reduce poverty and realise India's economic potential, it would be necessary to make decisive progress towards fiscal consolidation and push forward with the still long agenda for structural reform.&quot;</p>
<p>The IMF warned Indian authorities against reacting to a slowdown in growth by attempting to stimulate the economy too much and described a large public sector deficit as a drag on economic growth.</p>
<p>Tax cuts should be complemented with measures to improve tax administration, widen the tax base and reduce the number of tax exemptions. Reforms to the financial sector should be speeded up and bank supervision should be strengthened.</p>
<p>&quot;Directors stressed that the best prospects for achieving a fundamental improvement in the banks' operating efficiency would result from an increase in the rpivate sector's role in bank management,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The IMF also said authorities should accelerate disinvestment, raise petroleum prices substantially and phase out fertiliser subsidies.</p>
<p>IMF officials have long called on India to deepen economic reforms, viewing this as a recipe for even faster growth. The government has targeted eight percent growth in the year to April 1998, after 6.8 percent in 1996-97.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
