<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="732915" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch ECT facing counter bid for terminal takeover.</title>
<headline>Dutch ECT facing counter bid for terminal takeover.</headline>
<dateline>ROTTERDAM 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch stevedoring group ECT is facing a counter bid for control of Rotterdam's Bell Mertens Terminal from a joint venture between Irish Continental Group and Mersey Docks and Harbour Co, the companies said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Nearly all 153 employees of Bell Mertens, the Dutch unit of bankrupt Irish group Bell Lines, have been blocking the road into one of ECT's two terminals all day to protest at what they see as an inferior offer from ECT (Europe Combined Terminals).</p>
<p>ECT is owned by three Dutch firms -- Nedlloyd, Pakhoed, Internatio-Mueller -- and state-owned Dutch Railways.</p>
<p>Bell Mertens' spokeswoman Gerda van Dijk said ECT was offering insufficient guarantees to safeguard jobs and employees favoured the bid from IGC/Mersey Docks.</p>
<p>In a further complication, the port of Rotterdam, which controls an option on the lease for the Bell Mertens Terminal, issued a statement on Wednesday supporting the ECT bid.</p>
<p>Bob Richardson, the IGC representative conducting the talks in Rotterdam told Reuters the authority's position had caused a stalemate.</p>
<p>&quot;We and Mersey Docks have put in a joint offer, seriously addressing the employment situation and offering a generous social plan,&quot; he said, adding that under the plan, 50 current members of staff would lose their jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;But by virtue of the port authority effectively giving the option on the lease ot only one party, they're denying the staff the option of getting the best deal for themselves,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bell Mertens' Van Dijk said the company's employees saw this a better deal than was being offered by ECT.</p>
<p>&quot;We want ECT to withdraw their offer, and our employees are making that point. We have nothing to lose,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>An ECT spokesman said the company planned to sit down with the trade unions involved and try and work out any problems with its offer, which also involved the unlisted Rotterdam firms of Steinweg and Lehnkering Montan.</p>
<p>&quot;We're trying to find a solution,&quot; Jos Dekkers told Reuters.</p>
<p>The blockade of ECT had not affected its cargo loading and unloading but it had stopped lorries leaving and entering the terminal, used for intercontinental container traffic.</p>
<p>The Bell Mertens terminal started operations about a year ago and handles around 260,000 containers a year, mostly for short sea routes from Britain and Ireland to Rotterdam.</p>
<p>Waterford-based Bell Lines went into liquidation on July 4 with debts of around 40 million Irish pounds.</p>
<p>-- David Evans, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 02 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROTTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
