<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733431" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU unveils farm reform plans for expansion east.</title>
<headline>EU unveils farm reform plans for expansion east.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG, France 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission unveiled proposals on Wednesday for further price-cutting farm reforms to prepare for expansion eastwards and prevent the return of costly food mountains.</p>
<p>The proposals, known as Agenda 2000, reinforce 1992 reforms to make European farmers more competitive by lowering prices towards world levels and shifting support for agriculture to direct payments to farmers.</p>
<p>&quot;We wish to remain competitive, continue to export and to develop rural areas,&quot; European Commission President Jacques Santer told the European Parliament.</p>
<p>Santer said that lower intervention prices would also ease the integration of eastern European countries, whose prices are generally much lower, reduce the risk of an uncontrolled growth in production and keep spending under control.</p>
<p>Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler said that higher payments to farmers to compensate for income losses due to the planned price cuts could be defended in the next round of world farm trade talks.</p>
<p>The U.S., which has completely decoupled subsidies from production, is likely to lead an attack on the aid in World Trade Organisation (WTO) negotiations starting in 1999 on reducing trade distorting farm subsidies.</p>
<p>&quot;It won't make life easy in the WTO but we are going to defend it,&quot; Fischler told a news conference.</p>
<p>Fischler added, &quot;The U.S. won't like our intention to increase (farm) exports.&quot;</p>
<p>By reducing support prices to competitive levels, the EU hopes to export more grain and other farm products without the routine use of subsidies and thus avoid curbs imposed under the GATT Uruguay Round Agreement.</p>
<p>Another major feature of the reforms is to suspend a compulsory scheme to cut output by setting aside farmland, unpopular with both farmers and taxpayers.</p>
<p>But in a controversial new move reflecting criticism that cereal farmers have been heavily over-paid, the EU executive proposed that they should only be compensated for half of a planned 20 percent cut in support prices in 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;This payment will be reduced if market prices are sustained at higher levels than currently foreseen,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The Commission also proposes limiting direct aid payments to individual farmers. While excluding renationalisation, the EU would allow member states to fix criteria for distributing the aid according to commonly agreed rules.</p>
<p>Beef and dairy producers, who face price cuts of 30 percent and 10 percent, respectively, would be more generously compensated than their cereal counterparts.</p>
<p>Fischler said that the reforms would bring savings of 3.7 billion ecus in market intervention and export refunds by 2006.</p>
<p>Although higher compensation payments would add 7.7 billion ecus, including 4.1 billion for beef producers, farm spending would remain well inside a growing expenditure ceiling, he said.</p>
<p>Farmers predictably attacked the planned price cuts and will press farm ministers to dilute the reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposals are unacceptable as they stand. Their implementation would have very damaging consequences for the future of farmers and their families...,&quot; said Risto Volanen, the Finnish Secretary General of COPA, the EU farmers' lobby.</p>
<p>The eventual entry of 10 eastern European countries, with Poland, Hungary, the Czech Republic, Estonia and Slovenia in the first wave from 2002, along with Cyprus, would increase EU farmland by half and double the number of farm workers.</p>
<p>But the new members will not be eligible for the direct income payments as these could provoke severe income disparities and social distortions in rural areas, the Commission said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
