<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733584" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Stg/mark pares losses after UK policy minutes.</title>
<headline>Stg/mark pares losses after UK policy minutes.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sterling pared overnight losses against the mark after minutes from the UK monetary policy committee's June meeting showed that strong domestic demand persuaded it to raise rates in the face of a rising pound.</p>
<p>Traders drove sterling up by more than a pfennig immediately after the report, which also showed that the committee expected the economy to continue to grow above its trend rate and inflation to accelerate.</p>
<p>Expectations these factors will persist in the coming months and force interest rates higher overshadowed an unexpected decline in average earnings.</p>
<p>Underlying average earnings rose by 4.25 percent in the year to May down from 4.5 percent in April.</p>
<p>&quot;The data was, if anything, marginally negative for sterling but currency traders decided to focus on the minutes of the June policy meeting,&quot; said Mark Geddes, treasury analyst at ABN Amro.</p>
<p>&quot;The one proviso is that sterling is 20 big figures higher than it was at the June meeting and is likely to be more important at the next meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>Sterling was trading between 2.8090 and 2.8270 when the monetary policy committee met and was at 99.6 against a trade-weighted basket of 20 currencies.  </p>
<p>Since then, the pound has climbed as much as eight percent against the mark and six percent on a trade-weighted basis.</p>
<p>Sterling was at 3.0075/85 marks at 0915 GMT from an overnight low of 2.9920 marks and 3.0173/83 late Tuesday in Europe. Cable was at $1.6784/94 from $1.6759/64 yesterday.</p>
<p>It is not just expectations of higher UK interest rates which have propelled the pound higher in recent months, though.</p>
<p>Concern that the planned European single currency will not be as strong or as stable as the mark has weakened the mark against sterling, and other currencies which are not involved in the project.</p>
<p>The dollar, for instance, yesterday surged above 1.80 marks for the first time in 71 months.</p>
<p>Signs the German monetary authorities do not want a weaker mark have triggered broad mark gains and seen sterling retreat from the 80-month high of 3.0327 marks it set on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Germans are worried about the credibility implications of the market thinking the euro is going to be a weak currency,&quot; said Ian Amstad, analyst at Bankers Trust.</p>
<p>German finance minister Theo Waigel said on Tuesday the government will call for a strong mark and a strong euro after their cabinet meeting today.</p>
<p>Also, Bundesbank council member Franz-Christophe Zeitler backed Bonn's calls for a strong mark yesterday.</p>
<p>While these comments have sparked speculation that Germany could intervene to support its currency, traders said it will take more than this to put an end to sterling's year-long rally.</p>
<p>&quot;Sterling may be in the final stages of its rally but there is no reason to sell it right now,&quot; said Amstad at Bankers Trust. &quot;You need two things before you will get a turn around in the pound -- signs of slower growth and a marked deterioration in the trade numbers.&quot;</p>
<p>- Swaha Pattanaik, London newsroom +44 171 542 6284</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
