<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733582" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-British jobless rate falls to 7-year low.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-British jobless rate falls to 7-year low.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's jobless total fell on Wednesday to its lowest level since April 1990 and earnings data showed tightness in the labour market was yet to prime inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>The Office for National Statistics said the jobless total fell 36,500 last month to 1.60 million, or 5.7 percent of the working population, according to official figures. The fall was larger than analysts had expected.</p>
<p>Average earnings, a key indicator of inflationary pressures, rose 4.25 percent year-on-year in May. This was lower than the 4.5 percent increase in April and showed few signs of wage-push inflation.</p>
<p>But analysts said this benevolent situation would not last for long and did not alter expectations of further rises in official interest rates in coming months.</p>
<p>Andrew Milligan, economist at General Accident, said the average earnings figures were a pleasant surprise. &quot;It would be surprising to see any further decline in earnings. All the pressure should be upwards from now on,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Interest rates have been increased three times in as many months -- to 6.75 percent -- since the May 1 election as authorities try to dampen inflationary pressures caused by strong economic growth.</p>
<p>Sterling, already around seven-year highs, pushed higher after Wednesday's data, fanned by rate-rise expectations. Share prices, also at record highs, continued climbing fuelled by buying in banks, pharmaceuticals and retail stocks.</p>
<p>Labour has handed responsibility for setting rates to the Bank of England. The minutes of the first meeting of the central bank's new monetary policy committee, released on Wednesday, showed it unanimously decided to raise rates in June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
