<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733759" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: S&amp;P AFFIRMS TRAVELERS GROUP INC RATINGS.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P AFFIRMS TRAVELERS GROUP INC RATINGS.</headline>
<text>
<p>NEW YORK, July 15 - Standard &amp; Poor's today has assigned its single-A'-plus rating to the $200 million depositary shares of Travelers Group Inc.</p>
<p>Additionally, Standard &amp; Poor's has affirmed its ratings on the Travelers Group Inc. as follows:</p>
<p>-- Counterparty credit and senior debt rating at double-A'-minus, and</p>
<p>-- Commercial paper rating of A-1'-plus.</p>
<p>Although management has no specific strategic plans for the use of this capital at the present time, Standard &amp; Poor's believes that its presence within the capital structure will immediately enhance the overall financial flexibility of the organization.</p>
<p>Travelers Group Inc. is the holding company that owns Commercial Credit Co., Smith Barney Holdings Inc., Travelers Property Casualty Corp., and The Travelers Insurance Co., and is wholly reliant upon dividends and other advances from these subsidiaries to pay interest and principal on its debt.</p>
<p>Travelers Group Inc.'s debt and preferred stock ratings are therefore based on Standard &amp; Poors' favorable expectations with respect to the earnings capacity of these operating subsidiaries.</p>
<p>These expectations derive from these companies' strong market positions, excellent financial measures, and highly capable management teams, which have regularly increased revenues, decreased unit costs, and actively sought ways in which to leverage one anothers' expertise.</p>
<p>A further consideration in the ratings of the issues of Travelers Group Inc. is the diversity of sources of income.</p>
<p>Each of these four subsidiaries contributes materially to the total earnings of the group, with a minimum of 9% and a maximum of 33% of the group's total expected earnings for 1997 coming from each business.</p>
<p>The success of management's plan has been evident in the fact that the net earnings of each of three of these subsidiaries have steadily increased over the past four years, while the fourth, Commercial Credit, has been stable.</p>
<p>Management has taken steps to improve the earnings profile of this subsidiary as well, announcing on June 10, 1997 its intention to acquire Security Pacific Financial Services, an acquisition that will both improve unit costs in this company and add substantial distribution capability.</p>
<p>At year-end 1996, interest and preferred coverage of the consolidated insurance operations were 10.7 times while the debt plus preferred shares to total capital ratio was 30.4%.</p>
<p>With the new issue of preferred shares, combined with an earlier draw down of this shelf and the above referenced acquisition, as well as the previously announced redemption of preferred shares, debt plus preferred to capital remains within the expected range for the current ratings.</p>
<p>OUTLOOK: Stable.</p>
<p>The outlook assumes continued revenue enhancement and expense containment at each of these subsidiaries, along with further realization of strategic benefits from their affiliation with the group.</p>
<p>It further assumes that the group as a whole will be managed with a view toward maintaining coverage of fixed charges at or above their present levels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
