<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73378" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NATO opens new Navy HQ for crisis management.</title>
<headline>NATO opens new Navy HQ for crisis management.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>NORTHWOOD, England 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO on Tuesday opened a new naval headquarters to provide a high-speed response to crises from the Atlantic to the Baltic.</p>
<p>The new maritime nerve centre just north of London has up to 18 frigates, destroyers and minesweepers on call to be dispatched to trouble spots.</p>
<p>Speed is the prime motivation.</p>
<p>&quot;We can react quickly. We have standing forces ready and available. They are a core on which we can then expand,&quot; said NATO spokesman Jonathan Worthington at the opening ceremony for the new headquarters at Northwood, near London.</p>
<p>&quot;This will now be NATO's principal maritime headquarters this side of the Atlantic. Any crisis in this area -- we will deal with it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The newly named Atlantic building, which marks the end of the first stage of NATO (North Atlantic Treaty Organisation) restructuring after the end of the Cold War, has a staff of 220 from 10 NATO countries.</p>
<p>The ships supplied by the member states are rotated on a six-monthly basis.</p>
<p>Their forces were already involved in NATO's Operation Sharp Guard which enforced the arms embargo against former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>They are now back on duty in the Atlantic but can return to the Adriatic should the situation change.</p>
<p>The new headquarters were officially opened by American General Jack Sheehan, NATO's supreme allied commander, Atlantic.</p>
<p>Underlining the need for NATO to adapt to its new role of co-operating with its former Warsaw Pact enemies in the Partnership for Peace programme, he said: &quot;We can no longer afford to view NATO in East-West terms.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Collective security does work,&quot; he told the top naval brass assembled from alliance countries</p>
<p>After the opening ceremony, NATO delegates sat down with their new East European partners for a seminar on how best to tackle the maritime problems they face together.</p>
<p>These range from fishery patrols and oil rig protection to the counter-terrorism measures and intelligence sharing needed across the continent to combat arms smuggling.</p>
<p>&quot;Terrorism is a cross-border affair. It makes sense to try and deal with the problem together,&quot; Worthington said as the two sides met behind closed doors.</p>
<p>Northwood is also the command headquarters masterminding Britain's new joint rapid deployment force of elite troops that can be flown speedily to the troublespots of the world.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORTHWOOD, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
