<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733877" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France sends Cambodian rivals ceasefire appeal.</title>
<headline>France sends Cambodian rivals ceasefire appeal.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>France has sent identical messages to Cambodia's two rival prime ministers, appealing to them to call a ceasefire and respect human rights, a government spokeswoman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Hubert Vedrine told a cabinet meeting that France was in contact with both premiers, Prince Norodom Ranariddh and Hun Sen, spokeswoman Catherine Trautmann told reporters.</p>
<p>She said the message referred to &quot;the need for an immediate ceasefire, respect of human rights and of humanitarian rules, and, as soon as possible, a return to normal for institutions.&quot;</p>
<p>France also insisted on the holding of an election in May 1998.</p>
<p>As many as 40 Cambodians have been killed since the overthrow of First Prime Minister Ranariddh but it was not clear if the killings were part of a planned purge, a diplomatic source in Phnom Penh said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The source, who declined to be identified, said there was evidence of torture among some of the victims, including four bodyguards of Prince Ranariddh's top military commander, General Nhiek Bun Chhay.</p>
<p>Second Prime Minister Hun Sen overthrew Ranariddh on July 6 after a weekend of fighting in the capital.</p>
<p>Hun Sen said on Tuesday Cambodia would have a free and fair election on May 23 as planned but the United States said that Hun Sen's rhetoric in recent days, seemingly in favour of democracy, was not matched by action.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
