<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733825" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Judge extends trial schedule for Clinton and Jones.</title>
<headline>Judge extends trial schedule for Clinton and Jones.</headline>
<dateline>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. 1997-06-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>- A federal judge has agreed to requests by lawyers for President Bill Clinton and Paula Corbin Jones for more time to submit legal paperwork in the sexual harassment lawsuit Jones has brought against Clinton.</p>
<p>A federal district judge at Little Rock agreed on Tuesday to extend by two weeks the time allowed for lawyers for Jones to respond to Clinton's motion to dismiss the lawsuit.</p>
<p>The judge also granted Clinton extra time in which to then respond to Jones' written arguments.</p>
<p>Lawyers for Clinton and Jones had requested the extensions.</p>
<p>Jones' brief arguing against dismissal was due on Thursday, but Judge Susan Webber Wright granted her lawyers until July 29 to file the papers. The judge also granted Clinton's legal team until Aug. 15 to file an answer.</p>
<p>Jones was a state employee and Clinton was governor of Arkansas in 1991 when, she claims, Clinton summoned her to a Little Rock hotel room where he asked her to perform a sex act. She said she refused.</p>
<p>Clinton has said the episode did not occur and that he has no memory of meeting Jones.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LITTLE ROCK, Ark."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
