<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733800" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ascend gained second-quarter market share, Europe soft.</title>
<headline>Ascend gained second-quarter market share, Europe soft.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ascend Communications Inc, a leading supplier of Internet access equipment, said it grew at or above industry rates in key product lines during the second quarter, but warned of softness in its European business.</p>
<p>Ascend executives made the comments in a conference call with analysts late Tuesday after the company reported a second-quarter loss of $48.8 million, or 26 cents a share.</p>
<p>That compared with a profit of $44.4 million, or 23 cents a share, in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>Earnings were hit by pretax costs of $150.3 million in acquiring Cascade Communications Corp. and Whitetree Inc., the company said. Without those charges, the company would have made a profit of 31 cents a share.</p>
<p>Ascend had sales of $311.7 million, compared with $205.6 million a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We see the third quarter in Europe to be flat and the majority of the reason is because of seasonality,&quot; Ascend's Chief Financial Officer Bob Dahl said.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany and the (United Kingdom) were soft in the last quarter, and we are going to see that in the next quarter,&quot; Dahl said of sales growth in the second and third quarters.</p>
<p>But Ascend President Mory Ejabat, speaking during the conference call, said Japan's contribution to Ascend's overall business rebounded during the second quarter to contribute 25 percent of revenues, up from 9 percent in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Ascend officials said they expected Japan's contribution to Ascend revenues to return to historic levels around 20 percent or 21 percent during the third quarter.</p>
<p>Overall, executives said they expected international sales, including Europe, to grow in the single digits during the upcoming third quarter. They said they expected North American growth to be strong, but provided no figures.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
