<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733998" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU COMMISSION'S OPINION ON HUNGARY.</title>
<headline>EU COMMISSION'S OPINION ON HUNGARY.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are extracts from a summary issued on Wednesday by the European Commission of its opinion on Hungary's fitness to begin European Union membership talks:</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Hungary submitted its application for membership of the European Union on 31 March 1994.</p>
<p>1. Political Criteria</p>
<p>Hungary's political institutions function properly.  They respect the limits on their competences and cooperate with each other. Elections are free and fair and led to alteration of power in 1990 and 1994. The opposition plays a normal part in the operation of the institutions.</p>
<p>There are no major problems over respect for fundamental rights. The rights of minorities are guaranteed and protected. Certain improvements are still needed in the operation of the judicial system and in protection for the Roma, but the measures recently taken by the government constitute progress. The fight against corruption needs further reinforcement.</p>
<p>Hungary presents the characteristics of a democracy with stable institutions guaranteeing the rule of law, human rights and respect for and protection of minorities.</p>
<p>2. Economic Criteria</p>
<p>After a fall in GDP of nearly 20 percent between 1989 and 1993, Hungary has seen renewed growth since 1994 (1.5 percent in 1995, 1 percent in 1996). This has been accompanied by progress towards stabilisation of public finances, external accounts and inflation (19.8 percent in 1996). Hungary has 10.2 million inhabitants and its GDP per capita is equivalent to 37 percent of the EU average. 8 percent of the working population are employed in the agricultural sector which contributes 7 percent of gross value added. Trade with the EU has grown considerably since 1989 and now represents 60 percent of Hungary's external trade.</p>
<p>On the basis of its analysis the Commission's judgement as to Hungary's ability to meet the economic criteria established at Copenhagen is as follows:</p>
<p>Hungary can be regarded as a functioning market economy. Liberalisation and privatisation have progressed considerably, and there has been strong growth of new private firms. In order to guarantee longer term stability, the reform of pensions and social security needs to advance rapidly. The proposed method of pension reform would have the added benefit of deepening capital markets.</p>
<p>Hungary should be well able to cope with competitive pressure and market forces within the Union in the medium term, provided the macro-economic conditions for strong investment growth remain in place. Hungarian enterprises are already competitive in EU markets. Restructuring of industry and banks is well underway. Hungary's record of consistent commitment to steady market reforms and its ability to take difficult decisions when they are necessary is an important positive factor. It has had a consistently high level of foreign direct investment. However, the key task is now to avoid unsustainable budgetary or external deficits, which hinder investment and restructuring, and halt the recent acceleration of growth.</p>
<p>3. Capacity to take on the obligations of membership</p>
<p>Hungary's ability to take on the acquis has been evaluated according to a number of indicators:</p>
<p>- the obligations set out in the Europe Agreement, particularly those relating to the right of establishment, national treatment, free circulation of goods, intellectual property and public procurement;</p>
<p>- implementation of the measures set out in the White Paper as essential for establishing the single market;</p>
<p>- progressive transposition of the other parts of the acquis.</p>
<p>Hungary has met the bulk of its obligations under the Europe Agreement, and the timetable set out in the Agreement has been met. The Agreement has functioned very well and it has been possible to resolve any bilateral difficulties which have arisen, in particular in the field of trade. Hungary has achieved a good rate of transposition of the rules and directives set out in the White Paper.</p>
<p>For the whole field related to the single market, and in particular competition, public procurement, intellectual property, company and accounting law, taxation, product liability, financial services, the legislative foundation is almost completely in place. Despite the efforts undertaken, the Progress made in transposing legislation still needs to be accompanied by concrete measures of implementation, as well as establishment of an effective administrative underpinning. Hungary has some instruments which operate correctly (for instance in the field of public procurement, appeal procedures set out in the directives are applied and court cases have been started) but substantial efforts are still needed in a number of sectors, notably standardisation.</p>
<p>As for the other parts of the acquis, Hungary should not have difficulty in applying it in the medium term, provided it continues its current preparation for accession in the following fields: education, training and youth; research and technological development; telecommunications; audio-visual; small and medium enterprises; international trade relations, and development.</p>
<p>By contrast substantial efforts will be needed for Hungary to be able to apply the acquis in consumer protection and customs controls.</p>
<p>Given the extent of restructuring and modernisation efforts undertaken so far, there are good reasons to expect that most sectors of Hungarian industry in the medium term can be competitive operators in the single market.</p>
<p>For the environment, very important efforts will be needed, including massive investment and strengthening of administrative capacity for enforcement of legislation. Full compliance with the acquis could only be expected in the long to very long term and would necessitate increased levels of public expenditure.</p>
<p>Hungary has already made considerable progress on taking on the transport acquis. If it continues its efforts on road transport and technical controls this sector should not pose significant difficulties. Hungary will need to provide the investment necessary to extend the European transport network in order to ensure effective operation of the single market.</p>
<p>Hungary should also be able in the medium term to apply the acquis on employment and social affairs but efforts are still needed to improve the health system and apply EU health and safety at work standards. Hungary already has an effective labour inspectorate.</p>
<p>For regional policy Hungary has adopted a regional development policy which, if implemented, should permit it in the medium term to apply Community rules and make effective use of structural funds. Hungary will also need the necessary financial control instruments.</p>
<p>In the agriculture sector if progress is made in the veterinary and phytosanitary fields, and if the structures needed in the agrifood sector and for applying the CAP are reinforced, membership in the medium term should not pose significant problems for Hungary in applying the CAP in an appropriate manner.</p>
<p>For energy, efforts are still needed in respect of monopoly operations, price fixing, access to networks and state intervention in the solid fuel and uranium sectors. Hungary has a nuclear power station at Paks which produces nearly 40 percent of the country's electricity. It needs to modernise this in the medium term in order to bring it up into internationally accepted safety standards. It will also need to find a solution for nuclear waste.</p>
<p>On the basis of the analysis of its capacity to apply the acquis, Hungary could be in a position in the medium term to take and implement the measures necessary for removal of controls at its borders and establishment of these at the Union's external border.</p>
<p>Hungary should be in a position to participate at the appropriate time in the third stage of economic and monetary union, which implies coordination of economic policy and complete liberalisation of capital movements. But it is premature to judge whether Hungary will be in a position, by the time of its accession, to participate in the Euro area. That will depend on how far the success of its structural transformation enables it to achieve and sustain permanently the convergence criteria. These are, however, not a condition for membership.</p>
<p>Hungary should be able to meet the justice and home affairs acquis in the next few years, even though particular attention will need to be paid to frontier controls, treatment of asylum seekers, visa policy and the fight against organised crime. Hungary has indicated a wish to join the Schengen Agreements.</p>
<p>Hungary should be able to fulfil its obligations in respect of the common foreign and security policy.</p>
<p>In addition, Hungary has reinforced its relations with its neighbours since 1989, and has signed Friendship and Good Neighbourliness Agreements with them recognising existing frontiers and resolving almost all the potential disputes with them. It has played an important role in regional stability.</p>
<p>4. Administrative and Legal Capacity</p>
<p>If Hungary pursues the administrative reforms which have already been started, the necessary structures could be in place in the medium term to apply the acquis effectively.</p>
<p>The capacity of the judicial system to ensure uniform application of Community law is of great importance, particularly for the implementation of the single market. If Hungary pursues its efforts, the judicial system should be capable of applying Community law in the medium term.</p>
<p>CONCLUSION</p>
<p>In the light of these considerations, the Commission concludes that</p>
<p>- Hungary presents the characteristics of a democracy , with stable institutions guaranteeing the rule of law, human rights and respect for and protection of minorities;</p>
<p>- Hungary can be regarded as a functioning market economy and it should be able to cope with competitive pressure and market forces within the Union in the medium term;</p>
<p>- If Hungary continues its efforts on transposition of the acquis relating particularly to the single market, and intensifies its work on its implementation, Hungary should become capable in the medium term of applying it fully. In addition, particular efforts will be needed to meet the acquis in sectors such as environment, customs control and energy. More generally, further administrative reform will be indispensable if Hungary is to have the structures to apply and enforce the acquis effectively.</p>
<p>In the light of these considerations, the Commission recommends that negotiations for accession should be opened with Hungary.</p>
<p>The reinforced pre-accession strategy will help Hungary to prepare itself better to meet the obligations of membership, and to take action to improve the shortcomings identified in the Opinions. The Commission will present a report no later than the end of 1998 on the progress Hungary has achieved.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
