<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73394" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Russia in key test of foreign investor sentiment.</title>
<headline>Russia in key test of foreign investor sentiment.</headline>
<byline>David Chance</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin's renewed health problems come just as the country is negotiating its debut eurobond and the sale to foreign investors of a stake in its largest company, Gazprom.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unfortunate timing, but one often sees that in Russia. A lot of people who may wish to buy Gazprom are new investors and negative reports might cause nervousness,&quot; said Kingsmill Bond, Russia fund manager at MC Securities in London.</p>
<p>Russian equity and bond markets dived on Monday and Tuesday after reports that Yeltsin may not be fit enough to face the surgeon's knife for his heart operation for another two months.</p>
<p>Foreign investors say this raises the spectre the president may die or become permanently incapacitated. Russia could face the uncertainty of new elections after a three month period during which Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin will hold the reins of power.</p>
<p>&quot;If Yelstin dies, once more investment in Russia will be on hold because a three month tenure by Chernomyrdin is not going to implement further fundamental change,&quot; Bond said.</p>
<p>During this period of flux, foreign investors are being asked to stump up $400 million to buy a one percent stake in Gazprom, the world's largest natural gas company.</p>
<p>Roadshows for the global depositary receipt (GDR) issue start on October 7, with the book closure on October 18. Pricing and allocation of the issue will be on October 23.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the books have not been started on Gazprom, so we do not have any true idea of the size of subscriptions, we are seeing a lot of interest from natural resource players as well as those already in Russia,&quot; said a banker in the syndicate.</p>
<p>Foreign investors say that if Yeltsin does die or become too ill to continue, the Russian share market could come off by 20 percent, deflating one of the best-performing markets in the world this year.</p>
<p>The CSFB ROS index of leading Russian shares fell 4.57 percent on Monday. But at 1,184 points it is still way up on its year low of 522 points, although down from its high of 1,546.</p>
<p>However, if 58-year-old Chernomyrdin won an election, the outlook would look good for Gazprom, an organisation he once headed and in which he retains a substantial equity stake.</p>
<p>&quot;Chernomyrdin is a man who has learned to appreciate the benefits of reform and it would clearly be a good time to invest in Gazprom,&quot; said Bond.</p>
<p>Investor sentiment towards Russian debt has also worsened this week. Dollar-denominated Vneshekonombank paper fell as low as 64 3/8 percent of face value on Monday from an all-time high of 70 on Thursday, although it rebounded to 65 1/8 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Russia is expected to attempt to raise $300-$500 million from its debut eurobond issue in November, and analysts believe that it is looking for up to $1.3 billion next year.</p>
<p>The eurobond could be more sensitive to Yeltsin's health problems than Gazprom, say bankers.</p>
<p>&quot;People have factored Yeltsin's existing problems in to their calculations, but if he dies, then they would have to reassess the situation,&quot; said a syndicate manager for the issue.</p>
<p>Another manager said that U.S. credit rating agencies Standard &amp; Poor's and Moody's held the key to the eurobond.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very hard to tell what will happen. These things do have a tendency to slip. But if you look at the size of the economy, Gazprom and the eurobond are drops in the ocean,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
