<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733910" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: American Airlines to cut Brussels-NY JFK route.</title>
<headline>American Airlines to cut Brussels-NY JFK route.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Airlines said on Wednesday it was being forced by unfair competition to end its daily flight from Brussels to New York's JFK airport with effect from October 1 after losing money consistently.</p>
<p>However, the airline's profitable regular service from the Belgian capital to its hub in Chicago will remain in operation, sales manager Olga Jacob said by telephone.</p>
<p>She said a three-way alliance between Sabena, Delta and Swissair -- which has hubs in Brussels and New York -- had the benefit of anti-trust immunity, while American Airlines' planned alliance with British Airways remained blocked.</p>
<p>&quot;Sabena-Delta put on a second daily Brussels-New York flight about a year ago. It is running with excess capacity and cutting prices,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Since they put on that extra flight, we have consistently lost money on the New York route.&quot;</p>
<p>As there is no &quot;open skies&quot; agreement between Britain and the United States, the British Airways alliance could not proceed, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are being blocked while our European competitors have anti-trust immunity and can set prices and take market share,&quot; she commented.</p>
<p>Hans Mirka, American Airlines' senior international vice president, said in a statement the decision to end the daily Brussels to New York flight, in operation since 1989, was sad but necessary.</p>
<p>He, too, complained that the airline faced an uneven playing field in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very difficult to compete effectively in a market such as Brussels where the rules are substantially different for our competitors,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
