<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733934" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: CPI still behind rise in Swedish bond yields.</title>
<headline>CPI still behind rise in Swedish bond yields.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish long debt yields rose slightly, partly because of higher-than-expected Swedish consumer prices announced on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said the Riksbank bought crowns against the dollar at 7.8550 in morning trade after the crown weakened to about 7.86 because of foreigners selling large amounts of Swedish bonds and buying dollars.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw a spillover effect from the CPI figure on Tuesday. Also the (25 basis point) interest rate rise by the Norwegian central bank might had some influence,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Dealers said it had a psychological effect.  </p>
<p>&quot;Trading this morning was volatile with short-term trading and big volumes for the summer,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The spread against German ten-year bonds increased two basis points to 91. The ten year debt yields inched up one basis point to 6.53 percent while the six-month T-bill rates were up five basis points to 4.25 percent.</p>
<p>The crown was quoted at 7.8337 against the dollar from 7.8310 late Tuesday. Against the mark it was somewhat weaker at 4.3720 from 4.3535 from Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1019</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
