<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="733981" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Jospin clashes with Chirac in cabinet.</title>
<headline>France's Jospin clashes with Chirac in cabinet.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Prime Minister Lionel Jospin, responding to criticism from Gaullist President Jacques Chirac, reminded the head of state of their respective duties at a cabinet meeting on Wednesday, a government spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Chirac broke an uneasy peace with the new leftist government on Monday, critcising it on policies ranging from privatisation to nuclear power, Europe and immigration.  </p>
<p>&quot;Following the statements of the president on July 14, the prime minister recalled in cabinet the prerogatives which constitutionally are those of the president and the prime minister,&quot; spokeswoman Catherine Trautmann told reporters.</p>
<p>Chirac, in a traditional interview broadcast on Bastille national day, laid out a roadmap of potential conflicts with the cabinet, with the transition to the single European currency near the top of the list.</p>
<p>Chirac said the Constitution gave him &quot;a pre-eminent role -- the last word&quot; on matters ranging from the transition to a single currency and maintaining social cohesion to upholding France's high-technology industries.</p>
<p>Jospin's Socialist Party has accused Chirac, shorn of much of his power by the left-wing election victory, of going too far in his criticism.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
