<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="734035" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORD POSTS RECORD Q2 PROFITS OF $2.53 BILLION.</title>
<headline>FORD POSTS RECORD Q2 PROFITS OF $2.53 BILLION.</headline>
<dateline>DEARBORN, Mich. 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ford Motor Co. said Wednesday its second-quarter profits jumped 33 percent to $2.53 billion, an all-time quarterly record.</p>
<p>The No. 2 U.S. automaker credited its performance to reduced automotive operating costs and the introduction of several new, redesigned cars and trucks.</p>
<p>Ford earned $2.06 on a per-share basis, beating the Wall Street analyst consensus estimate of $1.82, as reported by First Call Corp. A year ago, Ford posted profits of $1.90 billion, or $1.56 a share.</p>
<p>Worldwide sales and revenues were $40.3 billion, compared with $39 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>Included in the latest results was a gain of $100 million reflecting a gain from the initial public offering of Hertz Corp. and a charge for closing several plants and the sale of Ford's heavy truck business to Freightliner.</p>
<p>Net income from Ford's worldwide automotive operations rose to $1.74 billion from $1.10 billion. The increase reflected strong profits in Ford's core U.S. automotive operations, which nearly doubled to $1.19 billion from $697 million.</p>
<p>&quot;We're pleased to see automotive earnings continuing to improve,&quot; Ford Chairman Alex Trotman said in a statement. But he warned that more efforts were needed in Europe before the automaker will be able to achieve its long-term objectives.  REUTER  161311 GMT jul 97</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DEARBORN, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
