<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="734178" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Melbourne airport owner looks at more airport buys.</title>
<headline>Melbourne airport owner looks at more airport buys.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asia Pacific Airports (APA), the consortium which made the winning bid for Melbourne's international airport, said on Wednesday the group was keen to buy more Australian airports.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll say up-front that APA is unashamedly ambitious about acquiring more Australian airports,&quot; APA's chief executive, Andrew Jurenko told a luncheon hosted by the Committee for Economic Development of Australia (CEDA).</p>
<p>Jurenko said the consortium would be bidding for several of the major airports coming up in phase two of the Federal government's privatisation programme.  </p>
<p>In May this year the government completed phase one of its airport privatisation programme with the sale of the Brisbane, Melbourne and Perth airports for A$3.34 billion.</p>
<p>Phase two of the programme is the sale of 15 smaller airports, leaving just Sydney's international airport which the government has said it won't sell until after aircraft noise problems surrounding the operation are resolved.</p>
<p>Jurenko said APA intended to expand its operation from its Melbourne base and was hoping to take advantage of obvious synergies between Melbourne and other Australian cities, particularly those in Tasmania.  </p>
<p>The government's decision to keep open Victoria's second major airport at Essendon was welcomed by APA, Jurenko said, and the group was keeping its bidding options for that airport open.</p>
<p>&quot;Essendon plays an important role in providing access to casual fliers and specialist air services - competition doesn't do us any harm ... it just makes us better,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The APA group comprises British airport operator, BAA Plc with an initial 25.1 percent stake, insurance and funds group AMP Society with 49.9 percent and Sydney-based funds manager, Deutsche Banks AG's Axiom, with 25 percent.  </p>
<p>BAA's stake would fall to 15.1 percent if a proposed fourth partner, Melbourne-based Hastings Fund Management, exercised an option to take a 10 percent interest.</p>
<p>-- Michael Stapleton, Melbourne Bureau 61-3 9286-1435</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
