<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="734181" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia's Howard says not calling for rates cut.</title>
<headline>Australia's Howard says not calling for rates cut.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard said on Wednesday that he had not been calling for an easing in monetary policy when he said last week that he wanted to see lower interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;I wasn't specifically calling for a reduction in interest rates,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the conduct of monetary policy by the Reserve Bank over the last 18 months has been first class and I'm not indicating either way where I think interest rates ought to go.&quot;  </p>
<p>Howard was speaking in the east coast city of Newcastle, where he met workers and union officials to discuss the Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd's (BHP) plans to close its steelmaking operations by 1999, with the loss of 2,500 jobs.</p>
<p>Howard told a lunch gathering in the northern city of Townsville last week that rates were coming down and he wanted to see interest rates still lower.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the reasons why interest rates have come down in Australia, and I'd like to see them still lower ... is that we are no longer running such large (budget) deficits,&quot; he said in Townsville.  </p>
<p>The Reserve Bank has cut official cash rates a total 2.0 percentage points, to 5.5 percent, in four equal cuts between July last year and May.</p>
<p>Markets have been speculating on a possible fifth cut.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
