<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="734258" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Cashed up Hopewell still faces tough future.</title>
<headline>Cashed up Hopewell still faces tough future.</headline>
<byline>Kathleen Kearney</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hopewell Holdings Ltd took full advantage of the deep pockets of Southern Co Inc and sold its remaining stake in Consolidated Electric Power Asia Ltd (CEPA) at top prices, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But despite this large cash infusion, the same analysts saw a rough road ahead for the ambitious Hong Kong contractor.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is a good price. He sold the shares at a premium to CEPA's NAV (net asset value),&quot; said analyst Terry Yip at BZW Securities Asia. &quot;So there should be no regrets from Hopewell.&quot;</p>
<p>The company earlier announced it would sell its remaining 19.99 percent stake in CEPA to Southern Co of the United States in a deal worth about HK$5 billion (US$646 million).</p>
<p>&quot;This is equivalent to about HK$18.50 per share, the same price the first portion of shares were sold at,&quot; said Yip.</p>
<p>Hopewell earlier sold a 40 percent stake in CEPA to Southern Energy-Asia Inc, a unit of Southern Co. The U.S. company also bought about 40 percent of CEPA from minority shareholders in a subsequent general offer.</p>
<p>Hopewell retained 19.99 percent of CEPA in the first deal and Hopewell chairman Gordon Wu kept the chairmanship of the unique Asian independent power producer that he created.</p>
<p>In the latest sale agreement, Hopewell exchanged its CEPA stake for CEPA's 80 percent interest in an Indonesian power plant project and US$150 million in cash.</p>
<p>Analysts estimated Hopewell's net cash inflow from the sale will be just over HK$1.0 billion.</p>
<p>The company gave no specific reason for the CEPA stake sale.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the deal) enables Hopewell to complete development of this power plant in Indonesia and retain a significant interest in the power sector,&quot; Wu said in a statement.</p>
<p>Interpretations of the sale varied. Some analysts thought Wu fell out with his Southern partners. &quot;It seems there is a lot of difference between the Americans (Southern Co) and Gordon Wu,&quot; said Anthony Measor, director at Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>But the main reason was likely to be the need to strengthen Hopewell's balance sheet, they said. &quot;Hopewell is very cash needy,&quot; said analyst Bee Lim at Paribas Asia Equity.</p>
<p>The company has its hands full with huge highway projects in southern China as well as a mass transit deal in Thailand.</p>
<p>And how did Hopewell get in such a cash strapped position?</p>
<p>Wu is almost legendary for his large-scale visionary projects, but raising the necessary funds and meeting deadlines has not always been easy, said analysts and brokers.</p>
<p>&quot;Gordon Wu always walks a bit of a tightrope,&quot; said Measor.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that Gordon needs someone over him to handle the cash, someone like Cheung Kong to have taken over,&quot; he added. &quot;That would have been mutually advantageous.&quot;</p>
<p>Other analysts agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;Hopewell has lost the battle in China, The company hasn't signed up any new projects in China in the past two-three years,&quot; said Yip. &quot;In the meantime, Cheung Kong Infrastructure and New World Infrastructure have doubled the size of their assets.&quot;</p>
<p>But the big question hanging over Hopewell at this point is the future of its largest project to date, the Bangkok Elevated Rail Train System (BERTS).</p>
<p>The company has already invested HK$4 billion in BERTS and still requires a similarly large investment and a Thai partner to enable it to finish by the deadline, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Is it financially feasible?&quot; asked Yip. &quot;Earnings were to be derived from property development and sales along the system and tariffs on the rail line.&quot;</p>
<p>Most analysts recommended institutional investors avoid the stock, and the counter looked likely to remain that way. It fell HK$0.20 to HK$4.90 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock has been out of favour for so long,&quot; said Lim. &quot;He has good visions but he can't carry them out, and until he does institutions won't touch it.&quot; (US$1=HK$7.74)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
