<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73444" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: King Hassan sees election behind U.S. Gulf moves.</title>
<headline>King Hassan sees election behind U.S. Gulf moves.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>King Hassan of Morocco, a staunch ally of Washington, said the latest U.S. moves against Iraq appeared to be influenced by American internal politics, the official MAP news agency reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The agency reported the king, who was interviewed by a group of French journalists, as saying &quot;I do not think that the U.S. attitude (against Iraq) was not completely influenced by internal political considerations&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;But I am happy to note that U.S. recently took some steps back...Ourselves and all Arab countries were obliged to protest against the surge of tension in the (Gulf) region,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Presidential elections are due to be held in the United States in November.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the U.S. fired missiles at Iraq and extended a no-fly zone in southern Iraq after Baghdad sent troops to back a Kurdish faction in the north.</p>
<p>Washington sent reinforcements to the Gulf, including stealth bombers and aircraft carriers, in the ensuing crisis.</p>
<p>Iraq later promised it would no longer fire anti-aircraft missiles at U.S. and allied warplanes patrolling the no-fly zones.</p>
<p>King Hassan said the U.S. was not preparing for a new war against Iraq because &quot;America has no interest in doing it...I do not see what the U.S. will gain...neither Iraq which has nothing to gain from launching hostilities against the U.S.,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry has acknowledged that tension is abating and said he might remove one of the two U.S. aircraft carriers from the Gulf next week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
