<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="734518" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: UN anti-settlement vote shameful - Israel.</title>
<headline>UN anti-settlement vote shameful - Israel.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel on Wednesday condemned as &quot;shameful&quot; and &quot;morally bankrupt&quot; a new U.N. resolution which urges member states to &quot;actively discourage&quot; the building of Israeli settlements in occupied areas.</p>
<p>&quot;It is regrettable that the world organisation finds the building of apartments for young couples condemnable while ignoring the many true dangers to world peace posed by the very dictatorships which sponsored this resolution,&quot; Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's adviser David Bar-Illan said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an indication of moral bankruptcy and a shameful performance,&quot; Bar-Illan said.</p>
<p>Tuesday's General Assembly resolution, sponsored by 15 Arab and Moslem nations, condemned Israeli settlement activity and, in a move toward sanctions, demanded Israel provide information about goods produced in the settlements.</p>
<p>The resolution follows a report by U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan condemning Israel for not abandoning settlement construction at a site in Arab East Jerusalem called Har Homa in Hebrew and Jabal Abu Ghneim in Arabic.</p>
<p>The vote was 131 to three with 14 abstentions.</p>
<p>Voting against were Israel, Micronesia and the United States. Abstaining were: Andorra, Australia, Costa Rica, Croatia, Germany, Latvia, Lithuania, Marshall Islands, Nicaragua, Romania, Russia, Rwanda, Slovakia and Uzbekistan.</p>
<p>The draft was based on an earlier version that was softened to attract maximum support, including that of all 15 European Union members except Germany. Russia, co-sponsor with the United States of the Middle East peace process, abstained.</p>
<p>The Assembly demanded at an emergency special session in April that Israel halt work at the Jerusalem site, where bulldozers are preparing the infrastructure for 6,500 homes.</p>
<p>The start of construction last March plunged Israel-PLO peacemaking into crisis and triggered waves of Arab unrest in the West Bank and Gaza.</p>
<p>Arabs view the settlement as an attempt to preempt future peace talks on the fate of East Jerusalem, wanted by the Palestinians as capital of a future state.</p>
<p>Israel, which captured East Jerusalem in 1967 and later annexed it in a move the international community has failed to recognise, says all of Jerusalem is its united capital.</p>
<p>The new resolution recommends that the parties to the Fourth Geneva Convention, which bars settlements in occupied territory, convene a conference on measures to enforce the convention and asks the secretary-general to provide a report in three months.</p>
<p>The resolution recommends that U.N. members &quot;actively discourage activities which directly contribute to any construction or development of Israeli settlements in occupied Palestinian territory, including Jerusalem.&quot;</p>
<p>It demands that Israel &quot;make available to member states the necessary information about goods produced or manufactured in the illegal settlements&quot; -- presumably so they can be boycotted.</p>
<p>Only the U.N. Security Council can make sanctions binding.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
