<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="734539" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - July 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - July 16.</headline>
<text>
<p>VIENNA, July 16 (Reuter) The main stories in the Austrian press this Wednesday are:</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- The 1998 budget will be announced on July 24 but key points like pensions and civil service reforms will not be discussed until September.</p>
<p>- A poll of 1000 people says that 47 percent of the population consider the country to be in a worse state than it was at the elections to the Nationalrat in December 1995.</p>
<p>- A constitutional court finding will cost Austrian Federal Railways at least one billion schillings in unemployment insurance.</p>
<p>- Bank matters have become the toy of politics. Bank Austria looks set to fill the summer's political agenda.</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Chancellor Viktor Klima reacted calmly to a unanimous decision by the conservative People's Party to back Austria's entry to NATO. He says such an important issue must be decided calmly and carefully.</p>
<p>- The People's Party wants to divide up the state postal firm into two separate companies, one for post and one for telecoms services.</p>
<p>- Austrian industry is at the peak of its competitiveness and has made much greater advances in productivity than its main trade partners.</p>
<p>- The third mobile phone licence is to be auctioned at the beginning of August.</p>
<p>- Pope John Paul II is expected to visit Salzburg in 1998 to celebrate 1,200 years of the archdiocese there.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Rudolf Edlinger says plans for the 1998 budget stand firm and he is confident of reaching the budget deficit target of 2.6 percent, compared with 2.7 percent this year.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Fewer and fewer apprenticeships are available. The government promises help.</p>
<p>- Siemens Austria is threatening to close its cable firm if its 900 workers do not accept plans for a 13 percent cut in wages and longer working hours.</p>
<p>- Edlinger says banks are not suited for political games. He confirms there will be no change in the savings bank laws.</p>
<p>SALZBURGER NACHRICHTEN</p>
<p>- Bank Austria's downgrade by credit rating service Moody's will provoke an exchange of blows between the Social Democrats and the conservatives but is no big deal, says Vienna vice mayor Bernhard Goerg.</p>
<p>- Klima and his German counterpart Helmut Kohl will meet in Innsbruck on Thursday to discuss the Schengen agreement.</p>
<p>- Styrian Slovenians are demanding official recognition as a minority, citing the Austrian state treaty, in which they are named as a minority.</p>
<p>- Sportswear manufacturer Kneissl Dachstein is to react to the stagnated ski show market by cutting back its workforce from 862 to 750 employees.</p>
<p>- Small harvests of Austrian wine crops have driven prices higher.</p>
<p>WIRTSCHAFTSBLATT</p>
<p>- VA Stahl is launching a new strategy for a new positioning of the group. A joint venture with German steel giant Preussag is the first step.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
