<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="734610" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Hong Kong stocks close lower on property worries.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks close lower on property worries.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks closed lower on Wednesday on concerns about property prices under the government's increased land supply programme, brokers said.</p>
<p>But the sharp rise of heavily-weighted HSBC shares kept the Hang Seng index from losing more ground.</p>
<p>The blue chip index lost 41.22 points, or 0.27 percent, to finish at 15,446.02 after setting a record high of 15,635.52 earlier in morning trade.</p>
<p>&quot;HSBC and H-shares rose today while red chips held steady and property stocks were weak,&quot; said Antony Mak, sales director at Vickers Ballas.</p>
<p>HSBC jumped HK$10.00 to HK$264.00 after hitting a record of HK$269.00 on optimism over banks in the London bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;Follow-through buying pushed HSBC shares up after the stock posted heavy gains in London overnight,&quot; Mak said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng properties sub-index plunged 520.34 points, or 2.10 percent, to finish at 24,299.96 after the goverment said on Tuesday it would increase land supply by 140 percent over the next five years compared to the previous five years.</p>
<p>Financial Secretary Donald Tsand also said the government expected housing supply at 79,000 units per year over the next three years and 104,000 units a year over the following five.</p>
<p>Cheung Kong fell HK$1.25 to HK$75.50 and Sun Hung Kai Properties was down HK$2.25 to HK$88.50.</p>
<p>&quot;Property counters should continue to meet selling pressure since future housing supply will increase and there is down side seen on property prices,&quot; said Ben Kwong, director of research at Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>China incorporated H-shares were generally higher after news that Tsingtao Brewery was undergoing a corporate restructuring aimed at rebuilding its stock market image.</p>
<p>Tsingtao jumped HK$1.675, or about 42 percent, to close at HK$5.65.</p>
<p>&quot;Rumours about possible restructuring on other H-shares, especially on petrochemical stocks, lifted the whole sector,&quot; said Peter So deputy head of research at Schroders Securities.</p>
<p>The H-share index surged 59.79 points, or 5.61 percent, to 1,125.28. But Hang Seng China-Affiliated Corporation Index lost 47.56 points, or 1.38 percent, to end at 3,401.41.</p>
<p>Hopewell lost HK$0.20 to HK$4.90 after announcing the sale of its remaining stake in Consolidated Power Asia Ltd.</p>
<p>Total market turnover increased to HK$21.71 billion from HK$20.99 billion on Tuesday.</p>
<p>July index futures eased 80 points to 15,420.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
