<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="734634" id="root" date="1997-07-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan says Kanematsu involved in Brunei refinery.</title>
<headline>Taiwan says Kanematsu involved in Brunei refinery.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-07-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan monopoly Chinese Petroleum Corp said on Wednesday it would form a joint venture with Japan's Kanematsu Corp and the Brunei government to build Brunei's second oil refinery.</p>
<p>&quot;Kanematsu is also in the project,&quot; a Chinese Petroleum official told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Industry sources in Taipei said Kanematsu would build the proposed US$1 billion refinery complex, which officials say will have daily production capacity of 60,000 barrels.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum Corp, a state-run company, would sign a memorandum of understanding with Brunei's state petroleum bureau on July 23 to build the refinery plant, company officials said.</p>
<p>Signing for Chinese Petroleum would be its chairman, Lee Shu-chiu, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;The chairman (Lee) will visit our Singapore office on July 17 and go to Brunei to sign the refinery memorandum on July 23,&quot; a senior Chinese Petroleum official told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Once the memorandum is signed, Chinese Petroleum and Kanematsu will have 18 months to complete a feasibility study, after which a letter of intent would be signed and the start of construction could be authorised, the official said.</p>
<p>There were no estimates as to when the refinery might be completed and enter production.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum officials have estimated the joint-venture project was worth US$1 billion, but declined to give details.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum officials said the integrated chemical complex, once completed, would use Bruneian light sweet crude to produce 420,000 tonnes of p-xylene a year and 200,000 tonnes of benzene a year.</p>
<p>The refinery's output would be earmarked mainly for export.</p>
<p>Oil-rich Brunei, a southeast Asian sultanate of 270,000 people that shares the island of Borneo with Malaysia and Indonesia, has only one small refinery with a daily capacity of just 9,000 barrels. That plant is operated by Brunei Shell Petroleum Co Bhd, an equally owned joint venture between Royal/Dutch Shell and the Brunei government.</p>
<p>In May, Brunei's Oil and Gas Agency signed a letter of intent with German state-owned engineering firm IAB to build a 160,000 barrel-per-day refinery at cost of 2.6 billion marks (US$1.5 billion).</p>
<p>IAB has said a feasibility study for the project would be completed by the end of 1997 and construction would take four and a half years.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum said its project with Kanematsu was not related to the German project.</p>
<p>In 1996, Brunei produced about 165,000 barrels a day of crude and has proven reserves of 1.4 billion barrels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRUNEI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
