<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73471" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish wheat imports seen continuing.</title>
<headline>Turkish wheat imports seen continuing.</headline>
<byline>Ercan Ersoy</byline>
<dateline>ANTALYA, Turkey 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wheat flour producers in Turkey, the third largest flour exporter in the world after the European Union and the United States, said on Tuesday the sector would still need imports due to poor local crop quality.</p>
<p>&quot;Difficulties in finding standard quality wheat in Turkey makes it necessary for flour millers to carry on imports,&quot; said Ilker Tanik, secretary general of the Turkish Millers' Association.</p>
<p>&quot;I think wheat imports will further rise because millers will now go for importing wheat on condition of flour exports,&quot; Tanik told Reuters in an interview during an international grains conference in southern Turkey.</p>
<p>He said the imports would benefit from a government incentive of zero import tax on the condition that the imported goods be fully used to produce export items.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the sector will import about 750,000 tonnes in the harvest season from June this year to May next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Turkey imported more than 1.5 million tonnes in 1995/96, with private companies importing more than 700,000 tonnes of wheat by July this year, Tanik said.</p>
<p>Official figures supplied at the conference by the foreign trade undersecretariat showed Turkey had imported 1.253 million tonnes of wheat in calendar 1995, of which 1.2 million tonnes was milling wheat. The balance was durum.</p>
<p>Turkey on Saturday raised taxes on wheat and corn imports to 15 percent from three in an effort to attract local millers and pasta producers to local crop use after an expected rise in both the wheat and corn harvests.</p>
<p>Turkey expects a rise to 18 to 19 million tonnes of wheat in 1996/97 from 15.5 million tonnes a year earlier, but Western grain traders and local millers say this year's harvest cannot go above 16.5 million tonnnes.</p>
<p>Turkish pasta producers, whose exports are second only to those of Italy, have already said they would continue imports regardless of the import tax rise.</p>
<p>At least two pasta companies are said to have made deals to buy a total of 60,000 tonnes of durum wheat for October and December shipments, according to industry sources.</p>
<p>&quot;Our ideal is to produce flour for export purposes from local wheat crop but with the government's protectionist policies this is simply not possible,&quot; Tanik said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the tax rise would increase the cost of imports but the price of imported wheat would still be less than that in the domestic market, where prices are up to 25 percent higher than world levels because of government policies.</p>
<p>Tanik said Turkey's flour exports rose to 683,500 tonnes in calendar 1995 from 613,000 tonnes a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect at least the same export level for this (calendar) year as the one we had last year, or even a little bit more,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts and industrialists said flour exports from Turkey, which has a 10 percent share in the world flour export market, were adversely affected by the government's subsidising wheat prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Realistic base prices in line with free market rules rather than prices determined politically must be determined. Any change in the wheat prices are directly reflected on flour exports,&quot; said Rint Akyuz, chairman of the Rotel Foreign Trade company.</p>
<p>He told the conference the government should support the flour industry by providing cheaper production inputs such as energy and water.</p>
<p>&quot;An independent and autonomous farm board, made up of government officials and sector representatives, should be established to determine policies on wheat and other grains,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Both Tanik and Akyuz pointed to the need for setting up a futures markets for better control of grain prices.</p>
<p>Presently there is no such market in Turkey, and plans to establish one for the cotton trade remains tied up in a bureacratic row between rival government institutions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANTALYA, Turkey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
