<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73512" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Monsanto to buy Asgrow unit from Empresas.</title>
<headline>Monsanto to buy Asgrow unit from Empresas.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Monsanto Co. said Tuesday it will buy the Asgrow Agronomics business of Seminis Inc., a subsidiary of Empresas La Moderna SA de CV, for $240 million.</p>
<p>Asgrow Agronomics is a major U.S. soybean seed company with international operations, Monsanto said.</p>
<p>&quot;Asgrow's strength in soybeans is particularly important to us as we accelerate the sale of Roundup Ready soybeans and other new soybean products to farmers worldwide,&quot; Hendrik Verfaillie, executive vice president of Monsanto, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Roundup Ready soybeans are genetically altered to withstand the use of Monsanto's Roundup herbicide. Farmers who plant Roundup Ready soybeans are able to spray their fields with Roundup to kill weeds without harming the crop.</p>
<p>St. Louis-based Monsanto, which produces chemicals, phamaceuticals and biotechnology, said it has made another agreement with Empresas. Under a technology deal, Monsanto will become a preferred provider of agronomic and quality genetic traits it develops through biotechnology that will be used by Empresas in its fruit and vegetable seed and produce businesses.</p>
<p>Monsanto said Empresas, based in Mexico, is the global leader in the vegetable seed market and has a 22 percent market share worldwide.</p>
<p>Monsanto stock was up 12 cents in early trading to $35.25 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
