<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735331" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Who's Who is Liberia's race for presidency.</title>
<headline>Who's Who is Liberia's race for presidency.</headline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Charles Taylor, who launched Liberia's civil war in 1989, is widely rated as the man to beat in Saturday's presidential election. He faces 11 rivals including two fellow warlords-turned-politicians and a woman.</p>
<p>Thumbnail sketches of the candidates follow.</p>
<p>CHARLES TAYLOR</p>
<p>Now 49, he launched Liberia's civil war from Ivory Coast on Christmas Eve 1989. West African peacekeepers twice stopped him and his National Patriotic Front of Liberia (NPFL) taking the capital -- in 1990 and 1992. A descendant of freed American slaves who set up Liberia in 1847, he returned to Monrovia in triumph under a 1995 power sharing deal which unravelled. His fighters were in the thick of 1996 ethnic and political fighting in the capital. He heads the National Patriotic Party of Liberia.</p>
<p>ELLEN JOHNSON-SIRLEAF</p>
<p>The former Africa director of the U.N. Development Programme, she is the only woman candidate. Under slain ethnic Krahn president Samuel Doe, she defied a ban on politics and ended up behind bars on sedition charges. Escaping from prison in 1986, she fled to the United States. Johnson-Sirleaf, 58, is the Unity Party candidate.</p>
<p>ALHAJI KROMAH</p>
<p>A Moslem, he is a journalist turned warlord and politician. Head of the Mandingo wing of ULIMO, set up to fight Taylor in 1991, his forces fought alongside Taylor's against ethnic Krahn rivals in 1996. A member of the power sharing transitional ruling council, he heads the All Liberia Coalition Party.</p>
<p>GEORGE BOLEY</p>
<p>A politician turned warlord, Boley is running for Doe's former party, the National Democratic Party of Liberia. He led the Krahn dominated Liberia Peace Council (LPC), set up to oppose Taylor. Like Taylor and Kromah, he was one of six members of the transitional ruling council.</p>
<p>GABRIEL BACCUS MATHEWS</p>
<p>Matthews, 49, stands for the United People's Party and enjoys strong grass-roots support. Doe's first foreign minister, he led the 1979 protests crushed by Guinean troops on the orders of the then president William Tolbert. Reports at the time said 140 people died. Williams and others were sentenced to death for treason but freed when Doe seized power and killed Tolbert.</p>
<p>TOGBAH-NAH TIPOTEH</p>
<p>Now 56, he founded the Movement for Justice in Africa (MOJA), which advocated human rights and democracy in Tolbert's one-party era. He changed his name from Rudolph Roberts to Togbah-Na Tipoteh -- after sandals made from disused tyres which he popularised to symbolise poverty of ordinary Liberians. He was Doe's first planning and economic affairs minister. He fled into exile in 1981, accusing Doe of corruption and not sticking to economic reforms. He runs for the Liberian People's Party.</p>
<p>HENRY BOIMA FAHNBULLEH</p>
<p>Among a first group of &quot;progressives&quot;, educated Liberians opposed to the dominance of descendants of the freed slaves, he served as education minister and foreign minister under Doe. Now, 48, he runs for the Reformation Alliance Party.</p>
<p>CLETUS WOTORSON</p>
<p>A geophysicist, he is a former managing director of the Liberia Petroleum and Refinery Corp. Among the general public, he is better remembered as vice-chairman of the national Football Association in the 1980s. Aged 60, he runs for the Liberian Action Party.</p>
<p>HARRY FOMBAH MONIBA</p>
<p>Vice-president under Doe, he is a teacher turned politician and a former ambassador to London. Now 59, he runs for the Liberian National Union.</p>
<p>CHEA CHEAPOO</p>
<p>Doe's first justice minister and a former chief justice, Cheapoo, 54, runs for the Progressive People's Party.</p>
<p>FAYAH SAHR GBOLLIE</p>
<p>A former teacher and an agronomist aged 52, he runs for the Free Democratic Party.</p>
<p>MARTIN  SHERIFF</p>
<p>A businessman aged 45 representing the National Reformation Party. He has no previous experience in government or politics.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
