<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735382" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: PRESS DIGEST - Zimbabwe - July 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Zimbabwe - July 17.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Zimbabwe press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL GAZETTE</p>
<p>- The cabinet has decided to disband the state-run Central Purchasing Authority, which has been hit by a rash of scandals involving the misappropriation and disappearance of up to Z$100 million in public funds so far this year.</p>
<p>- The government's privatisation drive is gathering momentum and two state-owned companies -- the Commercial Bank of Zimbabwe and the Cotton Company of Zimbabwe -- are planning share offers to raise a total of Z$1 billion in the local market.</p>
<p>- All commercial attaches at Zimbabwe's foreign missions have been recalled as the government, struggling to inject new life into the economy, intensifies its campaign for foreign investment, sources said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS HERALD</p>
<p>- A consortium of local businessmen and Russian partners have set up a cargo airline whose first aircraft flew into the country last week.</p>
<p>- An official from the Finance Ministry says the government neglected to amend the Customs and Excise Act to allow for duty- free importation of capital goods, a lapse which is compromising the implementation of projects in export processing zones.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE HERALD</p>
<p>- Organisation of African Unity Secretary-General Salim Ahmed Salim arrived in Harare on Wednesday for talks with current OAU chairman Robert Mugabe.</p>
<p>- Zimbabwe's parliament on Wednesday ratified a Z$957 million loan agreement signed by the government with international agencies to finance the construction of a new terminal for Harare Airport.</p>
<p>--Harare Newsroom +263-4 72 52 28/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
