<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735323" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GABON: Brazzaville warring parties in Gabon for talks.</title>
<headline>Brazzaville warring parties in Gabon for talks.</headline>
<byline>Yvette Bivigu</byline>
<dateline>LIBREVILLE 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Envoys from Congo Republic President Pascal Lissouba arrived in Gabon on Thursday for talks aimed at ending over a month of political and ethnic bloodshed in their capital Brazzaville, officials said.</p>
<p>Sources close to Gabon's presidency said talks would begin in the capital Libreville late on Thursday or Friday. A U.N. source said Friday was more likely.</p>
<p>Residents in Brazzaville told Reuters by telephone that a fragile truce there was holding but said fighters from both sides were looting in areas under their control -- with hitherto untouched administrative buildings a target.</p>
<p>&quot;Each side is finishing off the looting of the district under its control,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Gabon's veteran president, Omar Bongo, is spearheading international mediation efforts with U.N. and Organisation of African Unity special envoy Mohamed Sahnoun.</p>
<p>Envoys of former military leader Denis Sassou Nguesso, Lissouba's rival and predecessor, arrived on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Shooting broke out in Brazzaville on Wednesday night but state radio there reported that rival fighters had met to bury the hatchet -- suggesting a celebration of peace progress.</p>
<p>The radio, heard across the river in Kinshasa after over 40 minutes of sustained shellfire and other shooting, spoke of reconciliation. Brazzaville state television showed the two sides fraternising.</p>
<p>The conflict began after soldiers surrounded Sassou's home as part of a crackdown on private militia ahead of a now postponed July 27 presidential election. Of numerous truces in the showdown none has been strictly adhered to.</p>
<p>Sahnoun says the aim of talks is to enable a presidential election to be held within the next two months. Plans for a U.N.-sponsored mainly African peace force are taking shape.</p>
<p>Medical workers say the clashes have killed hundreds of people in the capital of the oil-producing former French colony, many of them civilians.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CONGO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIBREVILLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GABON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
