<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735321" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya ruling party proposes reforms.</title>
<headline>Kenya ruling party proposes reforms.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The ruling Kenya African National Union (KANU) party proposed on Thursday the repeal or amendment of 11 controversial laws that an opposition-backed alliance demands should be reformed.</p>
<p>If enacted, the reform proposals made by KANU would reduce the powers of President Daniel arap Moi, 73 and Kenya's ruler for 19 years, who agreed under pressure to multi-party politics in 1991.</p>
<p>KANU's National Executive Council (NEC) also recommended the government should establish a commission to review the constitution.</p>
<p>KANU Vice-President George Saitoti, who holds the same post in the government, told a news conference the the formation of the commission and the changes to the 11 laws would come before presidential and parliamentary elections due later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The NEC recommends that the government should consider and publish a Bill for enactment by the current parliament providing for the establishment of a Commission to review the constitution of Kenya and make proposals,&quot; the NEC said.</p>
<p>&quot;The NEC further recommended that the Government should consider and publish a Statute Law...Bill for enactment by the current parliament which provides for the following laws to be repealed or amended where deemed necessary,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>An NEC statement then listed 11 laws which included what opposition groups hold as the &quot;minimal&quot; reforms they demand before the elections.</p>
<p>The shock announcement by the ruling party led by Moi dumbfounded opposition leaders, who earlier announced a list of new &quot;mass actions&quot; in Kenya to keep the heat on the president.</p>
<p>The president has held that there was no time for any constitutional reforms before elections this year.</p>
<p>Saitoti said Moi chaired the NEC meeting and indicated the review commission would work beyond the current parliament, where KANU has a majority.</p>
<p>Asked by reporters if KANU was reacting to pressure, Saitoti said: &quot;We have agreed to enact these changes. There have been no delays in the matter, we wanted to take in the wishes of everyone.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They (the opposition) asked for so-called minimum constitutional reforms. We have not only agreed to these, but have also proposed that comprehensive reforms be examined,&quot; said NEC member Nicholas Biwott, a government minister of state.</p>
<p>Asked for his reaction to the surprise announcement from KANU, opposition politician Richard Leakey told Reuters:</p>
<p>&quot;If this is actually truthful and it is implemented I think a very great many people in the opposition will be very pleased.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have to be sure this is not a time-wasting measure,&quot; said Leakey, who is secretary-general of the unregistered Safina party and on the National Convention Executive Committee (NCEC), an alliance of pro-reform opposition parties and other bodies.</p>
<p>&quot;If this is what we have been asking for and they have agreed to it then I cannot criticise it if this is a sincere offer,&quot; added Leakey, Kenya's former wildlife guardian and a renowned palaeontologist.</p>
<p>Saitoti said bills to be repealed or amended if necessary included the Public Order Act regulating public meetings, the Preservation of Public Security Act providing for detention without trial and the Societies Act, under which all parties must be registered.</p>
<p>Saitoti said KANU wanted the repeal or amendment of the National Assembly and Presidential Elections Act, which the opposition says favour's KANU, as well as the Vagrancy Act allowing police to detain anyone on suspicion they might be vagabonds.</p>
<p>The opposition-backed NCEC earlier called for &quot;mass actions&quot; including a rally in Kenya's second-city Mombasa, centre of its tourism industry on its Indian Ocean coast, on July 26 and a national general strike and sit-in on August 8.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
