<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735448" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo wheat harvest completed on 41 pct area-agency.</title>
<headline>Yugo wheat harvest completed on 41 pct area-agency.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite frequent rains, wheat harvesting in Serbia has been completed on some 340,000 hectares, or 41 percent of total wheat area, Tanjug news agency quoted the Serbian agriculture minister as saying on Thursday.</p>
<p>Average yields ranged between 3.0 and 9.0 tonnes per hectare and the total 1997 crop is estimated at more than 3.0 million tonnes, or double last year's.</p>
<p>&quot;This will completely meet the country's needs and enable creation of regular reserves, while exports of slightly more than 300,000 tonnes of wheat are planned,&quot; Jovan Babovic was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Annual needs are estimated at 2.3-2.4 million tonnes.</p>
<p>According to Babovic, the higher yields are the result of successful autumn sowing and better fertilising of the crop, sown on some 800,000 ha, more than 200,000 ha above the previous year's wheat area.</p>
<p>Weather conditions permitting, harvesting is expected to be completed in seven to ten days, Babovic said.</p>
<p>The purchase price of 1.10 dinars per kilogram of new wheat set by the Serbian government is encouraging and farmers and other producers are satisfied with the price, Babovic said.</p>
<p>Wheat market surpluses are estimated at around 1.7 million tonnes. The Serbian Commodity Reserve Agency has purchased around 540,000 tonnes so far through barter exchange for machinery, fuel and fertilisers.</p>
<p>The Commodity Reserve Agency will buy all offered market surpluses from farmers and producers. Payments will be in three instalments and will be made directly and without mediators, Babovic said.</p>
<p>The first 40 percent instalment will be paid in cash to farmers and through giro accounts for other producers by end of August. The second two instalments of 30 percent each will be in forward wheat contracts issued by Serbia's Commodity Reserve Agency by end September and end October this year.</p>
<p>Wheat is also purchased by milling and other organisations.</p>
<p>Babovic said seed wheat production this year will be enough for fall sowing. -- Amra Kevic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 311 4305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
