<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735564" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - CROATIA - July 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - CROATIA - July 17.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the main stories in Croatian dailies on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Croatian government endorses annual report on human rights, compiled by various ministries and other state bodies, and the ombudsman's report. Most of the complaints he dealt with in the past year related to infringements of tennant rights, social security and pensions, obtaining croatian citizenship and work of state telecoms and electricity board.</p>
<p>- Croatian Tourist Union, presenting its programme of tourist promotion in 1998, says its plan for next year is to bring a million more guests.</p>
<p>- A delegation of the Yugoslav soccer champion Partizan came to Croatia, for the first time since Croatia's secession in 1991, to watch a match by Croatia Zagreb, Partizan's rival in the qualifications for European champions' league.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- World Bank presented Croatia with a study called &quot;Challenges of Peace&quot;. The study calls for reduction of public spending and trimming of state companies' budgets, if Croatia wishes to see economic growth.</p>
<p>- 'Klein' remains after Klein - Even after U.S. general Jacques Klein, head of the U.N. administration of Serb-populated Eastern Slavonia, leaves, U.S. policies in the region will remain dominant.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Croatian Tourist Union promotes new slogan - &quot;Croatia - Paradise on Earth&quot;, to replace &quot;Croatia- a small country for a big holiday&quot;.</p>
<p>- About one thousand Croatians have emigrated to New Zealand since 1990, says Ministry for Immigration.</p>
<p>- After third person was gunned down on Zagreb streets in mafia style, fear spreads among citizens. Police repeat &quot;we don't have mafia in the proper sense&quot; but admit ther are several criminal groups involved in drug trafficking, car theft and racketeering.</p>
<p>- Croatian GSM mobile phone network offers a wide range of new service to clients, including getting unlisted numbers.</p>
<p>- Huge forrest fire near Omis on the Adriatic coast is spreadint and has come close to houses, prompting evacuation of some villagers. -- Zagreb newsroom +385 1 455 7075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
