<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735553" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Forint firms vs basket as zloty fears subside.</title>
<headline>Forint firms vs basket as zloty fears subside.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's forint opened easier against the dollar on Thursday but shaved some of its earlier losses versus the central bank currency basket triggered by a five percent plunge of the Polish zloty on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The forint opened at 192.90/193.00 to the dollar and stood at 192.80/85 at 0735 GMT, compared with Wednesday's close of 192.55/60.</p>
<p>Dealers said the forint eased against the dollar due to the mark's overnight weakening in the dollar cross, which was not offset by the forint's move towards the National Bank of Hungary's resistance level (NBH bid).</p>
<p>The forint, which usually trades at the NBH bid, opened ten fillers below the resistance level, compared with a 20 filler distance at Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>Dealers said the forint was likely to return to the NBH bid on Thursday as the impact of the Polish zloty's fall was vague and investors did not regard the countries of the region as a bloc.</p>
<p>&quot;The Polish government has serious (trade) deficit problems and the floods there also caused damage worth some $2 billion,&quot; said Istvan Gere of ING Bank. &quot;There is nothing like that in Hungary.&quot;</p>
<p>The Polish zloty already firmed on Wednesday following central bank intervention and Polish Finance Minister Marek Belka said Thursday morning that the recent sharp fall was caused by speculation rather than bad fundamentals.</p>
<p>Gere said foreign currency buying by foreign investors in Hungary on Wednesday were not substantial and a larger deal by domestic banks may also move the forint some 15 fillers within the intervention band.</p>
<p>The forint floats within the NBH's 4.5 percent wide intervention band, against a currency basket made up 30 percent of the dollar and 70 percent of the ECU.</p>
<p>-- Sandor Peto, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
