<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735656" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Rival Mexican union groups suspend talks.</title>
<headline>Rival Mexican union groups suspend talks.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>An official of the pro-government Mexican Workers Confederation (CTM) on Thursday said it had temporarily suspended talks with independent unions, and denied any agreements had been reached.</p>
<p>&quot;There's going to be dialogue, but in time,&quot; Javier Pineda, the CTM's Labor Secretary, told reporters.</p>
<p>He said the suspension was aimed at giving the Labor Congress, which groups the CTM and other pro-government labor confederations, time to work out a strategy in the talks.  </p>
<p>The Congress and the CTM have been shaken up since the death of veteran labor leader Fidel Velazquez last month, who had avidly opposed talks with independent unions to the end.</p>
<p>The CTM, of some 6 million workers, has been loyally supportive of government efforts to limit wage increases to keep a lid on inflation. But since Mexico's 1994-5 economic crisis, independent unions have flexed their muscles and drained some worker support away from the CTM.</p>
<p>This week, Agustin Rodriguez, head of the independent union association known as &quot;The Forum&quot;, told Reuters the two sides had agreed to discuss an emergency salary increase and job creation mechanisms. But Pineda denied that.</p>
<p>&quot;There's still no agenda,&quot; he told reporters as he entered a meeting with government and business leaders to discuss anti-inflation policies.</p>
<p>((-- Veronica Galan, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9553))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
