<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735630" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine blue-chips end lower in muted trade.</title>
<headline>Argentine blue-chips end lower in muted trade.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine stocks closed lower Thursday in a cautious, low-volume market largely deserted by institutional investors, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was emptier. The Brazil stock exchange fall meant institutional investors stayed away,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The blue-chip MerVal index  .MERV ended 1.33 percent lower at 815.35, after having been 0.45 percent up midsession.</p>
<p>&quot;The market had a go at rising at the beginning of the session, but without much confidence, especially because there was little volume,&quot; said Gabriel Ruiz of Tavelli y Compania.</p>
<p>He said Brazilian fears continued to prey on the market.  </p>
<p>&quot;Without doubt everyone is totally absorbed by the volatility in the Brazilian market,&quot; said Ruiz.</p>
<p>He said that the Buenos Aires market changed direction and headed south when Sao Paulo's Bovespa index began to fall and rumors reemerged of a possible Brazilian devaluation.</p>
<p>The MerVal ended up 2.28 percent at 826.37 Wednesday. But it was spooked by Brazilian devaluation rumors Tuesday and lost five percent in the first two days of the week.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is reorganizing itself with selective profit-taking. The base is solid and the Merval is showing strong support at 800 points,&quot; an analyst said.  </p>
<p>Turnover was $30.2 million, with 21 stocks closing higher, 36 down, and 17 unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook's good, especially for construction and oil after the good placement of YPF shares,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>Ten percent of shares in oil firm YPF, which previously belonged to the firm's employees, were sold at $29.25 each Wednesday. YPF closed up 0.35 pesos at 30.40 pesos.</p>
<p>Sao Paulo's Bovespa lost 7.22 percent Thursday.</p>
<p>((--Walter Bianchi, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0633))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
