<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73575" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE-Treasure hunters track Spanish galleon.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Treasure hunters track Spanish galleon.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Commins</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of treasure hunters whose home base is more than 1,000 miles (1,60O kms) from the nearest ocean is on the trail of a 16th century Spanish ship believed to have gone down with a fortune in gold and other booty from the New World.</p>
<p>Jon Burgess, who heads Minnesota-based Treasure Ventures Inc., said his salvage crew in the Bahamas recently uncovered artifacts including a bottle and pottery shards that indicate the presence of a Spanish ship.</p>
<p>But it is too soon to tell if the wreck is that of the Nuestra Senora de la Concepcion, which went down in 1563 and has become Treasure Ventures' Holy Grail. &quot;If we find the Concepcion, it will be the largest treasure find in modern times,&quot; Burgess said in an interview from a bar -- the only telephone available on Ragged Island, about 60 miles (96 km) off the northern coast of Cuba.</p>
<p>According to manifests found in Spanish archives, the Concepcion was carrying at least 25 tonnes of gold and silver, coins, chests of precious stones and jewelry to the king of Spain and personal items that belonged to the widow of Spanish explorer Hernando Cortes. If that is true, Treasure Ventures estimates the booty from the Concepcion could top $1 billion.</p>
<p>But that is a big &quot;if.&quot;</p>
<p>Treasure Ventures, which began sifting through eight shipwrecks this summer, has yet to find any treasure. Most of the wrecks they found appear to be from the late 1700s and early 1800s and have yielded a couple of cannon, a piece of gold jewelry, shards of pottery and spoons. Bad weather has hampered efforts to dive at the most promising site, said Burgess, the grandson of a Yukon gold prospector.</p>
<p>The real target of the quest is the Concepcion. The hunt began in 1993 when Treasure Ventures sent three researchers to Spain to search archives. Dr. Eugene Lyon, director of the Centre for Historic Research at Florida's Flagler College, said he directed the firm to a researcher in Spain. Lyon did the research that led to treasure hunter Mel Fisher's discovery of the Spanish galleon Atocha, which was said to have yielded some $400 million in treasure.</p>
<p>The Spanish archive search yielded clues to where the Concepcion was believed to have sunk. That information, along with a magnetometer air survey, which detects unusual deposits of iron, led Treasure Ventures to the 1,000 square mile (2,600 sq km) area they leased from the Bahamian government. This spring, divers began the search for the Concepcion.</p>
<p>Treasure Ventures has raised about $850,000 from investors thus far to fund the expedition, which has its own home page on the Internet. But it has only enough money in its coffers to finance about one more season of searching, Burgess said.</p>
<p>Treasure Ventures board member Michael Coopet, a Minnesota tax lawyer, is leading the search for a corporate sponsor. He said he and other board members, who include a Minnesota real estate developer and a Wisconsin orthopedic surgeon, were lured by dreams of the Concepcion and its treasure.</p>
<p>&quot;I got seduced by the whole project. I fell in love with it,&quot; he said. &quot;It's a very romantic story.&quot;</p>
<p>The search for treasure at the bottom of the sea is largely the work of professional salvagers. It can be at the same time exciting, expensive and painstaking.</p>
<p>For example, Terrawest Industries Inc., a publicly traded company based in Vancouver, British Columbia, began searching in Cuban waters in July 1995 in a five-year joint venture with Canpac Divers Inc. of Vancouver and the Cuban government.</p>
<p>Terrawest has found some wrecks but no treasure yet, said Don Myers, a spokesman for the company.</p>
<p>At the moment, Treasure Ventures is in the same boat. &quot;We just have to continue to look, searching, using our hunches,&quot; Coopet said. &quot;And come hell or high water, we're going to find the Concepcion.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
