<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735770" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Bangkok shies away from seeking aid, but may later.</title>
<headline>Bangkok shies away from seeking aid, but may later.</headline>
<byline>Yoshiko Mori</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top monetary officials of troubled Thailand on Thursday refrained from asking for money from either Japan or the International Monetary Fund (IMF) -- but left open the possibility of doing so in the future.</p>
<p>Thai Finance Minister Thanong Bidaya said on Thursday the country is not seeking financial assistance from the IMF and he had not come to Japan on his current visit, which began on Wednesday, to seek aid.</p>
<p>&quot;We just feel it's not necessary at all, that's why,&quot; Thanong, who is accompanied in Tokyo by Bank of Thailand Governor Rerngchai Marakanond, told reporters.</p>
<p>But separately, in a speech delivered to Japanese bankers on Thursday, Thanong said Thailand would ask Japan to join in any international support scheme if it were to call for one.</p>
<p>He called recent media reports suggesting the country was trying to raise a total of $10 billion to $20 billion groundless.</p>
<p>Thai central bank governor Rerngchai did not ask Japan for any financial support during a meeting on Thursday with Bank of Japan (BOJ) Governor Yasuo Matsushita, BOJ executive director Takashi Anzai said. &quot;There was no request from Thailand for financial support,&quot; Anzai said.</p>
<p>Analysts and bankers in Tokyo said the message appeared to be that Bangkok had not yet put together a concrete plan to bail out its economy from its worst slump in over a decade, and therefore was not ready make a formal request.</p>
<p>&quot;Who else is going to be able to lead such a global aid package, if Thailand doesn't ask Japan and the IMF?&quot; said a senior analyst at a major Japanese brokerage.</p>
<p>But some bankers said the three-day trip by the Thai officials includes scheduled individual meetings with top Japanese bankers -- which may yield some results in their favour.</p>
<p>In his speech on Thursday, Thanong asked Japanese banks to increase their credit lines extended to both financial and corporate Thai borrowers.</p>
<p>Financial market sources speculated that resources for any Thai rescue plan would have to come primarily from global financial bodies such as the IMF and the Asian Development Bank (ADB), as well as the Japanese government and commercial banks.</p>
<p>Thailand's reluctance to borrow from the IMF reflects its fear of losing autonomy over economic policies, analysts said.</p>
<p>In order to open a line of credit with the IMF, a country must agree with the fund on its economic policy framework and structural reforms, including tough conditions on spending, balancing trade and controlling inflation.</p>
<p>Japanese monetary authorities have indicated that a move by the IMF would be key to Japan's assistance for Thailand.</p>
<p>&quot;Usually, independence in tackling domestic problems suggests confidence in a country's policy management,&quot; said on senior analyst. &quot;But unfortunately, financial markets appear to be urging Bangkok to get international aid soon, rather than trying to settle it by itself.&quot;</p>
<p>On Thursday, the Thai baht fell to a quote of 30.12/17 per dollar in the domestic market after the reported comments by the Thai officials that they were not seeking aid from the IMF or Japan. The baht had been quoted at 30.08/15 in early trading.</p>
<p>The baht has lost 15-20 percent of its value against the U.S. dollar since the de facto devaluation of the Thai currency on July 2.</p>
<p>Despite the baht's weakness, there was no talk of any joint currency market intervention during Thursday's meeting between Rerngchai and Matsushita, Anzai said.</p>
<p>Analysts said that given the heavy commitment to Thailand by Japanese banks and manufacturers, Tokyo is likely to grant aid in some form to Thailand.</p>
<p>Japanese companies' direct investment in Thailand totalled 352.6 billion yen ($3.03 billion) in the three years to March.</p>
<p>Of Thailand's total $89.8 billion foreign debt, $73 billion is in the form of commercial credits, Thanong said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Japanese bankers estimated their lending to Thai companies was as much as half of the total commercial credits.</p>
<p>&quot;Japanese lending to Thai companies has surged since the creation of the offshore banking facility BIBF (Bangkok International Banking Facility) in 1993,&quot; said a senior banker at a major Japanese bank.</p>
<p>Most of the loans were denominated in U.S. dollars, and a steep baht depreciation is putting a heavier repayment burden on borrowers while causing huge currency losses on direct investment by Japanese manufacturers in Thailand, bankers said.</p>
<p>Thanong will also meet Japanese Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka on Friday.</p>
<p>Both Thai officials will also meet with leaders of the powerful Japanese business lobby Keidanren, or the Federation of Economic Organisations, on Friday. ($1=116 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
