<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735886" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: White House attacks fund raising hearings.</title>
<headline>White House attacks fund raising hearings.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, Political Correspondent</p>
<p>The White House and Democrats on Thursday launched a fierce attack on Senate hearings probing campaign fund-raising scandals, saying Republicans were playing fast and loose with the facts.</p>
<p>On the fifth day of testimony before the Senate Governmental Affairs Committee, any semblance of bipartisan cooperation broke down into an ugly brawl.</p>
<p>White House special counsel Lanny Davis said the Republican majority had adopted a &quot;partisan slashing approach ... This is not about a search for the truth. This is partisan politics.&quot;</p>
<p>Davis spoke after Democrats on the committee repeatedly assailed a Republican investigator who testified about contacts maintained by former Democratic Party fund-raiser John Huang while he was serving at the Commerce Department.</p>
<p>Republicans are trying to show that Huang may have betrayed U.S. secrets to his former employer, the Indonesian-based Lippo industrial conglomerate, which in turn could have passed them on to China. However, so far they have only presented circumstantial evidence.</p>
<p>Committee investigator Jack Cobb presented a series of charts showing that while at the Commerce Department, Huang had phoned officials or consultants of Lippo and other Asian individuals hundreds of times. Some had later made large contributions to the Democratic Party.</p>
<p>But Cobb could not prove that Huang had actively solicited funds, which would have been illegal. &quot;The charts reflect basically circumstantial evidence,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>New Jersey Democratic Sen. Robert Torricelli said Cobb had overstated his case while Michigan Democratic Sen. Carl Levin added: &quot;These charts do not come close to helping this committee.&quot;</p>
<p>Ohio Sen. John Glenn, the senior Democrat on the committee, said Huang was essentially being tried in absentia.</p>
<p>Huang, an Asian-American, worked at the Commerce Department from June 1994 to January 1996 before becoming a fund-raiser for the Democratic National Committee. He has refused to cooperate with the Senate investigation unless granted some form of immunity from prosecution.</p>
<p>Huang received secret briefings about China and visited the Chinese embassy and those of other Asian nations. He had access to classified State Department cables and saw up to 550 raw intelligence reports on China.</p>
<p>Cobb said he also visited the White House 67 times, several of them for meetings with President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>Davis said that was totally incorrect. In fact, Huang had only entered the White House 40 times during that time and all but one of his supposed meetings with Clinton were receptions involving large groups of people.</p>
<p>&quot;They (the Republicans) know that they are misleading you. The numbers are inaccurate. The charts are misleading. This is a partisan attack,&quot; Davis said.</p>
<p>Earlier, Committee Chairman Fred Thompson, a Tennessee Republican, said Huang was at the centre of a scheme to knowingly raise illegal foreign funds for the Democrats.</p>
<p>Thompson said Huang &quot;did not raise illegal contributions in 1996 from mistake or lack of knowledge.&quot;</p>
<p>Summarizing the results of the first five days of testimony, Thompson said Huang had raised more than $1.6 million, which the Democratic Party had subsequently returned. Most of that money came from foreign interests.</p>
<p>The committee also heard evidence from the secretary of a stockbroking company with offices across the street from the Commerce Department who testified that Huang often used a telephone in the office and received packages.</p>
<p>But secretary Paula Greene knew nothing of the content of the packages and did not know who Huang called.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
