<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735855" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Cyprus Trading Co to seek Athens listing.</title>
<headline>Cyprus Trading Co to seek Athens listing.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Cyprus Trading Corporation (CTC)plans to seek a listing on the Athens bourse as part of a drive to strengthen the capital base of the company, it said on Thursday.</p>
<p>CTC plans to raise some five million Cyprus pounds ($9.5 million) through a listing on the Athens Stock Exchange by the end of 1997 or the beginning of 1998, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;From assurances and indications we have from a financial banking institution in Greece, which is acting as an advisor to the company and which is prepared to assist in this new issue, there will be no difficulties in achieving this goal, and the sucess of this new issue in Cyprus pounds through the Athens Stock Exchange,&quot; CTC said in a statement.</p>
<p>The CTC statement said the Cypriot authorities are informed of the company's plans and are expected to approve them.</p>
<p>CTC, which imports a large range of consumer items into Cyprus, is launching an ambitious capital raising programme to accomodate the rapid growth of the company in recent years, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The programme will see an increase in the capital base of the company to 27.2 million pounds from its current levels of 17.7 million.</p>
<p>CTC plans to raise some five million pounds from a local rights issue, calls on two previous ordinary share issues and from excersising options on share warrants. ($=0.527 Cyprus pounds)</p>
<p>-- Nicosia newsroom 357 2 469625</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
