<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735842" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Mideast and African port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>Mideast and African port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>ISRAEL, July 15 - Haifa - Five vessels due, 1-2 days delay expected. Discharging at berth, 2 general cargo, 4 bulk, 3 containers loading/discharging at berth. Waiting at anchorage to load/discharge, 1 container, 2 tankers. 2 Bulk waiting at anchorage to discharge, 2 under repair. Ashdod - Two to three days delay expected. Discharging at berth, 9 general cargo, 2 bulk. 4 Containers loading/discharging at berth, 1 general cargo discharging at berth, 1 bulk loading at berth, 2 containers loading/discharging at berth. Eilat - No vessels.</p>
<p>MOZAMBIQUE, July 14 - Nacala - Port working normally (first come, first served basis). No restriction on berthing and sailing during night time. Draft restriction of 9.5 metres at general cargo berths and 14 metres at container berths. One tugboat available. Beira - General cargo berths working normally. 24 Hour berthing/sailing for vessels up to 140 metres loa. Some restriction for larger vessels and subject to prior arrangements with port captain. Max. draft for 24 hour navigation 7.5 metres. 2 Tugs available. General access channel - 2 Waverider buoys have been deployed in the approach channel. Each buoy is an approx. diameter of 1 metre with flashing orange light with flash frequency of five one second flashes every 26 seconds.</p>
<p>Maputo - Berthing/sailing of 24 hours for vessels up to 120 metres loa. Some restrictions for larger vessels and subject to prior arrangements with port captain. All berths fluid. Draft restriction in the channel is 9 metres less 0.5 metres plus rise of tide of the day. Max. draft for 24 hour navigation is 9 metres.</p>
<p>NAMIBIA, July 14 - Walvis Bay - Working normally.</p>
<p>SOUTH AFRICA, July 14 - Richards Bay - General cargo berths - Working normally. Bulk import berths - Working normally. Bulk export berths - Congested with delays of approx. 48 hours. Bulk coal berths - 4 Vessels alongside, 9 anchored, 10 due by 21/7. Berthing delays of up to 48 hours are currently being experienced. Durban - Container terminal - Delays of up to 12 hours can be expected whilst 2 new cranes are being positioned at the container terminal. Point/New Pier/Maydon Wharf berths - Working normally for general cargo vessels. Maize terminal - 3 Vessels due in July. Bunker supplies - Suppliers are currently experiencing problems with offpec fuel oil. Delays of up to 48 hours have been experienced during the weekend and are expected to continue until 15/7 p.m. Drydock and floating dock - 100 Percent committed for July and August.</p>
<p>East London - General cargo/combi terminal/tanker berths - Extremely busy, but no delays foreseen at this stage. Drydock - Fully booked until mid-December. Two tankers due weekly. Port Elizabeth - Three vessels in port, no delays expected on tanker, general or fruit berths. Fruit berths vacant. Container berth - 2 Vessels in port, 5 due on 16/7 and 17/7. Berthing delays of 12-18 hours can be expected. Ore berth - 1 Vessel in port, 1 due on 15/7, expected delays of 3 to 4 days. Cape Town - Breakbulk berths (general cargo) - Several bulk dischargers are expected until the end of the month and possible delays may occur. Fruit berths - Fully occupied. Container terminal - Working normally with vessels berthing and working on arrival. Bunker berths - Vessels now berthing and bunkering on arrival. Drydock and repair quay fully occupied and booking essential. Saldanha Bay - Working normally.</p>
<p>TUNISIA, July 12 - Tunis - Four vessels awaiting instructions, 1 motor tanker discharging bitumen, 1 discharging big bags (sodium sulphate), 2 general cargo vessels. Rades - Seven vessels in port of which 3 ro-ro, 3 discharging containers, 1 military vessel. Goulette - North side - 4 Vessels in port of which 1 each discharging cars, general cargo, 1 military vessel, 1 passenger vessel. South side - 1 Vessel discharging grain, 1 motor tanker discharging lab syrene. 3 Vessels in roads. Sfax - Nine vessels operating of which 2 discharging timber, 1 each discharging bulk wheat, bulk soya, 1 each loading bulk tsp, bagged tsp, bulk rock phosphate, bulk olive oil, tuna fish.</p>
<p>Sousse - Three vessels in port of which 1 loading bulk cargo, 2 discharging bagged sugar. No waiting time, no vessels awaiting orders. Gabes - Two vessels loading at berth of which 1 bulk fertiliser, 1 pellets of flour. 2 Vessels discharging at berth of which 1 bulk barley, 1 gas tanker, 1 bulk fertiliser waiting at anchorage to load. July 15 - Bizerta - Vessels operating, 2 discharging timber, 1 loading fuel oil, 1 discharging crude oil, 2 discharging steel, 1 other. No berthing delays or congestion. Zarzis - No vessels in port.</p>
<p>UNITED ARAB EMIRATES, July 13 - Dubai - Vessels operating from 6/7 to 12/7, 93 container vessels, 13 general cargo, 4 general cargo/containers, 6 bulk carriers, 5 car carriers, 16 tankers, 5 naval vessels, 1 U.A.E. naval vessel, 7 bunkers/repairs/stores etc., 6 dhows, 10 barges, 7 tugs, 16 supply boats, 2 passenger vessels, 1 lpg tanker, 1 self-propelled barge, 1 chemical tanker. Containers 30 vessels due, no delays expected, 3 loading at berth. General cargo, 12 vessels due, no delays expected, 1 loading at berth, 7 discharging at berth, 4 under repair/laid up. Tankers, 2 vessels due, no delays expected, 1 loading at berth, 1 discharging at berth, 7 under repair/drydock.</p>
<p>YEMEN, July 13 - Hodeidah - Berths Nos. 2 and 5 are occupied, all others vacant. Vessels alongside, 1 sugar, 1 general cargo. Vessels anchored, 3 wheat flour, 1 passenger vessel. Berthing waiting time, general cargo, containers up to 1 day, bagged cargo up to 3 days, bulk cargo up to 5 days. Mokha - No vessels alongside, none anchored, no berthing delays.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NAMIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
