<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="735912" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fund investors shouldn't overlook income.</title>
<headline>Fund investors shouldn't overlook income.</headline>
<byline>Clint Willis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>These days, it's hard to find a financial adviser who will talk much about bonds and other income investments. They'd rather celebrate the stock market's big gains. But income investments deserve at least a small place in every investor's portfolio.</p>
<p>By now, most investors have heard they should invest their long-term savings in stocks. After all, stocks have delivered the greatest long-term returns and offer the best chance at staying ahead of inflation during the coming decades.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, however, stocks are likely to be quite volatile. And while investors have been willing to ride out recent setbacks in stocks, they might act differently if a severe bear market takes prices 20 percent, 30 percent or even 40 percent lower. And what if stocks don't rebound right away as they have after recent corrections?</p>
<p>Some investors might find it hard to ride out even short-term stock market setbacks. For example, a middle-aged father with kids in college might need to tap his savings to meet current bills. Similarly, a retired investor who wants to keep a cushion for medical bills would be uncomfortable investing too much in stocks.</p>
<p>The solution is to invest at least some of your money in funds that can produce current income and protect your principal. Such funds invest in a wide range of securities, including high-yield stocks and a variety of bonds and other fixed-income securities. Such investments tend to hold up better than growth-oriented holdings during periods when stock prices are falling. Moreover, they provide current income that can bolster your portfolio's performance when capital gains are scarce.</p>
<p>How much should you invest in income funds? Some financial advisors recommend that the portion of your long-term savings invested in income-oriented assets should equal your age expressed as a percentage: That is, if you are 30, invest 30 percent in income-oriented funds; at age 70 the percentage can climb to 70 percent.</p>
<p>Many planners recommend a more aggressive approach if you are in sound financial shape and don't mind some bumps and bruises in the pursuit of higher gains.</p>
<p>But whatever balance you choose between income and growth, you should try to select funds that will efficiently implement your strategy. Here are some funds that can add a dose of income to your investment portfolio.</p>
<p>Investment-grade bond funds: These funds hold high-quality government and corporate bonds with little credit risk. Their share prices do fluctuate with interest rates, but you can minimise that risk by sticking with funds that hold short-term and intermediate bonds.</p>
<p>One good candidate is Stein Roe Intermediate Bond (800-338-2550; $2,500 minimum investment; no load). The fund's average maturity is 8.4 years. Fund manager Michael T. Kennedy invests in a variety of investment-grade corporate and government bonds.</p>
<p>If you're willing to take some more interest rate risk, check out Vanguard Bond Index-Total Bond Market (800-662-7447; $3,000 minimum; no load). It tries to track the performance of the Lehman Brothers Aggregate Bond Index.</p>
<p>International funds: Investing in foreign bond markets may sound like an odd way to add stability to your portfolio. But buying overseas bonds can reduce the risk of your income holdings, because they will be less dependent on the day-to-day fluctuations of the U.S. bond market. That said, make sure the fund you choose is broadly diversified and has a good track record.</p>
<p>Compass Capital International Bond Fund (888-426-6727; $5,000 minimum; no load) recently invested 58.5 percent of its assets in Europe, with the rest distributed primarily among Japan, Canada and the United States. The fund has generated annual gains of 9.4 percent during the past five years vs. 5.9 percent for the typical international bond fund, with 38 percent less volatility.</p>
<p>Multisector funds: Your best choice may be a fund that invests in different sectors of the bond market. Such funds sometimes shift their assets among a wide range of income investments, including high-quality and low-quality issues in the United States as well as developed and emerging overseas markets.</p>
<p>Multisector funds that make extremely large bets on a single type of security when they think it offers good value can be dangerous. But some entries in this category have generated superior returns with average risk by investing in a broadly diversified mix of income investments.</p>
<p>Dreyfus Strategic Income (800-645-6561; $2,500 minimum; no load) is a good example. It's gained 8.6 percent annually during the past five years vs. 7.8 percent for the typical multisector fund. Manager Kevin McClintock invests in a variety of bond sectors, including U.S government and corporate issues as well as some foreign debt.</p>
<p>(EDITORS: Clint Willis is a free-lance writer who covers mutual funds for Reuters. Any opinions in the column are solely those of Mr. Willis.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
