<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="736070" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida court rules woman can sue store for gun sale.</title>
<headline>Florida court rules woman can sue store for gun sale.</headline>
<dateline>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A woman who was paralysed after being shot by her ex-boyfriend can sue a chain store for selling the undoubtedly intoxicated man a gun and ammunition, the Florida Supreme Court ruled Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot close our eyes to this obvious danger or fail to impose some responsibility on those who control access to dangerous firearms,&quot; Justice Harry Anstead wrote in an 11-page opinion.</p>
<p>Deborah Kitchen was shot and critically wounded in December 1987 by Thomas Knapp, who testified he had consumed whisky and a case of beer before entering a Kmart Corp store in Tampa to buy a .22 calibre bolt action rifle.</p>
<p>Although he was too drunk to write legibly, Knapp was allowed to buy the gun and ammunition after the clerk filled out the required application for him.</p>
<p>He then went back to the bar where he and Kitchen had been and followed her as she and friends left in an car. Knapp rammed the vehicle with his truck, forcing it off the road, and shot Kitchen in the base of the neck.</p>
<p>The shot left her a quadriplegic and she sued Kmart, saying it was responsible for her injury.</p>
<p>A jury agreed, and awarded Kitchen $11.5 million.</p>
<p>But that reward was reversed by an appellate court, which ruled that Kitchen had no right to sue. But the high court disagreed in a unanimous ruling, sending the case back to the original trial court which can either uphold the $11.5 million reward or hear the case again based on precedent and evidence that came out during the appeals process, attorneys said.</p>
<p>One of Kitchen's attorneys said he was delighted and hoped the decision would change the way Florida governs the sale of guns.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very pleased and not just for Deborah Kitchen,&quot; said attorney Richard Kupfer, who represented Kitchen during her initial appeals. &quot;I just think this decision creates desirable public policy in the state.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLAHASSEE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
