<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73609" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy senate gives green light to energy watchdog.</title>
<headline>Italy senate gives green light to energy watchdog.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian Upper House of parliament (Senate) gave the final approval to the creation of a watchdog authority to oversee the electricity and gas sectors, a parliamentary official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The privatisation of electricity giant Enel has been held up for months while the watchdog bill crawled its way through parliament. The government hopes to sell off the state utility in the Spring of 1997.</p>
<p>The Senate's industrial production committee approved the nomination of Pippo Ranci as the watchdog's chairman, with Giuseppe Ammassari and Sergio Garribba also appointed to the authority's board.</p>
<p>The lower house of parliament has already approved the nominations and the bill now passes into law.</p>
<p>Chicco Testa, recently appointed Enel chairman, said earlier this month that the company was ready for privatisation and was only awaiting the creation of the authority and final clearance from the Treasury.</p>
<p>The government has not yet indicated how much of the company, one of the largest electricity utilities in Europe, it plans to place on the market in the initial flotation.</p>
<p>Enel said on Monday its pre-tax profit rose by just under two percent in the first six months of the year to 2.99 trillion lire. It gave no pre-tax profit figure or revenue data.</p>
<p>Critics of the planned privatisation programme have used the authority bill to delay the sell-off, adopting filibustering tactics to snarl progress of the draft law.</p>
<p>The government finally out-manoeuvred opponents by ordering the parliamentary industrial committees to rule on the nominations rather than the full chambers, where bills can be ambushed with greater ease.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +396 6782501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
