<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="736013" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Shoney's shareholders asking for meeting.</title>
<headline>Shoney's shareholders asking for meeting.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Shoney's Shareholders' Committee will arrive in U.S. District Court in Nashville on Tuesday July 22 with more than enough shareholder support to set a date for a special meeting, a company respresentative said.</p>
<p>The committee said in a statement that it has received agent designation cards from common stock shareholders of Shoney's representing over 39 percent of all oustanding shares.</p>
<p>The company representative told Reuters that under Tennessee law and company bylaws, representation of only 10 percent of the shares outstanding need to be present to hold a meeting.  </p>
<p>The committee, headed by Raymond Schoenbaum, the son of the franchise founder, said the 39 percent of shares represented supports its call for, and demand of, the special meeting. The representative said the meeting was tentatively set for Aug 17.</p>
<p>Shoney's chief administrative officer, Craig Barber, responding to the news said, &quot;Given that the Schoenbaum's started with approximately eight percent of the oustanding common stock, we are not surprised that they claim to have received enough consents to call a special meeting.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the calls delivered by the Schoenbaum's are determined to be valid, the next step will be for the Shoney's board of directors to set a record date and a special meeting date pursuant to Shoney's amended bylaws,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A Tennesee judge will determine if amendments to the bylaws adopted by the current board on June 22 are legal. The shareholder committee is arguing that the amended bylaws were made to improperly slow down the process of calling a special meeting by three months from the time it is requested.  </p>
<p>In a previously released statement, Shoney's chairman and chief executive officer, C. Stephen Lynn said, &quot;These amendments were adopted for the purpose of creating orderly procedures for the call and conduct of special meetings by shareholders.&quot;</p>
<p>The committee said that if the special meeting is held, Shoney shareholders will consider and vote on a number of proposals, including the replacement of the current board with a slate of nominees from the committee.</p>
<p>Schoenbaum commented on behalf of the committee, saying, &quot;The shareholders of Shoney's have spoken clearly and decisively that they are dissatisfied with Shoney's performance and want the opportunity sooner rather than later to elect the board of directors that will guide our company in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Shoney's stock closed at 6-1/4 down 3/16 on Thursday.  The stock is down 39 percent from its 52 week high of 10-1/4, reached July 17, 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
