<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="736208" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton urges blacks resist calls for segregation.</title>
<headline>Clinton urges blacks resist calls for segregation.</headline>
<byline>Arshad Mohammed</byline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton said on Thursday he would ask Congress for $350 million to improve teaching in poor urban and rural areas and urged blacks in America to resist calls for segregation in education.</p>
<p>Speaking to the NAACP's annual convention in his first speech on race since he launched a year-long effort to promote racial reconciliation last month, Clinton cautiously addressed a vivid debate within the group on the merits of integration.</p>
<p>Before about 3,000 members of the National Association for the Advancement of Coloured People, whose guiding principle has been integration since it was founded by blacks and whites in 1909, Clinton left little doubt where he stood.</p>
<p>&quot;For this whole century the NAACP has been a moral beacon, reminding us that in the end we have to become an integrated society, or one America,&quot; Clinton said. &quot;That's going to be more important than ever before.&quot;</p>
<p>Although there seems little chance of the NAACP changing its stance, a minority within the group has begun arguing that integration is undesirable or unnecessary.</p>
<p>Some members contend that the school desegregation that resulted from the landmark 1954 Brown v. Board of Education Supreme Court decision has not helped racial minorities enough.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a growing frustration among our people about whether educational opportunity and educational equality, after 43 years, is in fact a reality or just another dream deferred,&quot; NAACP President Kweisi Mfume, an ardent proponent of racial integration, told the convention.</p>
<p>In his speech, Clinton said he planned to ask Congress for $350 million over the next five years to encourage teachers to work in low-income areas and to improve teacher training. He also repeated his call for higher educational standards.</p>
<p>&quot;We must not replace the tyranny of segregation with the tyranny of low expectations,&quot; Clinton told the convention, which peppered his speech with applause.</p>
<p>The initiative was Clinton's first effort to reduce the U.S. racial divide since he made a much-publicised speech in San Diego last month warning Americans that the United States risks a return to racial segregation in higher education.</p>
<p>In that speech, Clinton said he planned to lead a one-year effort to promote dialogue on race to try to bring the country together. At the time, he also named a seven-member panel to examine the state of race relations in the country and give Americans a report outlining problems and possible solutions.</p>
<p>The White House said the $350 million would be spent to offer scholarships to people studying to be teachers if they committed to work in low-income areas for three years.</p>
<p>The money would also be used to give grants to between 10 and 15 exceptional teacher training institutions to help them improve training at other institutions and to place graduates in poor urban and rural schools.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
