<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="736280" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Refinancing spike no surprise in wake of low rates.</title>
<headline>Refinancing spike no surprise in wake of low rates.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fact that lower interest rates have bolstered refinancing activity should come as no surprise and refinancings should continue, according to the Mortgage Bankers Association's chief economist.</p>
<p>As reported, the Mortgage Bankers Association said that total application activity rose 29.6 percent in the week ended July 11. The seasonally adjusted refinancing index rose 22.7 percent, accounting for 27.2 percent of the week's activity, the MBA said.</p>
<p>As rates slide, &quot;We are starting to really move up again with refinancings,&quot; said MBA Chief Economist David Lereah.  </p>
<p>Lereah tied the increase in refinancings to low rates and said that, given the current interest rate environment, refinancings should continue to increase.</p>
<p>The MBA average contract rate for 30-year fixed-rate loans was 7.60 percent, down marginally from 7.61 percent the prior week. Lereah forecast a continued decline, following a recent downturn in the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corp (FHLMC) commitment rate. If such rates continued to drop, &quot;our contract rate will decline too,&quot; said Lereah.</p>
<p>The FHLMC weekly commitment rate was 7.47 percent.  </p>
<p>Lereah also predicted that the seasonally adjusted MBA refinancing index would break through the 500 level from 497.3 in the latest week. That index, however, reached the 1,500.00 level during the crest of a prior refinancing boom, he noted.</p>
<p>If the average contract rate fell to 7.25 percent, &quot;that will free up some money. We would see another big upward tick in refinancing activity,&quot; he said. The refinancing index could approach 600 or 700, as a result.</p>
<p>But Lereah said: &quot;I am not looking for rates to go that low. The summer is the only opportunity. Favorable inflation numbers and the perception of a neutral Fed is providing a positive tone to the bond market.&quot;</p>
<p>His outlook was for upward pressure in rates toward the end of 1997.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, savvy consumers with a heightened awareness of how to save on borrowing costs would mean more refinancings during the low-rate period, he maintained.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumers, I think, are primed&quot; to lock in lower rates, Lereah said.</p>
<p>(( --Aleksandrs Rozens, 212-859-1668 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
