<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="736426" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian gold up on thin supplies, silver down.</title>
<headline>Indian gold up on thin supplies, silver down.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold 24 carat closed 55 rupees higher at 4,505 rupees per 10 gramme against the previous close of 4,450 rupees per 10 gramme amid limited supplies while a recovery in the world market dragged prices up at the close, dealers said.</p>
<p>Gold opened weak but later on prices bounced back towards the close.</p>
<p>&quot;Hike in the premium of import licence for bullion also aided rally in the gold prices after an easy start,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;These premiums have gone up to 13/13.50 percent from 12/12.50 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prices of a gold biscuit (116.64 gramme) closed 700 rupees higher at 52,700 rupees per piece. They were down by 100 rupees on Tuesday while the market was closed on Wednesday for a Hindu festival.</p>
<p>Silver (.999) closed 60 rupees lower at 6,215 rupees per kg against the previous close of 6,275 rupees on higher arrivals of imported metals while losses in the world market prompted fresh selling.</p>
<p>Silver prices opened 65 rupees lower at 6,210 rupees in early trade but later scattered industrial buying helped prices recover modest ground towards the close. Silver was down by 45 rupees per kg on Tuesday and the market was closed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>($1=35.70 rupees)</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22 265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
