<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="736434" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: PRESS DIGEST - PAKISTAN - JULY 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - PAKISTAN - JULY 17.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following are the leading stories in the Pakistani press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE MUSLIM</p>
<p>- Pakistan plans to conduct fifth population census from October 18 to 31.</p>
<p>- Pakistan and Iran will hold second session of the talks on establishment of a broad-based government in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>THE NATION</p>
<p>- Pakistan allowes import of cotton, cotton yarn, tyres and a score of other items from India in its new trade policy.</p>
<p>DAWN</p>
<p>- Pakistan announces its trade policy for fiscal 1997/98 (July-June) aimed at reducing the trade gap to $2.33 billion from $3.37 billion in 1996/97.</p>
<p>- A special plane brought 194 Pakistani fishermen to Karachi from Bombay after they were released by India in an exchange with 193 Indian fishermen.</p>
<p>- The federal cabinet decided to hold the much delayed population and housing census in October this year under supervision of the armed forces.</p>
<p>- Two people were killed and one was wounded when unidentified gunmen shot them in Lahore.</p>
<p>- Following a mass flushing of illegal residents last year, the United Arab Emirates authorities have deported 119 Pakistanis found in violation of immigration laws during the first six months of 1997.</p>
<p>- A three member Military Appellate Court has started hearing the appeals of four army officers who were dismissed from services and jailed for conspiring to overthrow the government of former prime minister Benazir Bhutto.</p>
<p>- Twenty Pakistani fishermen held in custody by Omani Coast Gaurds for the last two months have been released and will be returning home soon.</p>
<p>- Offices of a private radio and a television channels were raided and sealed by the Federal Investigation Agency.</p>
<p>- The World Bank announced that it had disbursed $2.67 billion to South Asia during fiscal year ending June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>- U.S.-based Dupont and ICI Pakistan would float a private company by the end of this year to jointly manage the $450 million PTA plant under construction in Karachi.</p>
<p>- A team of the Asian Development Bank has begun feasibility study of Pakistan's three stock markets to sanction loans to speed up their modernisation.</p>
<p>BUSINESS RECORDER</p>
<p>- The federal government has been advised by the International Monetary Fund to introduce one-year and three-month treasury bills with fixed coupon rate, in order to rejuvenate the secondary market for government debt paper.</p>
<p>- The government has decided to open gold import, ending monopoly of three private firms.</p>
<p>- A Polish joint venture company will start oil exploration in the southern Punjab area.</p>
<p>-- Islamabad newsroom 9251-274757</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
