<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="736501" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: FOCUS-Sri Lanka shares seen rising another 15 pct.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Sri Lanka shares seen rising another 15 pct.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Relative political stability and excellent corporate results should push up the Sri Lankan stock market by almost another 15 percent this year, a Reuters poll of local stock brokers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Seven leading members of the bourse forecast the benchmark Colombo Stock Exchange All Share Index would average 878.6 points by the end of September, and around 937.1 by the end of the year, up almost 15 percent from its closing position at 817.5 on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had two years of total disaster. The market was in hibernation. But now it appears to be waking up at last,&quot; said Sarinda Unamboowe, director and general manager of John Keells Stockbrokers in Colombo.</p>
<p>The All Share Index has already risen 35 percent this year from 607 points on January 2.</p>
<p>But this rise has been only a partial recovery after a disastrous performance in 1996, when the monsoons failed and drought led to widespread power cuts across industry and a sharp decline in agricultural output.</p>
<p>Investor confidence was also damaged by an intensification of the battle between government forces and Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE) rebels, who are fighting for a homeland in the north and east of the country.</p>
<p>But the rebels have been pushed back gradually over the past year and a half and the national state of emergency was recently lifted across large parts of the country.</p>
<p>Confidence has also been boosted by the convincing win of President Chandrika Kamaratunga's ruling People's Alliance in local elections in March and the opposition's subsequent pledge to work with the government to try to solve the 13-year-old ethnic conflict.</p>
<p>On the corporate front, year-on-year financial results for the second quarter are expected to show handsome 20-30 percent rises for many blue chip stocks.</p>
<p>Add to this a government programme to sell large parts of state industry, effectively an injection of assets into the stock market, and foreign buying interest is booming.</p>
<p>Brokers point out that the All Share Index is still nowhere near its peak of 1,378 points, reached in March 1994, and average price earnings ratios are now between 12 and 15 times, way below their historic high of around 30 times.</p>
<p>Forecasts in the Reuters poll for the position of the index at the end of the year ranged from 850 points to 1,200 points, with five of the seven brokers predicting a range between 900 and 950.</p>
<p>None of the brokers predicted the index would fall from its current position or remain flat for the rest of 1997.</p>
<p>Sanjeeva Gunawardena, senior manager of operations at Ceylinco Stockbrokers, said the recovery was unlikely to be dented, even by a large military attack by the LTTE on Colombo, such as the one which destroyed the Central Bank building in January 1996.</p>
<p>He and many other brokers said any impact might only be temporary unless there was a series of attacks.</p>
<p>&quot;There might be a risk from an incident,&quot; Gunawardena said. &quot;But sentiment was nothing like as positive when the last explosion happened.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
