<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="736508" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India coalition prepares for crisis meeting.</title>
<headline>India coalition prepares for crisis meeting.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's shaky ruling coalition faces a test of its unity on Thursday when its leaders meet to discuss deep divisions over ethics and ideology.</p>
<p>The 13-month-old government is struggling with a crisis triggered by a chain of events linked to a split in Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral's Janata Dal party. The crisis is compounded by a corruption scandal involving the politician who caused the split.</p>
<p>Indian markets are anxiously watching a meeting of the ruling United Front's standing committee. At 0730 GMT the Bombay Stock Exchange's Sensitive Index was down 0.31 percent or 12.82 points at 4170.60 in choppy trade.</p>
<p>&quot;The standing committee's meeting begins at 5.00 p.m. (1130 GMT),&quot; an aide to Information and Broadcasting Minister Jaipal Reddy told Reuters.</p>
<p>Gujral is being accused by critics of lack of control over his squabbling partners. The urbane prime minister heads a two-month-old cabinet that was formed after an upheaval in March nearly toppled the coalition.</p>
<p>Stock markets were shaken earlier this week after a regional group threatened to pull out of the coalition, prompting Thursday's meeting. Gujral and the group have said they are confident of resolving the crisis.</p>
<p>Communist parties in the 15-member coalition and the regional Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam (DMK) party from the southern state of Tamil Nadu are at loggerheads on how to deal with the breakaway Rashtriya Janata Dal (RJD) party.</p>
<p>The Communist Party of India-Marxist (CPI-M) wants Gujral to expel the RJD from the coalition because its leader, Laloo Prasad Yadav, has refused to resign as the chief minister of Bihar state after federal police indicted him in a corruption scandal.</p>
<p>The DMK threatened to pull out from the government early this week saying the communists are overstepping their limits by interfering in the affairs of Gujral's party.</p>
<p>Yadav said he was innocent in the $280 million scandal involving state animal welfare funds. He broke away from Gujral's Janata Dal on July 5 to set up the RJD, citing differences over an election for the party's top post.</p>
<p>&quot;The divisions will persist as long as Mr Yadav remains in office because it is the threat of destabilisation if he is made to go which has made the United Front his prisoner,&quot; the Times of India said in an editoral on Thursday.</p>
<p>The United Front has 178 lawmakers in the federal parliament's 545-member lower house, and gets vital support for its minority rule from the Congress party, which has 140 deputies. Congress itself was thrown out of power in national elections in May 1996.</p>
<p>The disparate coalition is ranged against the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), which controls 193 votes. Opinion polls widely predict the BJP stands a good chance of capturing power if a mid-term election were held now.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
