<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="736755" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GPU Q2 weather impact offset by Midlands.</title>
<headline>GPU Q2 weather impact offset by Midlands.</headline>
<dateline>PARSIPPANY, N.J. 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>GPU Inc Wednesday reported second quarter earnings of $0.58 per share, compared with $0.61 a year earlier, saying the decline was largely offset by increased GPU International Group earnings, resulting primarily from the May 1996 acquisition of Midlands Electricity Plc.</p>
<p>GPU also noted the United Kingdom government has proposed a windfall profits tax on privatized utilities. To recognize this tax, GPU plans to take a charge in the third quarter of 1997 of about $110 million, or $0.91 per share, resulting from its 50 percent ownership interest in Midlands.  </p>
<p>The decrease in second quarter earnings was due mainly to lower weather-related sales resulting from cooler spring temperatures this year compared to last, GPU said.</p>
<p>The First Call consensus estimate for the latest quarter was $0.65 per share.</p>
<p>The company said kilowatt hour sales to domestic utility customers increased 3.4 percent for the quarter to 10.1 billion due to increased industrial customer usage and an increase in the number of commercial and residential customers. Offsetting these increases were lower residential customer sales.  </p>
<p>Operating revenues from domestic utility operations increased 1.6 percent to $927.3 million for the second quarter of 1997 versus the comparable 1996 period.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased with the continued strong financial contribution of our GPU International Group, chief executive Fred Hafer said.</p>
<p>&quot;As we look ahead to a greater degree of competition in our industry, we do so with a strong balance sheet, aided substantially by our international investments, which have performed better than we expected.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to explore opportunities for additional investments internationally that help us meet our strategic goals, not the least of which is to be a leader in an increasingly competitive electric utility industry,&quot; Hafer said.</p>
<p>GPU International Group earnings were $12.1 million for the latest quarter, compared with $1.6 million for the second quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>The group has 50 percent ownership interests in distribution and supply businesses located in England and Australia. It also has ownership interests in generation facilities located in the United States and foreign countries.</p>
<p>((--Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARSIPPANY, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
