<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737130" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton threatens action on Boeing merger.</title>
<headline>Clinton threatens action on Boeing merger.</headline>
<byline>David Lawsky</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton threatened on Thursday to go to the World Trade Organisaton or impose sanctions on Europe if it blocks the Boeing-McDonnell Douglas merger, but said a trade war could &quot;probably&quot; be avoided.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a system for managing this through the World Trade Organisation and we have some options ourselves when actions are taken by Europe in this regard,&quot; he told reporters in the White House Rose Garden.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, Clinton said he believed a trade war can be avoided.</p>
<p>&quot;There's an orderly process for our handling this and I think we'd better let the orderly process play itself out before we talk ourselves into a trade war,&quot; Clinton said. &quot;I think we're a long way from that and I think we'll probably avoid it.&quot;</p>
<p>The European Commission votes next Wednesday on the proposed $14 billion merger of Boeing and McDonnell Douglas. Although the EU has strongly suggested it will vote to block the merger, it has left the door open to last-minute negotiations with Boeing.</p>
<p>At the heart of the issue are very different views of the merger in Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>Europeans say the merger would create an unfair competitor for their consortium, Airbus Industrie, narrowing the number of large commercial airplane companies in the world from three to two.</p>
<p>They characterise the issue as one of antitrust or, as it is called in Europe, competition.</p>
<p>Members of Congress note that the Federal Trade Commission in the United States, which handles antitrust issues, approved the merger. They say this is a trade issue, all about protecting Airbus.</p>
<p>Clinton backed the American congressional view, noting it &quot;would be unfortunate if we had a trade stand-off&quot; with the Europeans.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm concerned about what appear to be the reasons for the objection to the Boeing-McDonnell Douglas merger by the European Union,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Europeans have more people living in their continent than we do in the United States and I don't believe Airbus has an effective competitor in Europe,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A White House official said later that Clinton &quot;made it clear that American businesses need to be treated fairly.&quot;</p>
<p>The increasing presure from the United States prompted an expression of concern from French President Jacques Chirac, who said he feared U.S. pressure on individual members of the EU might have an effect.</p>
<p>&quot;We back the Commission without reservation,&quot; he told a news conference in Brussels. &quot;I don't fear for the Commission. The problem is more about the position of the (EU) states which clearly risk being submitted to a strong psychological predssure.&quot;</p>
<p>EU Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert said again Thursday that the EU had handled the case under merger regulations and not for political reasons.</p>
<p>A committee of European antitrust experts from the 15 European Union states advised the Commission on Wednesday to block the merger, agreeing with the Commission's competition services that Boeing had not fully met its concerns that the deal would threaten competition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
