<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737329" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain's BCH shares jump on talk of split.</title>
<headline>Spain's BCH shares jump on talk of split.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Spanish bank Banco Central Hispano bucked the market downtrend and rose amid talk it would soon approve a share split, dealers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a rumour going around that the next directors' meeting will approve a stock split, and that's what's sending the shares higher,&quot; a trader at a foreign bank said.</p>
<p>BCH said in March it was considering a split, but a spokeswoman told Reuters Thursday that no decision had yet been taken. The next board meeting is set for next week.</p>
<p>&quot;In March we said we would see how the share developed and think about it for next year,&quot; she said. &quot;It can't be ruled out but it's still a little bit early.&quot;</p>
<p>She acknowledged, however, that the share had soared from some 3,800 to more than 6000 pesetas since the announcement BCH was considering a share split -- a move which has gained popularity in the Spanish market this year.</p>
<p>But a dealer at foreign brokerage who requested anonymity said this did not justify a gain in the shares.</p>
<p>&quot;A split doesn't affect the valuation in the slightest, and at above 6,000 pesetas BCH is already overpriced. If they were thinking of a buyback then that would be something,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At 1330 GMT, shares in the group rose 100 pesetas, or 1.64 percent, to 6,200, while the IBEX-35 index of shares fell 65.57 points, or 0.92 percent, to 7071.34.</p>
<p>--Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
