<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737384" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Thursday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Thursday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Thursday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Willy Helin read a statement from Commissioner Karel Van Miert in which he said the proposals made by Boeing on its potential merger with McDonnell Douglas were not enough to ease the Commission's antitrust concerns.</p>
<p>Helin also said Van Miert would not react to the verbal controversy the issue had created in political and business circles in the U.S. (see BC-MERGER-BOEING-VANMIERT).</p>
<p>Spokeswoman Lousewies van der Laan briefed on tommorrow's visit by Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin to the Commission. She said the main points on the agenda were EU enlargement, EMU, trade and investment, borders and customs cooperation, science and technology and TACIS 1998 priorities.</p>
<p>Helin read a statement by Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan who welcomed U.S. President Bill Clinton's decision to continue to suspend the right of U.S. citizens to file suit under the Helms Burton Act.</p>
<p>Spokesman Gerry Kiely said Commissioner Franz Fischler regretted the rejection by the Standing Veterinary Committee of the Commission's proposal to exclude specific risk material from the food chain. He said it was unacceptable that some member states refused to protect human and animal health, given concerns about BSE.</p>
<p>In answer to a question, Helion once again confirmed that the Commission would take its decision on the proposed Boeing/McDonell Douglas merger on July 23.</p>
<p>Asked whether a solution was still obtainable, Van Miert's spokesman said &quot;it is going to be tough for Boeing to come up with something in due time unless there is a miracle&quot;.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/97/654: Biotechnology: Commissioner Monti welcomes European Parliament Opinion.</p>
<p>- IP/97/663: The Commission approves eight research projects on transmissible spongiform encephalopathies.</p>
<p>- IP/97/664: Monitoring the application of Community law: 1996 report.</p>
<p>- Eurostat news release No 51/97: Focus on EU youth.</p>
<p>- Oil bulletin No 876.</p>
<p>- Taxes and duties at June 1997 in Ecus and national currencies.</p>
<p>- Memo/97/70: EU/Russia relations.</p>
<p>- ME97/17.7: Midday Express.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
