<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737480" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: GREEK FOOD INDUSTRY PLEDGES CONTINUED PRICE FREEZE.</title>
<headline>GREEK FOOD INDUSTRY PLEDGES CONTINUED PRICE FREEZE.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Representatives of Greece's food producers and supermarkets reaffirmed on Thursday a commitment to keep a lid on prices until the end of the year, and said they would begin talks aimed at freezing prices for the following two years.</p>
<p>After talks with Deputy Development Minister Mihalis Chrysohoidis, both sides agreed to set up a committee to thrash out problems that have arisen over the past few days, according to a press release from the development ministry.</p>
<p>Producers claimed on Tuesday that leading supermarket retailers were taking advantage of their monopoly to increase their profits at the expense of producers.</p>
<p>The ministry said a committee headed by Chrysohoidis would draft a report on proposed reforms to restore relations between the two and on changing legislation on unfair competition.</p>
<p>The committee has until the end of August to complete its report, after which the ministry will begin talks on an agreement aimed at freezing prices for the next two years.</p>
<p>In separate meetings with the two sides earlier on Thursday, Chrysohoidis called for self-restraint from both sides, stressing that a climate of trust and transparency was to the benefit of both and a prerequisite for the government's anti-inflationary efforts.</p>
<p>On Wednesday National Economy Minister Yannos Papandoniou said a central goal of economic policy was to cut inflation below 3.0 percent in 1998.</p>
<p>Year-on-year retail price inflation was 5.5 percent in June compared with 5.4 percent in May. --Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
