<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737589" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian dollar enjoys rare rally, while it can.</title>
<headline>Australian dollar enjoys rare rally, while it can.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A downtrodden Australian dollar enjoyed its first real bounce in more than a week Thursday, but shied away from tackling serious chart resistance.</p>
<p>Analysts saw tentative signs a bottom may have formed at the week's US$0.7310 low, but emphasised that US$0.7380 needed to be cleared to have any confidence. A break higher from here could yield a rise to US$0.7430 given how short the market was.</p>
<p>However, traders detected a distinct reluctance among customers to chase it higher since they suspected a firmer dollar would merely give the Reserve Bank more elbow room to cut domestic interest rates.  </p>
<p>By 4.45 pm (0645 GMT) the dollar was struggling to get some momentum going at US$0.7365/70 having crept ahead from an early US$0.7345/50 and Wednesday's late US$0.7325/30.</p>
<p>This was the first session in five days the currency had not set a fresh 18-month low, but most dealers continued to favour a policy of selling into rallies while the risk of a domestic rate cut loomed so large.</p>
<p>Many felt the bank could move as soon as next Friday after second quarter consumer price and wages data on July 23 and 24 respectively, which were widely expected to confirm a very benign outlook for Australian inflation.  </p>
<p>Annual underlying inflation is likely to fall below the RBA's 2-3 percent target band while the CPI for the quarter may actually be negative, so implying deflation.</p>
<p>There has been some speculation, largely in the equity and bond markets, the weakness of the dollar could actually stay the RBA's hand. Its five percent fall since May has been a de facto easing in policy and another cut risked sending it yet lower and fuelling imported inflation, the argument went.</p>
<p>David Bassanese, an economist at Bankers Trust, said monetary conditions had clearly eased since May when assessing real interest rates and changes in the real exchange rate.  </p>
<p>However, there had been little real easing in monetary conditions over 1996/97 when compared with the previous year, largely due to the past appreciation of the currency.</p>
<p>Indeed, given the lagged effect of exchange rate moves and uncertainty over whether the recent weakness will be sustained, he felt it likely the RBA attached a relatively low weight to current currency levels when determining policy.</p>
<p>&quot;For this reason, our view remains that the RBA is still more likely than not to ease policy despite the lower level of the currency,&quot; said Bassanese.  </p>
<p>He also argued the trade weighted index would have to fall below 55.0 to seriously threaten inflation and so put a cut on hold. The TWI rose to 57.0 today from 56.6 late Wednesday.</p>
<p>A study on the same subject from Commonwealth Bank estimated dollar weakness had a much greater impact -- it assumed a three percent depreciation had the same impact as a one percent cut in the real 90-day bank bill rate while BT assumed a 5-1 ratio.</p>
<p>&quot;On our measure, monetary conditions are now at their most accomodating since early 1995,&quot; said Bruce Freeland, chief economist at CBA. &quot;The majority of this easing has occurred via the exchange rate.&quot;  </p>
<p>Nevertheless, this loosening in conditions did not rule out another rate cut.</p>
<p>&quot;Structural change and excess capacity mean that the economy can grow more quickly, for a time at least, without leading to inflationary pressures,&quot; said Freeland.</p>
<p>Thus he still put a 75 percent probability on another official rate cut over the next few weeks.</p>
<p>He did offer some comfort for A$ bulls, however.</p>
<p>&quot;On the basis of the quite accomodating stance of monetary conditions and our expectation of a snap back in activity, we would see this as the last cut in the cycle,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The dollar made progress on the yen, reaching 85.56/66 yen from 84.90/00 late Wednesday, mirroring the relief of US$/yen when Japan's June trade surplus turned out smaller than feared.</p>
<p>The surplus rose almost 28 percent from a year earlier to 934.21 billion yen, but this was a lot less than the 1.23 trillion markets had forecasted. Analysts noted export growth had slowed to 12.5 percent from 20.5 percent in May, while imports growth picked up to 8.7 percent from 6.0 percent.</p>
<p>The market assumed this would soothe Japan/U.S. trade tensions and took the U.S. dollar to 116.20/30 yen from 115.50/55. -- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
