<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737614" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia's SFE to launch electricity contract.</title>
<headline>Australia's SFE to launch electricity contract.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Sydney Futures Exchange (SFE) said on Thursday it would launch two electricity futures contracts on September 29 based on electricity pool prices in the states of New South Wales and Victoria.</p>
<p>Deregulation and privatisation in the Australian electricity industry has raised risk management as a key issue for market players, Les Hosking, SFE chief executive, said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Sustainable profitability for organisations operating in the electricity industry will depend heavily on risk management using tools such as futures contracts,&quot; Hosking said.  </p>
<p>A futures market in electricity would also help participants by providing readily available public quotations for current and forward prices of electricity, Hosking added.</p>
<p>&quot;Such transparency of price information will greatly assist the cornerstone objective of a national electricity market in creating a competitive wholesale market for electricity.&quot;</p>
<p>The settlement price for the contracts will be calculated by taking spot market prices every half-hour and averaging them over a one-month period.  </p>
<p>Spot market prices are determined in New South Wales by the Transgrid energy providing group and in Victoria by the Victorian Power Exchange.</p>
<p>Each contract will equal 500 megawatt-hours of electricity and will be quoted for each month up to 12 months ahead.</p>
<p>Introduction of the contracts follows deregulation of the Australian electricity industry in New South Wales and Victoria allowing inter-state power flows.</p>
<p>The Victorian electricity market has been fully deregulated with generators and distributors now privatised.  </p>
<p>In New South Wales deregulation has allowed participants to purchase electricity in the spot markets, although generation and distribution assets are still owned and operated by state government.</p>
<p>The new contracts will trade each business day on the SYCOM screen-dealing system, the SFE said.</p>
<p>Currently retailers and generators agree on deals in advance of contract delivery because of significant hour-to-hour volatility in spot electricity prices.</p>
<p>The price agreement may then be traded or form the basis of swaps or options arranged by intermediaries.  </p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
