<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737619" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAPUA NEW GUINEA: PNG's Somare moves closer to new government.</title>
<headline>PNG's Somare moves closer to new government.</headline>
<byline>Abby Yadi</byline>
<dateline>PORT MORESBY 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Papua New Guinea's first prime minister after independence, Sir Michael Somare, looks increasingly likely to return to power after winning the support of an influential former premier.</p>
<p>Sir Rabbie Namaliu, a founding member of the Pangu party which ruled in partnership with ousted prime minister Sir Julius Chan's People's Progressive Party, turned against the coalition late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not believe the best interests of our nation, our people are served by a continuation of the current coalition,&quot; Namaliu said.</p>
<p>Parliament will sit next Tuesday to elect a new prime minister to replace Chan, who lost his seat in a voter backlash against his failed attempt to use African mercenaries against secessionists on Bougainville island.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been my fervent hope that now that the elections are behind us, we could achieve a re-unification with our founding leader, Sir Michael Somare, and other members who left the party during the last parliament,&quot; Namaliu said.</p>
<p>&quot;Unquestionably, the people of PNG voted for change. They did not vote for a continuation of what we have experienced and endured over the last three years,&quot; Namaliu said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our people deserve good government. They deserve a government that will be honest, open, responsible and accountable in everything it does on their behalf.&quot;</p>
<p>Political analysts said on Thursday that Somare, who was the South Pacific nation's first leader after it won independence from Australia in 1975, now apeared to have the numbers to form a new coalition government.</p>
<p>The National newspaper on Thursday reported that Somare's cross-party National Alliance had a total of 59 seats pledged, four more than the 55 required to form government.</p>
<p>The volatile nature of Papua New Guinea politics means the post of prime minister will, however, still be contested.</p>
<p>Despite Chan losing his seat, his People's Progressive Party and the Pangu party both polled well, winning 16 and 15 seats respectively in the 109-seat parliament.</p>
<p>Despite Namaliu's defection, senior Pangu officials remained confident they could form a government headed by former deputy prime minister Chris Haiveta.</p>
<p>&quot;We are soldily stable and remain loyal to our effort and commitment to make our current leader, Chris Haiveta, prime minister,&quot; Pangu national president Pate Wamp said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT MORESBY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAPUA NEW GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
