<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737788" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Thailand says not seeking aid from IMF or Japan.</title>
<headline>Thailand says not seeking aid from IMF or Japan.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai Finance Minister Thanong Bidaya said on Thursday the country is not seeking financial support from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and he had not come to Japan on his present visit to seek aid.</p>
<p>&quot;We just feel it's not necessary at all, that's why,&quot; Thanong told reporters when asked why Thailand had not planned to ask the IMF for financial assistance to rescue it from its recent economic troubles.</p>
<p>But Thanong separately said in a speech delivered to the Japan Federation of Bankers' Associations that Thailand will ask Japan to join in any international support scheme if it calls for one.</p>
<p>&quot;We ask that Japanese banks will continue to sustain and increase the credit lines extended to Thai borrowers, both financial and corporate,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;We ask you to join when the kingdom calls for public support through international syndications, both public and private.&quot;  </p>
<p>Asked whether he had sought financing at the meeting with Japanese bankers, he told reporters: &quot;No, not at all. We haven't come here for the financing needs.&quot;</p>
<p>Thanong told reporters: &quot;I think that the turning point has come. We still feel that we can recover everything within a year.&quot;</p>
<p>On the baht, he said in his speech : &quot;In short, the value of the baht, like water, will find its own level, consistent with the Thai financial environment.&quot;  </p>
<p>Thanong told reporters that he was &quot;happy&quot; that the baht was now more stable, but he said: &quot;It's too early to say. It's only one week.&quot;</p>
<p>He said in the speech that the Thai economy remained fundamentally sound and the country continued to aim to balance its budget for both 1997 and 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the economic slowdown and less than robust outlook for growth, Thailand still adheres to a conservative fiscal and monetary stance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;While revenues have fallen, the government has severely curtailed the public budgets and still aims for a balanced budget for both 1997 and 1998,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
