<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737878" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: MOF calls on banks to cut ties with racketeers.</title>
<headline>MOF calls on banks to cut ties with racketeers.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka on Thursday called on regional bankers to take measures to break off links with corporate racketeers.</p>
<p>&quot;We request that the banking sector quickly take concrete measures to strengthen their stance towards obeying the law and take steps to eliminate dealings with corporate racketeers,&quot; Mitsuzuka told a conference of regional bankers.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Finance (MOF) is currently considering strengthening penalties under the banking law against those who withhold information from inspectors and make false reports.</p>
<p>It also plans to bolster inspection and supervision to promote transparent and fair markets, through such measures as strengthening the Securities and Exchange Surveillance Commission (SESC) and imposing stricter penalties on insider trading.  </p>
<p>Public trust in financial institutions has seriously deteriorated since revelations of the involvement of two top financial institutions in a widening scandal.</p>
<p>Many former senior officials of Nomura Securities Co Ltd and Dai-Ichi Kangyo Bank Ltd have been arrested for allegedly making payoffs and also making loans without appropriate collateral to a racketeer.</p>
<p>Mitsuzuka said these illegal acts may even damage the credibility, both at home and abroad, of the fairness of Japan's financial system.</p>
<p>&quot;These things should never happen and the event is grave beyond words,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He urged financial firms to regain trust of the public as soon as possible by applying strict moral codes, reviewing their business stances and securing appropriate business management practices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
