<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737968" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Cruise liner Hanseatic free of sandbank.</title>
<headline>Cruise liner Hanseatic free of sandbank.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Elderly passengers stranded for four days aboard a grounded cruise liner in the Arctic were temporarily evacuated to a rescue ship on Thursday, an official said.</p>
<p>The 145 people, mostly German and with an average age of 70, were taken off shortly before their liner, The Hanseatic, was refloated.</p>
<p>They were later allowed back on board.</p>
<p>The German-owned cruiser had been stuck on a sandbank off the Norwegian Arctic island of Spitzbergen since Sunday. Efforts to pull her free had been hampered by drifting ice.</p>
<p>Elisabeth Aarsaether, spokeswoman for the governor's office at Longyear on Spitzbergen, said the 9,000 deadweight-ton liner, was freed at 3.45 a.m. (0145 gmt) by the coastguard ship Tromsoe.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a deadline until 4 a.m. when the high water would be gone,&quot; she told Norwegian radio.</p>
<p>Officials said all 145 passengers were evacuated to the Tromsoe a few hours before the liner, with a crew of 115, was pulled free.</p>
<p>They said the passengers were let on board the Hanseatic again after an inspection showed the navigational instruments were in order and that the hull was not leaking.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no problems with the ship or the passengers,&quot; a spokesman for the governor's office said. &quot;Divers are checking the hull a bit closer now. The Hanseatic may sail for Longyear in the afternoon.&quot;</p>
<p>The passengers were expected to arrive late on Thursday or early Friday in Longyear, where they would be put on a charter flight to Hamburg.</p>
<p>Coastguards unloaded the ship's 480 tonnes of heavy fuel oil before dragging her free.</p>
<p>The ship's owner, Hamburg-based Hapag-Lloyd AG, had originally planned to start evacuating passengers at 8 a.m. (0600 GMT), but the wind changed late on Wednesday and pushed away the icefloes massed around the liner.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
