<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737923" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan to watch if surplus keeps rising--MOF.</title>
<headline>Japan to watch if surplus keeps rising--MOF.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan will keep careful watch to see whether its trade surplus will continue to grow drastically, a Ministry of Finance (MOF) official told reporters on Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;The reason for the drastic increase in the trade surplus from a year ago in the April-June period is from the special factor of the consumption tax increase. We will continue to watch whether the trade surplus will keep on growing drastically,&quot; the official told a news conference.  </p>
<p>Japan's trade surplus in the April-June quarter grew 94.3 percent from a year ago to 2.48 trillion yen, figures released by MOF earlier on Thursday showed.</p>
<p>In June, exports grew by a double-digit figure, year-on-year, for a sixth consecutive month due to strong shipments of products such as cars and office equipment, the official said.  </p>
<p>For imports, the rise in the consumption tax from April 1 affected purchases of cars and clothing from abroad, and oil prices had declined compared with the January-March period, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw double-digit growth in imports for the January-March period but since April we have only seen single-digit growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked about the smaller growth in the overall trade surplus for June compared with April and May, the official said the figures for April and May had jumped in reaction to comparatively low figures in those months last year. Last year's June figure had not been as low as those for the two preceding months.  </p>
<p>Asked how long the impact of the consumption tax rise would linger, the official said he could not make any predictions. The tax was raised to five percent from three percent on April 1.</p>
<p>The average currency rate used for the first half of calendar 1997 was 120.41 yen to the dollar, compared with 106.16 yen for the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>The data showed that Japan's contentious trade surplus rose for the third successive month in June, jumping 27.7 percent from a year earlier to 934.21 billion yen.</p>
<p>The customs-cleared trade surplus with the United States, often a source of friction, rose 26.8 percent in June from a year earlier to 373.14 billion yen. The figures were not adjusted for seasonal factors.</p>
<p>Japan's customs-cleared trade surplus in the first half of calendar 1997 rose 28.4 percent from a year earlier to 3.98 trillion yen, the ministry said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
