<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="737951" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi says will never sever ties with Iran.</title>
<headline>Saudi says will never sever ties with Iran.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabia's Defence Minister Prince Sultan said his country would never cut off ties with Iran, the daily al-Hayat newspaper said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Ties between Saudi Arabia and Iran will never be severed,&quot; he said, as quoted by the London-based, Saudi-owned paper.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia and Iran, two of the world's biggest oil producers, have had strained ties since Iran's 1979 Islamic revolution. Riyadh and Tehran severed diplomatic relations from 1988-1991.</p>
<p>Differences focus on the presence of Western forces in the Gulf, Tehran's arms programme, the annual Moslem pilgrimage to the Saudi city of Mecca and charges that Iran meddles in its neighbour's affairs.</p>
<p>Shi'ite Moslem Iran denies the charges and its leaders have repeatedly said they want to rebuild trust with their mostly Sunni Moslem neighbours.</p>
<p>Ties were cut between the two states after 402 people, mostly Iranians, died in riots during the 1987 Mecca pilgrimage.</p>
<p>Relations were restored after the 1991 Gulf War, in which Iran remained neutral over Iraq's 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>A rare visit to Tehran by an envoy of Saudi Arabia's King Fahd earlier this month was seen as a new sign of thaw in relations between the two regional powerhouses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
