<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738077" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP Budgets Committee agenda - July 22-23.</title>
<headline>EP Budgets Committee agenda - July 22-23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Adoption of draft opinion 11.3 Communication on accidents and wounds (T04308) COD97132 COM(97)0178 C4-0229/97 + BUDG Avis A HAUG Jutta. (PSE) (PE222.901 ) F ENVI Fond R (PPE) - Adoption of draft opinion 12. South Africa - concluding the Agreement for scientific and technological cooperation (T04572) CNS97112 COM(97)0119 C4-0264/97 + BUDG Avis L (PE222.909 ) F ENER Fond R SCAPAGNINI Umberto. ( ) (PE222.954 ) - Adoption of draft opinion 13. Amendment of the Staff Regulations of officials of the European Communities (T05486) CNS97123 COM(97)0163 C4-0262/97 + BUDG Avis L (PE222.919 ) F JURI Fond - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 14. The agri-monetary system for the Single Market - 1 July 1995 - 30 June 1996 (T05372) COS0517 COM(96)0636 C4-0026/97 + BUDG Avis L (PE222.917 ) F AGRI Fond R HALLAM David J. (PSE) (PE221.794 ) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 15. The control of new synthetic drugs (designer drugs) (T05536) COS0566 COM(97)0249 C4-0244/97 + BUDG Avis L. (PE222.914 ) F LIBE Fond R PIRKER Hubert. (PPE) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 16. Interim Agreement with Uzbekistan (T05413) CNS97902 10521/96 C4-0082/97 + BUDG Avis L (PE222.916 ) F RELA Fond R WIERSMA Jan M. (PSE) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 17. Air pollution by emissions from motor vehicles (amendment of Directive 70/156 and 70/220/EEC) (T05439) COD96164B COM(97)0061 C4-0088/97 + BUDG Avis L F ENVI Fond R LANGE Bernd. (PSE) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 18. Effects of certain plans and programmes on the environment (T05466) **II SYN96304 COM(96)0511 C4-0191/97 + BUDG Avis L F ENVI Fond R GAHRTON Per. (V ) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 19. Date of next meeting (PE/III/OJ/97-14 ) A D D E N D U M ===] 1997 budget 8.1 Possible transfers - Transfer of appropriations 14/97: KEDO - Transfer of appropriations 24/97: ECIR - Transfer of appropriations 25/97: Telecom - Transfer of appropriations 26/97: IDA - Transfer of appropriations 27/97: Data-processing cooperation - Transfer of appropriations 29/97: Staff 8.2 Transfers concerning information policy - Transfer of appropriations 28/97: Euronews - Transfer of appropriations 31/97: Audiovisual equipment ===] Appointment of draftsmen 1. Common organization of the market in wine (T05554) CNS97161 COM(97)0267 C4-0309/97 + BUDG Avis F AGRI Fond 2. Support system for producers of certain arable crops (derogation from Regulation 1765/92/EEC) (T05567) CNS97196 COM(97)0360 C4-0343/97 + BUDG Avis F AGRI Fond 3. Commission report on monitoring the common fisheries policy in 1995 (T05564) COS0578 COM(97)0226 C4-0334/97 + BUDG Avis F PECH Fond 4. Developments in relations with Turkey since the entry into force of the Customs Union (T05311) COS0487 COM(96)0491 C4-0605/96 + BUDG Avis F POLI Fond R McMILLAN-SCOTT Edwar (PPE) (PE222.635/DT ) - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT No text received.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
