<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738040" id="root" date="1997-07-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest-July 17.</title>
<headline>Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest-July 17.</headline>
<text>
<p>--------------GAM--------------------</p>
<p>REUTERS GERMAN ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST</p>
<p>-----------July 17, 1997-----------------</p>
<p>News from Reuters and the German press on Advertising, Marketing, Media, the Internet, Brand-name Products and Consumer Trends</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Germany's top television channel RTL loses ground in June to the ProSieben network, media marketing company IP Deutschland says. RTL sees a drop in ratings to a 15.9 percent viewer share, down from 17 percent in May. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BERLIN - Elf Oil's German unit awards its advertising account to the TBWA group, says TBWA Germany's chief executive and chairman, Helmut Sendlmeier. Elf selects TBWA Hamburg and TBWA Berlin from the six agencies who presented a pitch. The new campaign aims to strengthen Elf's position in eastern Germany.</p>
<p>(Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BREMEN - Kraft Jacobs Suchard invites several agencies to pitch for its $170 million worth of media planning business in Germany. Insiders say KJS may consolidate its massive media planning business with a single agency. (Advertising Age)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>HAMBURG - The agreement with the Kirch group on digital television cost media company CLT-Ufa 850 million marks ($473.1 million), publication Manager Magazin says. The costs to the Luxembourg-based company comprised the share purchases of Premiere (12.5 percent), Beta Research (33 percent) and DSF (50 percent), in addition to start-up costs expected with the launch of digital TV. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - Authorities have blacklisted a recording of neo-Nazi songs urging Germans to kill foreigners, a spokeswoman for the Family Ministry says. She says Family Minister Claudia Nolte put the CD entitled &quot;12 German Sing-Along Songs&quot; on an index of banned publications considered dangerous to young people.</p>
<p>(Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - German television news coverage of Chancellor Helmut Kohl has grown increasingly critical in recent months, according to a study of leading German networks. The Medien Tenor newsletter says nearly 40 percent of the comments made about Kohl's economic and financial policies in television network news reports in the first half of 1997 were negative. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Karstadt AG, the German retailer whose shares have been on a rollercoaster ride, is back on the uptrend amid views by analysts that a pilot project to revamp stores is taking hold. Karstadt surged six percent, rising 37.50 marks to 663 and far outpacing a 1.9 percent gain during bourse trading in Germany's 30-share DAX index. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt says concessions offered by Boeing Co to Europe over its merger with McDonnell-Douglas did not go far enough to satisfy Bonn's concerns. &quot;Boeing has offered things which are not enough,&quot; Rexrodt says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>NECKARSULM - Auto parts maker Kolbenschmidt AG says it is ending its partnership in France with piston and engine block maker Mahle GmbH of Stuttgart. Mahle would take over Kolbenschmidt's 50 percent share of Pistons de Colmar S.a.r.l., which had 1996/97 sales of 460 million francs ($75.8 million) and employed 600 workers. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MUNICH - Troubled Apple Computer Inc. says its units in certain European countries saw third quarter sales in units and revenue rise slightly compared to the second quarter of fiscal year 1997. Sales in Germany and France increased sequentially -- but fell compared to the third quarter of fiscal 1996, Apple spokeswoman Therese Wermelskirchen says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>AACHEN - Aachener und Muenchener Beteiligungs-AG says it is looking toward a steady future amid lower costs, despite being knocked from the No. 2 spot in German insurance by the newly formed Ergo group. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - Intel Corp says it expects European growth to continue to lag in the second half after trailing behind the chip maker's worldwide sales increases in the first half of 1997. &quot;I think Europe, at least in the third and fourth quarters, will not be gangbusters,&quot; says Hans Geyer, Intel vice president for Europe.</p>
<p>(Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BREMEN - Plans by German chocolate manufacturers to raise ex-plant prices of their products in the autumn may be unrealistic in a competitive environment, Kraft Jacobs Suchard says. &quot;I believe the price rises may be delayed, perhaps until early next year, because none of the leading firms will step forward to be first, but that's my personal opinion,&quot; spokesman Rolf Sauerbier says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>PEOPLE NEWS:</p>
<p>MUNICH - Siemens AG says the head of its public communications unit, Peter Pribilla, will become a member of the group management board. Pribilla, 55, is to take over responsibility for components and automotive technology on October 1, replacing Walter Kunerth, 56, who is due to leave the company at that time. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>DUESSELDORF - Deutsche Telekom board member Erik Jan Nederkoorn, who has been responsible for international business since April 1996, is leaving his board post, the newspaper Wirthschaftswoche says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Juergen Schlebrowski, general manager for Central Europe at Nike in Moerfelden, has left his post. (Horizont)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Michael Cremer-Panitz has been promoted at Haribo to advertising department director. His predecessor, Horst-Volker Hulbe, will focus on media within the ad division. (Horizont)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>WALLDORF - Michael Rebstock is the new press spokesman at Viag Interkom. He was previously in the communications department at the Hypo Bank. (Kress)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>Deborah Cole, Berlin Newsroom, 49-30-203-98114</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>For further information and news, see Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. And visit us on the Internet:</p>
<p>http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>($ = 6.065 French Francs)</p>
<p>($ = 1.796 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
