<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73817" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold, silver firmer, watching U.S. rates.</title>
<headline>London gold, silver firmer, watching U.S. rates.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The precious metals were mostly firmer on Tuesday as the market focused on expectations of a U.S. interest rate rise later in the day, dealers said. The exception was palladium, which edged lower and fixed at at a fresh three-year low of $116.50 an ounce, down $0.25 from the previous fixing.</p>
<p>Gold bullion, however, fixed at $381.60 an ounce, up $0.60 from Monday's afternoon fixing. Dealers said it had found a comfortable groove in the centre of the $380-$385 range.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold has found support at $381-$382. But I don't think it's out of the mire yet,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The market was looking for direction from the U.S. Federal Open Market Committee meeting, which dealers expected to raise short-term interest rates by one quarter percentage point.</p>
<p>But opinions were mixed as to whether or not an interest rate rise, which would increase the holding costs of gold, would have much of an effect on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The expectations are for a modest rise. I think it's been built into the prices so we're not exactly waiting with bated breath,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Stock and currency markets were holding their breath until after the FOMC's decision, which would not be known until after European trading was over.</p>
<p>Precious metals prices headed south late last week when U.S. investment funds launched a speculative play. Silver was the worst hit, plummeting below the key $5.00 an ounce level.</p>
<p>Dealers and analysts said prices were likely to move sideways for at time, or even edge higher, before shifting lower again if the funds had another go at the downside.</p>
<p>Silver, like gold, regained some lost ground. It was four cents higher than Monday's close, at $4.93 an ounce. &quot;Silver seems to have found a little favour at these lower levels, but it may not be ready to bounce to $5.00 yet,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Platinum bounced up $1.50 to $388.00 an ounce, after fixing at a fresh 2-1/2 year low on Monday.</p>
<p>But palladium remained vulnerable since sliding below its $120 an ounce support level last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
