<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73833" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Deflation fears recede as prices rise in Vietnam.</title>
<headline>Deflation fears recede as prices rise in Vietnam.</headline>
<byline>John Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fears that Vietnam's economy could be slipping into a deflationary spiral receded on Tuesday after the government released figures showing that consumer prices had risen for the first time since April.</p>
<p>The General Statistics Department said prices rose 0.8 percent this month from August, breaking a four-month run of declines.</p>
<p>However, the year-on-year rate of inflation fell for the sixth month in a row to 2.9 percent. This is its lowest level for about three years and compares with a rate of 17.1 percent just 12 months ago.</p>
<p>Vietnam's economic statistics, which lack the scientific rigour of those in more developed countries, are routinely issued ahead of the period which they measure.</p>
<p>The government, fearing that the country's fast-growing economy could be coming off the boil, has expressed disquiet in recent weeks over the decline in consumer prices.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider that if the inflation drops too drastically then it could affect the economy in terms of business operations and production,&quot; Deputy Prime Minister in charge of economic affairs Tran Duc Luong said earlier this month.</p>
<p>He said measures may be taken before the end of the year to prevent the inflation rate from going below zero.</p>
<p>The governor of the central bank said in an interview at the weekend that interest rates, which have already tumbled this year, would be eased further and the local currency adjusted to bolster the economy and narrow a yawning trade gap.</p>
<p>Foreign bankers said governor Cao Si Kiem's oblique reference to the need for &quot;raising&quot; exchange rates was an indication that a managed depreciation of the currency was on the cards.</p>
<p>The official rate of the local currency, the dong, against the dollar is around 11,022. It has been around 11,000 per dollar for more than two years.</p>
<p>Peter McLean, head of treasury at Standard Chartered Bank in Hanoi, said the monetary easing proposed by Kiem would inject dong into the market place and should ensure that inflation turns higher towards the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have seen the bottom in the downturn in inflation,&quot; McLean said. &quot;I think the inflation rate will move higher over the next few months.&quot;</p>
<p>Bankers say the decline in consumer prices has been partially fuelled by a slowdown in foreign direct investment, a development the communist government has been reluctant to admit.</p>
<p>However, McLean said foreign investment was likely to pick up again in the last quarter of the year because some investors had been holding back ahead of a ministerial reshuffle expected next month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
