<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73831" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW-Lotus sees wider groupware lead.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Lotus sees wider groupware lead.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>IBM's Lotus Development Corp should extend its lead in the messaging and groupware market with the launch of Domino, the latest version of Notes software, chief operating officer Jeff Papows said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that Domino will allow us to continue to extend our lead in client-server-based messaging,&quot; Papows told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Notes is widely considered the leader in a fast-growing category of software known as groupware, which allows users to share programmes and send electronic messages over a computer network. Domino is expected to be shipped in November.</p>
<p>&quot;Notes volume has been increasing dramatically this year. In the first two quarters this year, Notes seats (installations) grew 260 percent worldwide,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In Asia, Notes has grown eight-fold in the first half compared to the same period last year.</p>
<p>Notes was now on track to reach 20 million installations by the end of 1997 as projected, Papows said.</p>
<p>&quot;We were at 6.5 million seats the earlier part of this year. With that kind of growth volume, that puts us on a trajectory which suggest that we'll make 20 million seats by the end of next year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>What was significant about Domino was that Lotus would now compete in the Internet Web server business, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In Domino, Notes becomes an interactive Web application server, which is very different. If you think about Web servers today, prinicipally Netscape...which is about static publishing, just posting information on an Intranet or Internet, Domino is about a much more dynamic application development, actual transaction, commerce and security,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For instance, users can write and collaborate from different countries round the world and through Notes can get the information published in the Web.</p>
<p>Papows said Lotus was not interested in getting involved in the Internet browser war, but aimed at the Internet server software end of the market, which is projected to be worth US$9.0 billion by 1999 from below US$2.0 billion this year.</p>
<p>The collaboration segment of that market -- a combination of messaging and interactive application development -- was being contested by Lotus, Netscape and Microsoft, he said.</p>
<p>Lotus is working with Microsoft to integrate its Explorer browser with Domino and Papows confirmed that Lotus had talks with Netscape on an alliance which fell through.</p>
<p>&quot;What's shocking to me is that Microsoft would be so desirous of working with us in Notes and Domino and Netscape would make that so difficult,&quot; he said without elaboration.</p>
<p>With Domino, users can choose to get into the Internet via Microsoft's Explorer or Netscape's Navigator and Papows said the move was the Lotus answer to analyst criticisms that Notes needed a more mainstream browser.</p>
<p>He said the Internet explosion had boosted the Lotus groupware business, with less effort now spent on explaining why there was a need to share information and more on how to do it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
