<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738493" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS -BA, American open Spanish front.</title>
<headline>FOCUS -BA, American open Spanish front.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways Plc and American Airlines defied critics of their controversial alliance plans on Friday by announcing two new deals with Spanish carrier Iberia.</p>
<p>The two airlines announced separate agreements to link up with Iberia and tap into the Spanish carrier's southern European and Latin American markets.</p>
<p>American revealed that it has agreed a full marketing alliance with Iberia and is also buying a 10 percent stake in the parent of Iberia's associated Argentinian airlines Aerolineas Argentinas and Austral.</p>
<p>Meanwhile BA said it had signed a memorandum of understanding to negotiate a marketing deal with Iberia and also to discuss the possibility of taking a minority stake in the Spanish state-owned carrier, which is being reorganised for eventual privatisation.</p>
<p>Iberia said both BA and American have taken options to buy minority stakes by the end of this year, which would kick off the privatisation programme.</p>
<p>The news came as a surprise to industry analysts, who had expected BA to hold off from confirming persistent rumours of a deal with Iberia while it was still struggling to win approval from European and U.S. authorities for their own long-delayed alliance.</p>
<p>The news was immediately seized by rivals for extra ammunition to fire in their allegations that BA and American are just too big to be allowed to fly together.</p>
<p>&quot;Iberia has found it increasingly difficult to compete in the important South American markets because of American's dominance at Miami, the key gateway (airport) to the continent,&quot; said leading rival, UAL Corp's United Airlines.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposed alliance between BA and American has added to this pressure on Iberia and has led it to ally rather than compete. We expect that the European Union will study these proposals from BA, American and Iberia very closely,&quot; United said in a statement.</p>
<p>Industry sources said they suspected BA had decided it would be better to declare the Iberian connection to the authorities sooner rather than later.</p>
<p>BA and American are still awaiting EU Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert to make a ruling on their own alliance and also have to secure clearance in the UK and U.S. as part of the negotiations for a new Anglo-U.S. aviation trade agreement.</p>
<p>But the sources said it was likely that BA had secured an informal approval from Van Miert for the Iberian talks before it decided to go ahead and make Friday's announcement.</p>
<p>No one at BA was immediately available to comment, but the airline said in a statement the EU competition authorities &quot;have been briefed informally on the proposed arrangement and will be kept informed of developments.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Because of American's formal deal with Iberia we think that rather than have everyone else whisper it into the ear of the EU Commissioners BA thought it best to just come out and say it,&quot; said one executive with a rival airline.</p>
<p>Analysts also speculated that the protracted delays in winning approvals for the alliance with American had forced BA to declare its hand now on Iberia or risk losing out to rivals in Europe such as Dutch carrier KLM Royal Dutch Airlines NV which was also seen as a suitor for Iberia.</p>
<p>&quot;The risk maybe was that if BA had not agreed to get involved with Iberia at this stage then American might have said 'okay, we will go with KLM,'&quot; said Mike Powell of NatWest Markets. &quot;The bottom line on today's news is that it really demonstrates BA's commitment to American and vice-versa...It's all part of what could be quite a successful tripartite alliance,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
