<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738511" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Sea physical wet crudes mixed, paper firm.</title>
<headline>N.Sea physical wet crudes mixed, paper firm.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea physical crudes were mixed on Friday with Bent trading weaker and other grades talked at steady to stronger levels, traders said.</p>
<p>Outright prices staged a late slide on reports Hurrican Danny would not hit Gulf of Mexico offshore oil installations as hard as originally feared.</p>
<p>September Brent was trading at $18.24 a barrel at 1714 GMT, down 45 cents.</p>
<p>The tighter morning tone in physical and paper persisted in the afternoon despite a trade of a wet Brent at a differential 10 cents under a Thursday deal.</p>
<p>The July 27-loader was done at a five cent discount to August Brent, sharply down from August -5 cents paid on Thursday for another Brent loading the same dates.</p>
<p>The buyer said minimal demand for late July had made the stem &quot;almost distressed&quot;. But some other traders said fair value appeared to be a few cents higher and the Friday trade had more to do with swaps plays.</p>
<p>Sellers talked up the value of other grades, pointing to a slew of bullish factors including Hurricane Danny, strong gasoline, a continuing lack of Iraqi barrels and problems with the North Sea Nelson field, which feeds into the Forties system.</p>
<p>Buyers described themselves as relaxed.&quot;We are constructive, but we are not excited,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>One seller offered Forties at least 10 cents firmer at a 43 cent premium to Dated Brent after output at the North Sea's Nelson field was lowered by around 20,000 barrels per day (bpd) due to production problems.</p>
<p>The fault with gas dehydration equipment has meant the deferral of about 1.25 million barrels from the July loading programme to the August probramme. More cuts from the current level of around 110,000 bpd are forseen for next week, according to a source at operator Enterprise Oil.  </p>
<p>A late July Statfjord as well was talked around three cents firmer at around Dated +40 cents while an early August loader was offered a few cents weaker.</p>
<p>A seller offered a first decade Oseberg at around Dated +30 cents and Ekofisk was talked around the same level, around two to three cents firmer.</p>
<p>Sellers maintained they saw reasonable demand.</p>
<p>&quot;Quite a few cargoes were traded in the past couple of days and that has cleared out a lot of first decade August. And while margins are not that good, they are not terrible,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Paper markets raced higher in the morning but tailed off slightly in the afternoon.</p>
<p>Brent swaps or Contracts for Difference were inactive but talked at high values. CFDs for next week were discussed at September Brent +10/+13 cents, 10 cents up on the day and one cent off the highest prices heard.</p>
<p>CFDs for the following week (July 28-August 1) were talked at September Brent -5/0 cents, up four cents from Thursday but down four from the day's strongest numbers.</p>
<p>The August/September Brent intermonth spread traded early at +10 cents, but swiftly headed further into backwardation to change hands at a high of +19 cents with a European major dominating the buying.</p>
<p>The spread eased to +10/+15 in later talk.</p>
<p>Med crude markets continued tight with very little Russian Urals seen available in July and buyers hedging against further delays in the return of Iraqi barrels by booking barrels in early August.</p>
<p>A major bought a 130,000 tonne August 1-5 loader on Thursday for a price heard to be around 80 cents below Dated Brent. Earlier a trader sold a smaller, earlier cargo for a price believed to be in the mid 70's below dated.</p>
<p>However, a large late July Urals loader held by a Swiss trader was not heard sold. The cargoe's fate was unclear.</p>
<p>An end July Siberian Light cargo went to an unknown buyer for a price heard to be between 15 and 25 cents a barrel over Dated Brent, stronger than the grade's normal seven to 10 cent premium.</p>
<p>--W Maclean S Maguire London newsroom +44 171 542 7646 (c) Reuters Limited 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
