<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738677" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Taylor rally closes Liberia's election campaign.</title>
<headline>Taylor rally closes Liberia's election campaign.</headline>
<byline>John Chiahemen</byline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Liberia's former chief warlord Charles Taylor climaxed his campaign for Saturday's presidential elections with a rapturous rally in the capital.</p>
<p>Campaigning for the elections, the first in the civil war- battered West African nation for 12 years, ended officially on Thursday night.</p>
<p>Taylor's exuberant supporters, predominantly teenagers and including his converted guerrillas, packed a 35,000-capacity stadium with many more blocking traffic in adjoining roads. Officials of Taylor's National Patriotic Party (NPP) estimated the turnout of supporters in the hundreds of thousands.</p>
<p>Taylor's chief rival and the only woman candidate Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf staged a far less spectacular rally on Wednesday. But she kept up a spirited campaign on Thursday, walking the streets of Monrovia trailed by hundreds of supporters.</p>
<p>NPP supporters dubbed their gathering &quot;the pre-victory rally&quot; and Taylor delighted them with a speech, pledging education, jobs and equal opportunities for all.</p>
<p>He said he offered &quot;the hope that soon your children will go school, the hope that soon there will be jobs, the hope that soon we all will be a united people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The elections wrap up a regional peace process ending seven years of war in the country, founded by freed American slaves in 1847.</p>
<p>With two other militia leaders among the field of 12 presidential candidates, many Liberians fear a resurgence of violence if losers refuse to accept the verdict of the voters.</p>
<p>But electoral officials have publicly played down such fears and given assurances of an impartial vote.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no government in power that has to retain power at all cost, and no institution powerful enough to influence the commission,&quot; election commission chairman Henry Andrews told a news conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>He said a total of 716,845 people had been registered to vote at some 1,900 polling stations across the country.</p>
<p>International election experts in Liberia say some voters in inaccessible locations may not have been registered but add that they view the total figure as credible.</p>
<p>A total of about 500 international observers are in Liberia to monitor the poll, including 330 from the United Nations and 52 from the European Union. Former United States president Jimmy Carter is the highest ranking foreign observer.</p>
<p>The West African peacekeeping force ECOMOG gave assurances of readiness to deal with troublemakers. Ten countries led by Nigeria have troops in the 10,500-strong force, which will provide security as well as help transport ballot boxes, personnel and equipment.</p>
<p>Apart from Taylor, two other warlords are running for president -- Alhaji Kromah, who headed the second largest faction during the war, and George Boley, the leading politician in the Krahn tribe that dominated power in Liberia in the 1980s.</p>
<p>Kromah's power base is in his stronghold in northwestern Liberia close to Sierra Leone and home to his predominantly Moslem Mandingo folowers.</p>
<p>He was Taylor's main rival in the war, but many Liberians say his position has been weakened by the arrival of Johnson- Sirleaf. A runoff ballot, if it came to that, would most likely be between Taylor, 49, and Johnson-Sirleaf, 58.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
