<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738603" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya reform leaders call for support for crusade.</title>
<headline>Kenya reform leaders call for support for crusade.</headline>
<byline>Peter Smerdon</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leaders of a political reform campaign in Kenya urged supporters on Friday not to abandon their crusade for change in the face of Kenya's ruling party seeking to hijack their demands.</p>
<p>The ruling Kenya African National Union (KANU) party on Thursday proposed changes which could effectively pull the reform rug from under an opposition-backed alliance, which had forged rare unity among opponents of President Daniel arap Moi.</p>
<p>The proposals surprised opposition leaders and  stunned ordinary Kenyans, the backbone since June of rallies and clashes with riot police that hit tourism and scared foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;They (KANU) have dented the pressure,&quot; admitted Willy Mutunga, a leader of an alliance of opposition parties, human rights groups and other bodies campaigning for reforms before elections this year. &quot;It's up to us to make the next move.&quot;</p>
<p>Opposition leaders in speeches urged 400 supporters at an open-air service for the dead from clashes this month not to abandon the campaign they hoped would unseat Moi, 73, and in power for 19 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The freedom we have fought for has not been restored,&quot; said Democratic Party chief Mwai Kibaki. &quot;Struggle to the very end.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Moi is now acting out of weakness. Moi will not beat us. We will win...When we fight for change we don't want Moi to give it to us. We want to win it ourselves,&quot; James Orengo, deputy leader of the opposition in parliament, told a cheering crowd.</p>
<p>Police however remained out of sight as what was billed as a memorial service with the bodies of two of the dead in coffins at the feet of speakers turned at times into a political rally.</p>
<p>KANU's National Executive Council chaired by Moi proposed on Thursday parliament pass a bill for 11 controversial laws to be &quot;repealed or amended where deemed necessary&quot; before elections and to set up a commission to review Kenya's constitution.</p>
<p>If enacted by parliament, where KANU has a majority, the repeal of the 11 laws, some dating back to the colonial period, would reduce Moi's power. But it would also remove a main pillar of the reform drive and possibly split the opposition again.</p>
<p>Moi has been tipped to win another five-year term and could move to catch the opposition off guard after losing its common cause by calling elections shortly after repealing the 11 laws.</p>
<p>Opposition politicians and pro-reform leaders said they would have to wait to see if parliament would repeal the laws and meet their demands for &quot;minimal&quot; reforms before the polls.</p>
<p>&quot;It's too early for us to raise the flag and say we are all on board,&quot; opposition politician Richard Leakey told Reuters. &quot;I think by the middle of next week we should have more evidence of what is going on.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing I have seen so far that convinces me their commitment is genuine. We must see what is brought to parliament next week,&quot; added Leakey, the secretary-general of the unregistered Safina party and a renowned palaeontologist.</p>
<p>&quot;I am apprehensive. KANU is trying to stem the crisis, not to change genuinely,&quot; said Reverend Timothy Njoya, a Presbyterian cleric who like Leakey is a member of the National Convention Executive Committee (NCEC) behind the reform drive.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want them (KANU) to represent themselves as the reformists. But we welcome KANU's change of heart,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Njoya's arm was broken by police on July 7 during clashes between riot police and pro-reform demonstrators in Nairobi and several other cities and towns. At least nine people were killed in the worst political violence to hit Kenya in seven years.</p>
<p>KANU's proposals were announced after the NCEC called for a series of new &quot;mass actions&quot; including a rally in Kenya's second city Mombasa, the centre of its coast tourism industry, on July 26 and a nationwide general strike and sit-in on August 8.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
