<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738699" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bomb damages flat of U.N. policeman in Bosnia.</title>
<headline>Bomb damages flat of U.N. policeman in Bosnia.</headline>
<dateline>BANJA LUKA, Bosnia 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bomb damaged the apartment of an international police officer early on Friday morning in the latest Bosnian Serb retaliatory attack over a NATO swoop on indicted war criminals.</p>
<p>U.N. spokesman Alun Roberts said the sleeping officer was not injured in the blast in Gradiska, about 50 km (30 miles) north of Banja Luka, in Bosnia's Serb entity.</p>
<p>&quot;There was quite a bit of damage to the balcony and living room windows,&quot; Roberts told Reuters.</p>
<p>The explosion was the fifth in as many days aimed at peacekeepers or civilian international officials. In a sixth incident, a U.S. soldier was slightly hurt in an attack with a sickle.</p>
<p>Roberts said the wave of minor explosions &quot;appear to be a form of low-level intimidation&quot; in retaliation for the NATO arrest operation last week.</p>
<p>Serb nationalist leaders were outraged over the swoop on two Serbs charged with war crimes by a U.N. tribunal. One suspect was seized and extradited, and another was shot dead when he resisted British soldiers trying to arrest him.</p>
<p>Roberts also said posters had been plastered around the region with a picture of Radovan Karadzic, the former Bosnian Serb president who is also wanted by the tribunal for war crimes.</p>
<p>Below Karadzic's picture were the words: &quot;Don't touch him - he means peace&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANJA LUKA, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
