<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738791" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian shares firm, gains seen short-lived.</title>
<headline>Slovenian shares firm, gains seen short-lived.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenia's blue-chip SBI index firmed 0.59 percent on Friday to end the week 2.6 percent higher but traders forecast a downward correction in the coming two weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the correction could push the index down to 1,440 or 1,450 points,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The SBI index rose 8.74 points to 1,478.21.</p>
<p>Overall ten shares rose, five fell, two were unchanged and 11 were untraded.</p>
<p>Issue A of drug firm Lek had the highest turnover, keeping steady at 34,600 tolars on volume of 8,230 shares for a total turnover of 286.3 million tolars.</p>
<p>Lek's issue C was the biggest gainer, up 4.33 percent to 33,490 tolars on volume of 138 shares.</p>
<p>Ordinary shares of trader Kovinotehna led decliners, falling 4.81 percent to 475 tolars on volume of 1,166 shares in what traders said was a technical correction to recent gains.</p>
<p>Analysts said drug maker Krka, petrol traders Petrol and Istrabenz and trader Mercator would probably prove to be the best performers in the short-term.</p>
<p>They pointed to good business results, relatively low share prices and a lot of international investor interest.</p>
<p>Of the four only Mercator ended in positive territory. It firmed 1.5 percent to 5,390 on volume of 5,117 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
