<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738870" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - July 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - July 18.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Friday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Andris Shkele has called an extraordinary press conference today to speak about the situation in the country and the scandalous deal between Latvenergo and Banka Baltija. Politicians denied unofficial information that Shkele met parties to advise them of his decision to resign.</p>
<p>Many leading politicians have expressed hope that Shkele will stay at the helm to see the country through the latest patch of political turbulence.</p>
<p>- Neither Prime Minister Andris Shkele, nor the administration of Ventspils Nafta could so far confirm whether the deal between the oil transport company and Bank Baltija involving a Liechtenstein company as a mediator will be suspended.</p>
<p>The prime minister met the director of the privatisation agency, Janis Naglis, to discuss the possibility of revoking both deals.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- Chief prosecutor Olgerts Shabanskis said that no documents have been obtained proving that the deal between Latvenergo and Banka Baltija was illegal.</p>
<p>BIZNES &amp; BALTIJA</p>
<p>- Latvian politicians comment on the decision of the European Commission not to start talks with Latvia.</p>
<p>SM</p>
<p>- Representatives of the opposition party For Latvia issued a statement urging prime minister Shkele to resign. The party has called Shkele Latvia's disaster and blamed him for the fact that Latvia is not invited to start talks with the EU.</p>
<p>DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- Around 170 million lats is expected to be invested in the port of Ventspils by the year 2000. A substantial part will be used to modernise the terminal's railway.</p>
<p>-- Riga newsroom +371 721 52 40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
