<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738923" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru's new ministers seek to calm political crisis.</title>
<headline>Peru's new ministers seek to calm political crisis.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peruvian President Alberto Fujimori's five new ministers took up their posts on Friday as the dust settled from a turbulent cabinet reshuffle widely interpreted as strengthening the military's grip on power.</p>
<p>The new foreign, defence, interior, justice and fishing ministers were sworn in late on Thursday by Fujimori.</p>
<p>They sought immediately to calm the political atmosphere from a torrid week that culminated in a string of cabinet resignations and a huge protest march on Thursday on Fujimori's Government Palace residence.</p>
<p>Incoming Justice Minister Alfredo Quispe Correa said the case of Israeli-born Baruch Ivcher -- whose loss of Peruvian citizenship last weekend became a lightning rod for opposition to Fujimori -- would be settled &quot;autonomously&quot; by the courts.</p>
<p>Ivcher is the majority-owner of the Frecuencia Latina channel, which has increasingly irked the government and security forces in recent months with a string of allegations of corruption and rights abuses.</p>
<p>Particularly damaging were the cases it aired of intelligence agent Leonor La Rosa, tortured by her own colleagues, and the inexplicably large income of security adviser Vladimiro Montesinos, believed to be Fujimori's link with the military.</p>
<p>The channel's most recent allegation of systematic phone-tapping by the secret services came an hour before the annulment on Sunday of Ivcher's nationality, which meant under Peruvian law he can no longer own a local media outlet.</p>
<p>New Foreign Minister Eduardo Ferrero Costa moved quickly to calm fears of a fresh border conflict with neighbouring Ecuador, which opposition sectors have said the government and military might use to distract public attention from internal problems.</p>
<p>He promised &quot;the same policy&quot; as outgoing Foreign Minister Francisco Tudela, widely respected for his diplomatic efforts to bury a century-old dispute with Ecuador that has brought a series of armed conflicts including a brief 1995 war.</p>
<p>&quot;The (peace) process in Brasilia, the conversations between Peru and Ecuador with the presence of the guarantor countries, will continue the same way with total normality,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Costa was named after Tudela, one of the most popular figures in the cabinet, resigned -- apparently to disassociate himself from the authoritarian style of Fujimori.</p>
<p>Analysts said the appointment of military heads Gen. Cesar Saucedo and Gen. Jose Villanueva to the defence and interior ministries respectively boosted the armed forces' sway over the cabinet.</p>
<p>&quot;The new ministers do not represent a change in direction by the government, less still a correction of the mistakes committed,&quot; columnist Manuel d'Ornellas of the normally pro-Fujimori Expreso said. &quot;On the contrary, the insertion in the ministerial team of two active generals points toward a greater militarization of the regime.&quot;</p>
<p>Both Saucedo and Villanueva, whose portfolios include the armed and police forces, are considered allies of Montesinos and military chief Gen. Nicolas Bari de Hermoza.</p>
<p>Recent polls have shown that most Peruvians consider those men in control of the real power, rather than Fujimori.</p>
<p>The recent political crisis, combined with public anger over widespread poverty and unemployment, has sent Fujimori tumbling to his lowest popularity level in seven years of power, 23 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
