<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738989" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil oil law heralds privatization-analysts.</title>
<headline>Brazil oil law heralds privatization-analysts.</headline>
<byline>Simona de Logu</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Congressional approval of a bill regulating the opening of the Brazilian oil and gas industry to private capital is a first step toward the future privatization of Brazil's oil monopoly Petrobras, analysts said.</p>
<p>The bill, which still has to be signed by President Fernando Henrique Cardoso to become law, allows private sector companies to compete or establish partnerships with Petrobras which has acted alone in most areas of Brazil's petroleum industry for the last 40 years.</p>
<p>The bill also sets up a regulator, the National Petroleum Agency (ANP), which is due to start overseeing the industry in 120 days time. In the transition period the Mines and Energy Ministry will carry out the regulatory functions.</p>
<p>&quot;Some time ago the privatization of Petrobras was inconceivable, but now one can imagine the concept,&quot; said Marcio Brito, oil analyst at Banco Icatu. &quot;The petroleum law represents a step forward with respect to the past.&quot;</p>
<p>Brito said the privatization was unlikely to take place before 2004 given that Cardoso, who is likely to be re-elected as president next year, has repeatedly said he would not privatize Petrobras.</p>
<p>Fabio Anderaos, head of research at Schahin Cury, however, believes privatization could come earlier, in three to four years time.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the government is interested in privatization, but the company's performance needs to be improved first in order for the government to sell it off for a better price,&quot; Anderaos said. &quot;The oil law is the first step toward making the company Anderaos said only privatization could turn Petrobras, which suffers from low profitability, into a truly efficient company.</p>
<p>Analysts said the immediate effect of the oil law would be the creation of a competitive environment, forcing Petrobras to become more efficient over time, and an increase in Petrobras' investment capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the beginning of the game, a game that will greatly benefit Petrobras,&quot; said Ricardo Kobayashi, oil analyst at Banco Pactual. &quot;Petrobras is in a privileged position because it will be the prefered partner for any investment in the oil and gas sectors in the next few years.&quot;</p>
<p>Petrobras has identified 150 projects it would like to carry out in partnership with private companies. It has received scores of proposals for the projects which are mainly in exploration and production and are worth around $3 billion in investments over three years.</p>
<p>Anderaos said Petrobras' new private partners could boost investment levels by as much as $1 billion to $1.5 billion a year. This will allow the company to increase production to 1.5 million barrels of oil per day (bpd) in four years time from the current 900,000 bpd and help decrease Brazil's dependency on oil imports, he said.</p>
<p>Oil consumption now stands at 1.5 million bpd and is expected to rise by 4.7 percent a year.</p>
<p>Brito said the oil law also gave Petrobras greater administrative flexibility by simplifying the company's tender process for the acquisition of equipment and services and by allowing Petrobras and its subsidiaries to take minority stakes in new joint ventures with the private sector.</p>
<p>((--Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
