<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="738994" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Bougainville parties say NZ peace talks raise hope.</title>
<headline>Bougainville parties say NZ peace talks raise hope.</headline>
<dateline>CHRISTCHURCH, New Zealand 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The main factions in a nine-year secessionist war on Papua New Guinea's Bougainville Island agreed on Friday they had made a key breakthrough after two weeks of peace talks in New Zealand.</p>
<p>Leaders of the rebel Bougainville Revolutionary Army (BRA) and its political wing and of the PNG-backed Bougainville Transitional Government (BTG) set out a fragile outline for a way forward, but acknowleged there were hurdles.</p>
<p>They signed a declaration pledging to set up a process to negotiate jointly with the PNG government, which was not a party to the talks, and set a target for the first round of such contact by September this year on neutral ground.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the declaration contains and details the main constituents of peace and justice on Bougainville and for (a) harmonious relationship with PNG,&quot; BTG Premier Gerard Sinato told the signing ceremony.</p>
<p>The other signatory, Joseph Kabui of BRA and its political arm the Bougainville Interim Government (BIG), called the document &quot;an historic undertaking with each other which we can all be truly pround of&quot;.</p>
<p>But he said there were &quot;many more trials and tribulations&quot; left for the islanders to confront.</p>
<p>The agreement's text proposes many elements of the BRA's agenda for peace seen in past talks, such as the linking of the arrival of an international peacekeeping force to any declaration of ceasefire, and a call for demilitarisation.</p>
<p>But the absence of direct input from Port Moresby, especially after the uncertainty created by recent elections in Papua New Guinea, was just one challenge to further progress, observers said.</p>
<p>Bougainville has been a huge political headache for Papua New Guinea, and departing Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan this year provoked the country's biggest crisis since independence by trying to bring in Anglo-South African mercenaries to put down the rebellion.</p>
<p>New Zealand Foreign Minister Don McKinnon, who arranged the gathering of 70 or so delegates at Burnham military camp near the South Island city of Christchurch, expressed guarded optimism that progress had been made but also warned of risks.</p>
<p>&quot;A level of trust will be required and I hope all parties will see merit in a period of contemplation rather than violence or payback,&quot; McKinnon said.</p>
<p>Thousands have died in the Bougainville conflict since landowners revolted in 1988 over damage caused by the huge Panguna copper mine, and the royalties they received from it.</p>
<p>The mine, now closed and the fortified headquarters of BRA, is owned by a unit of the Anglo-Australian giant Rio Tinto Ltd.</p>
<p>Analysts say ruthless and often ill-disciplined military and paramilitary forces have prolonged the war and made a mockery of previous peace efforts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHRISTCHURCH, New Zealand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
