<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73910" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thailand sets up fund to boost shipping.</title>
<headline>Thailand sets up fund to boost shipping.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Thailand, in an effort to narrow a widening current account deficit, has set up an 8.0 billion baht fund (US$320 million) to support the domestic shipping sector, a central bank statement said on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>The fund would be jointly operated by the central bank, the Export-Import Bank of Thailand (EXIM Bank) and the Industrial Finance Corporation of Thailand (IFCT), the statement said.</p>
<p>To be eligible for the fund, a company must be locally registered and at least 50 percent-owned by Thai nationals. The company must be involved in the transport of goods between Thailand and foreign countries.</p>
<p>Loans will be granted for the purchase of either new ships or second-hand ships not older than 20 years. If a loan is granted for the purchase of second-hand vessels, it will also cover possible repair costs.</p>
<p>Ships bought under the loan programme must be registered in Thailand and carry the national flag, the central bank said.</p>
<p>High payments to foreign shippers has been identified as one of the major factors exacerbating the country's current account deficit, which stood at 8.1 percent of gross domestic product in 1995.</p>
<p>($1=25 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
