<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739172" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oklahoma bomb defendant says FBI copies his mail.</title>
<headline>Oklahoma bomb defendant says FBI copies his mail.</headline>
<byline>Robert Boczkiewicz</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oklahoma City bombing defendant Terry Nichols on Friday accused federal prison authorities of violating his constitutional rights by copying his mail and turning it over to investigators and prosecutors.</p>
<p>&quot;In short, the FBI (Federal Bureau of Investigation), with the cooperation of the Bureau of Prisons, has been treating Mr. Nichols' private correspondence as fodder for their investigation on behalf of the prosecution,&quot; his lawyers claimed in a court filing.</p>
<p>They asked U.S. District Judge Richard Matsch to suppress evidence obtained from Nichols' prison mail.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't think anything wrong is occurring, but we have to look at it in view of this motion being filed,&quot; prosecutor James Orenstein said.</p>
<p>Nichols is being held at a suburban Denver prison, awaiting his Sept. 29 trial for the April 19, 1995, bombing of the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building in Oklahoma City. The attack killed 168 people.</p>
<p>His co-defendant Timothy McVeigh was convicted in June and sentenced to death.</p>
<p>Separately, the Justice Department accused Nichols' lawyers of unfairly criticising the ethics of its prosecutors based in Oklahoma City assigned to the bombing case.</p>
<p>The alleged &quot;attacks&quot; are in a sealed portion of a request asking Matsch to remove the prosecutors.</p>
<p>In an unsealed part of the request, Nichols' lawyers contended that the Oklahoma City prosecutors have a &quot;personal stake in the outcome of this case.&quot; Only two of seven of the prosecutors are from Oklahoma City.</p>
<p>In its response to the court, the Justice Department urged Matsch to keep under seal Nichols' lawyers' &quot;highly subjective speculation about the professional capacities&quot; of the prosecutors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
