<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739192" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASD to move soon on Wall Street bias case policy.</title>
<headline>NASD to move soon on Wall Street bias case policy.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Morrison</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Association of Securities Dealers will soon decide whether it should try to end a Wall Street custom that prevents employees of securities firms from taking their discrimination claims to court.</p>
<p>Currently, employees of securities firms are required to sign a standard form in which they agree only to arbitrate disputes rather than sue in court.</p>
<p>While claims involving discrmination or sexual harassment make up only about 2 percent of all disputes, the issue has attracted widespread attention in recent months following several high-profile cases involving big securities firms.</p>
<p>In May, Mary Schapiro, the president of NASD's regulatory arm, said it was reviewing the policy and would likely make a decision this summer.</p>
<p>The NASD, the self-requlatory body of the securities industry, has been flooded with comments on the issue from lawmakers, the securities industry and women's and civil rights groups.</p>
<p>Opponents of the arbitration-only requirement say the practice prevents women, minorities and older workers on Wall Street from enjoying the same protections under U.S. law given to every other U.S. worker.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry's policy of mandatory arbitration unfortunately has forced folks who are victims of discrimination into second-class justice,&quot; said Helen Norton, Director of Equal Employment Programmes at the Women's Legal Defence Fund.</p>
<p>&quot;We think that the NASD has an opportunity here to really improve conditions for women and people of colour working in the securities industry,&quot; Norton said.</p>
<p>The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC), the federal agency that oversees anti-discrimination laws, has repeatedly urged the NASD not to ignore established labour discrimination laws, citing the limitiations of arbitration. Last week, the EEOC publicly declared its opposition to the manadatory arbitration requirement for discrimination claims.</p>
<p>&quot;When employees are forced into private, employer-designed arbitration systems to resolve their discrimination claims, there is no public accountability for decisions that are made,&quot; said EEOC Chairman Gilbert Casellas in a July 10 statement.</p>
<p>Last week, the Securities Industry Association (SIA), a Washington lobby group, urged the NASD not to make any changes to the industry practice of requiring employees to agree to arbitrate any disputes. The group says arbitration is, among other things, cost-efficient.</p>
<p>&quot;Industry arbitration is the best mechanism for resolving disputes relating to the business of the securities industry,&quot; the SIA wrote to Schapiro in a letter dated July 10. &quot;Discrimination claims are, as a practical matter, inextricably linked with issues of business.&quot;</p>
<p>Several big Wall Street firms have been hit by discrimination lawsuits recently. A sexual harrassment and discrimination suit filed last year againt Smith Barney Inc., is still pending, while Gruntal &amp; Co. agreed to pay $750,000 to settle a harrassment case against 6 former employees.</p>
<p>NASD spokesman Michael Robinson declined to comment on the NASD's next move, but Schapiro has said one option would be to modify the current practice to allow employees to take discrimination lawsuits to court. Other types of disputes would still be resolved through arbitration.</p>
<p>Alternatively, Schapiro has said the NASD could leave the policy as it is and work instead to improve the arbitration process.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
