<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739240" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: On-line hay market seeks to match buyers, sellers.</title>
<headline>On-line hay market seeks to match buyers, sellers.</headline>
<byline>Greg Frost</byline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new website on the Internet will give Minnesota livestock producers the chance to obtain badly needed hay supplies from across the Midwest, sources associated with the on-line project said Friday.</p>
<p>Cheryl Fox, program development officer for the Minnesota Forage and Grassland Council, said local and state agriculture officials set up the &quot;Minnesota Haylist&quot; (http://www.mes.umn.edu/Haylist) in response to a hay shortage earlier this year.</p>
<p>Neal Martin, University of Minnesota extension forage agronomist, said the Haylist will allow sellers a chance to advertise their supplies, while buyers will be able to browse listings and check availability. The list will initially act as a seller's forum, but buyers' names will be added later.</p>
<p>Martin said dry weather last year and a cool dry spring this year combined to create tight hay supplies in east-central Minnesota.</p>
<p>The problem became so severe that some Minnesota producers sold off livestock because of a lack of hay and the high price of available hay, Martin said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Farmers are asking for hay supplies now and have been for some time,&quot; Martin said. &quot;Minnesota's hay stocks on farms May 1 were 540,000 tons, the lowest record for that time of year.&quot;</p>
<p>The new website will allow users immediate access to list, modify, search and print information on specific hay lots. Data are organized by state and area code and all entries are listed by forage type and location.</p>
<p>The site was launched earlier this month, and Fox said that although initial user statistics were not yet available, early signs indicated that the service had been received favorably.</p>
<p>&quot;I did hear that in the first several days people had listed hay for sale,&quot; Fox said.</p>
<p>The service is offered at no charge to buyers and sellers, Fox said.</p>
<p>In addition, Minnesota producers who cannot acess the World Wide Web from their homes are free to do so using the Internet connections at their local county extension offices.</p>
<p>Fox said because the Haylist exists on the Internet, its use could very well spread beyond state boundaries. Extension agriculture officials in states as far away as Kansas have encouraged producers to check out the new site.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not trying to limit it to Minnesota. We think anyone, anywhere could use this,&quot; Fox said.</p>
<p>((--Kansas City bureau, 816 561-8671))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
