<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739235" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soy products end higher on soybean gains.</title>
<headline>CBOT soy products end higher on soybean gains.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soymeal and soyoil ended firmer but off the day's highs on short covering ahead of the weekend amid uncertain weather forecasts, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very dangerous to take a position ahead of a weekend like this,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter. &quot;We could be limit up or limit down on Monday, depending on the weather.&quot;</p>
<p>Forecasts called for scattered showers across dry portions of central Illinois on Monday, a change from Thursday's outlook for widespread, heavy rains. Meteorologists said Hurricane Danny moved eastward instead of north, decreasing the likelihood of the heavy rains.</p>
<p>Some pockets of central Illinois, a major soybean producing region, have missed out on recent rains.</p>
<p>Persistent hot, dry weather can cause heat and moisture stress in developing crops and can cut yield potential. Illinois is traditionally among the largest soybean producers in the United States.</p>
<p>Gains were pared late as heavy rains hit Chicago which led to ideas rains would also hit central Illinois.</p>
<p>Soymeal ended $2.70 to $0.40 per ton higher with December up $1.60 at $194.90. Soyoil ended 0.20 to 0.07 cent per lb higher with December up 0.20 at 22.66.  </p>
<p>Nearbys drew mild support from the National Oilseed Processors Association's weekly crush report which showed soybean crushings were lower last week.</p>
<p>NOPA put the weekly crush at 21.871 million bushels, down from 23.014 million the previous week. The trade had expected a lower crush figure because processors were taking downtime, cash sources said.</p>
<p>A Midwest heat wave this past week prompted some soybean processors to slightly reduce production as power companies instructed industrial customers to cut electricity use, industry officials said.</p>
<p>On the day, trade was said to be thin in both soymeal and soyoil ahead of the weekend. Traders blamed uncertainty over the weather for the thin volume.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch sold 600 lots December soymeal and 100 August while Smith Barney and Tenco Inc each sold 500 December and 100 August, pit sources said. Refco Inc bought 400 Decemer and 100 August and Rosenthal Collins bought 300 December.</p>
<p>In soyoil, Produce Grain sold at least 900 lots on the day, divided between the September, October and December. Prudential Securities and Rosenthal Collins each bought 400 December.</p>
<p>Soymeal volume was estimated by CBOT at 21,000 lots, compared with Thursday's actual volume of 22,238 lots. Soyoil volume was pegged at 15,000 lots, against Thursday's 14,157.</p>
<p>((Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
