<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739394" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. Council raps Angola's UNITA on peace process.</title>
<headline>U.N. Council raps Angola's UNITA on peace process.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Security Council members on Friday rapped Angola's opposition UNITA movement for not complying fully with peace accords that ended two decades of civil war and for mistreating U.N. personnel.</p>
<p>The Council made its views known in a press statement meant to coincide with a meeting of envoys from the United Nations, the United States, Portugal and Russia with UNITA leader Dr. Jonas Savimbi on Friday.</p>
<p>The last few weeks have seen heightened military activity including a government army offensive into UNITA-held territory in the country's northeast.</p>
<p>Saying UNITA had not complied with requirements of the 1994 peace accords, Council President Peter Osvald said the movement needed to complete demobilizing its forces, stop propaganda broadcasts and refrain from any act &quot;that could jeopardise the full implementation of the peace accords.&quot;</p>
<p>Osvald also said council members condemned attacks and general harassment against U.N. personnel by UNITA.</p>
<p>In the Angolan capital of Luanda, special U.N. representative Allione Blondon Beye told reporters that &quot;in the coming days we will know whether we are out of the current crisis.&quot; He said UNITA must show progress shortly on a number of issues in the 1994 peace accords.</p>
<p>These include handing over some of the vast territory it controls to the government and defining the number of UNITA troops still under arms.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the envoys seeing Savimbi also condemned UNITA for holding the U.N. planes, then blaming it on zealous locals but taking no disciplinary actions against the perpetrators.</p>
<p>In July, a U.N. helicopter was detained for more than 24 hours in Luanda Norte province and in June a plane from the World Food Programme was similarly held in Moxico province.</p>
<p>A Security Council resolution of June 30 gave the former rebels until Aug. 15 to comply with a series of demands, including the ones Beye addressed as the U.N. peacekeeping operation winds down, with 4,000 soldiers expected to be out of the country by November.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
