<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739460" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch shares tumble late in option-linked bale out.</title>
<headline>Dutch shares tumble late in option-linked bale out.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares tumbled to a sharply weaker close on Friday, undermined late in the session by a falling Wall Street market on a day when the biggest option expiry ever seen in Amsterdam dominated trading activity.</p>
<p>The main AEX index fell 11.58 points to close at 941.79, a level not visited since last Friday. The market has risen to successive new peaks this week, topping at 978.87 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Trading on Friday was volatile as expected, with the market dipping around 10 points on the opening before rebounding back into positive territory, and then falling back again at the close. A huge options expiry was behind the price gyrations.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of the contracts were closed out on Thursday but that still left a lot of business to be done today,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was some doubt on whether the options exchange could handle all the business.&quot;</p>
<p>But in general dealers said the market was still in good shape and predicted an early resumption of the uptrend once the option-related selling was out of the way. Before today's losses the Dutch market has risen nearly 50 percent this year alone.</p>
<p>&quot;There's some good quality buying just below the market. I still believe we can get beyond the recent peak,&quot; one commented.</p>
<p>Banking giant ABN AMRO dominated activity, with a huge numbers of options outstanding causing some 30 million shares in the company to be traded, dwarfing all other issues. By the close ABN AMRO was 0.10 up at 44.60 guilders.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Philips lost ground, dropping 4.40 guilders to 152.70, despite news the company had cut its stake in troubled German television and audio equipment maker.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like a good deal for Philips but the shares didn't react because of the options situation,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Philips, in a pre-bourse announcement, said it had reduced its stake in Grundig from 31.6 percent to a rump five percent.</p>
<p>Philips added it was disputing the 671 million mark 1996 loss reported by Grundig, saying the figure had been inflated by extensive provisions for new policies adopted after the year-end. It said it would ask the courts to nullify Grundig's 1996 annual accounts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
