<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739458" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian shares fall in pre-holiday profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Belgian shares fall in pre-holiday profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian shares tumbled with other European markets on Friday in what dealers said was a welcome correction ahead of a long weekend.</p>
<p>The biggest loser was chemicals and drugs maker UCB which gave up almost all of a week of rapid gains in a move which pulled lower the whole Bel-20 share index  .BFX.</p>
<p>UCB lost 10.88 percent to 132,350 francs, but it still ended the week above 129,000 francs, its week-ago close.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 ended down 1.86 percent at 2,494.03 points, compared with 2,492.41 points a week earlier. Fourteen Bel-20 issues were lower, five were higher and one was unchanged.  </p>
<p>&quot;The markets had gone up too strongly and a bit of profit taking is rather sound for the longer-term,&quot; Corluy &amp; Co analyst Patrick Millecam said. &quot;It's welcome and no reason to panic.&quot;</p>
<p>A lower start to Wall Street  .DJI and worries about France's budget woes, which hit neighbouring Paris, weighed on the bourse ahead of the long weekend, he noted.</p>
<p>Belgian markets are closed on Monday for the National Day public holiday.</p>
<p>How they open on Tuesday will depend on other markets' reaction to France's budget audit, due to be made public by the French government on Monday.  </p>
<p>The mid-afternoon expiry of July futures and options contracts had little impact, with most of the losses coming afterwards in the last hour of trade.</p>
<p>Few shares were able to put in a bright performance, though oil group PetroFina, electronics group Barco, steel cord and wire maker Bekaert and electricity utility Electrabel closed higher.</p>
<p>Outside the Bel-20, steel maker Cockerill Sambre rose two francs to 147. After the close of trade Germany's BVS privatisation agency said Cockerill was interested in raising its stake in EKO Stahl to 100 percent.</p>
<p>-- Nick Antonovics, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
