<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739433" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch closing debt market report.</title>
<headline>Dutch closing debt market report.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch bonds closed slightly easier on Friday, depressed by a small softening in the bund future and giving up some of Thursday's strong gains.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been very difficult to trade in this market, a lot of my clients are starting holidays,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;We've been up a lot recently and now people are taking a breather.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said they saw mostly interprofessional inquiry with actual business down to a minimum. &quot;The most business we've seen has been in the 30 year (bond) but even that's been pretty small,&quot; said the dealer. Another said he had seen slight international interest at the short end.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the bond market had been a little overshadowed by business on the Amsterdam bourse where the market slipped in huge volume related to options positions.</p>
<p>&quot;People are getting a little bit tired of the stock market but that hasn't really translated into any action on the bond market,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;Personally I think the bond market is offering good value and can go higher,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>At the long end the 7.50 percent January 2023 bond softened 0.02, giving up only a little of Thursday's half point gain. The bund future dipped 0.03 to 102.77 moving further away from the 103.00 resistance level.</p>
<p>-- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam newsroom 020-504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
