<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="73965" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Police quiz five IRA suspects, seek identity of sixth.</title>
<headline>Police quiz five IRA suspects, seek identity of sixth.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police on Tuesday questioned five Irish Republican Army suspects after dawn raids netted the biggest seizure of arms ever made in Britain.</p>
<p>Detectives, who believe they swooped just in time to stop the IRA wreaking havoc across Britain, are trying to identify a sixth suspect shot dead in Monday's raids.</p>
<p>The suspects, whose arrest dealt a body blow to IRA morale and torpedoed any chance of a new ceasefire, are being held at a high-security London police station.</p>
<p>They can be detained for a week without charge under anti-terrorism laws brought in to combat the IRA's guerrilla battle to oust Britain from Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>One of those arrested was a British Airways engineer working at London's Gatwick airport. Transport officials said they would be reviewing their already strict vetting procedures.</p>
<p>The airline insisted the arrest in no way suggested the airport was the target for an attack.</p>
<p>Police, jubilant that their close co-operation with secret service agents paid such rich dividends, put on display some of the 10 tonnes of explosives seized in the raids along with Kalashnikov rifles, car booby trap bombs and timers.</p>
<p>They believe the IRA were within hours of launching lorry bomb attacks and targeting high profile public figures.</p>
<p>Republicans feared an informer may have been responsible for the British police breakthrough. Security experts now believe the IRA could strike back to show it still has muscle.</p>
<p>The media speculated that IRA targets ranged from the Royal Family to the Channel Tunnel between France and Britain.</p>
<p>Members of the British and Irish parliaments met amid tightened security in the city of Bath to review the slim chances of finding an elusive peace formula in Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major, delighted by the find but swift to condemn the IRA, phoned his Irish counterpart John Bruton on Monday night to give him details of the police swoop.</p>
<p>The biggest casualty could be the peace process in Northern Ireland where Sinn Fein, the IRA's political wing, has been excluded from all-party talks.</p>
<p>Major, who has invested so much political capital in finding a solution to one of the 20th century's most intractable conflicts, said: &quot;It remains impossible to reconcile Sinn Fein's rhetoric with the IRA's preparations for murder.&quot;</p>
<p>Sinn Fein President Gerry Adams blamed Britain for creating such a dangerous political vacuum.</p>
<p>He virtually conceded that the chance of a renewed IRA truce had evaporated. &quot; This incident underlines the seriousness of the situation,&quot; a grim-faced Adams told reporters in Belfast.</p>
<p>The IRA ended a 17-month ceasefire in February with an attack on London's Docklands district that killed two people. In June, a huge lorry bomb devasted the centre of Manchester, injuring 200 people in the northern English city.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
