<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="739797" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIUM ADMITS ERRORS OVER BEEF BUT BLAMES BRITISH.</title>
<headline>BELGIUM ADMITS ERRORS OVER BEEF BUT BLAMES BRITISH.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium admitted on Friday there had been failings in its meat inspection system, but said Britain had most responsibility for the illegal British beef seized in Russia but branded as being Belgian.</p>
<p>&quot;The first responsibility is for the British authorities to reinforce their controls,&quot; Health Minister Marcel Colla told a news conference.</p>
<p>Russia said last week it held 730 tonnes of beef labelled as being Belgian but originating in Britain despite a ban on all British beef exports imposed over a year ago because of fears that so-called mad cow disease could be transmitted to humans.</p>
<p>The European Commission said earlier this month it had traced 1,600 tonnes of British beef illegally-exported to the Netherlands, Egypt and Russia either via Belgium or using Belgian certificates.</p>
<p>Some 170 tonnes have been seized in the German port of Hamburg destined for Russia.</p>
<p>Colla said that as soon as the problem had come to light his ministry had acted.</p>
<p>It had traced and blocked all meat -- whatever its stated origin -- either handled by or bearing the name of Belgian firms NV Tragex-Gel and SA Lefebvre, and written to Belgium's European Union neighbours informing them of the fact.</p>
<p>A total of 40 tonnes of this meat was found and impounded in Belgium. The two firms have appealed against the ban.</p>
<p>Belgium had also instituted a thorough internal enquiry into how illegal beef had escaped veterinary inspection and obtained illegal papers disguising its origin.</p>
<p>Colla said he had also proposed a complete revamp and reinforcment of the inspection service -- which is not government funded -- bringing in his ministry, the ministries of justice, agriculture and finance and the gendarmerie.</p>
<p>A special task-force set up to combat the trade in and use of illegal hormones in beef farming would also be expanded to take in all illegalities in the meat industry, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Noone underestimates the importance of this case. It is important for public confidence, Belgium and internationally,&quot; Colla said.</p>
<p>His declaration coincided with the second day of an official visit to Belgium and the EU of Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin who has said he would raise the issue during his stay.</p>
<p>Colla said despite that fact that Belgium did more than the EU's official requirements in veterinary inspections and had transposed into national law all the relevant EU regulations, there were still evident loopholes to be plugged -- both nationally and internationally.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
