<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740094" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE-AIDS survivors find life a new challenge.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-AIDS survivors find life a new challenge.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Orr</byline>
<dateline>WEST HOLLYWOOD, Calif. 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>When Greg was diagnosed with AIDS six years ago, he let his moderately unhealthy lifestyle veer out of control, increasing his drinking until he was up to 10 shots of vodka a night.</p>
<p>Why worry about every toxin he put into his body, he figured, when it was already housing a deadly virus?</p>
<p>But today the 49-year-old salesman is still healthy and is beginning to look forward to old age. He and many others like him are struggling to reverse the reckless lifestyles they adopted when they thought they had only a few years to live.</p>
<p>For these AIDS victims, a new generation of drugs has brought a dramatic reduction in their viral loads -- and a whole new set of problems. At a recent support group gathering here, many said they were having a hard time tending to some of life's more mundane tasks such as holding down a steady job and paying the mortgage. They put all that on hold years ago to take off on what they thought would be a final binge.</p>
<p>&quot;I've lived a third of my life with the HIV virus and my lover's been dead for 6-1/2 years,&quot; said a 45-year-old man who described how he tried to cram a lifetime of experiences into a couple of years. &quot;I sold my house, travelled, and then -- it didn't happen. I feel I lived my life in an accelerated fashion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Economically, it's hard,&quot; he added. &quot;I'm stuck with debt, I need a new car and have all these issues to deal with that are not really that exciting. I'm really glad I have a nondetectable viral load but it's a challenge getting used to the prosaic world of making a living.&quot;</p>
<p>AIDS VICTIMS ARE PAYING FOR THEIR EXCESSES</p>
<p>Such stories are plentiful in the Los Angeles gay community of West Hollywood and, experts say, around the country. AIDS victims who have managed to keep the disease at bay are now having to pay for spending beyond their means and other excesses they fed without hesitation after they or their lovers were diagnosed with AIDS.</p>
<p>Many are now fighting alcohol and drug addictions. Others are having to build a whole new life: buy a car, find a home and a job while explaining to prospective employers the long gaps in their work histories.</p>
<p>&quot;Before, the attitude was: 'Sure I can smoke. What's it going to do? Kill me?'&quot; said Michael Mallory of the AIDS Healthcare Foundation. &quot;Now, with protease, we're seeing that you can have AIDS and still live a long life.&quot;</p>
<p>Mallory was referring to protease inhibitors, a class of AIDS drug that came on the market about a year ago and dramatically changed the prognosis for many patients. Used in combination with other drugs, they have helped restore an essentially normal quality of life to thousands of AIDS victims. AIDS sufferers speaking about their renewed good health commonly refer to &quot;life after protease.&quot;</p>
<p>Protease inhibitors have not worked for everybody. Many AIDS victims either cannot tolerate the drugs or have developed a resistance to them. And in some poorer, more isolated regions patients have yet to be prescribed this &quot;wonder drug.&quot;</p>
<p>To them, worries about paying bills or kicking a drug habit are a luxury. They warn that people should not forget the real AIDS health crisis that continues to devastate millions of people around the world.</p>
<p>MOST RECEIVED BEST TREATMENTS</p>
<p>Most gay men in major U.S. cities acknowledge they have received the best treatments before they were widely available as a result of their own vigilance and their access to major research centres where clinical trials of new drugs are conducted. But they say the practical and emotional concerns they now face are serious.</p>
<p>One man who remained AIDS-free after the disease struck his lover and many of his friends equates his experience to returning from a war in which all his peers died. He says he feels like he is suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder in which just going through the motions of life is daunting.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people used to say, 'HIV is the best thing that happened to me.' It caused them to get rid of all the garbage of life like credit cards and cars,&quot; Robert Hales, coordinator of the AIDS outreach group Treatment Equals Life. said.</p>
<p>&quot;Recently I've even heard people be asked: 'Do you want to live?' And they actually have to stop and think about it.&quot;</p>
<p>Health officials are also concerned. Even with drugs bringing down virus levels, they point out, people with AIDS still have compromised immune systems. Unhealthy living may be extra hard on these people and in some cases may render a drug treatment less effective.</p>
<p>For Greg, the scare came during a recent visit to the doctor. After having his virus undetectable for more than a year, he was told it had crept back up and that alcohol consumption might be to blame.</p>
<p>The news was enough to cause him to stop drinking overnight. &quot;I was never before honest with myself about how much I was drinking,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WEST HOLLYWOOD, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
