<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74004" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FULL TEXT: BHP chairman's address.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FULL TEXT: BHP chairman's address.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following is an edited text of an address by the chairman of the Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd, Brian Loton, to the annual meeting in Sydney on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Good afternoon everyone and welcome, on behalf of the Board, to BHP's 1996 Annual General Meeting...</p>
<p>(Loton lists order of business, introduces panel and presents new management team)</p>
<p>...As most of you will be aware, 1996 was a rather mixed year for BHP. We recorded the second best profit in our history, but it was not as good as we had anticipated.  </p>
<p>The company's profit, before abnormal items, was almost A$1.3 billion -- down by 20 percent on the record 1995 year.</p>
<p>Steel and Petroleum profits were significantly lower and both groups made abnormal write-downs of assets. At the same time, the Minerals Group achieved a record result, and the Company made two major investments which lay the foundations for future growth in shareholder value. I intend to go into more detail about these investments shortly.</p>
<p>Before I do so, I want to explain to shareholders how the Board and senior management are addressing the issues that we confronted in 1996.  </p>
<p>We have not viewed these challenges as inevitable consequences of the business cycle and simply focused on reducing costs and awaiting better times.</p>
<p>We are carefully examining our existing businesses and investments to ensure they have the right asset mix to improve returns so that they will continue to deliver the value, quality and range of products which meet the needs of existing and potential customers.</p>
<p>At the same time, our investment strategy is forward-looking and aims to improve our competitive position.  </p>
<p>I will now explain in more detail the reasons behind the results and how the company is working to improve performance in future. There is much to be positive about.</p>
<p>Strong demand for many of our products is reflected in the 7.4 percent increase in sales and other revenues.</p>
<p>Many plants achieved record production. New projects which came on stream during the year, such as the Steel Group's Number 6 blast furnace at Port Kembla, and the Petroleum Group's Liverpool Bay project, boost efficiency or tap new resources.  </p>
<p>Dividends for 1996 were 51 cents per share, up one cent from last year and an effective 6.7 percent increase when the May 1995 bonus issue is taken into account. These dividends were fully franked, and I might add that any dividends paid in the next 12 months will be fully franked.</p>
<p>This is the case for the half-yearly dividend of 25 cents per share announced by the Directors last week.</p>
<p>However, to return to an examination of BFIP's performance in the 1996 period. As I have said, we faced many challenges.  </p>
<p>The Steel Group felt the impact of sluggish growth in key sectors of the Australian economy, such as housing, where we typically sell many high value-added products, At the same time, costs of raw materials, labour and maintenance rose, while export prices fell sharply.  </p>
<p>In Petroleum, although we achieved higher prices for our products, this was offset by a combination of factors. Among them was lower oil and LPG production, due to natural field decline and unplanned maintenance. The Hawaii refinery also had lower volumes. Results from both groups reflect the impact of the rise in the Australian corporate tax rate and the increase in value of the Australian dollar compared to the US dollar.</p>
<p>The results for Minerals for 1996 include the results for our copper businesses, although these now are part of the Copper Group. The Minerals Group result was achieved despite lower copper prices, and with strong customer demand evident for iron  </p>
<p>ore, coal, manganese andcopper. Prices for coal and iron ore also improved.</p>
<p>The Service Companies Group performed quite well in 1996, particularly the major businesses of Transport, Engineering and Information Technology. The Foster's investment also paid a higher dividend. Beyond that, of course, the group provided value-adding services, to the benefit of the Company as a whole.</p>
<p>Recognising this capacity to add value, it has been determined that the Service Companies Group should drive the search for new markets for our energy products, via participation in the power business.  </p>
<p>STRENGTHENING PERFORMANCE</p>
<p>While the Company is strongly committed to growth, the Board and management all recognise that if we are to deliver on this objective and, by doing so, increase wealth for shareholders, we have to address present performance - because this is what enables us to fund future growth.</p>
<p>Across the board, this is what we are doing. No text received  </p>
<p>We are focusing on improving our returns overall and especially in those businesses where performance was lower. We are continuing to scrutinise our costs and we are looking at ways to minimise our capital investment requirements for the tasks we wish to carry out. We are also moving to reduce our debt from the levels reached after our recent acquisitions.</p>
<p>In Steel, we have initiated a review to focus on ensuring that we have the right mix of facilities to produce the fight products for the markets we want to be in. We are committed to the Steel business, but we want to use technology to simplify and improve the efficiency of our plants. By doing this we aim  </p>
<p>to ensure that we can be a low-cost producer of products that meet the demands of the markets of Asia, the United States and Australia in particular. In 1996 we took the decision to write-off the primary end steelmaking facilities at Newcastle because of deteriorating cash flow projections from these assets. We will continue to look carefully at the options for all our facilities.</p>
<p>In Petroleum, we have refocused the business on core assets and activities - Bass Strait and northern Australia, the United Kingdom and the Gulf of Mexico - and the organisation has been restructured to reflect this focus. In line with this approach,  </p>
<p>the 151 million dollar investment in the Dai Hung oilfield in Vietnam was written off because, on present estimated reserves, it cannot achieve adequate cashflows. We have judged that the expense required to further appraise the field's reserves cannot be justified under the terms of the present contact.</p>
<p>	 INVESTING FOR THE FUTURE</p>
<p>The second part of the Company's strategy to deliver wealth to shareholders is to invest for the future - to grow and to improve our competitive position. BHP is very careful to assess all available opportunities to ensure it develops the right  </p>
<p>projects. It is in this context that the major acquisitions during 1996 should be viewed.</p>
<p>The Tubemakers business strengthens our position in the Australian and regional steel markets and of course, gives us a new product mix. We had an excellent existing relationship with Tubemakers and the acquisition enables us to reduce costs and to take advantage of the synergies that exist between our two organisations. The acquisition of the Magma Copper Company is strategically important to BHP because it has given us more options for  </p>
<p>marketing our copper products. The BHP Copper Group, which came into existence on the first of June, is not only a major copper producer, but involves us in every aspect of the business from mining, to smelting, refining and the production of finished metal products. We have thus, greatly increased our participation in the industry, with more customers and more products, and we now have access to the largest smelter in the important United States market for the output of Escondida and Tintaya.  </p>
<p>BHP has also acquired more skills - both management and technical - which will benefit our other copper operations. With the former Magma operations integrated -into our copper business we will have the opportunity to work more closely with customers to develop new products.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Magma operations will have the benefit of BHP's own well-honed skills in low-cost mining and we will continue to monitor their performance against cost and productivity criteria.  </p>
<p>Copper usage is growing, not only in developing countries, but in developed ones as well and under these circumstances BHP believes there are profitable opportunities in the copper business, despite recent fluctuations in the price.</p>
<p>The same strategic approach is driving our other new investments and projects. We are seeking to find, by exploration or acquisition, opportunities to build on our existing products in minerals and metals, Consistent with that, we are forging ahead with the diamond project in Canada, and developing the Hartley project in Zimbabwe to produce platinum, palladium and rhodium, nickel, cobalt and copper.  </p>
<p>The Cannington project in Australia positions BHP as a very competitive supplier of silver, lead and zinc materials which are in growing demand.</p>
<p>In this way we are adding to our range of mineral products while remaining committed to meeting the needs of our valued long-term customers for steelmaking raw materials. With this strategy of diversifying we are spreading our risks and enhancing our ability to withstand the pressures of commodity price cycles.  </p>
<p>In Steel, we have secured markets for our products in north America and many parts of Asia. Investments, such as the steel mill in Ohio and steel processing plants in Malaysia, Thailand and Washington State in America, enable the Company to grow the business and increase our ability to compete in these markets.</p>
<p>In Petroleum, I have mentioned the Liverpool Bay project which has opened new markets for us in the United Kingdom. We are further developing our existing Australian business with two new platforms to be installed in Bass Strait next calendar year and promising discoveries in the Timor Sea.  </p>
<p>Expansion of the North West Shelf project is being pursued to supply growing demand for energy, primarily from Japan.</p>
<p>The other area of our investment is in technology projects which aim to further our competitive edge.</p>
<p>BHP has highly developed skills in research and technology and we are in the process of utilising them to advance the Company.</p>
<p>To take one example, we have developed a new steel painting process which holds the promise of improved productivity and shorter lead times and we see great promise for this technology. Our thin strip caster project is also making encouraging  </p>
<p>progress.</p>
<p>In Copper, we are testing two new processes, one of which would enable the production of high-value copper from low-grade deposits.</p>
<p>The other process would enable us to recover the mineral with minimal disturbance to the landscape.</p>
<p>The focus on innovation is part of our strategy to create wealth and this is where there is potential for quite dramatic opportunities for the Company.  </p>
<p>Over its long history, BHP has successfully re-defined itself, by taking advantage of technological skills to better fit its businesses to changing world markets.</p>
<p>This process is continuing as we move towards the 21st century.</p>
<p>COMMITMENT TO STAKEHOLDERS</p>
<p>We are also addressing other important issues.  </p>
<p>Safety is an area which will always require our best efforts. We are achieving considerable improvement in safety performance. Many areas of the Company are achieving excellent results but in other cases, we need further improvement.</p>
<p>Across the company, we have put in place initiatives aimed at meeting our safety goals.</p>
<p>Another key issue is the environment. We aim to be a leading environmental performer in all our businesses and I reconfirm this as our objective.  </p>
<p>At BHP, environmental considerations are a significant component of all our projects - from concept through to development.</p>
<p>Not only that, but our environmental plans for virtually all projects, both here in Australia and overseas, are subject to quite intense scrutiny by regulatory authorities and discussion with communities.</p>
<p>An example is the diamond project -in the North West Territories of Canada, which was the subject of a lengthy assessment of our environmental credentials.  </p>
<p>This assessment included extensive participation from the local community. We have been undertaking a similarly extensive community consultation in regard to our proposed gas pipeline from Longford to Sydney.</p>
<p>Let me say that BHP welcomes clear processes for environmental assessment because they assist in addressing potential issues before they become major costs to the business. They also give all interested parties a chance to have an input to a proposed development.  </p>
<p>Good environmental practice is also good business practice and this can be seen from our approach to the issue of global warming.</p>
<p>We have in place action plans which should see our emissions of greenhouse gases per unit of production fall significantly to the year 2000.</p>
<p>Importantly, these initiatives focus on using energy more efficiently and thereby provide considerable savings.</p>
<p>Another matter that has been addressed is in relation to OK Tedi Mining Limited. Litigation over the Ok Tedi mine in Papua New Guinea was ended during the year.  </p>
<p>An agreement signed with the people of the OK Tedi and Fly Rivers paves the way for resolution of the issues and provides for independent assessment of options for disposal of tailings from the mine and further compensation for landowners and villagers.</p>
<p>The Board and management are anxious to see rapid progress in these matters.</p>
<p>FIRST QUARTER RESULTS</p>
<p>Finally, I want to turn to the results for the first quarter of the 1997 year.  </p>
<p>The operating profit of A$287 million was a decrease on the first quarter results for the previous year.</p>
<p>However we are seeing steady improvement on the results for the two preceding quarters - that is the periods ending on the 29th of February and the 31st of May.</p>
<p>In Steel, there are some signs of improvement in demand for structural, reinforcing and flat products, while in Petroleum a higher average oil price, improved margins from the Hawaii operation and an asset sale contributed to the result.</p>
<p>In our Copper business, results reflected lower prices and disappointing outcomes from the north American operations.  </p>
<p>The results of the Minerals Group were affected by provision of a loss from the sale of the Mali gold assets.</p>
<p>CONCLUSION</p>
<p>That concludes my report to you.</p>
<p>As you have seen, we have faced a challenging year and our most recent results, while more encouraging, demonstrate that those challenges continue. The Board and senior management - and indeed, the whole Company - are working to address the issues we face.  </p>
<p>The Board believes the Company has set in train the appropriate actions to improve performance and clearly, we continue to monitor our achievements on this score.</p>
<p>BHP's objective remains that of generating wealth for shareholders.</p>
<p>Our focus for the coming period is to achieve that by improving the performance of our existing assets, by continuing to develop a suite of projects to grow the business and by prudent investment to secure longer-term success.</p>
<p>BHP faces the future with confidence.&quot; -- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
