<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740115" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sallie Mae and opponents court shareholders.</title>
<headline>Sallie Mae and opponents court shareholders.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The management of Student Loan Marketing Association (Sallie Mae) and an opposition group called the Committee to Restore Value (CRV) are busy courting big institutional shareholders and Wall Street analysts two weeks before a crucial shareholder vote.</p>
<p>On July 31, shareholders will vote on a plan to reorganize Sallie Mae as a &quot;private&quot; company and end its life as a government-sponsored enterprise.</p>
<p>Both the management's and the CRV's proxy card call for a yes or no vote on privatization. But shareholders must also choose between rival slates of directors and business plans that are starkly different.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe the company has lost its continuity, its momentum, it's in disarray,&quot; Edward Fox, CRV nominee for director, told a group of institutional investors Thursday. Fox, who was president and chief executive of Sallie Mae from its inception in 1973 until he retired in 1990, would become non-executive chairman should the CRV slate win.</p>
<p>Albert Lord, who would be chief executive and a director should the CRV win, responded to the management's arguments that the CRV plan to &quot;originate&quot; student loans, making them directly to the borrowers, would alienate hundreds of banks who do business with Sallie Mae. &quot;It's an extraordinarily over-rated risk, it's also a manageable risk,&quot; Lord said.</p>
<p>The way the business has been run, the banks make the loans and Sallie Mae buys the loans from the banks, keeping some in its own portfolio and selling others in the marketplace.</p>
<p>Sallie Mae also provides an array of services such as application processing and electronic funds transfer.</p>
<p>In an interview earlier Thursday, Sallie Mae president and chief executive Lawrence Hough said the CRV has backtracked on its plans to originate loans and is now talking about &quot;targeted&quot; originations.. &quot;Their position has changed dramatically,&quot; he said. But he said the CRV is still making the same forecasts of 20 percent earnings growths which he believes are based on &quot;phony assumptions.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the management plan can deliver compounded annual earnings growth of 15 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;When you originate in our business there is a risk of cannibalization,&quot; Hough said, turning to what he argues is a major flaw in the CRV plan. He said the banks will argue that Sallie Mae wants to buy loans on the one hand and on the other compete against the banks in making the loans.</p>
<p>In its second-quarter earnings release last week Sallie Mae said banks during the period had postponed $1.1 billion in future commitments because of concern that Sallie Mae would be a competitor.</p>
<p>In an interview at the CRV presentation, Paul Carey, who would be chief financial officer, said there has been no change in the groups plans for originations. &quot;We havn't changed our plans one bit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our plan for over two years has been focus on controlling the costs of acquisition (of buying loans) and originations is an important tool in controlling that cost,&quot; Carey said.</p>
<p>Lydia Marshall, executive vice president for marketing of Sallie Mae, took part in the interview with Hough and said the CRV's plan to reduce the cost of buying loans is &quot;ill-conceived and a value destructor.&quot;</p>
<p>Marshall also said the CRV's plan to get involved in third-party servicing for other lenders &quot;is an idea that does not have traction.&quot; She said she saw no merit in letting banks have access to all of Sallie Mae's &quot;differentiated servicing&quot; without a requirement that the banks sell loans to Sallie Mae.</p>
<p>Marshall said Sallie Mae's efforts to date have won it more than a 40 percent share of the private lending segment of the student loan market.</p>
<p>Hough, who said the Sallie Mae focus should be on the school as its most important customer, explained his recent decision to step aside even if the management slate his elected.</p>
<p>He said after both the CRV and management failed to win sufficient backing in separate shareholder votes earlier this year, he consulted with big institutional investors including Fidelity Investments and decided it was time for a change. He said an executive search firm has been hired to find a new candidate.</p>
<p>((--Cal Mankowski/New York Newsdesk/212 859 1732))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
