<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74018" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Canberra names preferred bidder for airport.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Canberra names preferred bidder for airport.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia on Tuesday selected Foxerco Pty Ltd as preferred bidder for government-owned Avalon airport, about 50 km southwest of Melbourne.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Ian McLachlan also announced the closure of government's Avalon-based aircraft maintenance service, ASTAAS Pty Ltd.  </p>
<p>The government will now begin sales negotiations with Foxerco, a joint venture between transport and distribution company Linfox Transport (Australia) Pty Ltd and aviation concern Serco Aviation Services Pty Ltd, Finance Minister John Fahey said in a joint statement with McLachlan.</p>
<p>Avalon airport is home to a range of domestic and international pilot training programmes and several defence industries and is the venue for biennial international airshows.  </p>
<p>McLachlan said the decision to close the loss-making ASTAAS, a subsidiary of the government's Aerospace Technologies of Australia (ASTA), was taken after Canberra failed to find a buyer for the company.</p>
<p>Fahey said that despite several approaches to the private sector, the government had been unable to find any interest.</p>
<p>&quot;The depressed condition of the heavy aircraft maintenance market, particularly for non-airline aligned companies such as ASTAAS, was the major factor contributing to lack of buyer interest,&quot; Fahey said.  </p>
<p>ASTAAS had accumulated losses of A$32 million to October, 1995, and had received A$15 million in support from the government since July, 1995, he said.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
