<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740312" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Exchange controls seen hampering trade in Africa.</title>
<headline>Exchange controls seen hampering trade in Africa.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Vellien</byline>
<dateline>GRAND BAIE, Mauritius 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Exchange controls remain a major hindrance to intra-African trade and hamper the development of capital markets here, experts said.</p>
<p>They also urged governments to improve the financial infrastructure to help the continent's economies grow.</p>
<p>African and other experts at a forum on the development of African capital markets in the Indian Ocean island of Mauritius said exchange controls were the main barrier to growth and were the reason for continued capital flight from Africa.</p>
<p>Organisation of African Unity (OAU) Assistant Secretary General Vijay Makhan told reporters on Thursday that Africans must continue the path of macroeconomic reforms and also aim at deepening the integration of financial markets.</p>
<p>The OAU-organised three-day forum ended on Thursday.</p>
<p>Delegates recommended that central banks and capital market regulators keep up their supervision of financial institutions and markets to maintain integrity, professionalism and confidence.</p>
<p>Some 114 senior executives drawn from stock exchanges and regulatory authorities, central banks, lending institutions and finance ministries from 50 African countries attended.</p>
<p>World Bank official Elena Folkerts-Landau told Reuters that Africa must adopt a regional approach to its financial sector infrastructure to be more cost-efficient and effective.</p>
<p>Folkerts-Landau said each country must build and develop its financial market infrastructure -- laws, practices, standards and systems -- in a way that permits cross-border harmonisation.</p>
<p>&quot;When a country can integrate its financial market infrastructure with that of another country in the region, it will then have infrastructure which will support the regional financial market,&quot; Folkerts-Landau added.</p>
<p>She cited the Southern Africa Development Community where most trade sector infrastructure is being harmonized.</p>
<p>World Bank experts said African countries must in the long run attract capital to provide financial support to their own businesses in order to remain internationally competitive.</p>
<p>OAU Secretary-General Salim Ahmed Salim spoke of security and stability in Africa, saying financial progress was not possible in a turbulent environment.</p>
<p>Salim called for economic and social integration, and political stability and security through democratization, good governance and respect of human rights.</p>
<p>One banker said African financial markets were narrow and were dominated by commercial banks which in most countries accounted for the bulk of the consolidated assets of the financial system. He called for greater diversification.</p>
<p>--Port Louis ++230 211-9555</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GRAND BAIE, Mauritius"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
