<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740313" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU to resist pressure and ban Boeing merger.</title>
<headline>EU to resist pressure and ban Boeing merger.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS, Belgium</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite growing pressure from the United States, the European Union maintained a united front Friday over its determination to ban Boeing Co.'s planned $14 billion acquisition of McDonnell Douglas Corp.</p>
<p>The senior aides of the 20 commissioners that make up the EU executive were expected to endorse later Friday a decision to prohibit the deal on the grounds that it would harm fair competition in Europe, sources close to the negotiation said.</p>
<p>They said Boeing had not made any new proposals since Tuesday to try to head off a ban by assuaging Commission concerns about such things as Boeing's market share and the impact of its exclusive sales agreements with major airlines.</p>
<p>Senior Commission officials dealing with competition matters, meeting Thursday evening, unanimously backed the proposal by the executive's merger task force to block the deal.</p>
<p>A final decision is expected to be made by the commissioners at their regular meeting next Wednesday.</p>
<p>Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert, who has ferociously opposed the merger from the start, needs only a simple majority in the Commission for the decision to be approved.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission and the EU states are unanimous in considering that the operation cannot be allowed as it currently stands,&quot; one senior commission aide told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>A last-minute agreement was still possible, although unlikely, the sources said.</p>
<p>They said American lobbying was intensifying in the EU's larger states, particularly Britain, whose &quot;special relationship&quot; with the United States has been given fresh impetus following Tony Blair's election as Prime Minister.</p>
<p>&quot;Britain is under very strong pressure and so are France, Italy and Germany,&quot; an EU diplomat said.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton raised the possibility Thursday that the United States may go to the World Trade Organisaton or impose sanctions on Europe if it blocks the merger, but said a trade war could probably be avoided.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Britain's Department of Trade and Industry said the department did not have a position on the merger, adding it was a matter for the European Commission.</p>
<p>Other European nations were not as reticent.</p>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac has called the deal &quot;extremely dangerous&quot; for Europe and expressed concern that some of his partners in the 15-nation bloc would not resist the pressure coming from Washington.</p>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl weighed in Friday, urging European aerospace firms to consolidate in response to the competitive threat from the planned merger.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that Europe must give a very clear answer to the American challenge in the aerospace sector by founding its own large concern,&quot; Kohl told a news conference.</p>
<p>Aerospatiale of France, which is state-controlled, Daimler-Benz Aerospace and British Aerospace BAe are the main partners in the Airbus Industrie consortium, Boeing's only serious rival.</p>
<p>The consolidation of the European aerospace industry depends mainly in changing Airbus into a limited company.</p>
<p>Contrasting with the more measured tone of the British government, British Aerospace and its European partners have accused U.S. commercial aircraft industry of enjoying cross-subsidies from U.S. military contracts -- one of the sticking points in the negotiations between the EU and Boeing in the merger with McDonnell Douglas.</p>
<p>Boeing has offered to report regularly to the EU on any cross-subsidies from McDonnell-Douglas' military business to its own civilian operations, but German Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt said this was not enough.</p>
<p>The other Commission's competition concerns that remain unsolved regard Boeing's exclusive supply contracts with AMR Corp.'s American Airlines, Continental Airlines and Delta Air Lines and the perceived danger that Boeing will automatically replace McDonnell commercial aircraft, which accounts for 25 percent in fleets worldwide.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
