<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740330" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan top five carmakers' exports jumped in June.</title>
<headline>Japan top five carmakers' exports jumped in June.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's five major carmakers expanded vehicle exports in June, helped by the weak yen and new models, according to figures released Friday.</p>
<p>But industry analysts said that the rise was temporary and that automakers would be careful not to create new trade problems with the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure trade friction with the United States will not revive. I don't think the current growth rate will continue (on their exports),&quot; Koji Endo, a senior vice president of Lehman Brothers Japan Inc, said.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Japanese carmakers) will curb their exports later this year because they know that sharp gains in exports will reignite trade friction.&quot;</p>
<p>Toyota Motor Corp., Japan's top carmaker, said its exports rose 22.2 percent in June from a year earlier to 140,128, bringing its 1997 first half exports to 703,458, up 12.4 percent.</p>
<p>Toyota's June exports to the United States, however, fell 0.3 percent from a year earlier to 40,791 units.</p>
<p>Honda Motor Co. Ltd, the third-biggest carmaker, said its car exports jumped a steep 51.1 percent to 47,039, bringing its January-June total to 261,175, up 50.3 percent.</p>
<p>Of the total, its exports to the United States jumped by 128.2 percent to 25,769 in June, due to strong demand for the Civic compact and the CR-V light sport-utility vehicle.</p>
<p>&quot;Our exports are at the level as planned -- 240,000 in 1997 (up from 151,633 in 1996) but will be little changed from the 1995 year level,&quot; a Honda spokesman said.</p>
<p>Mazda Motor Corp., 33.4 percent owned by Ford Motor Co., Nissan Motor Co. Ltd, and Mitsubishi Motors Corp. also reported gains in their June exports by 51.3 percent, 31.3 percent and 25.8 percent, respectively.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
