<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740327" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FOCUS-Russia restates EU membership ambitions.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Russia restates EU membership ambitions.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, just two days after the European Commission opened the historic process of enlarging to countries behind the former Iron Curtain, said on Friday Russia too was set on joining.</p>
<p>&quot;In the near future, I think that Russia should be in the EU with all the implications and consequences, not all of which will be easy for us,&quot; Chernomyrdin told a news conference in reply to a question after meeting European Commission President Jacques Santer.</p>
<p>Restating ambitions already voiced by President Boris Yeltsin, Chernomydrin said all Russia's ongoing relations and talks with the wealthy 15-nation bloc had one goal: &quot;to become equal partners in this continent.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Yes indeed...I think that our work here, our entire scope of work, all issues and problems that we are discussing, are directed to one objective, that at a certain point Russia will become a member of the EU,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said that membership took precedence over any ambitions to seek compensation from the EU for a future EU enlargement to some of Moscow's main trading parters.</p>
<p>&quot;Compensation is not a top priority for us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This week the European Commission recommended to EU governments that the Union open membership talks with five out of 10 eastern European applicants -- Poland, the Czech Republic, Hungary, Slovenia and Estonia.</p>
<p>European Commission President Jacques Santer, whose executive said another five eastern countries, including some of Russia's neighbours, were not yet ready to start membership talks, did not directly comment on the Russian ambition.</p>
<p>But asked whether Russia was deemed to have achieved a market economy -- one of the main conditions for joining the EU -- he said he had &quot;every confidence that the reforms already started by the Russian authorities will bear fruit&quot;.</p>
<p>He said Russia's economic progress would be improved further by its planned accession to the World Trade Organisation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
