<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740438" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: OPINION-Jim Middleton's Canberra Closeup-Beating around the bush.</title>
<headline>OPINION-Jim Middleton's Canberra Closeup-Beating around the bush.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Jim Middleton (ABC TV political correspondent)</p>
<p>Can John Howard get there from here?</p>
<p>The line from the old Irish joke sprung to mind as the prime minister belted around the backblocks north of Newcastle this week at the start of his &quot;winter&quot; offensive -- his decision to visit no fewer than 18 marginal coalition electorates in six weeks.</p>
<p>Trips like this are like oxygen to Howard.</p>
<p>His staff may wilt under the pressure of working on the run; television journalists may grumble about the lack of good pictures; but this prime minister was made for micro-campaigning.</p>
<p>Awkward in many public contexts, Howard never looks more at home than on an electorate visit. It's almost like Bob Hawke in a shopping centre (pre-Silly Old Bugger, that is).</p>
<p>In the marginal Liberal seat of Paterson this week (margin 0.8 percent, majority less than 1,000) the prime minister was in his element.</p>
<p>He may have called a small business venture he was opening &quot;All Assets&quot; no fewer than five times when it was actually &quot;All Access&quot;; he may have been invited by a nursing home resident to sign up for entry; he may have dropped a shovel during a sod-turning ceremony. But Howard never looked anything less than relaxed and comfortable during his two days in the Hunter district.</p>
<p>It was a far cry from his recent overseas trip where he never looked at ease during his 17 days abroad.</p>
<p>The prime minister went about his work with genuine enthusiasm.</p>
<p>Fears of brutal anger on the part of Novocastrians about BHP's decision to shut down steel-making evaporated as self-confessed Labor voting shop floor delegates dismissed suggestions that it was all a case of too little, too late.</p>
<p>Howard seized the mood like a drowning man lunging for a life buoy. There was life in the Hunter Valley beyond BHP, beyong steel-making, he declared.</p>
<p>The region had taken knocks, but it was now looking to the future -- a future which, with care, could well be sunny.</p>
<p>The prime minister went to Newcastle with a grab-bag of goodies -- about A$30 million in all -- and the beginnings of an industry policy. &quot;At long last&quot;, was the muttered comment of some coalition figures.</p>
<p>Relief, too, from industry groups which have been openly critical of the government's lack of coherent action on the industry policy front.</p>
<p>This week's two day meeting of cabinet decided on a very big shift in assistance to industry.</p>
<p>Despite Treasury's reservations, cabinet endorses in principle an Asia-style approach.</p>
<p>Free trade zones with exemptions on import duty and sales tax are flavour of the month.</p>
<p>An inter-departmental committee is working through the implications. The prime minister obviously is an enthusiast.</p>
<p>The man who once decribed himself as the &quot;most conservative&quot; leader of the Liberal Party is now declaring that he's not &quot;governed&quot; exclusively by any particular economic dogma.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a question of producing outcomes which maximise benefits for the Australian people,&quot; he told his Newcastle press conference on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Industry welfare&quot; was Peter Costello's not so private dismissal of calls for industry assistance during the run-up to his first budget in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;I've heard that sloganeering,&quot; was the way Industry Minister John Moore hit back at the Costello slur on radio this week.</p>
<p>The industry minister is obviously feeling his oats; the treasurer was not even present at this week's cabinet meeting which authorised the sea change in industry policy.</p>
<p>Just how the new approach is translated into practical policy will be interesting to observe.</p>
<p>One prime ministerial adviser visibly shuddered when asked whether the initials &quot;MFP&quot; -- multi-function polis -- sprung to mind as all the talk of free trade zones sprung to life.</p>
<p>The danger is that approaches like this can rapidly develop a life of their own.</p>
<p>The imperative is for the government to get the framework out into the public arena as quickly as possible so it can contain expectations and produce practical benefits for export industries.</p>
<p>The mere mention of &quot;zones&quot; will have local councils and all state governments dusting off bottom drawer dreams to deal with &quot;that bit of wasteland&quot; in one marginal electorate after another.</p>
<p>A more sensible approach is for the prime minister to start talking about a &quot;regime&quot; rather than &quot;zones&quot;. It is about policy rather than real estate, after all.</p>
<p>The big remaining question is how Howard will find time over the next few weeks to get across the detail of his government's industry re-think.</p>
<p>Visits to three electorates a week over a month and a half don't leave much time for &quot;real&quot; work.</p>
<p>It may leave the prime minister with a warm inner glow, it will please the local member, but it will require a very slick operation indeed to keep the machinery of government ticking over and the potential for slip-ups is substantial.</p>
<p>Howard will be working to make sure his winter campaign doesn't turn into a retreat from Moscow.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Reuters Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
