<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740451" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Bougainville war parties agree PNG peace tactic.</title>
<headline>Bougainville war parties agree PNG peace tactic.</headline>
<dateline>CHRISTCHURCH, New Zealand 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The three main factions from a nine-year secessionist war on Papua New Guinea's Bougainville Island on Friday agreed to make a joint approach to the PNG government in future peace talks.</p>
<p>At the end of two weeks of talks hosted by New Zealand at Burnham army camp near the South Island city of Christchurch, participants signed what they called the Burnham Declaration in which they agreed to deal with PNG as a single group.</p>
<p>The document would have to be approved by the PNG government as well as some other rebels, the island leaders told reporters at a signing ceremony attended by New Zealand Foreign Minister Don McKinnon.</p>
<p>Only representatives of parties on the island have been taking part in the talks, which were intended to settle local issues as a precursor to negotiations with Port Moresby.</p>
<p>Joseph Kabui, representing the main rebel group, the Bougainville Revolutionary Army (BRA), and its political associate, the Bougainville Interim Government (BIG), called the agreement &quot;a significant move forward&quot;.</p>
<p>Asked if it would bring peace to the island he told reporters: &quot;This is an important start&quot;.</p>
<p>Kabui signed the accord for BRA and BIG while Gerard Sinato, Premier of the PNG-aligned Bougainville Transitional Government (BTG), signed for the other main party.</p>
<p>Thousands have died in the Bougainville conflict since landowners revolted in 1988 over damage caused by the huge Panguna copper mine, and the royalties they received from it.</p>
<p>The mine is owned by a unit of the Anglo-Australian giant Rio Tinto Ltd.</p>
<p>Discussions had stretched into the early hours of this morning, with the last area of disagreement centering on how to deal with five PNG prisoners of war, delegates told Reuters.</p>
<p>Although a full text of the declaration was not immediately available, its core was to commit the signatories to a future process for negotiation based on unity and reconciliation.</p>
<p>&quot;We will work together with the government of Papua New Guinea to set up a process of negotiation between leaders,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The document stopped short of including a ceasefire, but the signatories said they would aim to declare a ceasefire once the first contingent of a peacekeeping force arrived in the region.</p>
<p>Reaching that stage would depend on the agreement of the PNG government, however.</p>
<p>McKinnon told reporters that senior political figures in PNG had been informed of the progress of the talks.</p>
<p>New Zealand has not been party to the negotiations, but has supported them with logistics, bringing about 70 people to Christchurch from Bougainville and its offshore islands, the nearby Solomon Islands, and from Port Moresby.</p>
<p>Kabui said that key BRA leader Francis Ona, who did not attend the talks and has been blamed for the failure to implement previous peace proposals, had been kept in regular contact with developments.</p>
<p>While he had not yet seen the finished document, he would be made aware of its contents &quot;in due course&quot;, Kabui added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHRISTCHURCH, New Zealand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
