<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740456" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Canberra looks at visa rules amid Black Panther row.</title>
<headline>Canberra looks at visa rules amid Black Panther row.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Immigration Minister Philip Ruddock said on Friday he would seek an urgent review of Australia's immigration rules after a row over the entry of U.S. Black activist Lorenzo Ervin into the country.</p>
<p>&quot;The issues that need to be addressed in relation to effectively managing border arrangements are significant,&quot; said Ruddock, who returned early from a visit to Europe on Thursday to deal with the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;The government must have effective legislation and procedures for detecting and managing illegal arrivals and for handling visitors who may not be of good character and pose a threat to Australia,&quot; he said in a radio interview.</p>
<p>Ruddock's return home came as the government faced mounting criticism over its handling of a controversial case.</p>
<p>Ervin, a former member of the Black Panther movement, has been given until Monday to lodge official paperwork showing he is of good character, after Canberra last week reversed its original decision to cancel his visa.</p>
<p>Ervin forced a government backdown when he appealed against a decision by acting Immigration Minister Amanda Vanstone to declare he was not of good character and cancel his visa.</p>
<p>The government changed its mind, without giving reasons, before the court ruled on the appeal.</p>
<p>Ervin, convicted of hijacking a plane in the United States in 1969, was briefly held in a maximum security jail in Brisbane last week before the government reversal.</p>
<p>Ruddock would not comment on the details of Ervin's case.</p>
<p>The Labor opposition has urged a public inquiry into the visa system, warning government funding cuts had eroded Australia's ability to bar terrorists and criminals.</p>
<p>Ervin's Australian lawyer, Terry Fisher, said Ervin was granted clemency by the U.S. government after serving several years of his jail term over the hijacking.</p>
<p>Ervin arrived in Australia on July 4 for a four week speaking tour at the invitation of anarchist group Angry People.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
