<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740605" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Robert Bosch says to buy Zexel shares from Izusu.</title>
<headline>Robert Bosch says to buy Zexel shares from Izusu.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>German automaker Robert Bosch GmbH said on Friday that it would buy 40 million shares in Zexel Corp from Japanese automaker Isuzu Motors Ltd.</p>
<p>Isuzu Motors separately announced that it would sell a part of its Zexel share holdings for 28.8 billion yen, which it said would bring 17.7 billion yen worth of profits to the company.  </p>
<p>Isuzu said in a statement that the money to be earned from the sale of shares will be used to strengthen its production and sales base and to finance investment in diesel engine development for General Motors Corp.</p>
<p>Isuzu added that, since the decision was made quickly, it remains unclear how the share sale will affect its business and it has therefore not yet made any revisions to its earnings outlook.</p>
<p>As a result of the planned sale, Isuzu's stake in Zexel , a Japanese manufacturer of fuel injection pumps for diesel engines, will fall to 4.22 percent from the current 20.48 percent.</p>
<p>Robert Bosch, which makes and sells car equipment, would obtain a 16.26 percent stake in Zexel, replacing Isuzu as the biggest shareholder. The transfer of the Zexel shares will be implemented in the middle of August.  </p>
<p>Zexel and Robert Bosch said in a joint statement that they had asked Isuzu to transfer the shares as a means of strengthening their business links, in order to promote the expansion of their activities in the growing Asian car market.</p>
<p>Isuzu accepted the offer, believing that stronger ties between Zexel and Robert Bosch would help ensure a stable supply of competitive car parts, the statement said.</p>
<p>Zexel and Robert Bosch said they would continue to strengthen their cooperation in developing and producing fuel injection pumps for diesel engines.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
