<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740686" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Lead prices seen too low for China producers.</title>
<headline>Lead prices seen too low for China producers.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese lead producers are not impressed with the current price of the metal on the world market, with domestic prices hovering around $700 a tonne, trading sources said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The domestic FOB (free on board) price for lead is around $700 a tonne, so why would Chinese producers want to sell at the current world price,&quot; said a Chinese smelter source.</p>
<p>Lead on the London Metal Exchange (LME) bounced up $9 a tonne on Thursday to $641 after touching a high of $644 on short covering.</p>
<p>LME broking firm Brandeis said Far Eastern buying and short covering by small funds and brokers helped lead touch the high, but a lack of follow-up interest after that compounded broker profit-taking.</p>
<p>Good support was evident around $628-$630, Brandeis said in its daily market review, but needed to climb above $650 a tonne to spur further gains.</p>
<p>One of China's biggest lead producers, Zhuzhou smelter, said earlier this year it would cut lead output from 90,000 tonnes in 1996 to 70,000 tonnes this year in favour of zinc on falling prices for lead and rising prices for zinc.</p>
<p>A source at the smelter said then that $720 per tonne FOB China was a more favourable price for domestic producers.</p>
<p>A Western trader in Singapore said Chinese production costs were close to $700 a tonne, as most smelters carried tens of thousands of staff -- and the high overheads that went along with providing benefits for them and their families.</p>
<p>Official Chinese figures show China's lead production between January and May this year was down 1.5 per cent on the same period of 1996, to 227,300 tonnes.</p>
<p>Chinese lead has been indicated in recent weeks at a $20 a tonne discount basis Hong Kong C&amp;F (cost and freight).</p>
<p>Premiums C&amp;F Malaysia on Chinese lead were $80/90 over the LME cash price, an executive with a regional producer said.</p>
<p>Chinese exports were still going on under long-term contractual arrangements, he said.</p>
<p>But with the softening this year of prices -- from highs that neared $1,000 a tonne in 1996 -- Chinese lead exports could be expected to fall from last year's levels, he said.</p>
<p>China's 1996 net exports of refined lead metal were 250,000 tonnes, according to a report by SBC Warburg in Sydney.</p>
<p>The report put Chinese consumption of refined metal at 344,000 in 1996, rising to 370,000 tonnes this year. More than 60 percent of total consumption was in batteries, it said.</p>
<p>The SBC Warburg report said China's lead demand would pick up to five to six percent a year over the next five years.</p>
<p>China's total output of refined lead metal in 1996 was put at 650,000 tonnes, the report said, and should remain constant in 1997.</p>
<p>-- Lynne O'Donnell, Shanghai Newsroom (8621) 6279-8544</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
