<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740788" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: International labour group blasts HK move on laws.</title>
<headline>International labour group blasts HK move on laws.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>An international labour organisation blasted the new Hong Kong government on Friday for striking down key laws on workers' rights, calling them a &quot;slap in the face&quot; for the territory's workers.</p>
<p>&quot;That this action comes so soon after the handover is a cynical move on the part of the Hong Kong authorities, aimed at showing that independent trade unions will not be tolerated, and that, as in mainland China, any move to assert trade union rights will lead to harassment or even repression,&quot; the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions said in a statement.</p>
<p>Britain handed Hong Kong back to China on July 1, ending 156 years of colonial rule.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's China-appointed parliament passed a government bill late on Wednesday suspending a clutch of labour rights laws pending a review and fresh legislation.</p>
<p>The laws were enacted in the week before the British flag came down in the territory.</p>
<p>&quot;This makes a mockery of official assurances given by China to the International Labour Organisation that basic labour standards, in particular ILO Conventions 87 and 98, would remain valid in Hong Kong after the handover,&quot; the Belgium-based ICFTU said.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision... is a slap in the face for Hong Kong workers, who were the source of Hong Kong's economic miracle.&quot;</p>
<p>It added that the ICFTU, which has 124 million members in 195 affiliates in 137 countries, would step up its worldwide campaign agains the suspension of the laws.</p>
<p>Hong Kong unions have vowed to fight at home and abroad to restore the legislation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
