<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740814" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares stumble at outset of bourse dealings.</title>
<headline>German shares stumble at outset of bourse dealings.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares stumbled in early dealings on Friday, hurt by profit-taking ahead of the weekend and selling tied to the expiry later in the day of options on the DAX index.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index down 34.85 points at 4,192.46 points. The IBIS DAX, which reflects all-day computer dealings, was down 11.66 points at 4,192.25 points.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market looks a bit tired,&quot; said one Frankfurt dealer. &quot;We could fall rather quickly today like we did on Thursday for no apparent reason. The market needs to take a rest before moving higher.&quot;</p>
<p>Some traders looked for the DAX to find support at about 4,155 to 4,160 points on any pull-back, saying the losses would be constructive for the market to post further gains and reach new record levels.</p>
<p>Dealers linked some of the losses to the expiry of the DAX options amid signs of heavy open interest at 4,200 points.</p>
<p>&quot;We should hover around the 4,200-point level but the risk is obviously to the downside,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Overnight losses on Wall Street and losses in German debt markets, worried about the risk of a Bundesbank rate hike to curb the dollar's strength, also capped market interest.</p>
<p>The market showed little reaction to the June Ifo business climate index report for west Germany, which rose beyond market expectations in June to 96.0 from a revised 95.4 in May.</p>
<p>In east Germany, the climate reading eased back slightly with the index at 103.6 from an upward revised 103.7 in May.</p>
<p>Despite the general downward trend, banking stocks were in the focus after Commerzbank AG predicted many banks will report double-digit growth in first-half operating profit.</p>
<p>The report also said banking shares may also get a boost from speculation for mergers in the industry due to recent consolidation in the insurance sector.</p>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG, which will report results on July 23, rose 1.20 marks to 108.80 marks, a new bourse session high.</p>
<p>Bayerische Hypo was also a top gainer, rising 67 pfennigs to 58.45 marks, and Dresdner Bank AG was up 35 pfennigs at 74.35 marks.</p>
<p>But Commerzbank was down 15 pfennigs at 54.05 marks.</p>
<p>Retailer Karstadt AG, which had surged more than 100 marks this week on takeover speculation, slumped on Friday down 22.50 marks to 671.50 marks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
