<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740846" id="root" date="1997-07-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - Italy - July 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Italy - July 18.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>* Former star anti-graft magistarate Antonio Di Pietro defended his decision to run for Senate for the governing centre-left Olive Tree coalition. He said he would withdraw his candidacy if magistrates investigating his involvement in a corruption scandal ask for an indictment.</p>
<p>* Murdered fashion designer Gianni Versace's ashes were due to return to Italy on Friday after a cremation service in Miami Beach.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>* Foreign buying pushed Italian stocks to a record high again on Thursday with the historic Mib index finishing the day at 14.825 points and the Comit index at 922.68 points. (all)</p>
<p>* Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi said a fall in Italy's public deficit had pushed Italian stocks up. He also denied any Franco-German plot to exclude Italy from the first wave of entry to Europe's planned single currency in 1999. (La Repubblica/La Stampa)</p>
<p>* The Italian regions have spent only 30 billion lire of a 500-billion lire fund set aside for investment projects. (Sole 24 Ore)</p>
<p>** Reuters has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
