<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740932" id="root" date="1997-07-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-POOLEY, JURGENSEN SHARE LEAD AT DEPOSIT GUARANTY CLASSIC.</title>
<headline>GOLF-POOLEY, JURGENSEN SHARE LEAD AT DEPOSIT GUARANTY CLASSIC.</headline>
<dateline>MADISON, Mississippi 1997-07-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Don Pooley, a 22-year PGA Tour veteran, and Steve Jurgensen, who flunked out as a tour rookie last year, were tied for the lead Friday after 36 holes of the $1 million Deposit Guaranty Classic.</p>
<p>Pooley, 45, who has won more than $3 million on tour, shot a second-round 68 for a 36-hole total of 11-under-par 133. Jurgensen, 35, followed his first-round 66 with a 67.</p>
<p>Jurgensen lost his PGA Tour exemption last year when he finished 152nd on the money list. He is playing the Deposit Guaranty on a sponsor's exemption after finishing 10th in the tournament last year.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be great to win again, more for my kids,&quot; said Poole, whose last tour victory was at The Memorial in 1987. &quot;They were young last time I won, so it would be neat for them.&quot;</p>
<p>One shot back were David Ogrin (67-67) and Steve Lowery, whose second-round 65 was the day's low score at the Jack Nicklaus-designed Annandale Golf Club.</p>
<p>Scott Verplank, who won the 1985 Western Open as an amateur, was another stroke away at 135 (67-68), where he was joined by Woody Austin (66-69) and Billy Ray Brown (69-66).</p>
<p>Verplank, a former U.S. Amateur champion, is trying to play his way back into form after elbow problems, which led to three surgeries and threatened to end his career.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm getting there,&quot; Verplank, 33, said. &quot;I'm playing better. I've shot six straight rounds in the 60s on tour, so obviously I'm playing pretty well. I'm not completely over the hump, but it's getting better.&quot;</p>
<p>Three shots out of the lead at 136 were Bobby Wadkins, Mike Standly, Brian Claar, Brian Henninger, John Adams, Jack O'Keefe, Skip Kendall and Joey Sindelar.</p>
<p>First-round co-leaders Mike Brisky and Craig Kanada, who shot 64s Thursday, did not fare well Friday. Kanada shot 73 and Brisky soared to a 74.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADISON, Mississippi"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
