<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740984" id="root" date="1997-07-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain, Ireland welcome new IRA ceasefire.</title>
<headline>Britain, Ireland welcome new IRA ceasefire.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain and Ireland on Saturday welcomed the IRA's restoration of its 1994 ceasefire.</p>
<p>British Prime Minister Tony Blair spoke of a &quot;new mood of hope for peace and a lasting political settlement in Northern Ireland&quot;.</p>
<p>The IRA announcement was also warmly welcomed by Blair's Northern Ireland Secretary, Mo Mowlam, who flew immediately to Belfast, and by Irish Prime Minister Bertie Ahern.</p>
<p>Blair said the British government would assess the ceasefire with great care.</p>
<p>He said the entry of Sinn Fein, the Irish Republican Army's political wing, into all-party peace talks on Northern Ireland in September would depend on whether the ceasefire was &quot;genuine in word and deed&quot;.</p>
<p>Britain and Ireland, co-sponsors of Northern Ireland peace efforts, have said Sinn Fein cannot enter talks unless the IRA maintains a genuine ceasefire.</p>
<p>Blair said in a statement: &quot;I welcome today's announcement which is good for the people of Northern Ireland and for the people of Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the continuing loyalist ceasefire and the courageous Orange Order decisions of last week, this can build on a new mood of hope for peace and a lasting political settlement in Northern Ireland.&quot;</p>
<p>Pro-British Protestant &quot;Loyalist&quot; guerrillas insist that the ceasefire they called in October 1994 is still intact, although police have blamed them for a number of killings.</p>
<p>Tension in Northern Ireland was considerably reduced last weekend when the Protestant Orange Order decided not to route traditional July 12 marches through Roman Catholic nationalist areas where violence had been feared.</p>
<p>A major potential problem for the prime minister now is the reaction of many of Northern Ireland's pro-British Unionist community, who see the new IRA truce as a tactical manoeuvre.</p>
<p>Blair will hold talks on Monday with the leader of the Ulster Unionist Party, David Trimble, who believes that British and Irish plans to achieve IRA disarmament are too vague.</p>
<p>Trimble's party is threatening to oppose the plans at talks in Belfast next Wednesday.</p>
<p>In his statement, Blair made clear that Britain wanted to be satisfied that the new IRA truce was genuine before Sinn Fein could be allowed to take its place at the peace talks.</p>
<p>Blair said: &quot;Obviously we will want to assess the ceasefire with great care. What we and others want to see is an end to violence for good and an irrevocable commitment to peaceful means.</p>
<p>&quot;Meanwhile, we remain determined to get the substantive political talks under way in September, as we have said.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether Sinn Fein will be there depends on whether the ceasefire is genuine in word and deed, as we have always said.&quot;</p>
<p>Mowlam added: &quot;I welcome the ceasefire. I am delighted.</p>
<p>&quot;It is good news for the people of Northern Ireland. I look forward to a continuation of the words and deeds in the days and weeks ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>Ahern said in his statement: &quot;I warmly welcome the IRA announcement and I would like to thank all those involved in bringing it about.&quot;</p>
<p>Ahern said he now wanted inclusive and substantive all-party talks in September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
