<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="740929" id="root" date="1997-07-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: OLYMPICS-NAGANO SAYS WORKING ON IMAGE PROBLEM.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-NAGANO SAYS WORKING ON IMAGE PROBLEM.</headline>
<byline>Scott McDonald</byline>
<dateline>NAGANO, Japan 1997-07-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nagano is unlikely to be accused of the tawdry commercial excesses which marked last year's Summer Olympics in Atlanta.</p>
<p>In fact, organisers of next February's Winter Olympics go into Tuesday's 200 day countdown to the Games hustling to shed an image of massive indifference.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working hard to change our image,&quot; said Ko Yamaguchi, the media head for the Games. &quot;I think it's wrong already.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the criticism levelled at the Nagano organisers earlier this year for not doing enough to promote the Games was no longer valid.</p>
<p>Nagano was blasted by International Olympic Committee president Juan Antonio Samaranch and even Japan's own Olympic chief for poor organisation.</p>
<p>A high-profile fight with the International Ski Federation over the starting height of the men's downhill has also bruised Nagano's image.</p>
<p>Organisers have repeatedly rejected federation requests to raise the height of start, saying that would put it into a national park.</p>
<p>The lack of publicity so far means there is not much Olympic spirit seen on the streets of Nagano yet, and none in larger cities such as Tokyo.</p>
<p>Fumiya Nonaka, a Tokyo businessman on a recent business trip to Nagano, said he was surprised by the lack of advertisements for the Games.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't seen many ads yet (in Nagano), and I haven't seen any in Tokyo,&quot; he said. &quot;There will probably be more later.&quot;</p>
<p>Yamaguchi also said momentum for the games will start to pick up in the autumn.</p>
<p>&quot;After the summer things will change,&quot; he said. &quot;I'm not worried, once it starts snowing, Nagano will prevail.&quot;</p>
<p>One of the bigger potential problems organisers face, especially after the fiasco in Atlanta with lost and late buses, is transport.</p>
<p>One-third of the 68 events at the Games are based in or near the resort of Hakuba, 50 km (30 miles) west of Nagano on a windy highway.</p>
<p>The trip took more than 2-1/2 hours during a pre-Olympic ski jumping event earlier this year.</p>
<p>Yamaguchi said organisers will seek the cooperation of the public and companies to try to cut the general traffic by about 30 percent during the Games.</p>
<p>Yamaguchi also said all of the competition facilities will be ready before the end of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that there is anything behind schedule, almost all of the construction is finished, and we are just adjusting some facilities now at the request of the IOC.&quot;</p>
<p>The budget has ballooned from the original 76 billion yen ($658.3 million) set when Nagano was awarded the Games in 1991 to 103 billion yen now, but Yamaguchi does not expect any further changes.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no plans now to increase or decrease the budget,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The budget does not include the cost of the competition facilities, which were paid for by local municipalities, or a new high-speed train which will cut the current three-hour travel time to Tokyo in half when it starts running in October.</p>
<p>Yamaguchi said interest in the Games was also picking up on the Internet, with Nagano's homepage (www.nagano.olympic.org/) averaging about 42,000 hits a day, 60 percent from outside the country.</p>
<p>Yamaguchi also said ticket sales have been going well and for the more popular events were available only through packages offered by travel agents.</p>
<p>&quot;We've sold out of the (men's) hockey final, the opening and closing ceremonies and the figure skating finals,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>After Cambodia pulled out last week in the aftermath of a political coup, 82 countries now are expected to send about 3,000 athletes and officials to participate in seven sports over the 16-day event. ($1 = 115.4 Japanese Yen) REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAGANO, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
