<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741023" id="root" date="1997-07-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Liberians vote massively against rule by the gun.</title>
<headline>Liberians vote massively against rule by the gun.</headline>
<byline>John Chiahemen</byline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1997-07-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Voters jammed polling stations in Liberia on Saturday in what political leaders described as an overwhelming rejection of rule by the gun.</p>
<p>Long lines snaked from polling centres as early as 4.00 A.M. (0400 GMT) as Liberians scrambled to cast votes for the war-scarred nation's first democratic elections for 12 years.</p>
<p>The presidential and parliamentary polls were designed by Liberia's regional peace brokers to wrap up an accord ending seven years of civil war that has devastated the country.</p>
<p>Nearly every family in Liberia has been touched by the war which killed more than 150,000 and displaced half the pre-war population of 2.5 million. Fear of a return to violence by losing candidates remains a source of concern.</p>
<p>However, the top two rated candidates in a field of 12 presidential contenders -- former warlord Charles Taylor and ex-minister and United Nations official Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf -- said voter enthusiasm showed Liberians were against war.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no violence now and there will be no violence after (the elections),&quot; Taylor told reporters after voting in his Congo Town stronghold district of the capital.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Liberian people are saying to the world that we are ready for democracy ... and that we must put violence behind us and look at the new millennium,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The supremely confident Taylor said he would work with any other winner but quickly ruled out any thought of losing.</p>
<p>His followers say, as leader of the largest militia before disarmament, a Taylor presidency would be the best guarantee of peace in Liberia.</p>
<p>&quot;He killed my father but I'll vote him. He started all this and he's going to fix it,&quot; said one at a polling station.</p>
<p>However, many local analysts say Taylor could face a coalition of rival warlords -- two of them are running for president -- if Johnson-Sirleaf, 58, forces a runoff ballot.</p>
<p>The charismatic Taylor, 49, looked relaxed as he arrived amid heavy security and was greeted by a party of West African foreign ministers observing the poll.</p>
<p>Johnson-Sirleaf voted at a polling centre inside a building used by African peacekeepers to disarm guerrillas last year.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel great. I think the Liberian people are ready for change, ready for a woman (president),&quot; she told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The campaign period was clear indication of the readiness to go on from war to peace,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Liberians were voting almost on the eve of the 150th birthday on July 26 of their country, founded by freed American slaves in 1847 as Africa's first modern republic.</p>
<p>Voters were also electing 26 senators and 64 lower house deputies in the poll based on proportional representation.</p>
<p>Taylor started civil war in 1989 and came close to taking the capital in 1990 and 1992 but was blocked on each occasion by troops of the Nigerian-led ECOMOG peacekeeping force.</p>
<p>The peacekeepers stayed on to disarm fighters and police the elections under peace accords signed by faction leaders.</p>
<p>Witnesses reported heavy but orderly voting across the capital and in outlying districts such as Harbel, where the U.S.-owned Firestone rubber plantation and factory are located.</p>
<p>Former U.S. president Jimmy Carter, the highest-ranking international poll observer, toured polling stations with members of his Carter Center delegation.</p>
<p>&quot;I have never seen so many people waiting in line so early to vote,&quot; said Carter, whose centre has monitored elections in locations ranging from Haiti to Ghana.</p>
<p>Polls close at 4.00 P.M. (1600 GMT) with early returns due from Sunday night. Final results should be known by Wednesday night, electoral officials said.</p>
<p>If no candidate polls more than 50 percent, a runoff ballot will be held on August 2, the date set for the inauguration of a new president if a winner emerges from the first round.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
