<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74118" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodia marks third anniversary of constitution.</title>
<headline>Cambodia marks third anniversary of constitution.</headline>
<byline>Katya Robinson</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodia on Tuesday marked the third anniversary of the signing of a constitution that restored the monarchy and promoted democracy after years of strong-arm rule.</p>
<p>Royal portraits, bunting and constitutional slogans adorned the public buildings of the capital, but for many Cambodians there was little reason to celebrate a document that has often been violated or ignored by the government, politicians and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;For the ruling elite, the constitution is a piece of paper that exists only to legitimise their regime,&quot; an international human rights worker said. &quot;It is something that facilitates rule, rather than governing rule.&quot;</p>
<p>Politicians say a barrier to enforcing the constitution has been a lack of laws and institutions to police the government.</p>
<p>Most notably, the formation of a constitutional council is long overdue, and parliament deputies worry that without that body, there is little hope of living up to the spirit of the constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been no interest from any major party to create (the council), so the laws being passed by parliament are not properly checked for (compliance with) the constitution,&quot; said Son Chhay, a Buddhist Liberal Democratic Party deputy.</p>
<p>Om Radsady, a deputy with the royalist FUNCINPEC party, said the issue of a constitutional council has been mired in politics for too long.</p>
<p>&quot;We always have these kinds of political games,&quot; he said. &quot;Before the next elections (in 1998), we must make setting up the constitutional council our priority.&quot;</p>
<p>There are other barriers looming over the promise of the constitution and Cambodia's first democratic elections in 1993.</p>
<p>The government has failed to set up an independent judiciary, a strong legal framework or even a royal council to appoint ageing King Norodom Sihanouk's successor.</p>
<p>Analysts said the lack of safeguards had seen former finance minister Sam Rainsy expelled from FUNCINPEC and then parliament in June last year for his repeated criticism of the government.</p>
<p>They also cited the case of Prince Norodom Sirivudh, a top FUNCINPEC member and half-brother of the king who was exiled last December on charges linked to an alleged assassination plot against Second Prime Minister Hun Sen.</p>
<p>Cambodia's human rights record, including the murders of several journalists, has come under fire from organisations like Amnesty International, which also criticised the recent amnesty for Khmer Rouge dissident Ieng Sary.</p>
<p>The foreign rights worker, who asked not to be named, said the lifting of Ieng Sary's 1979 death sentence for his role in the genocidal 1975-79 Khmer Rouge regime revealed conflicting aspects of the constitution, which simultaneously upholds the policy of reconciliation and respect for human rights.</p>
<p>&quot;The amnesty for Ieng Sary is a classic dilemma of peace versus justice,&quot; the official said. &quot;And that dualism is reflected in the constitution.&quot;</p>
<p>While they acknowledge the constitution lacks teeth, some government officials say expectations must be tempered after more than 20 years of civil war and decades of instability.</p>
<p>The 1993 constitution is Cambodia's seventh since World War Two, and they say it will take time to realise its vision.</p>
<p>The gap between the constitution's ideals and reality was clear in the lack of palace fanfare surrounding the anniversary.</p>
<p>When asked what was in store for the third anniversary of the constitution on Tuesday, palace official Oum Weakchiravuth said, &quot;No party, nothing.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
