<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741205" id="root" date="1997-07-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Millionaire Goldsmith dies after battling cancer.</title>
<headline>Millionaire Goldsmith dies after battling cancer.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anglo-French entrepreneur Sir James Goldsmith, cunning corporate raider and anti-European crusader, died surrounded by his family in the small hours of Saturday after battling with cancer, his lawyer said.</p>
<p>The 64-year-old billionaire's friend and attorney Samuel Pisar told Reuters that Goldsmith, who failed in an attempt to win a parliamentary seat in Britain's May general election, suffered a heart attack at his home near Malaga in southern Spain.</p>
<p>&quot;Sir James Goldsmith died of a heart attack in Spain tonight. Sir James was suffering from cancer,&quot; Pisar, a friend of 35 years, said from his Paris office. The financier's eight children were all with him at the time, including his daughter Jemima, wife of former Pakistan cricket captain Imran Khan.</p>
<p>The tall, barrel-chested Goldsmith first suffered pancreatic cancer in 1985 but a recurrence was kept secret when he led his Referendum Party in the British election. He was reported to be critically ill in a hospital near Paris early last month.</p>
<p>&quot;His nature was such that the illness was not noticeable because of his dynamism, his size, his energy. It was only in the last few weeks that it accelerated. I spoke to him yesterday evening, and his mind was the same,&quot; Pisar said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;He occasionally had to interrupt his activity for treatment but he would snap back immediately and pick up where he left off. That was evident in the British election,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Referendum Party, campaigning against further European Union integration, won more than 800,000 votes but won no seat in the election, which resulted in a landslide Labour victory.</p>
<p>Goldsmith lost his deposit after running against pro-European Conservative David Mellor, who was also defeated.</p>
<p>The financier masterminded million-dollar Wall Street deals and made a vast fortune as one of the most astute corporate raiders of his time, with a 1986 raid on the United States' Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company among his most notorious coups.</p>
<p>He amassed millions of dollars by buying into companies then selling the stock for big profits after takeover speculation had boosted share prices.</p>
<p>Renowned for his keen sense of market timing, Goldsmith's investment motto was: &quot;If you see a bandwagon, it's too late.&quot; Such was his touch that even a casual expression of his interest in a company was enough to discomfit a boardroom.</p>
<p>He used a significant part of his personal fortune to campaign against free trade and a single European currency, funding France's maverick Philippe de Villiers in the 1994 European Parliament election, which got him a seat, and paying for his own Referendum Party in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;He was a politician in the real and strong sense of the visionary for whom each world problem was a personal concern, and an entrepreneur who knew what earning a penny meant,&quot; de Villiers told France 2 television.</p>
<p>&quot;He knew the meaning of losing, of succeeding, of failing because he went through all that. He knew that nothing could be achieved without people,&quot; de Villiers said.</p>
<p>According to Pisar, Goldsmith sent a letter of resignation to the speaker of the European Parliament on the grounds that he was too ill to travel to assembly sessions in Strasbourg.</p>
<p>Goldsmith's career was marked by a love-hate relationship with the media, and in 1976 he filed 63 libel suits against satirical magazine Private Eye, which nicknamed him &quot;Sir Jams&quot; because of his grocery empire, the British Cavenham Food group.</p>
<p>As an interventionist owner of French magazine L'Express, he turned the weekly into a foe of the Socialist government which came to power in 1981.</p>
<p>James Michael Goldsmith was born in Paris on February 26, 1933, into an old European banking family of an Anglo-Jewish father and a French Catholic mother, and went to Eton. He was married three times and fathered three sons and three daughters.</p>
<p>At 20 he eloped with Isabel Patino, daughter of a Bolivian tin mining magnate, who died in childbirth. During his second marriage to Frenchwoman Ginette Lery, Goldsmith ignored social conventions by openly keeping an aristocratic mistress in London, Lady Annabel Vane Tempest Stewart, whom he wed after his marriage to Lery was dissolved.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
