<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741336" id="root" date="1997-07-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-ORIOLES SNAP LOSING STREAK AGAINST WHITE SOX.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-ORIOLES SNAP LOSING STREAK AGAINST WHITE SOX.</headline>
<dateline>BALTIMORE 1997-07-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chris Hoiles snapped a tie with a two-run homer in the sixth inning, and the Baltimore Orioles' bullpen shut down the Chicago White Sox for an 8-3 victory to snap a three-game losing streak on Saturday.</p>
<p>Hoiles added an RBI double and Rafael Palmeiro and Jeffrey Hammonds also homered for the Orioles, who won for just the third time in their last 12 games.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a strange game,&quot; said Orioles manager Davey Johnson, who held a closed-door meeting before the game. &quot;Raffy got a big hit and we hung in 'til Hoiles' hit. I was looking for a win any way we could get it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Davey didn't say much of anything, but anytime the manager talks with the team, it helps,&quot; Hoiles said.</p>
<p>Chicago's bullpen allowed five runs after permitting just two earned runs in its previous 32 innings over 10 games.</p>
<p>In Cleveland, Jeff Suppan allowed a run over six innings, and John Valentin blasted two solo homers to lead the Boston Red Sox to a 6-3 victory over the Cleveland Indians.</p>
<p>Suppan (4-0) scattered five hits and one walk with two strikeouts.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I was changing speeds on the fastball,&quot; said Suppan. &quot;I threw a few changeups and sliders. I was getting groundball outs and I just wanted to get outs early in the count instead of going deep.&quot;</p>
<p>Wil Cordero added a three-run double in the third for Boston, which has won the first four games of its six-game road trip.</p>
<p>In Milwaukee, David Wells tossed a three-hitter for his 100th career win and Paul O'Neill had four hits and four RBI as the New York Yankees routed the Milwaukee Brewers, 8-0.</p>
<p>Wells (10-4) struck out four without walking a batter for his first shutout of the season and 14th of his career.</p>
<p>Kelly led off the third inning by sending an 0-1 pitch over the left-field fence to give the Yankees a 3-0 lead.</p>
<p>In Oakland, Chuck Knoblauch had three hits and Paul Molitor delivered a two-run double to cap a four-run seventh inning and lead the Minnesota Twins to their third straight victory, 7-6 over the Oakland Athletics.</p>
<p>Knoblauch had a double and two singles, while Molitor, who missed two games with an abdominal strain, got the last of five straight hits in the seventh to give the Twins a 6-3 advantage.</p>
<p>&quot;Molitor's ball really hurt us,&quot; Oakland manager Art Howe said. &quot;We had two strikes on him and he ended up hitting a ball off the wall. The seventh inning got us.&quot;</p>
<p>At Texas, Brian Hunter's single with one out in the top of the eighth inning scored Matt Walbeck with the go-ahead run and lifted the Detroit Tigers to a 6-5 victory over the Texas Rangers.</p>
<p>Reliever Xavier Hernandez (0-4) got Damion Easley to ground out to start the eighth.  Walbeck walked and Deivi Cruz singled him to third.  Hunter then laced a single up the middle to put the Tigers ahead.</p>
<p>In Anaheim, Tony Phillips' two-out single in the bottom of the ninth inning scored Luis Alicea with the winning run, giving the Anaheim Angels their 11th win in 12 games, 5-4 over the Toronto Blue Jays.</p>
<p>With one out in the ninth, Alicea drew a walk off Mike Timlin (2-2), who struck out pinch-hitter Jack Howell. But Alicea stole second before Phillips grounded a 3-2 pitch between shortstop and third base to score Alicea.</p>
<p>In Seattle, Craig Paquette's RBI single snapped a tie and highlighted a four-run ninth inning as the Kansas City Royals overcame a six-run deficit to stop a 12-game road losing streak with a 9-6 victory over the Seattle Mariners.</p>
<p>With one out in the ninth, Tom Goodwin blooped a single to left field off Seattle closer Bobby Ayala (6-4).  Jay Bell's single moved Goodwin to second and Chili Davis walked before Jeff King's sacrifice fly tied the game, 6-6. Paquette lined the first pitch he saw into right-centre, scoring Bell to put the Royals ahead for good.</p>
<p>Shane Halter followed with his first career double, scoring pinch-runner Ryan Long and Paquette with Kansas City's final runs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALTIMORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
