<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741436" id="root" date="1997-07-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Floods bring debt, misery to thousands in Poland.</title>
<headline>Floods bring debt, misery to thousands in Poland.</headline>
<byline>Wojciech Zurawski</byline>
<dateline>KLODZKO, Poland 1997-07-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>For many thousands of Poles who lost everything in this month's floods, the threat of a new deluge was almost more than they could endure.</p>
<p>As more rain fell on Sunday there was dread in Klodzko near the Czech border, one of the first towns flooded when heavy rain unleashed devastation on Poland's southwest two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Michalina Klasa was scooping up filth from her little toy-shop on Klodzko's Polabska street.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm cleaning and I'm crying,&quot; she said as she shovelled mud mixed with damaged dolls and teddy bears onto the street.</p>
<p>She told a Reuters reporter much of her stock was bought on credit and almost nothing could be salvaged.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know how I will ever pay for it. The shop was insured against burglars, but who ever thought of floods?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We're frightened of this constant rain because it could mean mean the water will reach us again,&quot; said Krystyna Sobanska, whose small grain crop in an outlying Klodzko community was ruined and house so weakened it could collapse.</p>
<p>&quot;The water has robbed me of everything, two pigs, two cows, the chickens...everything we built up all our lives, including our farm machinery is gone,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>Like most small Polish farmers she was not insured.</p>
<p>&quot;Me and my husband couldn't afford it,&quot; she said, close to grief. &quot;I had two hectares of corn and grain. Nothing could be saved. It is all covered in a layer of muck.&quot;</p>
<p>Poland's agriculture ministry has told such farmers that any crops that have been swamped this way cannot even be used for animal-feed, only compost, because they may be tainted.</p>
<p>At the floods' outset, Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz upset ruined farmers by saying they should have been insured and could not expect compensation from government reserves.</p>
<p>Since then, the government has promised 3,000 zlotys (about $860) to each household hit by the floods, and a tonne of grain for each flooded hectare of grain crops -- estimated last week to total 165,000-180,000 hectares. It plans other forms of relief to victims, including eased credit terms.</p>
<p>&quot;What is this 3,000 zlotys from the state when it comes to rebuilding a house,&quot; said Sobanska. &quot;It may turn out that the foundations have shifted and we must pull it down.&quot;</p>
<p>Jan Malek, who lost nearly everything when his ground-floor flat was inundated with water, said: &quot;I'm scared our street could be flooded again.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The flat stinks and should be disinfected but there are no municipal services to do it,&quot; said Malek, adding that he was also waiting to get drinking water and powdered milk for his child.</p>
<p>Similar stories were being repeated across a Polish region where the worst flooding in centuries has claimed 49 lives and ravaged 1,000 towns and villages.</p>
<p>The tragedies have ranged from a mother who unwittingly drove her car into a flooded hole and survived, but could not save her baby, to the 80 animals drowned in Opole's city zoo.</p>
<p>Just across the border in the hard-hit Czech Republic the floodwaters turned thousands of normally humdrum lives into a nightmare.</p>
<p>Toyshop owner Klasa's words spoke for many.</p>
<p>&quot;I just don't know what I'm going to do,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KLODZKO, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
