<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741566" id="root" date="1997-07-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: WEEK AHEAD-Tokyo stocks struggle, high-techs firm.</title>
<headline>WEEK AHEAD-Tokyo stocks struggle, high-techs firm.</headline>
<byline>Masako Iijima</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Tokyo stock market's benchmark index is likely to struggle for direction after the three-day weekend, but brokers said a handful of stocks led by high technology issues were expected to be strong.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors, especially foreigners, will probably continue to seek issues based on global standards,&quot; said Nobuhiro Kaneda, general manager at Daiwa Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Participants are few and such issues are the only ones which are attractive, so it is only natural that blue chips keep reaching new heights,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Strength in the over-the-counter Nasdaq market and the Dow Industrials, as well as weakness in the yen against the dollar, boosted bellwether issues such as Sony Corp to record highs in the past week.</p>
<p>The Nikkei average managed to scramble back above the 20,000 barrier for the first time in about a week with the help of strength in such issues.</p>
<p>News early in the week that the Long-Term Credit Bank of Japan Ltd and Swiss Bank Corp were forming a strategic alliance to face Japan's &quot;Big Bang&quot; financial reforms also provided support to the market, brokers added.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Nikkei 225 shed 269.93 points or 1.32 percent to finish at 20,249.32, gaining about 400 points over the week. The financial markets will be closed on Monday for a national holiday.</p>
<p>&quot;The (Tokyo) market is lacking major factors to drive it at the moment,&quot; Neil Rogers, UBS Securities strategist, said.</p>
<p>Brokers said eyes would be on Wall Street. Further gains or losses on the Dow, and Nasdaq, would influence blue-chip and high-tech shares in Japan.</p>
<p>Dresdner Kleinwort Benson strategist Peter Tasker said that although the Nikkei index had a low correlation with the U.S market, the relationship of popular stocks had become much closer recently.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to recommend exposure to laggard sectors, including financials and quasi-asset plays,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tadahiro Kamogawa, Yamaichi Securities general manager, also said that banking shares still had room to grow. For the stock market to gain momentum, purchases needed to spread to those which were lagging.</p>
<p>But market sources added that signs of strength in the economy were vital to lift the Nikkei average out of its recent range.</p>
<p>&quot;What the market needs is reassurance that private consumption in the July to September period is doing OK,&quot; Tachibana Securities general manager Noboru Yorita said.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, more time is needed for such data to appear,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In the meantime, the Nikkei average was likely to be stuck near the 20,500 line, capped by profit-taking.</p>
<p>The downside, is likely to be limited by bargain-hunting moves, most likely by pension funds, in times of weakness, brokers said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
