<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741567" id="root" date="1997-07-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China Zhong Xin scores with Singapore offer.</title>
<headline>China Zhong Xin scores with Singapore offer.</headline>
<byline>Scott Hillis</byline>
<dateline>TIANJIN, China 1997-07-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Red chip&quot; share offers in Hong Kong may be grabbing headlines, but one Chinese company has stolen a little of the limelight with a stock debut in Singapore.</p>
<p>Tianjin Zhong Xin Pharmaceuticals Group did not trigger the buying stampede of some red chips -- Chinese-backed companies in Hong Kong -- but its offer was still a creditable seven times oversubscribed when it listed in late June.</p>
<p>The north China drug manufacturer, the first Chinese company to choose Singapore for a primary share listing, has seen its shares trade well above the offer price of US$0.68, ending on Friday at US$1.45, up US$0.05.</p>
<p>Company officials were pleased with the results.</p>
<p>FIRST TO LIST IN SINGAPORE</p>
<p>&quot;We were the first company to list in Singapore, so everyone was paying a lot of attention to us,&quot; said Zhan Yuanjing, deputy general manager of the firm.</p>
<p>Singapore may have been chosen partly out of political considerations because China's stock market regulators had lobbied for a listing there.</p>
<p>The former British colony of Hong Kong, which returned to China on July 1, has lured many Chinese companies seeking a listing, and some issues have been more than 1,000 times oversubscribed.</p>
<p>But China's market regulators, perhaps a little uneasy with the Hong Kong buying frenzy over red chips, want to diversify share offers, especially if that means listings in countries with close political ties to Beijing, such as Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;Regulators recommended that we list in Singapore,&quot; Zhan told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Tianjin Zhong Xin is 59.33 percent owned by the state-run Tianjin Pharmaceutical Group. Apart from the 100 million shares listed in Singapore, the company has 194.65 million state shares, 12.05 million legal person or state institutional shares and 22.95 million shares held by employees. None of these other shares can be traded.</p>
<p>As part of the listing agreement, Tianjin Zhong Xin has promised not to issue any more stock -- either in Singapore or elsewhere -- for one year, Zhan said.</p>
<p>The company wanted to make an A share offer for domestic Chinese investors after the waiting period expired, he said without giving details of its possible size.</p>
<p>GOVERNMENT TO LIMIT PROFITS?</p>
<p>But Tianjin Zhong Xin's future health could be less than robust if Beijing moves ahead with possible revisions of price controls on pharmaceutical products to limit &quot;excessive&quot; profits.</p>
<p>&quot;The state wants to control pharmaceutical prices but we don't know to what extent,&quot; Zhan said. &quot;If they control them tightly, that will affect profits.&quot;</p>
<p>Prices of about a dozen of Tianjin Zhong Xin's 300 or so products are now set by the state, but that number could grow if Beijing implemented a new pricing policy, said Shen Mingqi, financial secretary to the company's board.</p>
<p>Authorities were considering classifying medicines into four major groups and limiting profits from Western style pharmaceuticals to between eight and 35 percent while those on traditional Chinese drugs could range from 12 to 40 percent, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It won't happen this year,&quot; said Shen.</p>
<p>China currently offers lower tax rates to manufacturers of some types of traditional medications, and Tianjin Zhong Xin has a preferential 15 percent rate on earnings from its three factories turning out Chinese medical products compared with the nation's top corporate tax rate of 33 percent.</p>
<p>WESTERN MEDICINES BIG MONEY-SPINNER</p>
<p>Despite official attempts to give some Chinese drug makers a shot in the arm, Tianjin Zhong Xin still finds Western products to be its biggest money-spinner.</p>
<p>Tianjin Zhong Xin's 25 percent share in a joint venture with big multi-national SmithKline Beecham Plc, which turns out the popular Contac cold remedy, accounted for 82 percent of the listed company's 1996 profits, Zhan said.</p>
<p>&quot;The main profits are in Western medicines,&quot; Zhan said.</p>
<p>The company also has an 80 percent stake in a project -- now in the trial production stage -- with a Lithuanian research centre to make and sell genetic and chemical products. It also has 30 percent of a venture, now under construction, with Italy's Bieffe Medital S.P.A. to make dialysis solutions and infusion fluids.</p>
<p>With 1.2 billion people and an ageing society, China was the core market for Tianjin Zhong Xin, accounting for 93 percent of its sales. The remainder of its output is exported to Japan, Hong Kong and Singapore.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIANJIN, China"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
