<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741520" id="root" date="1997-07-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Ranariddh in Singapore to meet Prime Minister Goh.</title>
<headline>Ranariddh in Singapore to meet Prime Minister Goh.</headline>
<byline>Jerry Norton</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ousted Cambodian premier Prince Norodom Ranariddh will meet Singapore Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong on Monday as part of an effort to seek support from regional leaders, diplomatic sources said.</p>
<p>Ranariddh, whose forces were on the losing end of fighting with his co-prime minister, Hun Sen, early this month, is expected to make a swing through Southeast Asian and other capitals to seek support, with Kuala Lumpur his possible next stop after Singapore, diplomatic sources have said.</p>
<p>Cambodia was in line to have joined the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) at the group's annual meetings in Kuala Lumpur this week. But Hun Sen's bloody coup against Ranariddh this month put that plan on hold.</p>
<p>Ranariddh arrived in Singapore from Bangkok on a commercial flight and was taken to a luxury hotel where media access was barred.</p>
<p>A Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesman said Ranariddh would call on Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong on Monday. The spokesman gave no other details.</p>
<p>Hun Sen on Saturday dismissed efforts by ASEAN to find a solution to Cambodia's political crisis.</p>
<p>Ranariddh condemned Hun Sen for rejecting mediation efforts, saying it would bring about isolation, an end to democracy and a return to civil war.</p>
<p>Cambodia's Foreign Minister Ung Huot will press for a last-minute ASEAN change of heart on membership at this week's Malaysia meetings, which Cambodia will attend as an observer.</p>
<p>Diplomats say Cambodia could be admitted as early as August 8, when ASEAN celebrates its 30th anniversary, or later in December when the group holds its annual &quot;informal summit&quot;.</p>
<p>But some ASEAN observers question whether the group would be in any mood to bring in Cambodia soon without stronger conciliatory gestures from Hun Sen.</p>
<p>On Saturday in Thailand, Ranariddh said: &quot;In rejecting ASEAN mediation, I think Hun Sen is now isolating Cambodia by himself.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Now I'm really afraid, we will have again a civil war in my country,&quot; said Ranariddh in his first news conference in the region since Hun Sen's troops made a bloody power grab on July 5-6. Ranariddh left Cambodia for France on the eve of the fighting.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very sad for my country. From now on democracy is finished, it is ended in Cambodia.&quot;</p>
<p>Ranariddh said he had heard at least 100 opposition politicians -- many from his FUNCINPEC party -- had been killed and about 1,000 detained in the wake of the coup.</p>
<p>Diplomatic sources in Phnom Penh have said there were at least 40 politically motivated killings after Ranariddh's ouster. Most were in the capital and neighbouring provinces.</p>
<p>Ranariddh also announced that FUNCINPEC and three other parties were forming a movement aimed at finding a non-violent, diplomatic solution to the political crisis.</p>
<p>He said the movement, the Union of Cambodian Democrats (UCD), wanted all the nations of the world to reject &quot;the illegitimate government&quot; in Phnom Penh and to condemn the slaughter of innocent people.</p>
<p>The UCD also urged all nations to suspend international assistance to Hun Sen's government and to channel humanitarian assistance through non-governmental organisations.</p>
<p>It called on signatories of the 1991 Paris Peace Accords to recall their ambassadors from Phnom Penh to protest against the violation of the accord.</p>
<p>The international peace treaty laid the ground for United Nations-sponsored elections in 1993. Ranariddh won the poll and agreed to an uneasy power-sharing coalition with Hun Sen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
