<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74161" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: India seals Kuwait term diesel about 70-ct premium.</title>
<headline>India seals Kuwait term diesel about 70-ct premium.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>State-owned Indian Oil Corp (IOC) is to buy more high speed diesel from Kuwait Petroleum Corp (KPC) at a higher premium under its new annual term contract, sources close to the talks said on Monday.</p>
<p>It also agreed to pay a higher premium for the same volume of superior kerosene in a renewed the term contract for April 1996 to March 1997 sealed last week, they said.</p>
<p>The 1.0-percent sulphur diesel price was agreed at a premium of around 70 cents per barrel to Middle East spot quotes, on a free-on-board (fob) basis, compared to the 40-cent premium in the previous deal, the sources said.  </p>
<p>They said IOC would take about 10 percent more 1.0 percent sulphur diesel under the new contract. In the 1995-1996 term deal, IOC bought about 1.5 million tonnes of diesel from KPC.</p>
<p>Sources said there was still room under the new deal to add more 0.5 or 0.25 percent sulphur diesel.</p>
<p>India has gradually shifted to buying 0.5 percent sulphur diesel by monthly spot tenders. It also buys two cargoes of 0.25 percent sulphur diesel each month by tender.</p>
<p>Under the new term deal, IOC would also take about 1.08 million tonnes of kerosene, the same volume as in the previous contract, the sources said.  </p>
<p>The kerosene price was agreed at a premium of 50-55 cents per barrel to MidEast spot quotes, fob basis, up from the 30-cent premium of the previous deal, they said.</p>
<p>The diesel and kerosene prices will be backdated to April 1996. The term contract renewal has been delayed since May due to Indian general elections and the subsequent changes in government.</p>
<p>After concluding its KPC deal, IOC will soon start talks on renewing terms deals with Bahrain National Oil Co (BANOCO) and with Abu Dhabi national Oil Co (ADNOC), trade sources said.</p>
<p>--Ramthan Hussain, Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
