<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741639" id="root" date="1997-07-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi minister in Yemen for border dispute talks.</title>
<headline>Saudi minister in Yemen for border dispute talks.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-07-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Interior Minister Prince Nayef arrived in the Yemeni capital Sanaa on Saturday for the second visit this month to resolve a 61-year-old border dispute, Yemeni radio said.</p>
<p>The radio, monitored by the British Broadcasting Corporation, quoted the minister as saying he was confident there would be an agreement on the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident and optimistic that the objective...will be realised, God willing, in the interest of the two countries and in a manner satisfactory to all sides,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prince Nayef visited Yemen for talks early this month. Yemen's President Ali Abdullah Saleh said during that visit that a final settlement would be reached within weeks.</p>
<p>Yemen, one of the region's poorest countries, and oil-rich Saudi Arabia signed a memorandum of understanding in 1995 to resolve the dispute. A joint committee looking into border demarcation has met dozens of times since but its work has moved slowly, diplomats say.</p>
<p>Yemen has hinted in recent months it might resort to international arbitration. The two countries' armed forces had several minor clashes in a border area potentially rich in oil and gas before signing the memorandum.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
