<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741610" id="root" date="1997-07-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt not thinking of buying wheat now- official.</title>
<headline>Egypt not thinking of buying wheat now- official.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-07-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt's main wheat importer said on Sunday he was not thinking of buying wheat until the issues raised by a government import ban on genetically engineered grain were settled.</p>
<p>Egypt issued a decree that it would require imports of commodities meant for human consumption to be accompanied by proof that genetic engineering was not used in their production.</p>
<p>The decree also said that any imported grain or pulses must be accompanied by a certificate saying it has not been genetically altered.</p>
<p>&quot;A freezing in the world market concerning Egypt will continue for 15 to 20 days,&quot; Samir Shakankiri, vice chairman of the state's General Authority for Supply Commodities (GASC), told Reuters. &quot;We have ceased watching the market until this problem is solved.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We used to watch the market to buy when prices go down. Even if we could get the wheat for free, we would not buy it because it would not enter the country without the certificate,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Shakankiri, whose organisation is the biggest wheat importer in Egypt, said contacts were underway with exporting governments to see how they could issue such certificates.</p>
<p>Egypt imports about six million tonnes of wheat a year from suppliers including U.S., France, Australia, and Argentina.</p>
<p>U.S. industry sources in Cairo said they were trying to set up a meeting soon with Egyptian authorities for an explanation of why the decree was issued.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +202 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
