<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741787" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Johnson says fishing, diving sales soft.</title>
<headline>Johnson says fishing, diving sales soft.</headline>
<dateline>RACINE, Wis. 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Johnson Worldwide Associates Inc said Monday that third-quarter results were disappointing and reflected a weak market overall and worldwide softness in its fishing and diving businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;Camping quarterly results worldwide, however, are up over a year ago, reflecting a particularly good performance in Europe,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>The company reported net sales for the third quarter ended June 27 totaled $86.9 million compared with $110.7 million for the prior year's quarter. Net income was $3.3 million compared with net income of $4.2 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Results of Uwatec AG and Ocean Kayak, two recently completed acquisitions, are not included in the third quarter figures.</p>
<p>&quot;The strengthening U.S. dollar magnified the decline in sales for the quarter,&quot; the company said. &quot;With sales lagging and the mix of sales contributing to lower gross margins, we have been able to reduce our operating expenses to keep them proportional to sales ... In this period of slower sales, we also have emphasized prudent asset management and have made good progress reducing JWA's inventories.&quot;</p>
<p>Johnson makes and markets outdoor recreation products, including Scubapro, Uwatec and Aladin diving equipment and instruments; Mitchell and Johnson fishing equipment; Minn Kota electric motors; SpiderWire fishing line; Eureka! and Camp Trails tents and back packs; Old Town and Ocean Kayak canoes and kayaks and other products.</p>
<p>((--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RACINE, Wis."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
