<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741716" id="root" date="1997-07-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - July 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - July 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Bangladesh press on Sunday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE DAILY STAR</p>
<p>At least 16 people, including five jail guards, were injured on Saturday in clashes between some convicts and under-trial prisoners in Chittagong jail.</p>
<p>The Chittagong Port Authorities have threatened to impose the penal rents on imported container cargo if their delivery is not taken within 15 days from the port jetties.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>The Indo-Bangladesh Joint River Commission (JRC) began meeting in Dhaka on Saturday after a seven-year gap.</p>
<p>The Khulna Newsprint Mills is trying to export newsprint following the decrease in its demand in the domestic market.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGLADESH OBSERVER</p>
<p>Rebel Shanti Bahini leader Jyotirindra Bodhipriya Larma on Saturday said peace talks with the government would continue and asked tribal people to &quot;have patience and not to be misled&quot;.</p>
<p>Trade volume between Britain and Bangladesh stood at 350 million pound sterling in 1996-97 (July-June).</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL EXPRESS</p>
<p>Six labour organisations have called for strike in garment factories on July 24 to press their demand for higher wages and better working facilities.</p>
<p>Nepal would soon get transit facilities through Mongla port.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
