<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="741747" id="root" date="1997-07-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Time running out in Europe for Boeing on merger.</title>
<headline>Time running out in Europe for Boeing on merger.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS, Belgium</dateline>
<text>
<p>Time was running out Sunday for Boeing Co. in Europe, where regulators are set to rule against the U.S. aircraft maker's proposed $14 billion merger with McDonnell Douglas Corp. when they meet on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Boeing executive vice president Richard Albrecht met European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert on Friday evening but the two sides failed to break a deadlock.</p>
<p>&quot;He came empty-handed. He had nothing to offer,&quot; a commission source told Reuters.</p>
<p>While the commission says only a &quot;miracle&quot; will prevent the deal being blocked given the short deadline -- Monday is a bank holiday to celebrate Belgium's independence -- Boeing did not seem to be contemplating major concessions.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no meetings planned either at higher or lower level,&quot; Jim Frank, the company's vice president for European affairs, told Reuters on Sunday. Albrecht was expected to be &quot;wandering around&quot; until Wednesday, he said.</p>
<p>The commission's determination to block the merger has triggered sharp criticism on the other side of the Atlantic, and President Clinton has warned the United States may go to the World Trade Organisation or impose sanctions if European Union regulators rule against the merger.</p>
<p>At stake in the dispute is a strategic industry representing $80 billion in sales worldwide, evenly distributed between defence and civilian aircraft markets.</p>
<p>European regulators believe the deal would strengthen Boeing's already dominant position in the commercial sector, a conclusion rejected by the manufacturer, which says McDonnell Douglas no longer constitutes a serious competitor.</p>
<p>Boeing's opinion was shared by the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, which cleared the merger without conditions earlier this month.</p>
<p>Despite intense political pressure, EU leaders have sided with the commission.</p>
<p>The EU executive commission has the power to reject the deal if it finds it would harm fair competition in the 15-nation bloc. Were the merger to go ahead, it is empowered to impose fines of up to 10 percent of the companies' sales.</p>
<p>The commission maintains that the merged company would have a share of sales of commercial planes worldwide of 70 percent compared to Boeing's present 64 percent and a customer base of 84 percent, up from Boeing's 60 percent.</p>
<p>Although McDonnell Douglas has become a minor player in new orders for commercial aircraft, its planes -- among them the successful 100-seat DC-9 and its successor the MD-80 series -- make up about a quarter of commercial aircraft fleets worldwide.</p>
<p>McDonnell Douglas's strength in the military sector causes regulators here to fear that Boeing would benefit from defence funds to subsidise its commercial programmes.</p>
<p>But the most contentious point in the talks between Boeing and the commission remains exclusive supply contracts signed with American Airlines, Continental Airlines and Delta Air Lines in the United States.</p>
<p>The contracts, which last about 25 years, would shut out Boeing's main rival Airbus Industrie, a European consortium whose owners are France's Aerospatiale, Daimler-Benz Aerospace of Germany, British Aerospace and Casa of Spain.</p>
<p>European Competition Commissioner Van Miert has called the supply contracts &quot;unacceptable,&quot; but Boeing is only willing to cut them back to about 13 years, EU sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not prepared to tear up the deals with the airlines,&quot; a source close to Boeing said.</p>
<p>Antitrust lawyers well versed in EU merger law believe the two sides will come back to the negotiating table eventually even if regulators rule against the deal on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
