<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="742072" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: CYCLING-PANTANI PRODDED TO 15TH STAGE WIN.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-PANTANI PRODDED TO 15TH STAGE WIN.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>MORZINE, France 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marco Pantani's victory in the Tour de France on Monday despite illness was due as much to his manager's insistence as to his own efforts.</p>
<p>The brilliant Italian mountain rider was on the point of quitting the Tour because of a sore throat. He took the Alpe d'Huez stage on Saturday but suffered a three-minute deficit at Courchevel on Sunday.</p>
<p>But his team manager Giuseppe Martinelli would have none of it, according to the slightly-built rider who is nicknamed &quot;Elefantino&quot; because of his prominent ears.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a type to complain a lot and my team manager told me I had to reach Paris and make a show of tenacity,&quot; Pantani said.</p>
<p>&quot;On Sunday, I believe I went to the limits of suffering, especially on the Col de la Madeleine and today's victory taught me you must never give up,&quot; said the 27-year-old who has come back from a terrible leg injury in 1995 which put him out of action for 16 months.</p>
<p>Pantani's victory has set up a fascinating battle for third place with Tour de France title holder Bjarne Riis.</p>
<p>Pantani, third after his stage win at Alpe d'Huez, had dropped to fourth behind Riis on Sunday.</p>
<p>But the Italian, third overall in his previous Tour in 1995, leapt back in front of the Dane on Monday with a 1:42 advantage.</p>
<p>The pair are both more than 10 minutes behind leader Jan Ullrich with Frenchman Richard Virenque second, 6:22 adrift of the German.</p>
<p>&quot;My objective was more to win the stage than to narrow the gap with Riis,&quot; said Pantani. &quot;This third place is quite uncertain,&quot; he said as he looked ahead to the second time trial of the Tour on the penultimate stage at Disneyland.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a 63-km time trial. I'm not a specialist and Riis can recover several minutes,&quot; he said. Pantani was 34 seconds slower than the Dane in the 12th stage time trial on a 55-km circuit around St Etienne on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure I'm one of those who lost most minutes in the first week,&quot; Pantani said of his relative lack of strength on the flat stages.</p>
<p>But speaking of his command of the conditions in the mountains, he said: &quot;I can do a lot of damage when I attack. It's psychologically good.&quot;</p>
<p>Riis, fighting to reach the podium on the Champs Elysees for the third year in succession after his third place in 1995 and victory last year, believes he has done as well as could be expected.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't do badly, I made a good effort,&quot; the Dane said. &quot;But there are others stronger than me and I have to accept that.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm still among the world's best,&quot; said the 33-year-old Riis. &quot;When I see I am no longer, then maybe I'll quit.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MORZINE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
