<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="742113" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-MARLINS ACQUIRE DAULTON FROM PHILLIES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-MARLINS ACQUIRE DAULTON FROM PHILLIES.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Florida Marlins, seeking an offensive boost in a drive for their first-ever postseason berth, acquired three-time All-Star Darren Daulton Monday from the last-place Philadelphia Phillies.</p>
<p>The Phillies sent Daulton to the Marlins in exchange for minor league outfielder Billy McMillon.</p>
<p>The Marlins are currently five games behind the first-place Atlanta Braves in the National League East and are 1 1/2-games ahead of the New York Mets in the wild card chase.</p>
<p>The trade of Daulton, one of the Phillies' most recognisable players, could mark the beginning of a house-cleaning in Philadelphia. The Phillies own the worst record in the major leagues at 29-66.</p>
<p>The Phillies have been shopping Daulton and his $5 million salary, and it was speculated that he would be sent to the American League, where he could serve as a designated hitter and rest his knees that have been operated on nine times.</p>
<p>The Marlins, however, won the bidding for Daulton, who is hitting .264 with 11 homers and 42 RBI.</p>
<p>Daulton, 35, may be used at first base in place of Jeff Conine, who is hitting just .235 with eight homers and 37 RBI.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old McMillon, the International League Rookie of the Year last year, was hitting .279 at Charlotte with eight homers, 26 RBI and eight stolen bases in 57 games this season. He has been assigned to Scranton Wilkes-Barre of the Triple A International League.</p>
<p>The acquistion of Daulton came after the Marlins were expected to keep closer tabs on costs following the announcement that owner Wayne Huizenga would put the team up for sale. Huizenga said he was losing money after committing $89 million to free agents this past offseason and signing outfielder Gary Sheffield to a $61 million contract extension.</p>
<p>Daulton has a $5 million club option on his contract for next season, but it is unlikely that any team would exercise that option. Should the Marlins elect not to use the option, Daulton would receive a $500,000 buyout payment.</p>
<p>Daulton considered retiring this past offseason after injuries limited him to five games in 1996. He was unable to beat out Rico Brogna for the job at first base, finally landing a job in right field.</p>
<p>Daulton last made the All-Star team in 1995, a season in which he hit .249 with nine homers and 55 RBI in 98 games. He has played his entire career in Philadelphia and has caught 965 games, the third most in team history.</p>
<p>His best season was 1992, when he hit .270 with 27 homers and 109 RBI. In 1993, Daulton hit 24 homers and had 105 RBI.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
