<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="742357" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SENEGAL: Competition growing in Senegal phone market.</title>
<headline>Competition growing in Senegal phone market.</headline>
<byline>Diadie Ba</byline>
<dateline>DAKAR 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Competition is hotting up in Senegal's phone market, where France Telecom plans to quadruple the number of fixed lines after buying a stake in state phone company SONATEL, and mobile phone firms are moving in.</p>
<p>France Cables Radio, a wholly-owned subsidiary of France Telecom, paid 650 million francs ($107 million) for 33.33 percent and one share in SONATEL under an agreement signed in Dakar on Monday.</p>
<p>France Telecom in Paris laid out an ambitious investment plan that it said would equip SONATEL for an opening-up of the mobile phone market in Senegal next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The central aspect of the development plan, which sees investment of nearly two billion francs, is the installation of over 300,000 extra lines over the next 10 years, to quadruple the size of the phone network,&quot; the French state firm said.</p>
<p>In the shorter term, France Cables Radio is to expand the fixed line network to 285,000 lines by 2001 from 100,000 now.</p>
<p>The Senegalese state intends to keep a stake of around a third in SONATEL.</p>
<p>France Telecom said the remaining third would go to Senegalese and foreign investors. Senegal has said 10 percent would go to SONATEL staff and five percent to an African partner that has not yet been chosen.</p>
<p>France Telecom started talks for the purchase of a one-third stake in SONATEL after the cancellation on April 16 by Senegal of a provisional deal worth 70 billion CFA francs ($116 million) with a consortium led by Swedish company Telia Overseas.</p>
<p>The Swedish consortium wanted a seven-year concession which would have lasted only until the proposed end of SONATEL'S monopoly over the fixed-line network. France Cables Radio has agreed a 20-year concession with Senegal.</p>
<p>SONATEL currently operates the West African country's only cellular phone network, but Senegal has promised to liberalise the sector next year and a U.S.-based consortium, Iridium LLC, wants to include Senegal in an ambitious global phone system.</p>
<p>&quot;We will provide to our subscribers cellular phones which will allow them to travel all over the world and make calls and be called, irrespective of their geographic location,&quot; Mademba Cisse, Iridium's director for Africa, told Reuters on the sidelines of a telecommunications seminar in Dakar.</p>
<p>Iridium is an international consortium of telecommunications and industrial firms, including Motorola and Lockheed Martin.</p>
<p>It is investing some $4.4 billion in a network of 66 low-earth-orbit satellites to provide telecommunications services on a worldwide basis from September 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;With an international roaming system, the problem of using your cellular phone abroad is solved,&quot; Cisse said.</p>
<p>Iridium, which has signed memorandums of understanding with 25 public or private phone operators in Africa, will need a local partner in Senegal for its system to work. The government has said a rival to SONATEL would be allowed from January.</p>
<p>Africa's mobile phone market has great potential but analysts in the sector said the lack of clear regulatory systems was a handicap. ($ = 6.06 French francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SENEG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAKAR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SENEGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
