<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="742447" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: FEATURE-After Mobutu's fall, Mugabe? Zimbabwe's rulers hope not.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-After Mobutu's fall, Mugabe? Zimbabwe's rulers hope not.</headline>
<byline>Cris Chinaka</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's embattled rulers are trying to woo back estranged comrades in what may be an attempt to nip in the bud a new opposition movement with enough credibility to challenge Robert Mugabe's 17-year rule.</p>
<p>Analysts say Mugabe's ZANU-PF party has been panicked by scandals engulfing the government, by growing demands on its state-funded political patronage base and by a wave of wildcat pay strikes that have rocked the economy.</p>
<p>Anxieties have been compounded by speculation that some former ZANU-PF leaders might launch a new party to challenge a government seen by critics as arrogant and insensitive.</p>
<p>Mugabe fought white supremacy as a guerrilla leader in what was then colonial Rhodesia, emerging as Zimbabwe's first prime minister on independence from Britain in 1980 and becoming executive president in 1987.</p>
<p>But now, he may be casting an anxious eye north to Kenya where his friend and fellow veteran leader, President Daniel arap Moi, is in trouble with an opposition that has recently taken to the streets to demand an end to the government's strangehold on power.</p>
<p>COULD MUGABE SHARE SAME FATE AS MOBUTU?</p>
<p>Moi and Mugabe are both 73 years old and in some eyes part of a dying breed of African leader who could share the same fate as Zaire's ousted Mobutu Sese Seko -- unless they grasp the nettle of democratic reform.</p>
<p>On July 30, the Zimbabwe Supreme Court is to hear a case from the opposition challenging a law allowing Mugabe's party to draw an annual state subsidy, and presidential powers to appoint electoral officials.</p>
<p>&quot;He is obviously worried about Kenya because he has a similar situation here,&quot; said John Makumbe of the University of Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>Political analysts believe Zimbabwe's ruling party is trying to co-opt potentially serious opponents.</p>
<p>&quot;ZANU-PF strategists do realise that the party is already in a corner and it is their idea to get back into the fold some of their former comrades,&quot; said Professor Masipula Sithole, a political scientist at Harare's University of Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea is to try to forestall any opposition party that may be formed around them, or to deny anybody within ZANU-PF who may be thinking of using them to form such a party,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Sithole was referring to current efforts to woo back Edgar Tekere, ZANU-PF's former secretary-general who was expelled in the late 1980s after accusing the party of condoning corruption.</p>
<p>Tekere formed his opposition Zimbabwe Unity Movement (ZUM) in 1989 and is credited by many for leading a campaign that stopped Mugabe from setting up a formal one-party state.</p>
<p>But ZUM has since all but disintegrated.</p>
<p>PARTY TRIES TO WOO ESTRANGED COMRADES</p>
<p>ZANU-PF says it wants Tekere back because it thinks &quot;he can help the party&quot; and Tekere has indicated he is ready to rejoin.</p>
<p>ZANU-PF is also wooing Rugare Gumbo, a highly respected former publicity secretary and ex-member of the ruling party's independence war council, who was sidelined in the late 1970s on charges of trying to topple Mugabe as party leader.</p>
<p>Gumbo has been included in a new directors' board of the state-owned Zimbabwe Broadcasting Corporation, which runs the country's only radio and television service.</p>
<p>Also back in favour is Callistus Ndlovu, former minister of industry and commerce who resigned in 1989 because of a car sales scandal. He was recently appointed director of the state Zimbabwe Public Administration Management (ZIPAM).</p>
<p>And the ruling party is trying to lure back Enos Nkala, a former defence minister who has been in political wilderness since he resigned over the same car scandal.</p>
<p>&quot;The assumption is that these politicians have some strength as individuals in their numbers...but I don't think that is correct,&quot; Sithole said.</p>
<p>&quot;The party is confused by the prospect of a credible opposition emerging and it is trying to plug every imaginable hole, but I doubt that will succeed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sithole and other local commentators such as John Makumbe and Lupi Mushayakarara believe that ZANU-PF -- which has dominated the country since 1980 against a weak and fractious opposition -- is starting to face stiff resistance from independent politicians who have emerged in the last three years.</p>
<p>&quot;That could be the nucleus of a real viable opposition...but ZANU-PF may also wake up to a split one day,&quot; Mushayakarara said.</p>
<p>COULD ZANU-PF SPLIT?</p>
<p>Factional differences that have surfaced over the last five years might tear down the party, particularly if Mugabe -- expected by many to retire in the year 2002 -- tried to impose a successor on the country.</p>
<p>&quot;There are many people who are very unhappy with current management, especially of the economy,&quot; Mushayakarara said of charges that Mugabe has not paid adequate attention to the economy. It has grown at an average 1.8 percent annually over the last 10 years against a population growth rate of three percent.</p>
<p>Unemployment doubled to about 50 percent in the same period.</p>
<p>Mugabe denies he has become immune to criticism or a hostage of family and political cronies abusing a scheme to empower Zimbabwe's majority blacks economically.</p>
<p>His government has been hit by scandals over the months, including charges that his officials raided a war victims' compensation fund, abused a housing fund meant to benefit the poor and bought themselves luxury cars while urging Zimbabweans to accept austerity measures.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
