<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="742527" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish floods approach end as rain set to subside.</title>
<headline>Polish floods approach end as rain set to subside.</headline>
<byline>Marcin Grajewski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poles, exhausted from two weeks of floods that devastated much of the country's south, took hope on Monday from weather forecasts suggesting that the worst deluge in centuries was nearing an end.</p>
<p>Some communities still faced grim battles with encroaching water. Others laboured amid debris and mud to repair damage which analysts say may cost Poland several billion dollars and affect the course of coming parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite rains on Sunday and on Monday, the situation is much better than it was and everything suggests it will improve,&quot; the spokesman of Poland's flood crisis committee, Krzysztof Pomes, told Reuters. &quot;Water levels are tending to subside on most rivers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rain drenching the flood-stricken region of Silesia on Monday will gradually subside until Wednesday and the rest of the week is likely to be sunny, said Anna Nemec of the state Meteorology and Water Management Institute.</p>
<p>Some areas in southwest and south Poland remained under the water that inundated more than 1,000 towns and villages. The death toll was at least 50 people and 140,000 have been forced to evacuate their homes.</p>
<p>A flood wave caused by the earlier rains was storming along the Odra river on the German border towards the northwestern port of Szczecin, but was unlikely to swamp the city, flood control officials said.</p>
<p>Poland's biggest river, the Wisla, was calm. Smaller mountain rivers overflowed in Nowy Sacz and Jelenia Gora provinces, where floods may still hit several towns and villages.</p>
<p>Residents of the damaged areas, some 50,000 troops and fire fighters were working hard to contain the damage. Food, water, clothes, and cleaning materials was flowing from all over the country and charity events were staged nationwide.</p>
<p>&quot;People are working themselves into a sweat. Many of them lost all their possessions,&quot; Grzegorz Ossowski, a local radio reporter in the southwestern city of Walbrzych, told Reuters.</p>
<p>President Aleksander Kwasniewski increasingly thought a state of emergency in the damaged areas, which would postpone general elections scheduled for September 21, was unnecessary, his spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The final decision has not been taken. But there are less and less circumstances that could compel the president to impose the measure,&quot; Antoni Styrczula said.</p>
<p>The right-wing opposition to the ruling coalition of ex-communists and a peasant party has demanded that the emergency be introduced to help combat instances of looting in the flooded areas, freeze prices and speed up decision making.</p>
<p>The ex-communists, who will be challenged by the Solidarity alliance (AWS) during the September 21 polls, found themselves on the defensive after media and politicians accusations that they mishandled the rescue operation.</p>
<p>The government was scheduled to meet on Monday to approve a comprehensive programme to rebuild road and other infrastructure and help flood victims.</p>
<p>The head of the government's flood relief office, Andrzej Pilat, said the government had gathered about $1 billion for the programme and got parliament's approval to borrow up to another $730 billion from the central bank for the purpose.</p>
<p>The flood and government measures to meet its costs added to concern over the state of Poland's finances, but Poland's zloty currency picked up half a percent on Monday, partially recovering last week's falls. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
