<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="742604" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: More than 30 massacred by Colombian death squad.</title>
<headline>More than 30 massacred by Colombian death squad.</headline>
<byline>Karl Penhaul</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A suspected right-wing death squad massacred more than 30 people in a remote village in eastern Colombia, a regional Red Cross chief said on Monday.</p>
<p>The attack took place at Mapiripan in Meta province over the weekend, Teddy Torbeaum, head of the Red Cross in Meta, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I met the mayor of Mapiripan this morning and he told me that at least 30 people had been massacred. But we will not know exactly how many dead there are until we can recover the corpses,&quot; Torbeaum said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;The mayor said a paramilitary group carried out the attack but I cannot confirm that personally,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Hundreds of inhabitants, fearing fresh attacks, were flown out of the village of about 1,000 people early on Monday aboard military aircraft, Torbeaum said.</p>
<p>In an interview with the Radionet radio network, provincial Gov. Alfonso Ortiz said details of the massacre were still vague and that many of the corpses were thought to be scattered in rural areas outside the main village.</p>
<p>He said some of the victims had been decapitated, adding that a severed head was dumped at the doors of the village medical post.</p>
<p>Ortiz said sketchy witness reports said a gang of about 100 members of a paramilitary gang entered the village, killing three people in the square and dragging others off to more isolated areas before murdering them.</p>
<p>&quot;Witnesses have said more than 100 paramilitaries came to the village to lay down law and order ... the presence of the state in the area is zero ... narcotraffickers and guerrillas have control of the region,&quot; Ortiz said.</p>
<p>Mapiripan is on the banks of the Guaviare River, which divides Meta and Guaviare provinces. The village is about 20 hours by land from the nearest main town.</p>
<p>Ortiz said some reports suggested the paramilitary members had come from the trouble-torn, northwest banana-growing region of Uraba - - the stronghold of the country's most-feared death squad, the so-called Peasant Self-Defence Group of Cordoba and Uraba (ACCU).</p>
<p>Right-wing death squads frequently target those they suspect of collaborating with leftist rebels.</p>
<p>If the number of dead is confirmed it will be one of the worst massacre since January 1994 when 35 people were slain by leftist guerrillas at a party in the town of Apartado in Uraba.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
