<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74284" id="root" date="1996-09-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Sept 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Sept 24.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in Norwegian papers this morning:</p>
<p>AFTENPOSTEN</p>
<p>- The Foreign Ministry is to open a service called Team Norway to give advice to Norwegian companies to expand overseas as single markets develop into one global market. The initiative comes from the government.</p>
<p>- Justice Minister Grete Faremo told a police conference she rejected calls to legalise drugs or to reduce prison sentences in cases involving narcotics.</p>
<p>DAGENS NAERINGSLIV</p>
<p>- State-owned oil group Statoil will focus on Web technology in the company's IT strategy. Statoil says everyone who wants to work close with them in the future must master the Internet. Large parts of tender processes may take place via electronic media, says Statoil's Berit Rynning yen, head of information.</p>
<p>- Hydro Aluminium has qualified in the final stage of the privatization of Venezuela's aluminium industry.</p>
<p>- The 1997 budget for the Defence Ministry will rise by two percent. Defence Minister Joergen Kosmo declined to comment on whether the ministry is winner or loser in the national budget, which will be presented by the government to parliament on October 4.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
