<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="742984" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sallie Mae says John Neff agrees to serve on board.</title>
<headline>Sallie Mae says John Neff agrees to serve on board.</headline>
<text>
<p>WASHINGTON, July 21 (Reuter) Student Loan Marketing Association (Sallie Mae) said Monday John Neff agreed to serve on the holding company board after the July 31 election at which shareholders will vote on a privatization plan and also elect one of two rival slates of directors.</p>
<p>The Sallie Mae management has proposed 10 nominees for director and left open five seats it said were available for a rival group, the Committee to Restore Value (CRV).</p>
<p>The CRV has said it is not interested in the five seats on a board led by the current management, and instead has proposed its own slate of 15 candidates.</p>
<p>In a news release, Sallie Mae said it will keep the five seats open until the conclusion of the election.</p>
<p>Neff is a well-known investor having retired in 1995 from his position as managing partner, senior vice president and a member of the executive commitee of Wellington Management Co. From 1964 until 1995 he was portfolio manager of Wellington's Vanguard/Windsor Fund.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
