<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="743043" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCOJ futures close up in breather from selloff.</title>
<headline>FCOJ futures close up in breather from selloff.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>FCOJ futures finished higher Monday as speculative and local buying helped the market rebound from Friday's selloff, but dealings were quiet, traders said.</p>
<p>Most-active September settled up 1.55 cents at 75.00 cents a lb, traded 75.10 to 73.35 cents. Volume was estimated at 1,500 lots.</p>
<p>&quot;We could go up to about 75.50 cents in the September contract, the 20-day moving average, but we are looking for heavy resistance there,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, the picture still looks lower. We are just getting a little bit of a breather after several down days,&quot; the dealer added.</p>
<p>Bernard Savaiko of PaineWebber said the market was acting like it was oversold.</p>
<p>&quot;The cold storage report highlighted there is still a lot of juice out there, but it was down a little bit from the last report so that might be a bit constructive,&quot; Savaiko said.</p>
<p>After the close Friday, USDA reported that on June 30, U.S. orange juice stocks totaled 198,251 gallons, compared with 219,886 gallons on May 31.</p>
<p>((Huw Jones, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
