<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="743012" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: In Miami Beach, crossdressers blend right in.</title>
<headline>In Miami Beach, crossdressers blend right in.</headline>
<byline>Jim Loney</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI BEACH 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slipping on a skirt may sound like a strange way for a man fleeing the FBI to elude detection, but in gender-bending Miami Beach even a cross-dressing multiple killer could blend right in.</p>
<p>The possibility that Andrew Cunanan, prime suspect in the murder of Italian fashion icon Gianni Versace, may be wearing a dress as he attempts to evade a massive manhunt has angered and scared transvestites in this bohemian enclave, though.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody's very upset and very scared. We're all on the lookout,&quot; said a local drag queen, who asked not to be named. &quot;We have pictures all over the club and we're all asking people to watch out for him.&quot;</p>
<p>Nearly a week after Versace's murder, an army of local and state police and FBI agents were still hunting America's most wanted man. Cunanan is also a suspect in four killings in northern U.S. states since April.</p>
<p>Versace was shot twice in the head last Tuesday on the steps of his oceanfront mansion among the Art Deco hotels of south Florida's hedonist heaven: the rollerblading, jet-set hotspot known as South Beach.</p>
<p>Cunanan has been likened to a chameleon for his ability to change his looks. The wanted poster circulated by the FBI has several pictures of the alleged &quot;spree killer&quot; looking markedly different in each one.</p>
<p>Miami Beach Police during the weekend issued a statement saying Cunanan may have shaved his body hair and begun disguising himself as a woman to evade the dragnet.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it would be easy for him. He looks like everybody we know,&quot; said Melanie Morningstar, a writer with &quot;The Wire,&quot; a weekly newspaper catering to the South Beach gay community.</p>
<p>&quot;Put a wig on him and it would be a breeze.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You see everything here. We have a lot of men that come in in drag and there's a large transvestite population, so he could blend right in,&quot; Jeff Walter, manager of the Pleasure Emporium sex shop on Miami Beach where Cunanan is believed to have shopped, told CNN.</p>
<p>South Beach, which has transformed itself from a tattered 1980s refuge for Jewish retirees and criminal immigrants to a glittery, jet-set epicentre for models and movie stars, also is one of America's gender-bending meccas.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people lined up for a recent drag club opening. With some 50 drag performers making the rounds of South Beach clubs such as Hombre and Twist, and a gay community numbering some 12,000 bolstered by thousands of monthly tourists, the drag scene is one of America's most vibrant.</p>
<p>Speciality clothing and shoe shops carry multi-coloured, man-sized platform boots and extra-large dresses. Wig shop windows are filled with bouffant neon-green and purple hairpieces and proudly display their drag clientele in photo arrays plastered on the walls.</p>
<p>At Lucky Cheng's, a South Beach dinner theatre, the waitresses are really waiters with names like Chyna Girl and Judy Too Much who perform cabaret numbers between rounds.</p>
<p>With its laissez-faire attitude and multitude of strangers, South Beach would be an ideal place for a transient transvestite to get lost.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people come for a week and stay for five years,&quot; Morningstar said. &quot;And if you're pretty like he (Cunanan) is, you're accepted automatically.&quot;</p>
<p>In a community where theatrical, even outrageous makeup and clothing is the norm, a man could dress as a woman and win acceptance, at least for a while, said University of Miami sociologist Joan Alway, who specialises in gender issues.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a strong element in that community that prizes or values the theatricality of it. There's an element where cross dressing and performing is tolerated and accepted,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;In that sense, I think it could be easy for a while to pass or participate without close examination.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI BEACH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
