<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="743183" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-French markets shrug off corporate tax hikes.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-French markets shrug off corporate tax hikes.</headline>
<byline>Christine Tierney</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>French financial markets fell on Monday after the government raised corporate taxes to enable France to qualify for European monetary union but stocks and bonds rebounded to finish with only fractional losses.</p>
<p>The bourse finished down 0.09 percent after having slid more than 1.5 percent on knee-jerk disappointment with the Socialist-led government's decision to tap Big Business for the lion's share of anticipated revenue shortfalls this year and next.</p>
<p>The bond market was slightly weaker in early trading but steadied after Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn reiterated that France would do everything possible to qualify for monetary union.</p>
<p>Traders said he did not spring any surprises and the markets were shifting their focus to U.S. Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's twice-yearly economic report to Congress on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The franc finished higher after reacting more to the dollar's dip in Europe than to the results of an audit of France's finances made public on Monday, traders said.</p>
<p>Strauss-Kahn said it showed the deficit running at 3.5 to 3.7 percent of gross domestic product, exceeding the three percent target set by the Maastrict treaty criteria for monetary union.</p>
<p>He announced steps to cut the deficit by 32 billion francs ($5.3 billion), including 22 billion generated by increases in corporate profits tax and tax on capital gains -- measures that will raise France's corporate tax rate above 41 percent for at least two years.</p>
<p>&quot;Essentially it's the corporate sector that takes the pain,&quot; economist Christopher Potts at Chevreux de Virieu told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index finished down 2.57 points, or 0.09 percent, at 2,874.12 after clawing back more than 40 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The impact on the markets was mitigated because 80 percent of what was announced today was known,&quot; said economist Jean-Louis Mourier at Louis Dreyfus Finance.</p>
<p>Jacques Chahine of consultants Jacques Chahine Finance said the tax increases would have a negative impact of between 6.5 and 7.5 percent on profits and stock prices.</p>
<p>But he said a good part of that was already priced into the bourse, which has underperformed other European markets by around 6.5 percent since the start of the month when the government flagged plans to raise business and possibly income taxes.</p>
<p>Other economists estimated a smaller impact on industry, which is starting to show the benefits of a stronger dollar and restructuring measures across many sectors.</p>
<p>Shares in retail and consumer goods companies rose against the trend on investor relief that taxes on households would not increase.</p>
<p>Pen and lighter manufacturer Bic's stock finished up 1.61 percent at 945 francs and supermarkets giant Carrefour shares gained 0.54 percent at 4,072 francs.</p>
<p>The franc rose to 3.3754 to the German mark, above its close on Friday of 3.3783 and well above Monday's early low of 3.3810 on European markets.</p>
<p>The 10-year bond future closed down 0.14 basis points at 130.22, in line with a dip in German bonds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
