<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="743347" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Boeing profits fall, but sales surge in quarter.</title>
<headline>Boeing profits fall, but sales surge in quarter.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boeing Co. sales surged but profits fell in the second quarter as the aerospace giant struggled to keep up with rising demand for commercial jets, the company said Monday.</p>
<p>The world's largest commercial aircraft maker said net income for the quarter fell to $399 million, or 55 cents a share, excluding the effects of an employee stock plan, from $468 million, or 68 cents a share, a year earlier.</p>
<p>Sales surged 48 percent to $9.29 billion from $6.28 billion as the company ramped up commercial aircraft production and expanded its space and missiles business.</p>
<p>The results for the quarter ending June 30 fell below the Wall Street consensus estimate of 59 cents a share, according to First Call, which tracks analysts' forecasts. Boeing stock was off $1.56 at $54.50 in afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said Boeing's profit margins were being squeezed by the company's efforts to ramp up production to a record 43 jets a month early in 1998 from 22.5 a month at the beginning of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no question that this ramp-up is a far greater challenge than investors expected and the company was anticipating,&quot; said Peter Jacobs, an analyst at Ragen MacKenzie in Seattle. &quot;They can get over this. It's just a matter of time.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts said investors also were nervous about a looming meeting of the European Commission on Wednesday, when it is expected to vote to block Boeing's planned $14 billion merger with McDonnell Douglas Corp.</p>
<p>After slashing employment by more than one-third in the early 1990s, Boeing has been expanding its work force by adding jobs and making acquisitions, including the purchase of Rockewell International Corp.'s aerospace buusiness last year.</p>
<p>Boeing Chairman Phil Condit said in a news release that the rapid increase in production has resulted in &quot;a substantial increase in employment, material and fabrication demand at the company and its suppliers.&quot; High overtime levels and parts shortages have caused a &quot;near-term decline in productivity,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts said profits also are being hurt by high spending on development of new models, such as the next-generation 737 line, and by strong sales of the new 777, which will carry low profit margins for its first several years of service.</p>
<p>Boeing said it expects to spend $1.4 billion on research and development in 1997, up from $1.2 billion last year.</p>
<p>Boeing also said it expects to deliver 340 to 350 commercial jetliners this year, up from a previous projection of 340. Last year, Boeing delivered just 218 jets as the company reached the end of a long industry downturn.</p>
<p>So far this year, Boeing has announced orders for 224 commercial airplanes valued at $15.6 billion, down from 225 airplanes worth $17.6 billion in last year's first half.</p>
<p>Jacobs said he expects Boeing to announce commercial jet orders worth $30 billion to $40 billion this year, compared with last year's record 717 jets worth $53 billion.</p>
<p>But he noted that even $30 billion &quot;is still a very high level by any kind of historical standards.&quot;</p>
<p>Boeing's results for the latest quarter were stated excluding the effects of the company's employee stock plan, which would have trimmed earnings to $334 million, or 48 cents a share. Boeing said results from last year's second quarter were boosted by one-time gains of $176 million, or 25 cents a share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
