<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="743468" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Alaska Air sees unit's results stabilizing in Q3.</title>
<headline>Alaska Air sees unit's results stabilizing in Q3.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alaska Air Group Inc said Monday it expects the year-over-year results of its unit, Horizon Air Industries Inc, to begin to stabilize in the third quarter and become positive as its fleet transition is completed.</p>
<p>&quot;Horizon is continuing to experience costs associated with its fleet transition,&quot; said John Kelly, chairman, president and chief executive officer of Alaska Air.</p>
<p>Horizon posted a pretax loss for the quarter of $700,000, compared to a pretax income of $2.6 million a year earlier, it said.  </p>
<p>Alaska Air said that for the second quarter it posted net income of $20.8 million, or $1.41 per share ($1.01 per share fully diluted), compared with net income of $18.0 million, or $1.24 per share ($0.88 per share fully diluted), for last year's second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Continued strong passenger loads and increasing average fares combined to produce an excellent quarter,&quot;  said Kelly, chairman, president and chief executive officer.</p>
<p>Cost control remains a top priority, he said, adding that the 6 percent increase in Alaska's cost per available seat mile was primarily due to additional staffing to handle large volumes of traffic, improve on-time performance and deal with new security requirements.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
