<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="743512" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall Street stocks seen softer at open.</title>
<headline>Wall Street stocks seen softer at open.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stocks were expected to open weaker on Monday, burdened by continued profit-taking in the tech sector and wary ahead of quarterly results from International Business Machines Corp and a speech Tuesday by Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan.</p>
<p>&quot;We're probably going to open easier,&quot; Larry Wachtel, an analyst at Prudential Securities said. &quot;The Greenspan appearance tomorrow and the IBM results after the close will hold back any kind of a snap-back. We should be on the defensive for most of the day.&quot;  </p>
<p>Greenspan will make a semi-annual testimony to the House Banking Subcommittee on Tuesday. Markets would pay close attention to anything the Fed chairman said about interest rates or inflation, analysts said.</p>
<p>IBM, which shrugged off Friday's declines in the technology sector to finish higher, was set to report second quarter earnings after the market close. The First Call consensus estimate was $1.42 per share compared to $1.26 per share in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's 500 futures index was up one point at 918. The long bond was unchanged at a 6.53 percent yield.</p>
<p>((Wall Street desk 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
