<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74357" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Alaska fund marks record income at annual meeting.</title>
<headline>Alaska fund marks record income at annual meeting.</headline>
<byline>Yereth Rosen</byline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska</dateline>
<text>
<p>A record annual income of $1.8 billion, led by healthy U.S. equity earnings of 26.15 percent, has prompted managers to consider investing a larger amount of the $17.6 billion Alaska Permanent Fund in corporate stocks, officials said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The earnings total was released at the start of the fund's two-day annual meeting of the fund, a state-owned endowment established 20 years ago and augmented each year with regular contributions from the state's oil earnings.</p>
<p>In fiscal 1996, the fund realised a 13.43 percent return on investments, led by the equity earnings, officials said.</p>
<p>Forty-nine percent of the fund was invested in U.S. and international equities. Forty-three percent was invested in fixed-income securities, which had an average annual return of 4.18 percent. The remainder was invested in real estate, which had a 7.98 percent return.</p>
<p>Under state law, the fund is allowed to invest up to half of its assets in equities.</p>
<p>At next year's legislative session, fund officials may ask the state legislature for authority to invest more of the assets in equities, said executive director Byron Mallott.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to continue to look at our statuatory allocation to see if we need to look for more investment in equities, because that's where the strength of the market is,&quot; Mallott said.</p>
<p>It is likely that fund managers would seek permission from the legislature next year to increase equity investment to 60 percent, he said.</p>
<p>The Alaska Permanent Fund was established by an amendement to the state constitution passed the year before the trans-Alaska oil pipeline began operations.</p>
<p>Conceived by former Gov. Jay Hammond, it was intended to grow through investement and perpetual deposits of about 20 percent of annual oil royalty income.</p>
<p>Fiscal year 1996, which ended June 30, was the first in which permanent fund earnings exceeded total state oil revenues. That was due to the bullish stock market, Mallott said, and is not likely to be repeated for about five years.</p>
<p>The state earned about $1.5 billion in the fiscal year from oil royalties, taxes and fees, according to Permanent Fund records.</p>
<p>In time, dwindling North Slope oil production will make the eclipse permanent, Mallott said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our surpassing oil revenue coming into the general fund is not likely to come again until after the turn of the century. At that point it will continue,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
