<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="743646" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Emerging market Eurobond issuers await stability.</title>
<headline>Emerging market Eurobond issuers await stability.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Emerging market borrowers wanting to raise new funds are waiting for the market to stabilise after volatility last week caused by fears of currency devaluations, bankers said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Some issuers have backed away, but this will be a short-lived effect and once the market quietens down we will see a resumption of new issuance,&quot; a syndicate manager at a U.S. bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;Time is running out before the summer holiday.&quot;</p>
<p>Fears that Brazil might devalue its currency after devaluations in the Philippines, Thailand and the Czech Republic led to sharp falls in Latin American debt and equity markets last week.</p>
<p>Spreads on emerging market Eurobonds widened by up to 30 basis points, and remain at these levels, after profit-taking ahead of holidays.</p>
<p>Borrowers which delayed new bond issues last week include Argentina, which had planned a $750 million global bond issue, and Brazilian private power utility Escelsa, which planned a $350 million bond.</p>
<p>Spread talk for the seven-year Argentina deal was around 175 basis points over U.S. Treasury notes last week, whereas now it would have to pay around 210 b.p. over, bankers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is still quit weak,&quot; a dealer at a European bank said. &quot;Argentina 2006 dollar bonds, for example, are trading at 280 b.p. over, up from 250 b.p. a week ago.&quot;</p>
<p>There was some talk that Argentina might come to the market this week, but many bankers said borrowers would wait-and-see.</p>
<p>&quot;The Brazilian markets will be closely watched, and investors will also want to wait for the Humphrey-Hawkins testimony to see where U.S. Treasuries are going,&quot; a Eurobond trader said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan gives his semi-annual Humphrey-Hawkins testimony on the U.S. economy. The market was expecting Greenspan to be vigilant on inflation.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasury bonds were jittery on Monday ahead of the speech, which will be closely watched for hints on future interest rate moves.</p>
<p>&quot;If markets don't get worse, there will be a flurry of activity next week, as borrowers rush to get deals done before the August holiday,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>-- Aline van Duyn, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
