<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="743719" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Mark and French franc snooze through French audit.</title>
<headline>Mark and French franc snooze through French audit.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German mark, French franc and the currencies of other European monetary union hopefuls were barely disturbed in European trading on Monday as traders shrugged off the long-awaited French public accounts audit.</p>
<p>The details of the audit were in line with market forecasts and new measures aimed at reducing the 1997 French budget deficit were either leaked well in advance or unsurprising.</p>
<p>The basic market assumption of EMU starting on time in 1999 remains in place, while concerns about slipping entry standards on national budgets were reinforced, analysts said. The net effect of that will underpin non-EMU currencies like the dollar.  </p>
<p>&quot;This still smacks of a take-it-or-leave-it approach to deficit cutting by the French and the most important market focus will be on the reaction from Germany,&quot; said Michael Burke, economist at Citibank. &quot;The market reaction has been minimal so far because it tells very little we didn't know already.&quot;</p>
<p>At 1038 GMT, the French franc was trading at 3.3790/95 compared with 3.3803/08 in late European trading on Friday and an early high Monday at 3.3810.</p>
<p>French finance minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn held a press conference on new budget measures after the details of an audit into central government finances was released.  </p>
<p>The audit showed the French budget deficit is now running at between 3.5 percent and 3.7 percent of gross domestic product. This is well above the three percent reference target for 1997 deficits laid out in the Maastricht Treaty as a precursor to EMU entry on its planned launch date of January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>As a result, Strauss-Kahn announced today a series of measures, weighted heavily toward increased taxation on the corporate rather than personal sector, to help cut the deficit closer to Maastricht targets.</p>
<p>Although he declined to give a deficit target for 1997, the new plans are expected to cut the gap to 3.1-to-3.3 percent.  </p>
<p>Strauss-Kahn said the budget measures would cut 32 billion French francs from the public deficit this year, the equivalent of 0.4 percent of GDP. He reaffirmed his commitment to starting EMU on time in 1999 and said France would meet the Maastricht goals under the same conditions as its European Union partners.</p>
<p>&quot;The French are keen to highlight their commitment to EMU and they intend to start this on time regardless,&quot; said Tony Norfield, treasury economist at ABN Amro. &quot;Ultimately this environment remains bullish for the dollar and sterling.&quot;</p>
<p>Norfield said the impact of extra EMU budget measures on economies across Europe was also dollar bullish.  </p>
<p>The Maastricht Treaty of 1991 states that to qualify for EMU annual budget deficits should be &quot;close&quot; to three percent, with exceptions made for excessive deficits caused by cyclical economic downturns. But the Treaty is vague about the extent of of what overshoot will be tolerated. As a result this is likely to remain open to political interpretation.</p>
<p>There is a body of German political opinion, notably in Bavaria, which is insisting on a strict 3.0 percent reading of the rules, but the German government and Bundesbank have recently distanced themselves from confining the target to a decimal place. They prefer to stress sustainability of the deficit reductions.  </p>
<p>&quot;The French measures are very positive for a punctual EMU start. It's still possible they will make three percent and ultimately politics will shape the fiscal outcome,&quot; said Avinash Persaud, head of currency research at JP Morgan. &quot;What this should leave us with is continued outperformance of non-EMU currencies like the dollar and sterling.&quot;</p>
<p>Persaud said this should not dissuade investors from taking out some form of market insurance against an outside chance of EMU unravelling. While he said there was now only a 20 percent chance of EMU being delayed, he said such an event could lead to currency swings of up to 10 percent.  </p>
<p>Elsewhere in Europe, reactions were similarly muted. The Swedish crown and Italian lira made the biggest gains.</p>
<p>Mark/lira slipped to 972.95/25 compared to a high just before the French news at 975.00. Analysts said the implied admission from the French that the 3.0 percent deficit target would not be met exactly would make it more difficult for Germany and France to exclude Italy from the first wave of EMU.</p>
<p>Mark/crown, meantime, fell to its 1997 low at 4.3220/50 compared with 4.3470/00 Friday as traders begin to classify the crown as a non-EMU haven like sterling and the dollar.</p>
<p>--Mike Dolan, London newsroom +44 171 542 6762</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
