<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="743920" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks fall, bonds shrug off tax hikes.</title>
<headline>French stocks fall, bonds shrug off tax hikes.</headline>
<byline>Christine Tierney</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>French stocks fell on Monday after the Socialist-led government tapped Big Business to make up the bulk of anticipated revenue shortfalls to allow France to qualify for European monetary union.</p>
<p>The stock market fell more than 1.5 percent in early trading but steadied above its lows after brokers calculated that most of the impact of the tax increases was already priced into stocks.</p>
<p>The bond market was underpinned by Finance Minister Dominique Strauss-Kahn's reaffirmation that France would do everything possible to qualify for monetary union.</p>
<p>Traders said his pronouncements did not contain any surprises and the markets were now shifting their focus to U.S. Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's twice-yearly economic report to Congress on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The franc was little changed from its close on Friday after reacting more to the dollar's dip in Europe than to the results of an audit of France's finances made public on Monday, traders said.</p>
<p>Strauss-Kahn said it showed the deficit running at 3.5 to 3.7 percent of this year's gross domestic product, exceeding the three percent limit set by the Maastrict treaty criteria for monetary union.</p>
<p>He announced steps to cut the deficit by 32 billion francs ($5.3 billion), including 22 billion generated by increases in corporate profits tax and tax on capital gains -- measures that will raise France's corporate tax rate above 41 percent for at least two years.</p>
<p>&quot;Essentially it's the corporate sector that takes the pain,&quot; economist Christopher Potts at Chevreux de Virieu told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>The bourse's blue-chip CAC-40 index was down 19.73 points, or 0.69 percent, at 2,856.96 at 1405 GMT after clawing back from an early low of 2,830.68</p>
<p>&quot;The impact on the markets was mitigated because 80 percent of what was announced today was known,&quot; said economist Jean-Louis Mourier at Louis Dreyfus Finance.</p>
<p>Jacques Chahine of consultants Jacques Chahine Finance said the tax increases would have a negative impact of between 6.5 and 7.5 percent on profits and stock prices.</p>
<p>But he said a good part of that was already priced into the bourse, which has underperformed other European markets by around 6.5 percent since the start of the month when the government flagged plans to raise business and possibly income taxes.</p>
<p>Other economists estimated a smaller impact on industry, which is starting to show the benefits of a stronger dollar and restructuring measures across many sectors.</p>
<p>Shares in retail and consumer goods companies rose against the trend on investor relief that taxes on households would not increase.</p>
<p>Pen and lighter manufacturer Bic's stock was up 0.75 percent at 937 francs, and supermarkets giant Carrefour shares were 0.69 percent higher at 4,078 francs.</p>
<p>The franc was trading at 3.3768 to the German mark, or slightly above its close on Friday of 3.3783 and well above its early low of 3.3810 on European markets on Monday morning.</p>
<p>The 10-year bond future was down 0.14 basis points at 130.22, in line with a dip in German bonds.</p>
<p>Mourier said the bond market took note of Strauss-Kahn's reaffirmation that the government would strive to meet the criteria for monetary union although he did not specify a target.</p>
<p>The deficit reduction drive did not entail any measures touching savings or otherwise affecting the bond market, he said.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452 ($ = 6.041 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
