<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74418" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-CARDINALS CLINCH CENTRAL TITLE.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-CARDINALS CLINCH CENTRAL TITLE.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH</dateline>
<text>
<p>The St. Louis Cardinals clinched their first division title in nine years with a 7-1 victory over the Pittsburgh Pirates behind two RBI apiece from Brian Jordan and Luis Alicea Tuesday.</p>
<p>Under first-year manager Tony La Russa, the Cardinals clinched the National League Central Division for their first division crown since 1987, when they won the NL East and reached the World Series.</p>
<p>&quot;When you think of all the newness, this club came together quickly,&quot; Cardinals manager Tony LaRussa said. &quot;It would have been easy to say that we'll learn a little bit and come together next year, but the guys made it a point to jell as soon as possible.&quot;</p>
<p>In Cincinnati, Willie Greene hit three home runs and drove in a career-high five runs as the Cincinnati Reds built a four-run lead on the way to a 6-3 victory over the Chicago Cubs.</p>
<p>&quot;It felt good,&quot; said Greene. &quot;I had three in Triple-A but to do it in the big leagues is exciting. I wasn't thinking about it the third time up. When I think about it, I either strike out or pop up.&quot;</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Rondell White had two hits and two RBI and Jeff Juden allowed one run in three innings of relief as the Montreal Expos snapped a four-game losing streak with a 6-2 victory over the Philadelphia Phillies.</p>
<p>The Expos temporarily moved within two games of the San Diego Padres for the National League wild-card berth. Juden (5-0), a former Phillie, allowed three hits, walked one and struck out four.</p>
<p>At Florida, Pat Rapp allowed one run over five innings and Devon White drove in three runs as the Florida Marlins routed the National League East Division champion Atlanta Braves 12-1.</p>
<p>Rapp (8-16) surrendered an RBI single to Ed Giovanola in the fourth inning for Atlanta's only run.</p>
<p>The Marlins scored six runs in the first inning, tying a club record with seven consecutive hits off Steve Avery (8-8), who did not survive the inning.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt as good as I looked,&quot; said Avery.  &quot;If I throw like that, I don't expect to be in the playoffs.  Tonight I couldn't get a guy out in the Class A playoffs.&quot;</p>
<p>In Houston, Bobby Jones fired a four-hitter for his first shutout of the season and four different players drove in runs as the New York Mets handed the Houston Astros their ninth straight loss 4-0.</p>
<p>Jones (12-8) walked two and struck out three in his third complete game of the season and third career shutout.  He</p>
<p>In Los Angeles, Ramon Martinez allowed two runs over seven innings for his seventh straight win as the Los Angeles Dodgers defeated the San Francisco Giants 6-2 to maintain their lead atop the National League West.</p>
<p>The win gives the Dodgers a 1-1/2 game lead over the San Diego Padres. Los Angeles hosts San Diego in the final three games of the season this weekend.</p>
<p>Martinez (15-6) allowed two hits, walked six and struck out six as he improved to 21-6 since last July 8th.</p>
<p>In San Diego, Dante Bichette's solo homer off Trevor Hoffman with one out in in the 11th inning lifted the Colorado Rockies past the San Diego Padres, 5-4.</p>
<p>Combined with the Dodgers' win earlier, San Diego fell 1 1/2 games behind Los Angeles for the lead in the National League West with four games left. The loss also cut San Diego's lead in the wild card race to 1 1/2 games over the Expos.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
