<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="744162" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - EMU forecasters find a fickle year in 1999.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - EMU forecasters find a fickle year in 1999.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Scott</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The euro will see the light of day in 1999 in a Europe where growth is bubbling up to trend and inflation is averaging a modest two percent, economists say.</p>
<p>On the other side of the globe, U.S. growth will be flat or even slowing down and the Japanese economy will be bursting back to life.</p>
<p>But 1999 will be an odd year.</p>
<p>The realisation of European Monetary Union (EMU) and even the approach of the millennium could ambush economic forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;Assuming we don't have too rough a path on the road to 1999, we ought to see European economies growing at trend or above,&quot; said Alistair Barr, research fellow at the London Business School's centre for economic forecasting.</p>
<p>&quot;So in growth terms, things look reasonably favourable.&quot;</p>
<p>FAVOURABLE CONDITIONS FOR LAUNCH OF EMU</p>
<p>Most economists believe that average growth in Europe will be about up to trend, and inflation fairly low, sparing the fledgling European Central Bank (ECB) from some awkward early interest rate decisions.</p>
<p>Graham Bishop, adviser on European economic affairs at Salomon Brothers in London, said 1999 should provide a relatively friendly environment for EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at Europe, the trend to economic recovery should be helpful to budget deficits, plus there'll only be minor upward inflation from previously low levels,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There seem to be no expectations of any serious upset in inflation -- trend and above-trend growth would put some upward pressure on inflation, but we're a long way from talking about a problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Barr said inflation would be close to the two percent the ECB will likely consider as constituting price stability.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if the EMU bloc includes Italy and Spain, we should have inflation around that level.&quot;</p>
<p>But the approach of EMU means economies are entering uncharted territory, making predictions difficult and varied.</p>
<p>Adrian Schmidt, international economist at Chase in London, said patchy growth in Europe by 1999, and the prospect that many countries will still face fiscal problems, mean the welcome for EMU will be less than warm.</p>
<p>&quot;The European economy is going to be rather mixed,&quot; said Schmidt. &quot;There's not much prospect of France and Germany being strong domestically...but southern Europe should be doing quite well.&quot;</p>
<p>Schmidt said the uneven growth and inflation rates across Europe made it a particularly difficult time to impose a uniform interest rate policy.</p>
<p>&quot;If we're talking about a wide EMU, the conditions won't be good,&quot; he said. &quot;The fact there is going to be a mixed picture in Europe means we're going to have an inflexible monetary policy being imposed when countries are least able to deal with it.&quot;</p>
<p>That, plus the constraints on the fiscal side of the stability pact, will emasculate governments just when some policy action is required, he said.</p>
<p>GROWTH SLOWING DOWN IN UNITED STATES</p>
<p>On the other side of the Atlantic, U.S. economic growth should be slowing down, depending on when the Federal Reserve raises interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates will have to rise significantly in the U.S., so there is a real risk of low growth rates in late 1998, early 1999,&quot; said Barr.</p>
<p>The difference in cycles means interest rates are likely to be higher in the United States than Europe at the euro's inception -- a factor which will support the new currency in its early days.</p>
<p>Economists said Japanese growth would probably be picking up. &quot;I see Japan growing significantly above trend in 1998-1999, in a bounce back from a period of sharp fiscal tightening in 1997,&quot; Barr said.</p>
<p>&quot;But it will just be a bounce back rather than a return to some golden age of Japanese growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said one of a number of possible upsets to the world economic cycle in the next few years is the degree of fiscal tightening left to be done in Europe between now and 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;Things depend quite a lot on how poor the fiscal position is now (in Europe) and how serious potential EMU members are on getting (their deficit to GDP ratios) below three percent,&quot; said Barr.</p>
<p>&quot;1998 could well be another year of fiscal consolidation which might hold growth back rather more than forecast.&quot;</p>
<p>HSBC James Capel chief European economist Stephen King also highlighted the drive to meet the Maastricht treaty criteria, which stipulate that annual government budget deficits should not exceed three percent of GDP, as a potential hiccup.</p>
<p>&quot;The risk is that countries will go into the project with deficits too high relative to where the European Central Bank would like them to be...so to offset that, the ECB may be forced to adopt tighter monetary policy than would otherwise be the case.&quot;</p>
<p>The net result of that may be tighter constraints on consumer spending than present forecasts suggest.</p>
<p>And if the fiscal, monetary and political uncertainties are not enough to cloud forecasts, economists also have to consider the wild card of the millennium.</p>
<p>&quot;The millennium effect is very important because of all the construction projects underway,&quot; said Alison Cottrell, chief economist at PaineWebber.</p>
<p>&quot;1999 is going to be an odd year.&quot; -- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 8682</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
