<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="744184" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian dlr makes rare rally, but RBA looms.</title>
<headline>Australian dlr makes rare rally, but RBA looms.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar kept the lion's share of last week's gains Monday, but the rally was far too tentative to suggest its four month-old downtrend was over.</p>
<p>The currency captured the 74 cent level in a short covering spurt late Friday, giving it a reasonable cushion above last week's 18-month low of US$0.7310. An offshore peak of US$0.7437 could not be sustained, however, and dealers doubted it would ever be while the risk of a rate cut loomed so large.</p>
<p>Many reckon the much-mulled easing could come as soon as Friday if upcoming inflation and wages data are as subdued as expected and, if so, see the dollar diving again.  </p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0700 GMT) the dollar had established a beachhead at US$0.7415/20 having pushed up from Friday's late US$0.7390/95 and the mid-week US$0.7310 low.</p>
<p>Traders said activity was thin with Tokyo off on holiday and offshore markets on hold for key economic testimony from Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan which starts on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The bounce was attributed partly to a natural correction of an oversold condition and partly to caution amongst bears in case the Reserve Bank did not after all ease this week.</p>
<p>Speculation of a cut has spurred aggressive A$ selling for the last month, particularly from U.S. and Swiss banks.  </p>
<p>The talk quietened a little last week as some wondered if the weakness of the dollar itself could stay the RBA's hand, but most analysts still felt a cut would be a better than evens bet if inflation is as well behaved as expected.</p>
<p>The median forecast for underlying inflation favours a 0.4 percent rise for the June quarter which would take the annual rate down to 1.7 percent from 2.1 in Q1, the lowest reading since the series began in 1971.</p>
<p>The consumer price index was expected to actually fall by 0.1 percent, the first drop since June 1992, taking annual growth to just 0.5 percent from 1.3 percent.  </p>
<p>Wages data on Thursday were expected to cap the improvement with analysts looking for average weekly earnings growth to slow to 4.1 percent from 4.3 percent in Q1, comfortably below the RBA's danger line of 4.5 percent.</p>
<p>Such an outcome, they argue, would justify a fifth 0.5 point easing to 5.0 percent, which would leave official rates below those in the U.S. -- an event almost without precedent.</p>
<p>The crossover would not be unjustified given Australian inflation had averaged less than that in the U.S. for most of this decade, but offshore perceptions of Australia as a high inflation, high yield country were changing at a glacial pace.  </p>
<p>Analysts suspected the reality of lower A$ returns would trigger yet more selling and see US$0.7280 support under attack, with a risk of eventually revisiting the 1995 low of US$0.7070.</p>
<p>Were the RBA to remain silent this Friday the dollar should enjoy some short-covering support but the uncertainty would be far from over since many would assume the RBA was just waiting for its next monthly board meeting on August 5.</p>
<p>Should August 6 pass with no move the market might feel safer about assuming the easing cycle was over, although some thought it not inconceivable the bank would wait for final data on wages on August 14 to see the private sector split.  </p>
<p>If all these events came and went with no news, the market would have to seriously reappraise its policy assumptions and that could see the dollar escape the four month-old downtrend.</p>
<p>In that event analysts reckoned US$0.7650 was a reasonable target although even then much would depend on whether the real side indicators like employment and retail sales showed a sustained pick up.</p>
<p>Back in the present, the dollar was holding firm at 85.75/85 yen from 85.44/54 late Friday and at 57.3 in trade weighted terms from 57.1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
