<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="744238" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian MP sentenced for defaming Suharto.</title>
<headline>Indonesian MP sentenced for defaming Suharto.</headline>
<byline>Jim Della-Giacoma</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A member of parliament from the minority Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI), Aberson Marle Sihaloho, was sentenced on Monday to nine months in jail for defaming President Suharto.</p>
<p>He was believed to be the first sitting member of parliament to have been sentenced to a prison term during Suharto's 30-year rule. He was free pending an appeal.</p>
<p>&quot;Aberson has been found guilty of deliberately defaming the president and we sentence him to nine months' jail,&quot; chief judge Soehardjo told the Central Jakarta State Court.</p>
<p>A supporter of former PDI leader Megawati Sukarnoputri, Aberson was accused of defaming Suharto in a speech at PDI headquarters in June last year during rallies to protest over Megawati's ousting as party chief.</p>
<p>He did not run in the May 29 general elections, but he retains his seat until the new parliament meets on October 1.</p>
<p>Chief defence lawyer Luhut Pangaribuan told reporters: &quot;We do not accept the decision and we will appeal.&quot;</p>
<p>Aberson denied the charges, saying the state constitution guaranteed legislators the right to criticise and express opinions different from the president's and state institutions.</p>
<p>The prosecution had sought an 18-month sentence for Aberson, who was also found guilty of defaming the armed forces d the House of Representatives. The main charge carried a possible six-year term.</p>
<p>The prosecution accused Aberson of telling a crowd of several hundred outside the PDI headquarters: &quot;Throughout the 30 years of Suharto's leadership, our fredom has been stolen and we are being colonised once again.&quot;</p>
<p>Supporters of Surjadi, the man who replaced Megawati as PDI leader at a government-backed rally in June last year, stormed the party headquarters with police support last July 27, sparking the worst riots seen in Jakarta for two decades.</p>
<p>Megawati was in court for the Monday hearing, and her supporters jeered as the verdict was announced. She made no immediate comment. Riot police provided strong security outside the court, but there was no trouble.</p>
<p>Another Indonesian legislator, Sri Bintang Pamungkas, was sentenced last February to a 34-month jail term for defaming Suharto in a speech to Indonesian students in Germany in April 1995.</p>
<p>He had been expelled from his minority United Democratic Party (PPP) in 1995, however, and as a result had lost his seat in parliament. The PDI, the PPP and the ruling Golkar are the only three parties legally permitted in Indonesia.</p>
<p>Sri Bintang was free pending a second appeal, but he subsequently was detained in March on subversion charges which carry a maximum death penalty and still awaits trial.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
