<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="744456" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Iraq could export up to 1.6 million bpd - MEES.</title>
<headline>Iraq could export up to 1.6 million bpd - MEES.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq can export up to 1.6 million barrels per day (bpd) on surge capacity but even this made it difficult for Iraq to export $1 billion of its oil under the second-stage of the United Nations oil-for-food deal, the Middle East Economic Survey (MEES) reported on Monday.</p>
<p>This export capacity questioned whether Iraq could export $1 billion of its oil in the window available under the United Nations oil-for-aid deal if exports started in early August.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraq can export around 1.3 million bpd under normal circumstances and approximately 1.5-1.6 million bpd with a surge capacity for a short period,&quot; MEES reported.</p>
<p>&quot;These figures would not allow SOMO (State Oil Marketing Organisation) to meet the $1 billion target by 6 September,&quot; the Cyprus-based newsletter reported.</p>
<p>&quot;In effect, the Iraqi oil marketing authority would have a window of only five weeks to sell $1 billion worth of oil.&quot;</p>
<p>Weaker oil prices would mean that Iraq would have to export even more oil to make the $1 billion mark, MEES reported.</p>
<p>Western diplomats said last week that Iraq would have about 40 days in which to sell around $1 billion of oil or more than 1.5 million bpd at current prices assuming that oil sales do not begin again until the last week of July.</p>
<p>SOMO had not made any commitments to its customers regarding volume for the second 180-day period of the U.N. plan which was due to come into effect on June 8 but was delayed by disagreement over the aid distribution plan.</p>
<p>Iraq sold about 660,000 bpd during the first term of the U.N. monitored deal to reach a target of $2 billion to buy food and other humanitarian goods.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
