<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="744474" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain says hanged ETA inmate killed himself.</title>
<headline>Spain says hanged ETA inmate killed himself.</headline>
<byline>Tracey Ober</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>An ETA Basque separatist rebel was found hanged in his jail cell in central Spain in an apparent suicide, Interior Ministry officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;At this time we can affirm that this squarely and clearly concerns a suicide,&quot; Interior Minister Jaime Mayor Oreja told reporters before attending a bilateral meeting with France.</p>
<p>He added that an investigating judge would have the final say on the cause of death.</p>
<p>Warders at Albacete prison in central Spain found Juan Carlos Hernando, 35, hanged with his hands loosely bound in front of him late on Sunday, prison officials said in a statement.</p>
<p>Hernando was jailed for six years in 1994 for collaboration with an armed band.</p>
<p>ETA, which has killed around 800 people in a campaign for Basque independence that has lasted almost 30 years, murdered a young politician last week in an incident that sparked national outrage and anti-ETA street protests of historic proportions.</p>
<p>Hernando was alone in his cell, suspended from a water pipe by a plastic cord &quot;similar to the kind used to adjust sports clothing&quot;, the prison statement said. Another cord that appeared to be a shoelace was wrapped around his hands with no knots tied.</p>
<p>The prison doctor tried to revive him without success, the statement said.</p>
<p>Prison officials said they were opening an investigation into Hernando's death as was usual in &quot;an event of these circumstances&quot;.</p>
<p>In February, another suspected ETA activist awaiting trial in prison was found hanged in his cell with hands and feet bound in what the government called a suicide.</p>
<p>Thousands of Basques took to the streets to protest against what they said was murder. An autopsy report said that prisoner had been depressed for several weeks and had killed himself.</p>
<p>Mayor Oreja said he lamented that Hernando had apparently killed himself at time when the country was in turmoil.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one more sign of the brutality that terrorist activity provokes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The guerrilla group kidnapped local politician Miguel Angel Blanco on July 10 and threatened to kill him 48 hours later if the government did not meet its demand that some 500 ETA inmates scattered across the country be transferred to jails in the northern Basque region.</p>
<p>The government refused, calling it blackmail, and ETA shot Blanco in the head on July 12. He died the following day.</p>
<p>Millions of Spaniards took to the streets in protest. Eight ETA prisoners have since condemned the attack. Most of them had previously renounced adherence to ETA's armed struggle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
