<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="744568" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Reuters French Advertising &amp; Media Digest -July 21.</title>
<headline>Reuters French Advertising &amp; Media Digest -July 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>----------------- FAM -------------------</p>
<p>REUTERS FRENCH ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST</p>
<p>-------------- July 21,1997 -------------</p>
<p>News from Reuters and the French press on Advertising,</p>
<p>Marketing, Media, the</p>
<p>Internet and Brand-name Products.</p>
<p>******************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING, MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>DUBAI - Arab satellite operator Arabsat says it stopped its transmissions of French channel Canal France International (CFI), saying it had shown a pornographic film and violated Islamic views of decency. It says it canncelled its contract</p>
<p>with CFI. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - The French state will keep a majority stake in</p>
<p>telecommunications operator France Telecom SA, the Finance Ministry says, the clearest indication so far that it is willing to sell a minority stake. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - France Television, which groups the two general French</p>
<p>public television stations, has asked the government for 150 million francs ($24.8 million) extra next year, newspapers say. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - TF1, France's biggest private TV station, signed an accord with ARP and BLIC, which represent independent film producers, agreeing to spend with their members 75 percent of what it is obliged to spend on co-productions, or some 150 million francs. (La Tribune)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Fun Radio and Skyrock, competing youth music radio</p>
<p>stations,are to turn their rivalry into entertainment, with their main presenters planning an hour-long &quot;face-to-face&quot; session in the autumn. (Liberation)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>BELGRADE - Serbian privatisation minister Milan Beko met</p>
<p>representatives of the French tobacco company Seita, which appears interested in investing in Yugoslavia's tobacco industry, the Information Ministry says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Mobile phone sales by France Telecom, SFR and Bouygues</p>
<p>Telecom surged by 200 percent in June compared to the same month in 1996, putting France on the road to catch up with other European countries in this market. (Le Parisien)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Orangina, which groups French beverage firm Pernod</p>
<p>Ricard SA's soft drinks, says it is revamping the image of its recently-acquired Ricqles brand to put more sparkle in the minty soda. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - The founders of Club Med quit in a dispute over the</p>
<p>direction of the French resort chain, which reported a big loss for the first half of its fiscal year. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - Customs officials have discovered that a clothes merchant at a famous Paris flea-market is supplied with practically undetectable copies of Chanel, Ted Lapidus, Timberland and Calvin Klein clothes by a highly computerised factory in a Paris suburb. (Le Parisien)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PARIS - IBM Corp and Gemplus, a French firm that makes  &quot;smart</p>
<p>cards&quot; in which a computer chip is incorporated onto a plastic card, agree to expand their activities in the market for the cards, which is expected to boom. The industry expects three billion chip-encoded cards to be in circulation by the year 2000</p>
<p>in telecommunications, banking, airline, insurance and health</p>
<p>markets. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>COLLEGEVILLE, Pennsylvania - Rhone-Poulenc Rorer Inc says it</p>
<p>receives marketing clearance in Colombia, Mexico, Peru, Uruguay</p>
<p>and Israel for Rilutek Tablets for the treatment of amyotrophic</p>
<p>lateral sclerosis (ALS), a fatal neurodegenerative disease also</p>
<p>known as Lou Gehrig's disease. (Reuter)</p>
<p>****************************************************</p>
<p>Paris Editorial, Sue Landau Tel 01.42.21.51.30</p>
<p>Fax 01.42.36.10.72</p>
<p>*****************************************************</p>
<p>For further information and news, see Reuters Adverising &amp; Media</p>
<p>Briefing. And visit us on the Internet at</p>
<p>http://www.Bizinfo.reuters.com</p>
<p>*****************************************************</p>
<p>($ = 6.041 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
