<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="744518" id="root" date="1997-07-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - July 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - July 21.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Finnish marketing reseach companies have gained a foothold in Russian and Estonian markets and are expanding their operations, sector representatives say.</p>
<p>-  By saying that the powers of the president should not be limited, Finance Minister Sauli Niinisto and Justice Minister Kari Hakamies have changed their stances, says speaker of parliament Riitta Uosukainen.</p>
<p>- In the 1990s, Finnish politicians have discovered the value of women's magazines, and many politicians, especially members of the opposition, fear being forgotten and eagerly give interviews.</p>
<p>- A bear wandering around southwestern Finland has been seen approaching the Moomin Valley amusement park.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- A stringent fiscal policy keeping long interest rates low and a moderate wage deal will help control economic growth during the next two years, says senior finance ministry official Martti Hetemaki.</p>
<p>- Competition between 'family retreat' businesses is growing ever tougher, sector representatives say.</p>
<p>- The State of Finland will not need to take extra loans this year, beyond those already planned, says deputy budget director at finance ministry.</p>
<p>- Abolishing shipping companies' rights to duty-free alcohol sales too quickly will create problems, and tax-free sales should be allowed beyond 1999, says deputy managing director at Helsinki Chambre of Commerce.</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- It would be odd to have a directly elected president with restricted powers, says Left Alliance party secretary Kari Laitinen, joining the debate over the proper scope of the powers of the Finnish president.</p>
<p>- Some young Finns shun work and prefer a free ride on social security benefits, a social worker says, calling for discussion of the topic.</p>
<p>- Police say they are catching more drunken drivers than before because motorists are reporting suspected cases by mobile phone.</p>
<p>TURUN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- The president's attendance at European Union summits is not well-reasoned, says Young Finns party MP Jukka Tarkka.</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- The central issue of the government's budget talks central issue should be to defend low-income workers, says Second Finance Ninister Arja Alho, a social democrat.</p>
<p>HUFVUDSTADSBLADET</p>
<p>- International diabetes conference has brought some 9,000 diabetes experts from 132 countries to Helsinki this week.</p>
<p>-- Nora Hallberg, Helsinki Newsroom +358-9-680 50 292</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
