<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74471" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIAN FIN MIN OPTIMISTIC ON IMF SUPPORT.</title>
<headline>BULGARIAN FIN MIN OPTIMISTIC ON IMF SUPPORT.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's Finance Minister Dimiter Kostov said on Wednesday he was optimistic about receiving crucial support from the International Monetary Fund (IMF), previously postponed.</p>
<p>&quot;I leave with optimism about support,&quot; Kostov told reporters on departure to the IMF/World Bank annual meetings in Washington. He declined to elaborate.</p>
<p>He was accompanied by the Zdravko Balyozov, head of Economic and Monetary Analysis department at the central bank.</p>
<p>The IMF postponed a second $115 million tranche of funding until the government fulfilled its pledges to close down loss- making state enterprises.</p>
<p>On Tuesday central bank governor Lyubomir Filipov said Bulgaria has fulfilled some of the bank reform and privatisation targets, but the macroeconomic farmework was overshot.</p>
<p>Annual consumer price inflation target of 105 percent was topped in August, when inflation for the first eight months reached 113 percent. Pledges to IMF to curb monthly inflation to 2.5 percent by year-end now seem unrealistic, economists said.</p>
<p>On Monday the central bank hiked annual interest rate to record-high 300 percent in a move to curb inflation and support the weakening lev. It also placed nine troubled banks under special supervision to prevent their collapse.</p>
<p>In a crisis solution meeting behind closed doors, during the weekend the socialist government decided to sell off a dozen state enterprises by year-end hoping to raise $1 billion.</p>
<p>The list of firms earmarked for sell-offs, includes the country's chemical giants Sodi Devnya and Chimko Vratsa, Pirdop Copper Smelter, Alumina aluminium producer and three cement plants among others.</p>
<p>Talks on the sell-off of a 25-percent stake in the Bulgarian Telecommunications Company started earlier this year.</p>
<p>Privatisation proceeds are expected to boost the central bank's foreign exchange reserves which will be used to stablise local banks, support the lev and cover foreign debt payments.</p>
<p>It is yet unclear whether Filipov, who said on Tuesday he will resign if his drastic bank stabilisation policies fail to work, will attend the annual meetings, but his deputies plan to depart on Friday.</p>
<p>Bulgaria stands to gain $580 million over 20 months under a reform funding agreement sealed in July. The first $115 million tranche was disbursed immediately on signing. The remaining parts of the funding, however will be provided on fulfillment of performance criteria. -- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
