<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74475" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY TO STRESS GROWTH IN 1997 - FIN.MIN.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY TO STRESS GROWTH IN 1997 - FIN.MIN.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's eighteen-month-old economic austerity programme will be transformed in 1997 into policies which aim at sustainable growth, Finance Minister Peter Medgyessy said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The (current) austerity programme will not in itself bring sustainable economic growth nor permanent stability -- this will only be brought by reforms,&quot; Medgyessy told a conference of local municipality officials at which he unveiled the key points of the draft 1997 budget.</p>
<p>The draft is expected to be finalised by the government at its cabinet meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>Medgyessy said that the country will continue budget cuts, including reduced funding in real terms for state agencies and local authorities, but will ease company tax burdens in an effort to reach two to three percent economic growth next year, compared to a two percent target in 1996.</p>
<p>Hungary also hopes to reduce its current account deficit to $1.5 billion in 1997, from this year's planned $2 billion, although Medgyessy acknowledged this forecast could be optimistic as greater economic growth may boost imports.</p>
<p>Medgyessy said Hungarians understood that the painful economic programme launched in March 1995 was necessary, but the measures, including social spending cuts, only solved immediate problems and created merely the basis of growth.</p>
<p>The stabilisation programme, which aimed at reining in the country's soaring budget and current account deficits, caused real wages to slump by ten percent last year and by a projected two percent this year.</p>
<p>Former Finance Minister Lajos Bokros, whom Medgyessy replaced in March, was often criticised for strangling the economy with high taxes and budget cuts.</p>
<p>Medgyessy said Hungary will further reduce budget spending with the budget only redistributing 49.5 percent of the GDP next year, compared with 62 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>Subsidies to agencies financed from the state budget will increase by 15 percent next year, while local authority funding will rise by 13 percent, compared with projected 18 percent inflation, he said.</p>
<p>Planned changes in the the tax and the social security system and amortization rules will favour enterprises and plug the social security's soaring deficit, which could reach 60 billion forints this year, compared with the 17.8 billion target, he added.</p>
<p>Medgyessy said one of the key points of the reforms are planned changes in the system of social security contributions, including a widen of the range of revenues upon which social security contribution is paid and a new minimum social security contribution</p>
<p>Medgyessy added Hungary will cut social security contributions in 1997 by substantially less than the previously planned 2.5 percentage points.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not like to get into a situation again when, with a 60-billion social security deficit in our back, we are searching for solutions,&quot; Medgyessy said.</p>
<p>He said he also planned to launch other regulation changes to crack down on tax evasion.</p>
<p>Hungary announced recently that it planned budget cuts of over 10 billion forints this year to plug the social security deficit and to reach the general budget target agreed with the International Monetary Fund (IMF).</p>
<p>As a condition of a stand-by loan which Hungary received from the IMF in March, the country undertook that it will keep its budget deficit below four percent of the GDP this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
