<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="744821" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSX sees coal flat, rate pressures ongoing.</title>
<headline>CSX sees coal flat, rate pressures ongoing.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coal shipments remain flat, meaning challenges for CSX Corp's railroad division, and rate pressures continue to plague the company's Sea-Land division, CSX said Tuesday at a presentation of second quarter results.</p>
<p>Merchandise traffic such as autos, chemicals and metals is growing faster than the industrial production index, but slow electricity demand and a strong dollar are hurting coal exports, said John Anderson, executive vice president of sales and marketing at CSX's rail division, CSX Transportation.</p>
<p>Coal shipments compose about a third of the revenues for CSX Transportation.</p>
<p>Given these factors, CSX Chairman John Snow said the company is &quot;reasonably optimistic,&quot; but also sees reason &quot;to be a little cautious.&quot;</p>
<p>CSX Transportation generated $1.253 billion in operating revenues in the second quarter. CSX's container shipping division generated $1.011 billion in operating revenues.</p>
<p>In all, the company reported second quarter revenues of $2.678 billion and earnings of $1.04 per share, including $0.09 a share impact from costs associated with its acquisition of Conrail.</p>
<p>Wall Street was expecting the company to report second quarter earnings of $1.07 a share, according to First Call estimates.</p>
<p>Snow said rate pressures in the containiner shipping industry should begin to ease in nine to 18 months, meaning an easier time for Sea-Land.</p>
<p>&quot;We're confident that in nine, 12 or 18 months we're going to be in a much more favorable rate environment,&quot; Snow said.</p>
<p>Snow added that Sea Land handled more load in the second quarter, even while experiencing a drop in operating expenses.</p>
<p>When asked if the unit would beat a goal of $350 million in 1997 operating earnings, Sea-Land spokesman Clint Eisenhauer said the unit is &quot;comfortable&quot; it will exceed last year's operating earnings of $318 million.</p>
<p>((Carol Huang -- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
