<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745067" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: MOTOR RACING-FIA RULES OUT PORTUGUESE GRAND PRIX.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-FIA RULES OUT PORTUGUESE GRAND PRIX.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Portuguese Formula One Grand Prix, scheduled for November 9, has been cancelled.</p>
<p>&quot;Following consultation with all the competing teams, it is clear there is no unanimous agreement to add an extra event to the 1997 Formula One world championship,&quot; the International Automobile Federation (FIA) said in a statement from its headquarters in Paris on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposed event on November 9, 1997, will therefore not take place.&quot;</p>
<p>The Portuguese race had originally been scheduled for October 26.</p>
<p>But it was replaced with the European Grand Prix at Jerez, Spain, after it appeared that required safety work at the Estoril track would not be completed in time.</p>
<p>Although the Portuguese Economy Minister stepped in and announced that the track would be ready for a race on a new date of November 9, the FIA responded that it would go ahead only if there was unanimous approval among the F1 teams.</p>
<p>The majority were in favour of the added event but it is believed McLaren, Ferrari and Sauber were against the idea.</p>
<p>FIA said it hoped the Portuguese event would be back on the calendar next year.</p>
<p>Portugal pledged to press ahead with work to modernise the twisting Estoril circuit, saying it was confident the race would return in 1998 and remain a fixture in the years ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy ministry recognises the efforts made by FIA to hold the Portuguese Grand Prix...and is certain that as a result of the necessary changes being made...a medium term contract (to stage the race) will be signed,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>The government recently took a controlling interest in the Estoril track as part of a deal to resolve a series of longstanding disputes with former owners Grao Para.</p>
<p>It has made one billion escudos ($5.5 million) available for the modifications demanded by FIA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
