<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745061" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: CYCLING-RIIS FADES AFTER UNTIMELY STOP TO RELIEVE HIMSELF.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-RIIS FADES AFTER UNTIMELY STOP TO RELIEVE HIMSELF.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>FRIBOURG, Switzerland 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bjarne Riis's bid for a place on the Tour de France podium faded on Tuesday when he succumbed to the call of nature at the worst moment.</p>
<p>&quot;He's lost his chance of the podium. He got off at the foot of the mountain to see to a natural need... It's at that point that the Mercatones started to ride,&quot; the Dane's Telekom team manager Walter Godefroot said.</p>
<p>The 1996 champion finished more than six minutes behind winner Christophe Mengin of France in the 181-km 16th stage from Morzine.</p>
<p>Riis dramatically fell four places to seventh overall eight minutes behind third-placed Marco Pantani after starting the day only 1:42 adrift of the Italian, whose second Alpine stage win on Monday made him a strong contender to finish third in Paris.</p>
<p>Pantani's Mercatone Uno team staged their attack on Riis as the main group began the ascent of the 1,778-metre Col de la Croix halfway through the stage.</p>
<p>The Danish veteran fought hard to close the gap down but could not stay with the group that also included Riis's team mate Jan Ullrich, the yellow jersey holder.</p>
<p>Riis, who went directly to the Telekom team hotel after the finish, was unavailable for comment on a stage he will no doubt prefer to forget.</p>
<p>Sources close to the Telekom team said Godefroot found his riders somewhat lacking in concentration on Monday night, talking of Paris as if the task was already done.</p>
<p>The defending champion has steadily had to set his sights lower as the Tour has progressed, having watched Ullrich snatch the yellow jersey in the Pyrenees last week.</p>
<p>Riis was set at least on sharing the podium with his German heir apparent like last year when Ullrich was second. By Monday it was down to a third-place battle with Pantani.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRIBOURG, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
