<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745097" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-BRAVES EDGE DODGERS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-BRAVES EDGE DODGERS.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jeff Blauser singled home the winning run in the 10th inning as the Atlanta Braves avoided a losing homestand with a 5-4 victory over the Los Angeles Dodgers on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a fastball or a sinker. I imagine it was a sinker,&quot; said Blauser on the pitch he hit from Dreifort. &quot;We needed that game. It was a hard-fought ball game. It's not a great homestand, but the way we won today was great.&quot;</p>
<p>Alan Embree (2-1) pitched a perfect 10th inning with two strikeouts to earn the victory.</p>
<p>All of the Dodgers' runs came on homers, including a solo shot by Eric Karros in the eighth off Chad Fox that tied the game at 4-4.</p>
<p>Fred McGriff was 3-for-4 and hit his 13th homer for the Braves.</p>
<p>At Florida, Wally Joyner had three hits, stole home and drove in a run, and pinch-hitters Mark Sweeney and Chris Jones each stroked two-run hits as the San Diego Padres routed the Florida Marlins, 10-2.</p>
<p>Tony Gwynn -- whose batting average fell to .385 -- had just one hit. The Padres collected 15 hits against four pitchers, including Marlins ace Kevin Brown and outfielder John Cangelosi, who became the first position player to pitch for Florida.</p>
<p>Cangelosi worked a hitless ninth, throwing 15 pitches, eight for strikes in his first mound appearance since 1988.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't like to do that,&quot; said Marlins manager Jim Leyland, who did it with Cangelosi in Pittsburgh.  &quot;It's a little bit of an embarrassment, really.  But you have to take care of your pitching staff.&quot;</p>
<p>In New York, Carl Everett's two-run homer with two out in the bottom of the eighth inning -- his second of the game -- lifted the New York Mets to their fifth straight win, 5-3 over the Cincinnati Reds.</p>
<p>&quot;With the sidearm, it's a little better for lefties, especially when you've seen him a few times,&quot; Everett said. &quot;I saw Sullivan earlier in the week, and he got me out with the same pitch that I hit out today. I just didn't want the sinker to beat me so I stayed on the plate and he hung a slider.&quot;</p>
<p>Reds starter Dave Burba allowed just one hit but walked five and could not get out of the sixth inning, when the Mets scored twice without hitting the ball out of the infield to take a 3-2 lead.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Kevin Polcovich, who failed to lay down a squeeze bunt three pitches earlier, hit a solo homer with two out in the seventh inning to snap a tie and lift the Pittsburgh Pirates to a 3-2 victory over the Philadelphia Phillies.</p>
<p>Al Martin accounted for the other two runs with a sixth-inning homer for Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>&quot;One bad pitch,&quot; lamented Schilling.  &quot;The ball that Martin hit out wasn't a bad pitch.  The one to Poclovich wasn't a good pitch.&quot;</p>
<p>In Montreal, Henry Rodriguez's grand slam with two outs in the bottom of the ninth inning capped a five-run rally, snapped an 0-for-15 slump and lifted the Montreal Expos past the reeling Colorado Rockies, 8-4.</p>
<p>Colorado closer Darren Holmes (3-2) started the ninth with a 4-3 run and immediately surrendered a single to Mark Grudzielanek. One out later, Chris Widger worked the hit-and-run to perfection, singling into right field. Grudzielanek, who took off with the pitch, scored all the way from first to tie the game.</p>
<p>In St Louis, rookie Matt Morris allowed just one unearned run over seven strong innings and Gary Gaetti hit his 12th home run, two doubles and three RBI as the St. Louis Cardinals defeated the San Francisco Giants, 7-2.</p>
<p>Morris (7-6) allowed five hits, walked five and struck out six in winning for the first time in four starts. He helped his own cause with two singles and an RBI.</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn't a solid effort,&quot; Morris said. &quot;I had trouble finding the plate but I was able to make the pitches when I needed to. It was nice to get a three-run lead but it took me out of my game.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
