<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745244" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Copper stocks pour into stores, hit price.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Copper stocks pour into stores, hit price.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Large tonnages of copper continued to flow into London Metal Exchange (LME) warehouses hitting the price of the red metal on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Other base metals were also influenced by inventory movements while elsewhere in commodity markets investors took a shine to the sugar market and wheat prices were boosted by export business.</p>
<p>On the LME, copper prices tumbled around $35 a tonne to $2,285 before staging a small rally at the close.</p>
<p>Traders and analysts attributed the fall to an 11,550 tonnes daily jump in the quantity of metal stored in LME approved warehouses which brought the total close to the 200,000 tonnes level and eased immediate fears of a supply squeeze on the Exchange.</p>
<p>Some traders believe that there is still more copper  to be delivered, particularly into the Singapore warehouse which has attracted metal from Korea and China, partly due to slower than expected demand in South-East Asia and also to high premiums ruling on the LME.</p>
<p>China was also reckoned to be delivering zinc into the Singapore warehouse but although 3,300 tonnes of it arrived, it was more than offset by more than 7,500 tonnes being shipped out of European stores, possibly to the U.S.</p>
<p>Traders said this was the driving force behind zinc achieving a seven year high price of $1,545 a tonne on the LME.</p>
<p>Aluminium, too, put on a firm performance with the benchmark three months delivery price gaining $6 a tonne as warehouse stocks fell by 4,750 tonnes.</p>
<p>The performance of world sugar markets surprised some traders with a move to fresh contract highs in New York and London as investors went on a buying spree.</p>
<p>But trade sources could not fathom out a fundamental reason for the rise, apart from technical factors such as chart patterns, and they were expected to be selling into the higher levels in the near future.</p>
<p>London white sugar October futures topped $330.00 a tonne at one stage before meeting some profittaking.</p>
<p>In Chicago wheat prices surged higher after Egypt confirmed buying 450,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat and said its controversial ban on imports of genetically altered crops was put on a temporary hold while discussions took place with U.S. officials.</p>
<p>On the Board of Trade September wheat futures rose more than 10 cents a bushel at one stage to around $3.50.</p>
<p>Some key prices at 1620 GMT.</p>
<p>						    Tuesday    Monday</p>
<p>Ldn Spot Gold($ per ounce)		   328.05    326.65</p>
<p>IPE Brent Crude Oil (Sep)		     18.16     18.11</p>
<p>London Metal Exchange (3 mths delivery)</p>
<p> Copper ($ per tonne)			2,300.00  2,319.00</p>
<p> Aluminium ($ per tonne)		   1,615.00  1,609.00 </p>
<p>LIFFE</p>
<p>Robusta Coffee ($/tonne) (Sep)	   1,505.00  1,547.00 </p>
<p>Cocoa (Stg/tonne) (Sep)			975.00    985.00 </p>
<p>White Sugar ($/tonne Aug)		    329.00    324.50 </p>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade </p>
<p>Wheat Sep($/bshl)				  3.48	3.33</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
