<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745234" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK govt details four possible concessions on FIDS.</title>
<headline>UK govt details four possible concessions on FIDS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Junior treasury minister Geoffrey Robinson on Tuesday detailed four possible concessions that the government might make to major British-based international companies who have protested at the planned abolition of Foreign Income Dividends (FIDS) announced in this month's budget.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to consult (with companies affected), and we made that clear, and we are looking forward to doing so,&quot; Robinson told the parliamentary committee examining the Finance Bill which implements the budget.</p>
<p>Major firms, backed by the opposition Conservatives, say the abolition of FIDS, planned to take effect in 1999, will mean that they are effectively taxed twice on profits earned abroad -- once by the foreign country involved and once by Advance Corporation Tax (ACT) in Britain.</p>
<p>Robinson told the committee the government already proposed to exclude international headquarters companies, defined as firms 80 percent owned by non-British residents, from the budget move.</p>
<p>He said one possibility would be to reduce this percentage, allowing other companies to escape.</p>
<p>Other possibilities would be to allow companies who pay more than a certain percentage of their dividends abroad to reclaim ACT; to relate their ACT liabilities to what they historically paid; or to keep FIDS but to restrict the proportion of total dividends which they could represent.</p>
<p>Conservative treasury spokesman David Heathcoat-Amory earlier warned the government they could drive some companies out of Britain unless they made concessions.</p>
<p>&quot;Companies like B.A.T or RTZ -- there are many of them -- would be tempted to relocate wholesale overseas. Why stay in the UK if they are treated like this,&quot; he said. -- London Newsroom +44 171 5427767</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
