<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745295" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian Imperial Bank to buy Oppenheimer.</title>
<headline>Canadian Imperial Bank to buy Oppenheimer.</headline>
<byline>Paul Casciato</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce, Canada's second biggest bank, said on Tuesday that its CIBC-Wood Gundy brokerage unit agreed to acquire mid-sized Wall Street brokerage Oppenheimer &amp; Co. for $525 million.</p>
<p>Toronto-based CIBC said the widely anticipated deal consisted of $350 million in cash and $175 million in a retention pool to be paid out over three years. The deal, which is subject to regulatory approval, is expected to close by the end of the year.</p>
<p>CIBC-Wood Gundy Chief Executive Michael Rulle will become chief executive of the merged firm, to be named CIBC-Oppenheimer Corp. Oppenheimer Chairman and co-Chief Executive Stephen Robert and President and co-Chief Executive Nathan Gantcher will become vice chairmen.</p>
<p>CIBC-Wood Gundy President John Hunkin told a news conference that the purchase would reduce CIBC's earnings by C20 cents (15 cents U.S.) a share in either 1997 or 1998 but add about 5 percent to CIBC's bottom line in the year after the deal was completed.</p>
<p>Industry insiders said the deal would wed CIBC-Wood Gundy's Wall Street loan financing operations to the high-end retail brokerage business of Oppenheimer.</p>
<p>&quot;They don't have much underwriting activity. (They are at) at the lower end of the lead underwriters list,&quot; Brown Brothers analysts Raphael Soifer said of Oppenheimer.</p>
<p>CIBC is among the top 10 in U.S. loan underwriting and is second-ranked arranger of credit derivatives and the third largest commercial paper asset securitization provider in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;The brokerage here (CIBC-Wood Gundy) is in all the businesses that we are not in,&quot; said Oppenheimer Chairman and co-Chief Executive Stephen Robert.</p>
<p>Commenting before the announcement of the deal - the details of which were widely reported beforehand -- the head of CIBC-Wood Gundy Canadian rival Midland Walwyn called the Oppenheimer acquisition a good strategic move for CIBC.</p>
<p>&quot;I think them (CIBC) or anybody else acquiring an investment dealer or bank in the U.S. is probably a good move. Whether that's the right firm and that's the right price I don't know,&quot; Midland Walwyn Chief Executive Robert Schultz told Reuters.</p>
<p>Analysts said Oppenheimer's dowry was a raft of high-net-worth clients and a strong equity presence for CIBC-Wood Gundy's Wall Street operations.</p>
<p>Oppenheimer primarily is a brokerage firm serving high-net-worth individuals, Soifer said. The brokerage has somewhere between 500 to 1,000 brokers looking after such clients, he said.</p>
<p>An Oppenheimer spokesman said the firm's brokerage arm posted revenues of $780 million in the fiscal year ended April 30. He added the investment bank manages more than $11 billion in client money.</p>
<p>Oppenheimer is the latest in a string of U.S. brokerage acquisitions by banks. NationsBank Corp is acquiring Montgomery Securities for $1.2 billion; BankAmerica Corp. is buying Robertson Stephens &amp; Co for $540 million; Swiss Bank Corp. bought Dillon Read &amp; Co. for $600 million in May; and Bankers Trust New York Corp bought Alex Brown &amp; Sons for $1.7 billion in April.</p>
<p>The deal also comes amid heavy buying by Canada's big six banks, which in the past month have made significant acquisitions in the trust, life insurance and banking businesses.</p>
<p>CIBC stock rose C2.75 ($2 U.S.) to C$40.65 ($29.67 U.S.) on the Toronto Stock Exchange on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
