<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745274" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: New cancer lamp could spare women surgery.</title>
<headline>New cancer lamp could spare women surgery.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Women suffering from a pre-cancerous gynaecological condition may be spared surgery if a new treatment being tested by British doctors is successful, a medical charity said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Cancer Research Campaign said 20 women are taking part in a trial to test a new lamp that acts like a laser and has already worked well with malignant and non-malignant skin conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;The lamp is quick and simple to use, costs at least 10-20 times less than a laser and is drastically cheaper than surgery and the nursing costs which go with it,&quot; Dr Colin Whitehurst, of the Paterson Institute in Manchester, central England, said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We already know it is successful in treating skin cancers and have high hopes for its success in the treatment of other diseases,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>All of the women taking part in the trial at St Mary's Hospital in Manchester suffer from vulval intra-epithelial neoplasia (VIN), which causes sore, irritated and painful skin. In five to 10 percent of cases VIN can go on to become cancerous.</p>
<p>The lamp is about the size of a toaster. A concentrated beam of light is cooled and passed through a series of optical elements onto the skin, which has been treated with a photosensitive drug four hours earlier.</p>
<p>Doctors will know if the trial is successful in about three months.</p>
<p>The standard treatment for VIN is either laser light which burns the skin and causes scarring or surgery to remove it.</p>
<p>&quot;The invention is very exciting for the campaign and for cancer sufferers everywhere,&quot; said Gordon McVie, the director general of the Cancer Research Campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;It is gratifying to see the lamp, which was developed for skin cancer, being used for other types of the disease.&quot;</p>
<p>The lamp, which was invented by Whitehurst and funded by the campaign, is also being tested on gastro-intestinal cancer.</p>
<p>The campaign has applied for a patent in Britain and has signed deals with companies in Canada and Australia to market it.</p>
<p>It hopes the lamp will be commercially available before 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
