<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745276" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Staff oppose Lufthansa/Menzies joint UK cargo plan.</title>
<headline>Staff oppose Lufthansa/Menzies joint UK cargo plan.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trade unions are resisting a plan for closer links in the UK between Deutsche Lufthansa AG and the airfreight division of John Menzies Plc, Menzies transport services division chief executive Peter Smith told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He would not comment on reports circulating at London Heathrow that negotiations focused on Lufthansa and Menzies forming a joint cargo handling company at the airport.</p>
<p>Union officials said a key factor is that workers could risk losing travel benefits -- one issue behind a current dispute between British Airways and a group of catering unions.</p>
<p>Kevin Egan, regional controller of the Manufacturing, Science and Finance (MSF) union, said he understood approval to form a joint British handling company plan had been given by the main Lufthansa Cargo AG board in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>He said the union, which represents about 200 - &quot;the majority&quot; - of the German carrier's Heathrow ground handling staff, was determined to fight any such plan.</p>
<p>&quot;I have asked for a meeting with the (Lufthansa Cargo) main board. We want to stop this proposal. Our members are happy with the salaries, benefits and pension arrangements provided by Lufthansa Cargo and want to stay with the airline,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Menzies' Smith said talks with Lufthansa were at an early stage and no firm decisions had yet been made. No comment was available from Lufthansa Cargo UK.</p>
<p>At present, Menzies company Concorde Express supplies 30 to 40 percent of all manpower at the Heathrow cargo terminal, which is operated by 100 percent-owned Lufthansa subsidiary Lufthansa Airport Ground Services (LAGS), both for the German carrier and other airline customers.</p>
<p>&quot;Lufthansa is looking at new ways of improving and developing its cargo services and we are in discussions on where we might extend our co-operation together,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>He added that Concorde Express &quot;knows a lot about operating warehouses&quot; and said it provided all labour, including supervisors, at express carrier DHL's Heathrow cargo terminal.</p>
<p>Egan said that if his members were required to join a new joint Lufthansa/Menzies cargo handling company, the reduced travel benefits they receive from the airline could be jeopardised.</p>
<p>&quot;IATA regulations state that staff must be mainline airline employees to obtain these benefits,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The formation of a joint company could see this benefits reduced, or more likely removed. This is exactly the same scenario being faced by British Airways' catering employees, a dispute in which the MSF is also involved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that the only way his members' travel benefits could be guaranteed would be for Lufthansa to take a majority stake in the proposed new joint handling company</p>
<p>LAGS MSF members will meet later on Tuesday to discuss the Lufthansa/Menzies issue.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be asking the Lufthansa Cargo board: What are you up to? We want it stopped,&quot; said Egan.</p>
<p>Smith said he did not expect any union problems because, &quot;as well as Lufthansa, our own staff are also unionised&quot;. -- Bob Murphy, Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+5017</p>
<p>www.racs.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
