<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74537" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Southwest Air sees cost pressures continuing.</title>
<headline>Southwest Air sees cost pressures continuing.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southwest Airlines is fighting to put a lid on creeping cost increases but will face continuing pressures in coming months, particularly in maintenance, Chief Financial Officer Gary Kelly said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to drive the costs down. That's what we are working towards, but it is far from a done deal. We've got a lot of work to do to achieve that,&quot; Kelly told Reuters.</p>
<p>Southwest is trying to make maintenance operations more efficient and launch a new reservations system to reverse a trend which saw costs per available seat mile rise to 7.49 cents in the first half of 1996, up 6.1 percent from 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't promise we'll do it, but we are certainly not sitting idly by watching the costs creep up,&quot; Kelly said.</p>
<p>He said in an interview that high fuel prices and a 4.3 cents per gallon fuel tax accounted for about half of the 6.1 percent increase in Southwest's costs. Any fall in fuel prices would bring immediate relief, he said, adding that industry leaders are also lobbying for repeal of the fuel tax.</p>
<p>Also hurting is a recent increase in maintenance work required for the engines of Southwest's fleet of Boeing 737s.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that next year we are probably looking at higher maintenance costs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kelly said the increased maintenance work did not indicate any fundamental problem with the engines but was instead due to typical quirks of timing.</p>
<p>&quot;The engines aren't precise in terms of when they need to be maintained. There is a fair amount of variability as to when the engine actually shows it needs to be pulled and taken to shop,&quot; Kelly said.</p>
<p>He said maintenance work in the current third quarter has been &quot;pretty heavy&quot; although the fourth quarter &quot;is shaping up to be real light&quot;.</p>
<p>Despite its rising costs, Southwest posted record profits in the first half of the year and still has a cost structure envied by its competitors.</p>
<p>&quot;While we don't like where we are, we are still way above the rest of the industry,&quot; Kelly said earlier at a briefing with journalists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
