<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745437" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Turkmen economy in crisis as gas exports halted.</title>
<headline>Turkmen economy in crisis as gas exports halted.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Solovyov</byline>
<dateline>ALMATY, Kazakhstan 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkmenistan's shaky economy has been severely hit by the halt to vital gas exports, and experts and officials say gas supplies to well-to-do Western Europe via Russian pipelines could be the answer to the crisis.</p>
<p>Figures released by Turkmenistan's State Statistics Committee on Tuesday revealed what could be the ex-Soviet republic's worst economic performance during six years of its troubled independence from Moscow.</p>
<p>The report said Turkmenistan's industrial output nose-dived 35.2 percent in the first half of this year from year-ago levels, while its trade surplus shrank in January-May to a mere $19 million from $374 million in the first five months of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The bad data for the first half of the year are largely due to the suspension of gas exports,&quot; a committee official told Reuters from the Turkmen capital of Ashgabat.</p>
<p>Gas production is the backbone of Turkmen industry and by far its most important export earner.</p>
<p>Turkmenistan, owed around $2 billion by other former Soviet republics for natural gas exports, halted supplies of the blue gold in March. Ukraine alone is said to owe around $1 billion, with many debts dating back to 1993.</p>
<p>But having halted exports to cash-strapped states like Ukraine, Turkmenistan -- a desert Central Asian country with a population of around four million -- may also have doomed its export-oriented gas extraction business to deep recession.</p>
<p>Output of natural gas plummeted in June to 0.551 billion cubic metres (bcm) from 2.689 bcm in March.</p>
<p>Turkmenistan, which boasts huge reserves of natural gas estimated at 21 trillion cubic metres and which ambitiously plans to boost production to 284 bcm by the year 2000 from 35 bcm last year, exports gas only via Russian pipelines.</p>
<p>In line with a deal signed last year between Russia's gas monopoly Gazprom and Turkmenistan, the Russian partner was to allow the Central Asian state to export 20 bcm of gas to Europe this year and around the same amount to ex-Soviet states.</p>
<p>But the ex-Soviet republics were unable to pay, while Turkmenistan officials said there have been no gas exports to Western Europe at all since January this year, when the contract with Gazprom came into force.</p>
<p>Turkmen officials and Western energy analysts agree that Turkmenistan will need a new deal with Gazprom in order to break through to the paying markets in Western Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Very soon, probably in August, (Turkmen President Saparmurat) Niyazov will visit Moscow, where this issue will be a topic of his talks with Russia's (President) Boris Yeltsin,&quot; an official from the state-run Turkmenneftegaz oil and gas company told Reuters.</p>
<p>Some energy analysts say the talks could be tricky.</p>
<p>&quot;Turkmenistan basically needs to come to an agreement with Gazprom to get access to markets in Western Europe, and it may not be in Gazprom's interests to allow this access,&quot; said Stephen O'Sullivan from London-based MC Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;One day Ukraine will be good but at the moment it faces a shortage of cash and can't really pay for the gas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Turkmenistan and a Western consortium plan to build a giant gas pipeline to Pakistan across the north of Afghanistan, but the project is hampered by a civil war raging in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Against the backdrop of a gas sector in deep crisis, aggravating general economic chaos, Turkmenistan's Niyazov, who enjoys a Soviet-era personality cult and rules his nation with a firm hand, may now be facing the acute problem of finding funds to provide the country with enough bread until the new harvest.</p>
<p>Niyazov's plans to achieve self-sufficiency in grain were ruined this year by a paltry harvest of 640,000 tonnes, barely half the initial target of 1.2 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The official Turkmen Press news agency has said that last year Turkmenistan spent $800 million on substantial grain imports, when it harvested a meagre 480,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>It said Niyazov already sacked three regional heads and a deputy prime minister over the poor crop this year, but has not given any estimates of Turkmenistan's possible grain imports.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURKM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY, Kazakhstan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
