<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745405" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin throws out controversial religion bill.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin throws out controversial religion bill.</headline>
<byline>Gareth Jones</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin on Tuesday rejected a controversial bill, opposed by the United States and Pope John Paul II, that would have imposed tough new curbs on religious freedom in Russia.</p>
<p>In a statement released by the Kremlin, Yeltsin said he had reluctantly decided not to sign the draft law &quot;On Freedom of Conscience and Religious Association&quot; because it contradicted Russia's constitution guaranteeing equality for all confessions.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a difficult decision,&quot; he said, noting that the powerful Russian Orthodox Church and a majority of deputies in parliament's lower house, the State Duma, had supported the bill.</p>
<p>&quot;But many articles in the bill infringe the constitutional rights and freedoms of the citizen, establish inequality of different confessions and contradict international obligations undertaken by Russia,&quot; Yeltsin said.</p>
<p>The bill, overwhelmingly approved by both the Duma and the upper house, the Federation Council, favoured traditional faiths in Russia. Apart from Orthodoxy, which Russians closely associate with their culture and national identity, these include Islam, Buddhism and Judaism.</p>
<p>It said only confessions that were registered at least 15 years ago -- when religion was still tightly controlled by the atheistic Communist Party -- could qualify as &quot;religious organisations&quot;.</p>
<p>Others would have had to wait 15 years before applying for full legal rights.</p>
<p>The bill would also have imposed new restrictions on foreign missionaries operating in Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;Signing the bill in its present form...would have led to religious conflicts inside the country,&quot; said Yeltsin, who rejected the bill while on holiday in central Russia.</p>
<p>Supporters of the law, which included the powerful Russian Orthodox Church, said it would help control the big post-communist explosion in religious sects that have fed on Russians' poverty, spiritual hunger or simple curiosity.</p>
<p>Japan's notorious Aum Shinri Kyo, for example, whose members stand accused of killing 12 people by releasing deadly nerve gas on the Tokyo subway in 1995, had many followers in Russia.</p>
<p>Critics of the bill argued that it marked a step back to Soviet-style control of religion and that it violated the constitution by giving a few major confessions big advantages over minority religions.</p>
<p>The Pope said the law threatened the Roman Catholic Church's survival in Russia, and the U.S. Senate had threatened to withhold aid worth about $200 million if it had been approved.</p>
<p>Last week the Russian foreign ministry said the U.S. Senate pressure could be counter-productive, raising fears among human rights groups that Yeltsin might sign the bill in a fit of nationalist pique and not on its possible merits.</p>
<p>Human rights groups had said they would appeal to the Council of Europe's Parliamentary Assembly and to Russia's Constitutional Court if Yeltsin approved the law.</p>
<p>The bill now goes back to parliament, in summer recess until September, for reconsideration. Yeltsin's veto could be overturned by a two-thirds majority in both chambers.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has recently vetoed a range of bills passed by the Communist-dominated Duma, including one that would block the return of art treasures seized in Germany by the Soviet army after World War Two.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
