<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745588" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: At least 30 Colombians said massacred by death squad.</title>
<headline>At least 30 Colombians said massacred by death squad.</headline>
<byline>Karl Penhaul</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A right-wing death squad massacred about 30 people and tortured others in a remote village of eastern Colombia, Red Cross and local officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>The attack took place in Mapiripan in Meta province over the weekend, but Teddy Torbeaum, head of the Red Cross in Meta province, told Reuters the final death toll was not yet clear because bodies were thought to be scattered in isolated parts of the surrounding countryside.</p>
<p>&quot;The mayor of Mapiripan ... told me that at least 30 people had been massacred. But we will not know exactly how many dead there are until we can recover the corpses,&quot; Torbeaum said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Samper's government condemned the massacre in a written statement and said a team of investigators and human rights officials had been sent to the area.</p>
<p>&quot;The national government, headed by President Samper, deplores this vile assassination of humble peasants... We are endeavouring to find out first-hand the circumstances of this latest massacre that has shocked the nation,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Police and army troops flew to Mapiripan, a village of about 1,000 inhabitants, aboard 10 helicopters.</p>
<p>Gen. Agustin Ardila, head of the army's Fourth Division, told reporters it was too early to say what had happened.</p>
<p>Municipal council employee Luis Prieto told Reuters a right-wing death squad arrived in the village early last week and later carried out the killings.</p>
<p>&quot;This paramilitary gang has been coming in and out of the village for the last week. Then they began killing people...at least 25 or 30 people have died but we have not been able to go out into the rural area near the village to check,&quot; Prieto said in a phone interview.</p>
<p>Six victims were found within the village boundaries -- at least two of them had been beheaded, Prieto said. Local media reported that the gang had tortured other people and threatened to mutilate them with chain-saws.</p>
<p>Witnesses said a gang of more than 100 paramilitary fighters entered the village, killing three people in the square and dragging others off to more isolated areas before murdering them.</p>
<p>&quot;These people were dressed in uniforms like the army and were armed to the teeth,&quot; villager Susana Perez told Reuters by phone. &quot;They had pistols, machineguns and knives. Everybody here was terrified.&quot;</p>
<p>The gang scrawled graffiti on walls saying &quot;Death to Guerrillas&quot; and &quot;United Self-Defence Groups of Colombia&quot;, Perez said.</p>
<p>Right-wing death squads, which call themselves self-defence groups, frequently target those they suspect of being leftist rebel sympathisers. Provincial governor Alfonso Ortiz said guerrilla groups had traditionally had a strong presence in the area.</p>
<p>Red Cross officials said hundreds of villagers, fearing further violence, fled in the wake of the killings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
