<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745692" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Police arrest two for murder of Mexico journalist.</title>
<headline>Police arrest two for murder of Mexico journalist.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican authorities said on Monday they had arrested two men and identified two others who were involved in the murder of a crusading anti-drug journalist whose death was probably ordered by a cocaine lord.</p>
<p>Benjamin Flores Gonzalez, 29, was gunned down in broad daylight last Tuesday outside the offices of the La Prensa newspaper he edited in the town of San Luis Rio Colorado, on the border of Arizona in Mexico's northern Sonora state.</p>
<p>The Sonora attorney general's office said one man, Vidal Zamora, had already confessed to the murder and his family testified he had planned the crime and had already accepted money for the hit.</p>
<p>Reporters at La Prensa who witnessed Flores's killing identifed another man, Luis Enrique Rincon Muro, as the gunman. Both men are now in jail.</p>
<p>In a statement, the officials said they were also looking for two brothers of drug lord Jaime Gonzalez Gutierrez, in prison on narcotics charges, for masterminding the murder.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything points to the idea that these men murdered Mr Flores Gonzalez in revenge for ... his constant reports and commentaries (about the drug trade),&quot; the statement said, referring Flores' investigative reports into the drug trade published in La Prensa.</p>
<p>Earlier reports had said a man known as Rolando Arroyo Palacios had been arrested for the crime, but officials on Monday denied that was the case.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
