<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745716" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Goldman Sachs forecasts NZ dlr slide to US$0.62.</title>
<headline>Goldman Sachs forecasts NZ dlr slide to US$0.62.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York-based investment bank Goldman Sachs expects the kiwi dollar to slip to 62 U.S. cents over the next six months, the New Zealand Press Association reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Goldman Sachs forecast the kiwi at 64 cents three months out, falling to 62 cents six-months out, and returning to 64 cents one-year out.</p>
<p>The kiwi was trading at 65.0 U.S. cents on Wednesday morning.  </p>
<p>&quot;In the near term, some support seems available around the 64 cent area but we would look to sell or stay short for a target of 62,&quot; the bank said in its Weekly Analyst newsletter.</p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has consistently viewed the New Zealand dollar as over-valued in recent years.</p>
<p>It said it had revised its forecasts on the deterioration in business sentiment reported in the New Zealand Institute of Economic Research quarterly survey of business opinion.  </p>
<p>While the recent sell-off in the kiwi, in line with the Reserve Bank's monetary conditions index (MCI), had led to a sharp rise in short-term interest rates, Goldman Sachs said that was unlikely to support the kiwi.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will believe these rates are not sustainable,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed, in the next few weeks the markets will look ahead to the September monetary policy statement in anticipation of a further additional easing in the MCI profile over the next six to nine months.  </p>
<p>&quot;We now see the kiwi dropping to 62 U.S. cents in the next six months as the RBNZ shifts to a policy of containing the economy's weakness.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
<p>-- e-mail wellington.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
