<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745735" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL palm oil ends down on weak fundamentals, soyoil.</title>
<headline>KL palm oil ends down on weak fundamentals, soyoil.</headline>
<text>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES	   PALM OIL PHYSICALS</p>
<p>(3rd pos)    1,155 rgt/tonne	    July (south) 1,195 *</p>
<p>Open/Hi/Low  1,165/ 1,165/1,151	 Prev close 1,207.50</p>
<p>Prev settlement 1,169		     * sellers prices</p>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES - Ended weaker on renewed selling due to weak fundamentals and lower Chicago soyoil futures overnight. Further downside expected although a weak ringgit against dollar limiting fall. Oct futures seen testing next support of 1,137-1,142 ringgit.</p>
<p>PALM OIL PHYSICALS - Also weakened. Activity focussed on nearby crude palm oil and RBD palm olein.  </p>
<p>Traders said concern about rising stocks continued to cloud the market.</p>
<p>They said production remained robust and offtake was not sufficient to keep stocks from piling up.</p>
<p>Private crop forecaster Ivan Wong has estimated stocks to reach 1.06 million tonnes by end-September. For end-July, he forecast stocks at 865,000-875,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Official figures from the Palm Oil Registration and Licensing Authority (PORLA) placed stocks at the end of June at 786,123 tonnes.  </p>
<p>At the close, third-month October futures contract was down 14 ringgit at 1,155 ringgit ($440.84) a tonne.</p>
<p>Immediate support for the contract is pegged at around 1,137-1,142 ringgit.</p>
<p>Physicals prices were also marked down.</p>
<p>July (south) crude palm oil was offered at 1,195 ringgit ($456.11) a tonne against bids at 1,190. It was traded from 1,195 to 1,190.</p>
<p>July (central) saw offers at 1,185 ringgit against bids at 1,180.  </p>
<p>Aug (south) was offered at 1,195 ringgit against bids at 1,190. It was traded from 1,195 to 1,190.</p>
<p>Aug (central) was offered at 1,185 against bids at 1,180. It saw trades at 1,180 and 1,175.</p>
<p>In refined palm oil, Aug RBD palm oil was offered at $485 a tonne FOB Malaysia, Sep at $482.50 and Oct/Nov/Dec also at $482.50.</p>
<p>Aug RBD palm olein saw offers at $522.50, Sep at $517.50 and Oct/Nov/Dec at $515. Aug was traded at $521 and $520, Sep at $515 and Oct/Nov/Dec at $515 and $513.</p>
<p>Aug RBD palm stearin was offered at $365, Sep at $362.50 and Oct/Nov/Dec also at $362.50. Aug was traded at $362.50 and $361.50.</p>
<p>Aug/Sep RBD palm fatty acid distillate saw offers at $290.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813) ($1=2.6200 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
