<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745761" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Criminal cases test legality of Hong Kong judiciary.</title>
<headline>Criminal cases test legality of Hong Kong judiciary.</headline>
<byline>Tan Ee Lyn</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lawyers argued on Tuesday that three people facing criminal charges should be freed in the first challenge on the legitimacy of Hong Kong's legal system to reach an appeals court after the territory's handover to China.</p>
<p>The case was among a number working their way through the courts which experts say will test the judiciary's independence and show whether rule of law will survive in Hong Kong after its return to China by Britain on July 1.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, protesters denounced Tung Chee-hwa, Hong Kong's China-appointed leader, for his positions on deporting children here illegally, labour rights laws and free speech.</p>
<p>Tuesday's appeal hearing opened with two lawyers arguing to have a criminal case overturned by challenging the legitimacy of the post-handover legal system and China-appointed legislature.</p>
<p>The Provisional Legislature replaced an elected assembly on July 1, when China resumed sovereignty over the 156-year-old British colony.</p>
<p>The lawyers argued that their clients -- charged with criminal conspiracy before July 1 -- should be freed because the charges had ceased to exist after the handover.</p>
<p>Defence lawyers argued the provisional legislature did not adopt Hong Kong's common laws when China took over, leaving it with no laws other than the 13 ordinances adopted by the interim assembly under an act passed in the early hours of July 1.</p>
<p>Chief Judge Patrick Chan of the Appeal Court said the case was of utmost importance because of the legal precedent involved and must be dealt with as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, trade unions, political parties and pro-democracy groups staged a protest near Tung's office to denounce new powers allowing police to ban protests and attacked the suspension of labour rights laws.</p>
<p>They also assailed a new law which threatens to deport young Chinese migrants for entering Hong Kong illegally. Critics say the children are entitled to residency rights because at least one parent is a permanent resident in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Dozens of children and their families have won legal aid to fight the new law which lawyers say contravenes the Basic Law, Hong Kong's new constitution.</p>
<p>Experts said confidence in the new government and the rule of law would plummet if the outcome of these legal challenges showed judges' impartiality had yielded to political expediency.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now entering a phase of legal challenges,&quot; said human rights and legal expert Nihal Jayawickrama.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot will depend on how the courts will respond to the challenges placed before them,&quot; Jayawickrama told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The critical issue is how the lawsuits will be handled, if judges will still have autonomy in giving their judgements and if the courts will have the final say,&quot; said analyst Li Pang Kwong at the Lingnan College.</p>
<p>Li said the outcome of the various cases could shake confidence in Hong Kong's legal system if they were seen to be judged and decided on political criteria.</p>
<p>On Monday a Hong Kong judge called for an urgent hearing of lawsuits against the new immigration law which targets children from the mainland. He told lawyers to identify test cases with the most serious legal issues, for hearings in August.</p>
<p>Despite criticism from labour groups, the government is also pressing ahead to put five labour rights laws on hold and plans to have experts review them, said Jacqueline Willis, chief of the government's Labour Advisory Board.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
