<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745858" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FBell Atlantic, Nynex report higher earnings.</title>
<headline>FBell Atlantic, Nynex report higher earnings.</headline>
<byline>Eric Auchard</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bell Atlantic Corp. and Nynex Corp. on Tuesday reported higher earnings that were a shade above expectations on Wall Street, putting them in a solid position to complete their planned $24 billion merger next month.</p>
<p>Bell Atlantic said second-quarter operating earnings rose 11 percent to $514 million in the quarter while Nynex said earnings rose 11 percent to $431 million.</p>
<p>Bell Atlantic sales rose 7 percent to $3.44 billion from $3.22 billion, while Nynex revenues rose 2 percent to $3.51 billion from $3.44 billion.</p>
<p>Bell Atlantic, which offers local services in six states in the Mid-Atlantic region and Washington, D.C., said demand for second phone lines and more profitable services such as caller ID boosted results about 20 percent from a year earlier.</p>
<p>Nynex, whose service region covers six Northeastern states, said growth was fuelled by 50 percent increases in enhanced calling features and by solid growth in business customer phone access systems.</p>
<p>&quot;In the face of increasing competition in our core businesses, revenues are rising, expenses are in check and operating income is increasing at double-digit rates,&quot; Bell Atlantic Chairman Raymond Smith said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;With the commitments we have just made to the FCC, we anticipate that our merger with Nynex soon will clear the final hurdle at the commission with no additional financial impact on our new company,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bell Atlantic and Nynex said Saturday that they would agree on concessions with the Federal Communications Commission designed to open their local markets to rivals.</p>
<p>In return, a majority of FCC commissioners said they were ready to vote to approve the merger, the final regulatory step before the companies can close their merger, one of the largest in U.S. corporate history.</p>
<p>The combined company, to be known as Bell Atlantic Corp., will be the nation's largest local phone company, controlling nearly one-third of U.S. local access lines across a region stretching from Maine to Virginia.</p>
<p>The results at both companies were slightly above expectations among Wall Street analysts, according to First Call, which tracks estimates.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's reports show they are well on track to meeting earnings expecations for the remainder of the year,&quot; J.P. Morgan analyst Simon Flannery said of the separate reports.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the merger's synergies will lead to combined earnings growth of 10 to 12 percent over three years,&quot; Flannery said, looking ahead beyond the completion of the merger, which is expected to close in early August.</p>
<p>&quot;This says that they've got very good momentum going into the merger,&quot; Montgomery Securities analyst Bill Vogel said.</p>
<p>The results excluded one-time charges both companies took to write down a joint investment in a wireless video company, CAI Wireless Services Inc. Bell Atlantic took a charge of $15 million, or 3 cents a share, while Nynex charged off $20.5 million, or 5 cents a share.</p>
<p>Nynex also took one-time charges of about $30 million, or 7 cents a share, in the latest and year-earlier quarters to cover costs related to early retirement plans meant to cut its work force by about 20,000 employees through 1998.</p>
<p>Bell Atlantic stock gained $2.69 to close at $74.19 and Nynex stock climbed $2.31 to $56.625, both in consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
