<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="745911" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Disney results boosted by parks, movies.</title>
<headline>Disney results boosted by parks, movies.</headline>
<byline>Jerry Dubrowski</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Walt Disney Co. on Tuesday reported better-than-expected profits for its fiscal third quarter, reflecting record attendance at its theme parks and solid results from films such as &quot;Con Air, &quot;Jungle to Jungle&quot; and &quot;Scream&quot;.</p>
<p>The Burbank, Calif.-based entertainment giant earned $473 million, or 69 cents a share, in the three months ended in June, up from proforma results of $401 million, or 58 cents, a year ago. Revenues rose 2 percent to $5.2 billion.</p>
<p>The quarterly results were slightly above Wall Street's consensus estimate of 67 cents a share, sending Disney's stock sharply higher. By midafternoon, it was up $1.81 to $77 in New York Stock Exchange composite trading.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said Disney's broadcasting unit posted better-than-expected results, while theme parks and Disney's creative content division showed signs of slowing momentum.</p>
<p>In addition, they said Disney benefited from lower expenses and tax rates during the quarter. When the effects of the lower expenses are excluded, Disney's third-quarter profit was in line with expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;The results for the quarter and year to date demonstrate the continued operating strength of the company,&quot; Chairman Michael Eisner said in a statement. &quot;I am particularly pleased with the performance of our creative content segment, which is benefiting from improved live-action films and the successful release of 'Hercules.'</p>
<p>&quot;Our theme parks continue to enjoy a year of record attendance driven by the popularity of the 25th Anniversary celebration at Walt Disney World,&quot; Eisner added. &quot;Our cable operations, especially ESPN and The Disney Channel, also continue to be strong contributors to the company's results as we proceed with our worldwide expansion of those businesses.&quot;</p>
<p>Operating income from Disney's creative content division, which includes filmmaking, video and retail outlets, rose 17 percent to $333 million, as films such as &quot;Con Air&quot;, &quot;Scream&quot; and &quot;The English Patient&quot; easily outpaced the weaker year-ago offerings of &quot;Celtic Pride&quot;, &quot;Last Dance&quot; and &quot;Eddie&quot;. However, revenues were down 4 percent, reflecting fewer live-action films released during the quarter.</p>
<p>Disney's theme parks posted record results, with revenues up 10 percent to $1.4 billion, and operating income adding 11 percent to $390 million. However, analysts said attendance growth slowed to about 3 percent to 5 percent in the third quarter from about 7 percent to 9 percent in the second quarter.</p>
<p>Analysts said attendance at Walt Disney World in Florida was up about 5 percent while Disneyland was flat to slightly lower than the year-ago period.</p>
<p>For the rest of the year, Disney's theme park business is expected to face difficult comparisons with last year's strong performance, but attendance should pick up considerably next year when Disney opens its newest park, called Animal Kingdom, next spring.</p>
<p>Broadcasting revenues for the quarter increased 5 percent to $1.6 billion, and operating income rose 7 percent to $337 million.</p>
<p>Disney said it was hurt by lower ratings at ABC, third among the four major broadcast television networks in viewership.</p>
<p>Broadcasting was helped by strong cable results, driven by increased advertising revenues and affiliate fees at its ESPN cable sports channel and increased subscribers at Disney Channel, as well as an increase in ad revenues at the television and radio stations.</p>
<p>The company bought ABC in February 1996 and completed the purchase during the second quarter of this year. Disney posted a $225 million charge last year from the acquisition.</p>
<p>The company also recorded a $300 million charge a year ago from an accounting change, and a $135 million gain from the sale of station KCAL-TV in the first quarter of the current year. Excluding the non-recurring items, revenues for the nine-month period increased 6 percent to $17.0 billion and net income increased 27 percent to $1.5 billion, or $2.15 a share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
