<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74603" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US corporate bonds end up, WCI Steel jumps.</title>
<headline>US corporate bonds end up, WCI Steel jumps.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. high-grade corporate debt shadowed U.S. Treasuries' steady climb to close up, while junk-rated WCI Steel Inc bonds gained five points on news its main shareholder may take it private, dealers said.</p>
<p>WCI Steel paper closed at a 109 bid, 110 offer after the firm said late Tuesday that 84 percent shareholder The Renco Group was considering making an offer to take the firm private.</p>
<p>If Renco decided to make an offer, it would do so within the next two weeks, depending on market conditions, WCI said.  </p>
<p>Overall, the junk bond market closed up 1/8 to 1/4, dealers said, with key gainers in the telecommunication sector for a second straight session as the previously underperforming paper strengthened its apparent turnaround.</p>
<p>Nextel Communication's zero coupon senior discount notes due 2003 closed up 1/2 of a point at 73-1/4 bid, 74 offer. The notes gained more than one point on Tuesday to end at a 72-3/4 bid. Nextel's new notes due 2004 gained a point at 64-1/4 bid, 64-3/4 offer on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>One part was for $100 million in senior notes priced at 99.642 to yield 7.361 percent or 71 basis points over the 5.75 percent Treasury due 2003.</p>
<p>The second part was for $25 million in senior notes at 99.694 to yield 7.544 percent or an 83 basis point spread.</p>
<p>Both issues carry a make whole call at the greater of par or Treasury plus 25 basis points and are rated Baa1/BBB-plus.</p>
<p>In the high-grade secondary market, ATT Corp debt was inactive after spreads widened slightly on Tuesday following news the firm's third-quarter profit would fall below expectations.</p>
<p>In the governments market, the benchmark 30-year bond closed up 23/32 at 97-24/32 to yield 6.93 percent. The Dow Jones Industrial Average finished up 3.33 at 5877.36.</p>
<p>-- Roanne Daniels, 212-859-1677</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
