<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="746037" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BMC says both divisions added to Q2.</title>
<headline>BMC says both divisions added to Q2.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>BMC Industries Inc said Tuesday each of its divisions contributed to the company's higher second-quarter earnings.</p>
<p>The company earlier said it earned $12.0 million, or $0.42 a share, during the second quarter compared with $9.8 million, or $0.35 a share, in the same period last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The second quarter of 1997 represented another quarterly earnings record for BMC and its twenty-fifth consecutive quarter of increased net earnings over the year-earlier period, excluding income from the sale of equipment and technology and other non-recurring items,&quot; BMC said.  </p>
<p>BMC's precision imaged products operation had record second quarter results.  Sales and profits rose 25 percent compared with last year, said BMC, which makes aperature masks for color television tubes and computer montiors.</p>
<p>Sales included more than $2 million of high-resolution computer monitor mask sales. High resolution mask sales were depressed by a number of factors including line time required for new customer and part qualification, and a continued market surplus of 14-inch monitor tubes due to an inventory build at the end of 1996, among other things.  </p>
<p>BMC's optical products operations also produced record second quarter results. Second-quarter sales rose four percent compared with the second quarter of last year, while profitability increased five percent.  Profits were impacted by a number of one-time expenses including: expenses preparatory to the shutdown of the Ft. Lauderdale plastic lens manufacturing facility which ceased operations in July, expenses incidental to the new polycarbonate manufacturing, centralized distribution and research and development facility and start-up costs for the operation's first anti-reflective coating machine.</p>
<p>In addition, resources devoted to the ongoing development of new products and materials were higher in the second quarter, BMC said.  Construction of a new facility remains on schedule for completion in the third quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>-- ((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
