<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="746046" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSX sees near-term merger gains pushed back.</title>
<headline>CSX sees near-term merger gains pushed back.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Merger benefits expected in 1998 as a result of CSX Corp's acquisition of Conrail assets could come later than expected, Chief Financial Officer Paul Goodwin said Tuesday.</p>
<p>The company expects, however, to realize all benefits it had targeted by the end of a three-year period after the acquisition.</p>
<p>&quot;The full-year '98 won't get the benefits we expected, but we expect to accelerate the ultimate benefits so we're getting them all by the year 2000,&quot; Goodwin said Tuesday at the company's presentation of second quarter results in New York.  </p>
<p>Goodwin declined to elaborate with specific figures on the dilutive and accretive effects expected from the merger.</p>
<p>In April CSX forecasted that its acquisition of 42 percent of Conrail for $4.3 billion would dilute its earnings by three percent in 1997 and two percent in 1998.  It originally expected the merger to have a break-even impact in 1998 and be accretive to earnings by eight percent in 1999 and 12 percent in 2000.</p>
<p>The Surface Transportation Board, which must approve the merger, plans to take 350 days to review the transaction, rather than the 255 days that CSX and Norfolk Southern Corp, which is also buying Conrail assets, had proposed.</p>
<p>&quot;The nice, neat three-year period we envisioned beginning in '98 will start later, but we will try to get the work done in less time,&quot; Goodwin told Reuters.</p>
<p>He added that once all the anticipated synergies resulting from the merger take effect, the company expects earnings accretion &quot;in excess of 15 percent a year.&quot;</p>
<p>((Carol Huang -- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
