<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74611" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Colombia's Samper welcomes U.S. funding for drug war.</title>
<headline>Colombia's Samper welcomes U.S. funding for drug war.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian President Ernesto Samper on Wednesday hailed the Clinton administration's decision to expand funding for a war on drugs and called for increased international efforts against narcotics.</p>
<p>The U.S. effort announced on Tuesday, in which Washington would give more than $112 million worth of military equipment and training to Colombia, Venezuela, Peru, Mexico and Caribbean countries, should help countries battle against the drug trade, Samper said.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the announcement of President Clinton,&quot; Samper told Reuters. &quot;This is not only a Colombian story, but is a problem of the international community.&quot;</p>
<p>The Colombian president has been dogged by allegations he knowingly accepted drug money during his 1994 campaign. The Colombian Congress cleared him in June of complicity in drug corruption, but this verdict failed to convince many.</p>
<p>However, Samper, in speaking with Reuters on the final day of a trip to address the United Nations, said that problem was behind him.</p>
<p>&quot;The political crisis is over,&quot; Samper said. &quot;It finished when the congress exhonerated my behavior on any charge.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. State Depertment had revoked Samper's visa in July because of the allegations, but the travel restrictions did not apply to heads of state visiting the world body.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Samper reiterated the themes of his U.N. speech callilng for a crackdown on money laundering, better coordination between intelligence organizations and a international accord to deal with drug trafficking.</p>
<p>But he also said he would approve of the extradition of Colombian drug offenders as part of an international strategy to fight narcotics.</p>
<p>&quot;I support the extradition treaty but in a multilateral context,&quot; Samper said.</p>
<p>Asked whether he would support extradition without such an global accord, the president said that Colombia had bilateral agreements with certain nations and was extraditing foreign nationals. &quot;I want a real commitment of the international community against drugs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the United States removed Colombia from the list of certified nations in the war on drugs, opening the country to potential trade sanctions.</p>
<p>Samper said that, with extensive military and police actions and government anti-drug spending near $1 billion, Colombia hoped to get back U.S. &quot;certification.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are doing our job and we are doing well,&quot; Samper said. &quot;We hope theat the United Stats understands that it is better for us not to be in a confrontation but in a cooperation.&quot;</p>
<p>Applying U.S. punitive sanctions against Colombia would be misguided as the commercial interests of both nations would be damaged, he said.</p>
<p>Samper said Colombia's business community was far more concerned about the health of financial markets, the curbing of demand and the lowering interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see a diminished growth rate this year, but I am totally confident that in January we will see a recovery of our economy,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
