<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="746598" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Folgers cuts price of 13 oz can of coffee.</title>
<headline>Folgers cuts price of 13 oz can of coffee.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Procter and Gamble Co. unit Folgers Coffee Co. said on Tuesday it will cut the list price of its standard 13-ounce can of ground regular and ground decaffeinated coffees by 30 cents due to the decline in prices on the world's futures markets.</p>
<p>The decrease, which will take effect on September 8, brings the price for a standard 13 ounce can of regular ground to $3.06, and decaffeinated ground Folgers to $3.76, the company said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The list price of Folgers coffee generally reflects the price of green coffee sold on the commodity market,&quot; the company said in a statement. &quot;While supply of high quality arabica coffee remains tight and the market volatile, green coffee prices began declining with added supply from the Brazilian crop now being harvested.&quot;</p>
<p>Industry sources said rumors had recently been swirling around the coffee market that Folgers would cut retail prices after the price of green coffee on New York's Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange slipped some 40 percent from 20-year highs in late May.</p>
<p>Folgers and other major roasters were forced to raise the retail price of a 13 ounce can of ground coffee four times since the beginning of the year from $2.41 to $3.36 to reflect the soaring cost of green coffee on the world's futures markets.</p>
<p>Tight supplies of arabica beans -- with inventories worldwide hovering near 20-year lows -- combined reduced 1997/98 crop estimates from Brazil and the prospect of reduced availability of coffee from Central America and Colombia in the 1997/98 season were some of the factors behind the sustained futures rally.</p>
<p>The company said the list price of Folgers Instant Coffee will remain unchanged at $3.96 for an 8-ounce size, and Folgers Singles will also remain unchanged at this time as it has different blens and processing methods than ground Folgers coffee.</p>
<p>--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodity Desk, +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
