<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74653" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: High techs lead Nasdaq to another strong close.</title>
<headline>High techs lead Nasdaq to another strong close.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>There's no stopping the high techs these days.</p>
<p>Led by rallies in Iomega Corp, 3Com Corp and Cisco Systems Inc, the Nasdaq Composite Index rallied 9.35 points, or 0.77 percent to 1224.92 at its unofficial close. Advances led declining issues by 2161 to 2004 on volume of about 623 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;We've receieved a number of upgrades either of individual stocks or of high tech sectors which have caused excitement in the industry,&quot; said Joseph Barthel, chief investment strategist at Fahnestock &amp; Co.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of techs had their own bear market between mid-1995 and July of 1996. Some technology indexes were down 30 to 40 percent which would qualify as a full scale bear market. So the rally phase comes from extreme oversold levels and what appear to be depressed and unsustainable valuation levels.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the techs, volatile Iomega topped the Nasdaq actives list and closed up 4-1/8 at 24-1/8, 3Com was up eight at 64-5/8 and Cisco closed up 2-11/16 at 63-3/16. Goldman Sachs raised its rating on 3Com to the recommended list from market outperform. The company reported higher than forecast fiscal first quarter earnings today.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
