<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74665" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends near lows, seen weakening.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends near lows, seen weakening.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fund liquidation pressured March CSCE world sugar futures below the psychologically key 11.00 cents a lb mark to close barely above the day's lows, a potential sign of near-term weakness, floor sources said.</p>
<p>They pegged support in March at 10.90, adding the trade has been a steady buyer at the lows.</p>
<p>Prices traded higher throughout the morning, prompting some market sources to forecast the beginning of an uptrend. Unable to sustain gains, however, the March contract sank under Tuesday's low of 11.02, to 10.91.</p>
<p>The contract closed 0.12 weaker at 11.92, having ranged from 11.14 to 10.91. Spot-October gained 0.04 on the day to settle at 11.21, while the deferred contracts finished 0.12 to 0.04 lower.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at a brisk 33,874 lots.</p>
<p>The October/March spread, steady for most of the session, widened to 0.29 on the close compared with 0.13 after Tuesday's close. Open interest in the spot month fell to 20,806 lots, off 3,322 lots. Open interest in March gained 3,219 lots to 70,964 lots.  </p>
<p>&quot;Any weakness in the market will result in more liquidation by the specs in March since October is not active,&quot; said one trader, noting the declining open interest in the October contract.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities Desk 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
