<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="746800" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss accounts list to appear in 28 countries.</title>
<headline>Swiss accounts list to appear in 28 countries.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A list of pre-1945 accounts in Swiss banks including assets left by Holocaust victims will be published in newspapers in 28 countries around the world on Wednesday, the Swiss Bankers Association said.</p>
<p>It said the publication would also include local telephone numbers for potential heirs to claim the money, a procedure that will be run by auditing firm ATAG Ernst &amp; Young.</p>
<p>&quot;It will take the form of an advertisement that will be more than a page long in some newspapers, depending on the format,&quot; association spokesman Silvia Matile said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be free telephone numbers for contacting the ATAG office responsible for that country,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The long-awaited list covers names and details of accounts opened by foreigners before the end of World War Two in 1945 and whose owners have not been heard from in at least 10 years.</p>
<p>These criteria mean the tally could include accounts whose owners dropped out of contact for other reasons than the Holocaust.</p>
<p>A second list will follow in October with dormant pre-1945 accounts opened by Swiss residents, who may have acted as proxies to hide away the assets of European Jews and others threatened by the Nazis.</p>
<p>The list and details of the claims procedure will also be available on the Internet, with the address of the site to be made public at a news conference on Wednesday, Matile said.</p>
<p>The news conference was moved from the originally scheduled site in the capital Berne to Zurich airport.</p>
<p>Along with Swiss Bankers Association presdient Georg Krayer, the news conference will include Israel Singer, secretary general of the World Jewish Congress (WJC), which has led a two-year drive for Swiss banks to hand out assets left by Holocaust victims.</p>
<p>Former U.S. central bank chairman Paul Volcker will also be there in his capacity as head of an independent commission set up by the WJC and Swiss banks to scour bank records for traces of Holocaust accounts.</p>
<p>Matile said the newspaper ads with the list would appear in Eastern and Western Europe, Britain, the United States, Canada, Argentina, Israel, South Africa and Australia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
