<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="746908" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SmithKline sees stg cutting FY pft by 8 pct.</title>
<headline>SmithKline sees stg cutting FY pft by 8 pct.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>SmithKline Beecham Plc finance director Hugh Collum said on Tuesday the strong pound was likely to reduce the group's full-year profits by around eight percent.</p>
<p>Collum told a telephone conference with reporters that the pound had risen by around seven percent since the second quarter of 1996 and by 20 percent against European currencies, cutting reported pre-tax profits by 42 million stg.</p>
<p>&quot;Our best estimate is that the impact on profits will be about eight per cent for the whole of 1997,&quot; Collum said.  </p>
<p>Collum said 50 percent of the reduction in profit caused by sterling's strength in the quarter was accounted for by comparisons with European currencies, with 20 percent from the U.S.</p>
<p>SmithKline also said it had no plans to follow the lead of Eli Lilly &amp; Co of the U.S. in writing down the value of its pharmacy benefit manager Diversified Pharmaceutical Services (DPS).</p>
<p>Chief executive Jan Leschley defended the decision to buy DPS, which cost SmithKline $2.3 billion in 1994, saying DPS and the troubled Clinical Laboratories operation &quot;give us a competitive advantage that others don't have.&quot;</p>
<p>Leschley told Reuters he would still purchase DPS if making the decision today.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
