<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747044" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Four arraigned in Mexican deaf mute ring.</title>
<headline>Four arraigned in Mexican deaf mute ring.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four people accused of holding dozens of deaf mute Mexicans in servitude were arraigned on Monday on federal charges, while authorities continued to seek the leader of the alleged smuggling ring.</p>
<p>The ringleaders allegedly forced their victims to live in dire poverty and sell trinkets on the streets and subways of New York City.</p>
<p>The ring was exposed on Friday when two deaf mutes walked into a police precinct with notes detailing their plight.</p>
<p>Officials rescued 57 people from two cramped city apartments over the weekend. They said they were smuggled from Mexico into southern California and transported to Los Angeles and to New York City.</p>
<p>Seven people were arrested, four of whom were arraigned on Monday in federal court in Brooklyn. They were charged in a conspiracy to bring, transport and conceal illegal aliens.</p>
<p>If convicted, they each face a possible prison sentence of 10 years for each illegal alien involved.</p>
<p>Police in the United States and Mexico said they were searching for a Mexican man believed to be the leader of the operation, identified by police as Reinaldo Paoletti.</p>
<p>Four of those arrested were members of the Paoletti family.</p>
<p>Arraigned were Alfredo Rastrian-Paoletti, 37; Rosa Beltran-Sanchez, 25; Santa Gonzalez, 21, and Jose Paoletti-Lemus, 28.</p>
<p>All but Rastrian-Paoletti are deaf.</p>
<p>Beltran-Sanchez, who is five months pregnant, cried heavily throughout the proceedings, and Bruce McIntyre, attorney for her husband Paoletti-Lemus, said his client was &quot;more victim than victimiser.&quot;</p>
<p>A bond hearing was scheduled for Aug. 4. Three others were arraigned on Sunday on state charges.</p>
<p>In Washington, Immigration and Naturalisation Service Commissioner Doris Meissner said the agency was deeply disturbed by the incident and would free up all necessary INS resources to aid the criminal probe into alien smuggling.</p>
<p>Meissner said she spoke on Monday with U.S. Attorney Zachary Carter, Mayor Rudolph Giuliani and Mexican Ambassador Jesus Silva-Herzog to pledge the agency's full cooperation and support to &quot;aggressively prosecute those responsible for these horrendous violations of our laws.&quot;</p>
<p>INS was considering options for custody of the victims in the New York City area once the New York police completed their investigation.</p>
<p>Authorities believe the ringleaders recruited their victims from homes and schools for the deaf and mute in Mexico, promising them a better life in the United States.</p>
<p>The victims said they were forced to work seven days a week as street peddlers, according to court documents.</p>
<p>They said they were forced to sleep on floors and were abused if they did not make enough money selling key chains, baseballs, pens and toys, the documents said.</p>
<p>Authorities said in one apartment they found $35,000, $10,000 of which was in one dollar bills.</p>
<p>All of the people found in the two apartments were illegal aliens, authorities said. Of the 57 rescued, 12 were children ranging in age from six months to 16 years.</p>
<p>The Mexicans were in the custody of city authorities and the American Red Cross was providing them with housing and food until their immigration status was determined.</p>
<p>In Washington, Secretary of Labour Alexis Herman said Labour Department officials and authorities with the Immigration and Naturalisation Service were investigating the case.</p>
<p>&quot;I share the public's sense of outrage at the discovery that dozens of deaf Mexican immigrants in New York City were forced to live in the most squalid conditions and work for little or no pay,&quot; she said. &quot;We need to address the continuing problems of the underground economy, which operates in the shadows and so is more difficult to monitor.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
