<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747059" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: United sees Q3 pressure on domestic side.</title>
<headline>United sees Q3 pressure on domestic side.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>UAL Corp, the parent of United Airlines, said it expects strength in international revenues will offset continued competitive pressure on domestic revenues in the third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;The third quarter will look very much like the second quarter,&quot; the company said in a conference call with reporters following its second quarter earnings report.  </p>
<p>United expects third quarter system unit revenues to be &quot;roughly flat&quot; in the third quarter, with international results &quot;quite strong&quot; and domestic down slightly due to the ticket tax.</p>
<p>Similarly, in the second quarter ended June 30, United Airlines' domestic passenger unit revenue growth was hurt by the return of the federal ticket tax, which was not in effect in last year's second quarter.</p>
<p>Weakness in the domestic market was offset by continued cost cutting efforts and strength in the Atlantic and Latin America markets, the company said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The reinstatement of the 10 percent ticket tax made this a particularly difficult quarter to produce year-over-year improvements in unit revenue and fully distributed earnings per share,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>UAL posted second quarter pro forma fully distributed earnings of $2.82 a share, which topped Wall Street expectations and last year's $2.52 a share.</p>
<p>Second-quarter yield, or passenger revenue per passenger mile, increased 0.9 percent to 12.59 cents from 12.48 cents in the second quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Domestic yield was flat in all markets, expect Denver, where yield fell six percent from last year. Load factors also were lower in most domestic markets.</p>
<p>Cargo revenue increased 12.0 percent to $215 million from $192 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Shares of UAL added 1-1/2 to 78, down slightly from an intraday high of 79-15/16.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
