<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747207" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU hopes to bring Arafat and Levy face-to-face.</title>
<headline>EU hopes to bring Arafat and Levy face-to-face.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union on Tuesday stepped up efforts to win a greater role in the Middle East peace process by trying to broker the highest-level meeting between Palestinian and Israeli officials in months.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat and Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy were due to hold separate talks with current EU president Luxembourg later on Tuesday, but officials were also hoping to persuade them to meet face-to-face.</p>
<p>With the stalemate in the peace process entering its fifth month, the meetings were being arranged on the sidelines of a regular gathering of EU foreign ministers.</p>
<p>A European diplomat would only say that  Luxembourg Foreign Minister Jacques Poos and EU Middle East envoy Miguel Angel Moratinos would hold separate meetings with Arafat and Levy.</p>
<p>&quot;If we get them together, that would be very good news indeed, but you must not judge progress on achieving this goal,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel told a news conference earlier that if the meeting went ahead, it would show &quot;the role of the Europeans has become more important&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe, through the work of Moratinos, has a little more of a foot in the door,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The last time Arafat and Levy met was on the fringes of an EU-sponsored Euro-Mediterranean conference in Malta in April, where the pair had a brief but cordial exchange.</p>
<p>Peace talks broke down in March after Israel began building a new settlement in Arab East Jerusalem, which Palestinians regard as the capital of their future state.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, Levy was given a hostile reception by many members of the European Parliament when he addressed its foreign affairs committee.</p>
<p>&quot;I know that some of you feel Israel is not helping the peace process, but this is not us being stubborn, this is us defending our lives,&quot; he said in a robust defence of Israeli policy.</p>
<p>At one point he shouted at a heckler: &quot;You have to be in Israel or with Israel to understand completely.&quot;</p>
<p>The Moroccan-born foreign minister -- speaking a mixture of French and Hebrew -- told MEPs: &quot;I am not so naive as to believe I could have come here and changed opinions. All I can do is explain our position.&quot;</p>
<p>But he reminded the committee of the threat Jews had faced in the past, particularly in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;We hate war...we have been victims of a war that was designed to eradicate us completely,&quot; Levy said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our right to expect from Europe...to allow the two sides to try to resolve the matter without interference.&quot;</p>
<p>The EU has long been a vociferous backer of Palestinian aspirations and is the biggest bankroller of aid to the fledgling Palestinian Authority.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
