<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747352" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Blair faces new pressure over IRA ceasefire.</title>
<headline>UK's Blair faces new pressure over IRA ceasefire.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Prime Minister Tony Blair faced fresh demands on Tuesday from political leaders of Northern Ireland's majority Protestant community angered at the terms of a new ceasefire declared by IRA guerrillas.</p>
<p>Blair was due to meet Ian Paisley and other leaders of the Democratic Unionist Party (DUP), second biggest of the pro-British Protestant parties in the province.</p>
<p>They insist Sinn Fein, political wing of the Irish nationalist IRA guerrillas, must not be allowed into Northern Ireland peace talks without a commitment from the IRA to hand in its guns.</p>
<p>Peter Robinson, deputy leader of the DUP, told reporters:</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister has to be told that the people of Northern Ireland do not accept IRA/Sinn Fein coming into a process holding onto their guns, without giving any commitment of the permanency of their ceasefire.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;I think we would want to talk to the prime minister about how we might have a proper talks process with constitutional legitimate parties.&quot;</p>
<p>Northern Irish Protestants have expressed scepticism at the IRA (Irish Republican Army) ceasefire declared on Sunday because it makes no reference to a permanent truce in its 28-year struggle against British rule.</p>
<p>The last ceasefire, declared in August 1994, was broken 17 months later when the IRA exploded a huge bomb in London's Docklands area, killing two people.</p>
<p>Hardline Unionists have said their political leaders should not sit down with Sinn Fein, which is now expected to be let into the peace talks following the IRA truce.</p>
<p>Leaders of the Orange Order, an influential organisation in the Protestant community, threw the peace process further into doubt on Monday when they called on all unionist parties to pull out of the talks at Stormont Castle in Belfast at once.</p>
<p>Orange Lodge Grand Master Robert Saulters, described the peace process as a &quot;poisoned chalice&quot;.</p>
<p>He called for &quot;all Unionist parties to withdraw immediately in an act of unity and solidarity from the Stormont talks, the existence and purpose of which is to solely satisfy the insatiable demands of the republican agenda&quot;.</p>
<p>Unionists have been angered by the prospect of the IRA's ceasefire winning Sinn Fein a seat at the peace talks without the guerrillas being forced to turn in their weapons.</p>
<p>One of the smaller unionist groups has already pulled out of the talks and the future of the negotiations depends on the reaction of the mainstream unionist parties.</p>
<p>Northern Ireland's leading unionist, David Trimble, leader of the Ulster Unionist Party (UUP), told Blair on Monday that the IRA must start handing its arms in or peace talks would fail.</p>
<p>But Trimble, who was to have further telephone contact with Blair on Tuesday, stopped short of pulling out from the talks.</p>
<p>Jeffrey Donaldson of the UUP said unionist politicians must not allow Sinn Fein to take over the peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to allow Sinn Fein/IRA to set the agenda,&quot; he told the BBC.</p>
<p>&quot;The democratic parties of Northern Ireland have got to take control of this process. After all we represent the majority of the people.&quot;</p>
<p>A further session of the peace talks was due to take place on Tuesday before the participants vote on Wednesday on a joint proposal from the British and Irish governments that decommissioning of guerrilla arms be tackled by a subcommittee in parallel with political negotiations.</p>
<p>The UUP has already made clear it will not vote for this proposal as it stands.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein, which convinced the IRA it was worth calling a ceasefire, says the handing over of weapons should be part of a final settlement, not ongoing negotiations.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein negotiator Martin McGuinness said at the weekend that the IRA would not hand in a single bullet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
