<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747316" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bristol-Myers, Schering-Plough earnings surge in quarter.</title>
<headline>Bristol-Myers, Schering-Plough earnings surge in quarter.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. and Schering-Plough Corp. Tuesday reported sharply higher second-quarter earnings, boosted by surging worldwide demand for their pharmaceutical products.</p>
<p>&quot;Our strong growth continued in the second quarter, with pharmaceutical, consumer medicines and beauty care sales volume increasing at robust double digit rates,&quot; said Charles Heimbold, Jr., chairman of Bristol-Myers.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers said its profits rose 13 percent, matching Wall Street expectations, to a record $738 million, or 74 cents a share, from $655 million, or 65 cents a share, in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Sales grew 10 percent to an all-time high of $4.1 billion from $3.7 billion. Domestic sales increased 15 percent, while international sales rose 4 percent.</p>
<p>Excluding foreign exchange effects, pharmaceutical sales jumped 18 percent over the same period of 1996. Domestic pharmaceutical sales soared 26 percent and international sales grew 9 percent, Bristol-Myers said.</p>
<p>Sales of Pravachol, the company's largest selling product, increased 21 percent to $307 million, with growing evidence of the product's benefits in lowering cholesterol, it said.</p>
<p>Sales of Taxol, Bristol-Myers' leading anti-cancer agent, rose 13 percent to $225 million.</p>
<p>Among other products, sales of Glucophage, an oral medication for treatment of non-insulin dependent diabetes, grew 93 percent to $145 million, while the anti-cancer agent Paraplatin rose 14 percent to $105 million.</p>
<p>Beauty care sales increased 18 percent excluding the effect of foreign exchange in the second quarter. Sales of the New York-based company's hair care products jumped 25 percent, led by the Herbal Essences and Infusium 23 brands.</p>
<p>Nutritional sales in the second quarter edged up 2 percent, excluding the effect of foreign exchange, while medical device sales fell 4 percent, it said.</p>
<p>At Schering-Plough, earnings rose 18 percent to $373.1 million, or 51 cents a share, in the quarter ended June 30. In the year-ago period, the Madison, N.J.-based company had profits of $317.1 million, or 43 cents per share, adjusted for a 2-for-1 stock split on June 3, 1997.</p>
<p>Sales jumped 16 percent to $1.7 billion from $1.5 billion, but were lowered by 3 percent due to the dollar's appreciation.</p>
<p>&quot;Schering-Plough's solid second-quarter performance was again led by our worldwide pharmaceuticals business,&quot; said Richard Jay Kogan, president. &quot;The company continues to perform well, with all major business components recording higher sales versus the same period a year ago.&quot;</p>
<p>Growing sales of prescription drugs were led by the Claritin line of nonsedating antihistamines and Intron A, an antiviral/anticancer agent, Schering-Plough said.</p>
<p>Second-quarter worldwide sales of the Claritin line, the antihistamine, surged 54 percent to $535.7 million. Sales of Intron A rose 15 percent to $144.0 million.</p>
<p>U.S. sales of prescription pharmaceuticals rose 29 percent in the second quarter.</p>
<p>International ethical pharmaceutical sales rose 12 percent, excluding foreign exchange effects.</p>
<p>Second-quarter sales of the company's worldwide animal health business edged up 2 percent, or 5 percent excluding foreign exchange effects.</p>
<p>Sales for Schering-Plough HealthCare Products grew 6 percent in the second quarter, largely due to the addition of Dynastep Inserts to the Dr. Scholl's foot care line, it said.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers' stock fell $1.94 to $82.25, while Schering-Plough rose $1.125 to $49.875 on the New York Stock Exchange in late morning trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
