<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747628" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: SAS cargo to add third macau frequency.</title>
<headline>SAS cargo to add third macau frequency.</headline>
<byline>Jim Gilchrist</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scandinavian Airline System is to add a third weekly Boeing 747 freighter frequency between Gothenburg and Macau.</p>
<p>The additional service will start on August 19, leaving Gothenburg on Monday nights arriving in the Portuguese enclave on Tuesday for turnaround after a technical stop in Sharjah in the United Arab Emirates, the airline's general manager for Hong Kong, South China, Taipei, the Philippines and Macau, Per Moller Jensen told Reuters.</p>
<p>Unlike the carrier's two other freighter services to Macau which use the same aircraft, it will not continue onto Osaka in Japan.</p>
<p>SAS is concentrating on its Asian cargo service after cancelling its weekly freighter link to New York because a fourth Boeing 767 passenger frequency offered additional transatlantic belly cargo space making the freighter unnecessary, Moller Jensen said.</p>
<p>He said cargo loads, especially ex Macau, have been &quot;extremely good.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Most east bound cargo from Scandinavia has been targetted towards the Japanese market but we know there is a huge market into Hong Kong and Southern China and we are hoping to grab some of that market with the additional frequency,&quot; he said in an interview.</p>
<p>SAS said it was the first airline to start transporting cargo between Hong Kong and Macau by barge last year. The concept has since been copied by other airlines such as South Korea's Asiana Airlines.</p>
<p>Moller Jensen said the Macau freighter service is supplementing the carrier's Boeing 767 passenger service from Hong Kong to Copenhagen which has restricted belly cargo capacity because of the long distance involved.</p>
<p>&quot;There is more growth in the Far East market at the moment and if we are to be competitive and stay in the market we need to supplement with all-cargo capacity,&quot; Moller Jensen added. - Reuters Air Cargo Service Tel+ 44 171 542 7706 Fax +5017 - www.racs.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MACAO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
