<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747692" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Ramos says Philippine peso up again after fall.</title>
<headline>Ramos says Philippine peso up again after fall.</headline>
<dateline>BAGUIO, Philippines 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Fidel Ramos said on Tuesday the peso was appreciating again after its recent sharp fall and that the Philippines must not be likened to other countries whose currencies had been under speculative attack.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope you are seeing that, as the government has predicted, the value of the peso now, after the first big depreciation, is starting to appreciate again,&quot; Ramos told a news conference in the northern mountain resort of Baguio city.  </p>
<p>He said the reason for the peso's recovery was because &quot;the economic fundamentals in the Philippines are very, very sound and we must not be equated to other ocuntries that may be suffering from the same speculative attacks.&quot;</p>
<p>The peso has been trading at a little over 28.00 to the dollar after falling sharply to 30.00 last week since the central bank effectively devalued the currency on July 11.</p>
<p>At its present rate, the peso has depreciated by about 6.7 percent from the level before the de facto devaluation, officials said.</p>
<p>Traders say the currency market in Manila has largely calmed down after the recent wave of speculative attacks on the peso and other southeast Asian currencies.</p>
<p>Greater currency stability has also allowed the government to start to lower punishingly high interest rates in the past few days and officials insist that the economy will still meet growth targets set for this year.</p>
<p>However, economists warn that the peso's tumble is almost certain to feed into inflation over the next few months, with petrol prices very likely to rise soon.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8913 Fax 817 6267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGUIO, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
