<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747713" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Ousted premier's troops on push south - Thai army.</title>
<headline>Ousted premier's troops on push south - Thai army.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forces loyal to Cambodia's ousted first prime minister have won full control over a key northwest town and are pushing rival government troops south toward another strategic village, Thai and Cambodian military said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Government officials in Phnom Penh, who said on Monday they still controlled the key town of Samrong, said they had no information on any offensive by forces loyal to First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh.</p>
<p>But a Thai officer at the Cambodian border said Ranariddh's forces had taken Samrong town, about 30 km (20 miles) from the border, and territory further south, sending about 30,000 Cambodians fleeing the fighting between soldiers of those forces and troops loyal to Second Prime Minister Hun Sen.</p>
<p>Hun Sen ousted Ranariddh in a coup just over two weeks ago after driving the prince's forces from Phnom Penh, but sporadic fighting between the two sides has continued in the country's northwest.</p>
<p>&quot;Soldiers loyal to Ranariddh have overrun Samrong...and are now heading to Chong Kal town south of Samrong. They expect to capture it soon,&quot; the Thai officer told Reuters.</p>
<p>Chong Kal is roughly 25 km (15 miles) south of Samrong.</p>
<p>Artillery and mortar fire could be heard from the border on Monday afternoon, but the sounds of fighting were less intense on Tuesday, he said.</p>
<p>Mia Pot, a 36-year-old Cambodian who said he was a royalist soldier, told Reuters by telephone from his hospital bed in Thailand that Ranariddh's forces had taken Samrong late on Monday.</p>
<p>Mia Pot, who was suffering from a leg wound, said eight other Ranariddh soldiers had been wounded in the fighting near Samrong. He and the others were recovering in a Thai hospital near the border, he said.</p>
<p>About 30,000 Cambodians who fled the fighting were stranded in a town one kilometre (half a mile) from the Thai border, the Thai army officer said.</p>
<p>He said Thailand was preparing a receiving area in Surin Province to handle the refugees should the fighting get worse.</p>
<p>Two generals contacted in Phnom Penh said they were awaiting an update on the situation in and around Samrong, but as of their last intelligence reports, thought the government still controlled the area.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
