<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747846" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PHILIPPINE STOCKS - factors to watch - July 22.</title>
<headline>PHILIPPINE STOCKS - factors to watch - July 22.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors likely to affect Philippine stocks on Tuesday:</p>
<p>* The market players will continue to tread cautiously in the light of regional currency volatility and the upcoming release of second quarter/first half company earnings, traders said.</p>
<p>* &quot;We, however, advise to start assembling a portfolio at the levels of 2,475. This level would be a good area to start buying slowly into the market. Selective buying is still the key,&quot; said Meridian Securities Inc in its daily outlook.  </p>
<p>* BPI Securities Corp said the volatility of the financial markets will stabilise in the next few weeks so that a wait-and-see stance may be appropriate in the meantime.</p>
<p>* On Monday, the Philippine composite index closed lower by 24.61 points at 2,648.34 points.</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones on Monday ended 16.26 points lower at 7,906.72. PLDT's ADR closed lower $0/01 at $33 3/8.</p>
<p>* The Philippine peso ended unchanged at 28 pesos to a dollar helped by the central bank's dollar sales of about $8.5 million at 28.25/28 pesos in limited amounts of $500,000 per transaction.</p>
<p>* The Philippine interbank call loan average was steady at 25.09375 percent.</p>
<p>* The peso is set to stabilise at 27.50/28.50 to the dollar with the easing of speculation, Raul Concepcion, president of the Federation of Philippine Industries, said on Monday.</p>
<p>* Treasury bill rates at the secondary market mellowed on Monday but trading remained subdued ahead of the auction, traders said.</p>
<p>* The Philippine 91-day treasury bill yield fell to 13.174 percent from 13.217 last week, the Bureau of Treasury said.</p>
<p>* Foreign currency reserves of the Philippines will reach $10.45 billion by Tuesday after the country draws down money from the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the central bank governor Gabriel Singson said on Monday.</p>
<p>* The Philippines can still achieve its gross national product (GNP) growth target of seven to eight percent this year despite the sharp depreciation of the peso, Planning Secretary Cielito Habito said.</p>
<p>* Habito said the depreciation of the peso would lead to the six to 6.5 percent original inflation target this year instead of the 5.2 percent to 5.7 percent lower revised target.</p>
<p>* Asia Brewery Inc (ABI), owned by one of the richest Chinese-Filipino tycoons Lucio Tan, said it would pursue criminal charges against market leader San Miguel Corp alleging that San Miguel disrupted ABI's distribution network by hoarding their bottles.</p>
<p>* San Miguel Corp said it expects a sharp rise in beer sales in the second half of the year because of the price cuts last month. San Miguel Brewing Phils marketing manager Val Tan said the firm aims at a 20 percent growth int he second half of the year.</p>
<p>* Petron Corp chairman Monico Jacob and Pilipinas Shell Petroleum Corp president Oscar Reyes said the oil firm will wait for the peso to settle down before adjusting domestic fuel prices.</p>
<p>* Manila wheat importers are expected to return to the market this week but analysts said a weaker peso and firmer U.S. prices would limit orders, Manila grain traders said.</p>
<p>* Globe Telecom is planning to raise 6.06 billion pesos in new capital to finance its fixed telephone line and cellular phone projects, the National Telecommunications Commission said.</p>
<p>* Cosmos Bottling Corp, the soft drinks arm of conglomerate RFM Corp said it expects a net income of 244 million pesos for the first six months of the year from 99 million last year.</p>
<p>* Philippine Finance Secretary Roberto de Ocampo said the country was not likely to draw from the $400 million parallel financing facility of the Japan Export-Import Bank.</p>
<p>* Newspaper BusinessWorld said the International Monetary Fund (IMF) imposed certain conditions when it approved Manila's request to extend the Philippines' $652 million Extended Fund Facility.  Among the conditions set are a public sector surplus of 0.3 percent of GNP or 7.7 billion pesos, discouraging the growth of foreign exchange liabilities through new liquidity requirements and the removal of tax disincentives on peso deposits.</p>
<p>- KATHERINE ESPINA  63 2 841-8939 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
