<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747815" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Companion plans HK$155 mln rights issue.</title>
<headline>Companion plans HK$155 mln rights issue.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Companion Building Material (Holdings) Ltd said on Tuesday it proposed to raise HK$155 million before expenses by way of a rights issue of about 620.42 million new shares at a subscription price of HK$0.25 each.</p>
<p>The subscription price represents a 60 percent discount to the closing price of HK$0.62 on Monday, the company said.</p>
<p>The rights shares will be distributed in the proportion of two rights shares for every five shares held, it said.</p>
<p>Companion Building said assuming exercise in full of the rights attaching to the existing company share options and warrants, it would be required to issue a further 108.63 million new shares under the rights issue.</p>
<p>The ceramics tiles, marble and granite products distributor also said it proposed to increase its authorised share capital to HK$512 million from HK$460 million.</p>
<p>The rights issue is conditional on shareholders' approval on increasing the authorised share capital at an extraordinary general meeting to be held sometimes later, it said.  </p>
<p>The register of members will be closed from August 13 to 20, determining the entitlement of the shareholders under the rights issue.</p>
<p>Of the net proceed of about HK$150 million, HK$100 million will be used to repay bank borrowings, HK$20 million to improve ceramics tiles production facilities in China and the balance will be for working capital, it said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
