<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74780" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Gamma rays from black hole mystify astronomers.</title>
<headline>Gamma rays from black hole mystify astronomers.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two &quot;dramatic&quot; bursts of gamma rays from a suspected black hole some 400 million light years away have mystified and intrigued astronomers.</p>
<p>A team of U.S., Irish and British astronomers and physicists said their observations gave stronger support to the idea that the object was a black hole and not, as other physicists have said, a compact cluster of stars.</p>
<p>Writing in the science journal Nature, they said the bursts were much stronger than any flare-up of gamma rays ever seen.</p>
<p>John Patrick Finley of Purdue University in Indiana said the gamma-ray flare probably came from matter being sucked into the black hole.</p>
<p>&quot;Something is probably falling into this central black hole and we are seeing the energy it is losing,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Black holes, believed to be collapsed stars that generate tremendous amounts of gravity, intrigue astonomers because they know so little about them. Their force is so strong that nothing can escape from them, not even light.</p>
<p>Scientists can see energy coming from the matter that circles around the black hole as it is pulled in.</p>
<p>This particular black hole, Markarian 421, is 400 million light years away in the northern sky. Finley and colleagues saw the two bursts in May while they were watching Markarian 421 from the Fred Lawrence Whipple Observatory in Arizona.</p>
<p>They had already seen visible light and x-rays coming from Markarian 421, but nothing like the gamma bursts.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that there is an enormous amount of energetic material shooting out in these beams,&quot; Finley said. &quot;They were incredibly intense in both cases. But also, the second one was incredibly short. That's actually more mystifying.&quot;</p>
<p>Bursts of energy can go on for days, but the second burst lasted only half an hour. This made Finley, an astrophysicist, suspect that Markarian is indeed a black hole.</p>
<p>&quot;People have speculated it could also be a massive, very compact cluster of stars,&quot; he said. But the short burst indicated that it was no bigger than our solar system -- with a mass millions of times that of our own sun.</p>
<p>Finley said the observations would not have been possible a few years ago. New cameras and imaging techniques now allow physicists to &quot;see&quot; gamma rays as they hit Earth's atmosphere.</p>
<p>&quot;The gamma rays that come from the object are coming straight towards us,&quot; he said. &quot;It makes basically a big flash of light in the atmosphere.&quot;</p>
<p>Most astronomers complain the atmosphere interferes with light or radio waves coming from distant stars and galaxies.</p>
<p>But Finley said: &quot;We are the only branch of astronomy which benefits from the fact that we have an atmosphere. Literally, the atmosphere is part of our detector.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
