<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747914" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Volvo profits up, but trucks spluttering.</title>
<headline>Volvo profits up, but trucks spluttering.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Schmelz</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish vehicle maker AB Volvo said on Tuesday favourable currency effects and one-off gains bolstered its first half profits, but the group's ailing truck division took the shine off results.</p>
<p>The group, now a pure transport company following a three-year long divestment programme, posted a profit after financial items of 7.95 billion crowns from 3.86 billion, including capital gains.</p>
<p>Volvo said earlier the first half profit would include a one-off gain of 3.03 billion crowns from the divestment of its stake in Pripps Ringnes brewery and of 221 million crowns from the sale of a stake in the airline SAS.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the divestment of its holding in Pripps Ringnes and smaller holdings in companies outside its core business, Volvo is now exclusively a transport vehicle group. All of its resources can thereby be focused on core operations,&quot; said Chief Executive Leif Johansson</p>
<p>The company posted an operating profit of 3.95 billion crowns in the first six months of the year compared to 2.28 billion in the same 1996 period. Net sales rose to 89.02 billion crowns from 78.06 billion.</p>
<p>Volvo said positive currency effects totalled one billion crowns, taking futures and options contracts into account.</p>
<p>Johansson vowed to turn around loss-making truck operations in North America, in the red for the second quarter running.</p>
<p>&quot;Major rationalisation and cost-saving programmes have been instituted but have not yet had full effect. Aggressive improvements must continue,&quot; Johansson said.</p>
<p>Gustaf von Essen, a Volvo analyst at brokerage Carnegie, said the truck division's operating profit, at 688 million crowns, was below his expectations of 860 million crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;It probably means more restructruing costs than were estimated and perhaps more price pressure in Europe than what we had thought,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Some analysts say Johansson, who took over the helm earlier this year after three years as head of Swedish appliance maker AB Electrolux, was dragging his feet in doing something about the trucks unit.</p>
<p>&quot;This is what he said for the second quarter so now it's a little bit hard to judge. No doubt it's taking longer than expected,&quot; von Essen told Reuters.</p>
<p>Von Essen said he had changed his forecast and now expected changes from the restructuring programme to filter through only in the final quarter of 1997 instead of in the third quarter as he believed at the start of this year.</p>
<p>Analysts say Volvo is probably looking at candidates for a possible takeover, with most fingers pointing to Pennsylvania-based Mack Trucks Inc. which is owned by French automaker Renault SA.</p>
<p>Performance of the car division was more-or-less in line with expectations. Operating profit for its car division rose to 2.15 billion crowns from 187 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>James Capel analyst Graham Philips said the group's result was slightly better than his expectations, but he was a little disappointed with the performance of the car division.</p>
<p>&quot;We thought Volvo Cars would have been slightly better in the second quarter since we believed currency and volume effects would have affected the profit more,&quot; Philips said.</p>
<p>Volvo said the total market for passenger cars declined slightly during the first half of the year, with the North American market down by approximately four percent and the European market flat.</p>
<p>The Japanese market increased by five percent but this was mainly in the first quarter. A tax increase in Japan in hurt sales in the second quarter.</p>
<p>Volvo said the number of cars sold rose 12 percent to 196,200 and the car division's net sales climbed 21 percent to 48.16 billion crowns.</p>
<p>At 0905 GMT the share was trading at 207.5 crowns, up 3.5.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
