<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="747966" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: INSTANT VIEW - French May ind production drops.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - French May ind production drops.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are economists' and analysts' comments after national statistics institute INSEE said overall industrial production fell 1.6 percent in May and manufacturing production dropped 1.7 percent. Year-on-year, industrial production rose 2.2 percent while manufacturing was up 3.1 percent.</p>
<p>IAIN LINDSAY, SENIOR BOND STRATEGIST, CREDIT LYONNAIS.</p>
<p>It's not as bad as we thought, we were going for a 2.5 percent drop instead of 1.6. It's quite an erratic number, but overall it appears to be on an upward trend.</p>
<p>In terms of markets, I doubt it's going to have much effect at all. For the market to start paying attention to economics again, we first have to asses the effect of yesterday's audit of public finances and whether the audit was a fair reflection of the state of the economy. There's some scepticism in the markets about political interference in the (audit) numbers.  </p>
<p>ERIC MULLER, ECONOMIST, UBS</p>
<p>I was expecting a correction after April's figures but it is a little bigger than I expected, mainly because of a weaker automobile component than I forecast but also because of semi-finished goods whose fall was double what I expected.</p>
<p>We should not use one month to determine the trend...The first half has been somewhat stronger on average than predicted but for the second half, things risk being less clear. Foreign demand remains the major factor (in driving production).</p>
<p>Today, the new elements are the audit and the tax measures that take effect from 1997. Domestically, there will be a small fall in confidence (as a result of the higher taxes on companies in the government's deficit-fighting package).  </p>
<p>PATRICK MANGE, ECONOMIST, DEUTSCHE BANK.</p>
<p>It's very disappointing and a little surprising. We had been following the monthly surveys of sentiment that indicated sustained production for that month and was it hard to predict such a sharp drop.</p>
<p>April rose strongly and this could mean that May is a correction.</p>
<p>But all the elements fell and it could be some political fears crept in. In May we were in the middle of the election campaign and maybe corporations were waiting for the results of the election to step up production.</p>
<p>There are also seasonal factors to consider.</p>
<p>Production will remain weak in June but if you look at the year trend or the six month trend, it is well oriented.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
