<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748024" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. sanctions chill investment in Iran.</title>
<headline>U.S. sanctions chill investment in Iran.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Paul</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. officials said on Wednesday that the threat of sanctions had deterred foreign companies from investing in oil and gas fields in Iran but European allies were not cooperating enough to isolate Tehran.</p>
<p>A year after a law went into effect requiring Washington to punish any foreigner who invested $40 million or more a year in oil or gas production in Iran or Libya, no sanctions have been imposed, although a few deals have tested the law.</p>
<p>&quot;It is notable that during the first year of ILSA (Iran Libya Sanctions Act) there has not been any activity that we have been able to learn about or identify that would be sanctionable under ILSA,&quot; said Alan Larsen, Assistant Secretary of State for economic and business affairs.</p>
<p>Iran had tried to attract interest in 11 oil and gas projects over the last year but had yet to sign any contracts to develop the fields. &quot;So we do think (the law) has had a chilling effect on foreign investment in Iran's petroleum sector,&quot; he told the House International Relations Committee.</p>
<p>Larsen said the State Department was closely watching two deals, one involving a German bank to finance an Iranian engineering firm's work to develop an oil field, and a $2 billion natural gas project under negotiation with French oil giant Total.</p>
<p>International Relations Committee chairman Benjamin Gilman said he would question the German government about the loan from the Westdeutsche Landesbank. He added that the huge gas project should be scrutinised because China National Petroleum Corporation was eyeing a role in it.</p>
<p>&quot;This could be a potential flash point in U.S.-China relations particularly in light of increasing Chinese support for Iran's military build-up,&quot; the New York Republican said.</p>
<p>State Department officials acknowledged that Washington had not achieved its goal to make Tehran give up policies that offended the United States, including its alleged support of terrorism and acquisition of nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>&quot;We would have better success were we not acting unilaterally,&quot; David Welch, assistant secretary for Near East Affairs said, pointing to a lack of cooperation from European allies.</p>
<p>While Gilman said the Clinton administration was correct to stick with its policy, Democratic lawmakers said it might be time to shift policy.</p>
<p>&quot;Why not try to engage in some way?&quot; said Representative Lee Hamilton of Indiana, the top Democrat on the committee, pointing to the recent election of a relative moderate, Mohammad Khatami, as president of Iran, and recent calls by former senior U.S. officials for Washington to ease tensions with Tehran.</p>
<p>Welch argued that the European approach of engaging Iran had failed as much as U.S. policy to change Tehran's behaviour.</p>
<p>&quot;What (U.S. allies) propose as an alternative, I find not very precise. And where they have suggested engagement, I believe it simply hasn't worked,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
