<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74802" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain to cut red tape in financial services.</title>
<headline>Britain to cut red tape in financial services.</headline>
<byline>Alexander Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain on Wednesday vowed to cut regulatory red tape for financial services firms which stuck to the rules and showed themselves to be low risk.</p>
<p>&quot;The government must do all it can to reduce the burdens of regulation and administration whilst maintaining high standards of investor protection,&quot; Treasury Minister Angela Knight told a seminar on financial deregulation.</p>
<p>Knight said the financial services industry was vital to the British economy and to London as one of the world's top three financial centres. The moves were needed &quot;in order to maintain and improve the competitiveness of the industry&quot;.</p>
<p>An invitation for the financial industry to put forward its views on regulation followed the release on Monday of the second report of the Deregulation Task Force.</p>
<p>This urged cutting existing compliance costs and suggested the government should press financial services regulators to contribute to a net reduction of 100 million pounds ($156.4 million) over two years across the industry.</p>
<p>Knight said the government accepted most of the task force's recommendations, adding that some were already underway. She said the regulators should aim to give the industry the right service at the right price, adding there would be cost savings for the industry if it helped to simplify the rules.</p>
<p>She told a news briefing that suggestions by the opposition Labour Party for all regulators to be brought more closely under the umbrella of the Securities and Investment Board (SIB) were flawed.</p>
<p>&quot;That would be both expensive and disruptive,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The aim of the changes was to &quot;get the existing system working better.&quot;</p>
<p>This view was backed by the minister for deregulation Roger Freeman, who said: &quot;It's not about the structure of regulation but how it works and how it is enforced.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The next initiative is to promote a more cost-effective regulatory system which SIB is pushing forward. I also want to see a lively debate on the Personal Investment Authority's (PIA) evolution project to ensure a simpler system for the retail financial services market,&quot; Knight said.</p>
<p>The deregulation task force also called for the introduction of a civil penalty regime &quot;for areas of malpractice such as market abuse, to tackle a wider range of cases quicker than the current criminal procedures permit&quot;.</p>
<p>In addition it said a &quot;serious examination of the continued use and selection of juries in criminal fraud trials&quot; was needed. The government said in its response that work on both areas was already in hand.</p>
<p>The role of juries was also raised on Wednesday by the director of the Serious Fraud Office (SFO) George Staple. He said a solution to the question of whether it was reasonable to ask an ordinary jury to sit through lengthy cases and at the end deliver a verdict was &quot;urgently required&quot;. ($1=.6392 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
