<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748022" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Columbia/HCA officials face eight lawsuits.</title>
<headline>Columbia/HCA officials face eight lawsuits.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eight separate shareholder lawsuits have been filed against officials of Columbia/HCA Healthcare Corp. in Tennessee since a massive federal probe of the company began in March.</p>
<p>The most recent suit was filed on Tuesday by Zwerling Schachter &amp; Zwerling, a New York law firm representing shareholders who allege misconduct by certain key officials of the company, the civil clerk's office at the federal court in Nashville, Tenn., said.</p>
<p>The clerk's office said seven similar actions have been filed since April 8 -- three weeks after Nashville-based Columbia/HCA said its El Paso, Texas, operations had been searched by federal agents.</p>
<p>A federal investigation of the largest U.S. for-profit hospital company has since spread to six states and caused a sharp drop in Columbia/HCA stock.</p>
<p>Shares in the company recovered early Wednesday, however, as rumours flew that it may be in merger talks and that its chief executive officer may face a possible ouster.</p>
<p>Columbia/HCA stock jumped $3.25 to $36.375 on the New York Stock Exchange after falling sharply in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal, quoting people familiar with the situation, said Columbia/HCA was in talks with Tenet HealthCare Corp., the second-largest U.S. for-profit hospital company, about a possible combination. But the newspaper reported that a merger was not imminent.</p>
<p>Separately, the Tennesseean newspaper in Nashville quoted an unnamed source as saying Columbia/HCA's board members in a special telephone meeting on Saturday discussed concerns about long-time Chairman and Chief Executive Richard Scott.</p>
<p>The source said the 10-member board was concerned about Scott's response to the mounting investigation of the company and other matters, and that members discussed the possibility that Scott may be forced to step down from his post.</p>
<p>Columbia/HCA spokeswoman Eve Hutcherson declined to comment on both reports.</p>
<p>Federal agents last week seized records relating to laboratory billing and home health care operations at Columbia/HCA facilities in Florida, Texas, Tennessee, North Carolina, Oklahoma and Utah, the company said.</p>
<p>Five Columbia/HCA mid-level executives in Florida have been subpoenaed to testify before a grand jury in connection with the probe, it said. Attorneys general of Texas and Alabama are pursuing separate inquiries into the company's activities.</p>
<p>Columbia/HCA had 1996 sales of $19.9 billion. It runs 342 hospitals, 150 surgery centres and more than 570 other locations in 36 states, England, Switzerland and Spain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
