<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748001" id="root" date="1997-07-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PEKPOL TO REVISE DOWN 1997 NET FORECAST.</title>
<headline>PEKPOL TO REVISE DOWN 1997 NET FORECAST.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish food producer Pekpol SA will revise down its 1997 2.5-million-zloty net profit prognosis after recording losses in May and June, the firm's deputy economics director told Parkiet in its Tuesday edition.</p>
<p>Earlier this year the firm said it would lift its net profit by 39.1 percent this year to 2.5 million zlotys and sales by 25.1 percent to 247.7 million zlotys.</p>
<p>&quot;The correction won't be as deep as the May and June data might suggest,&quot; Krystyna Szpyrkowska was quoted as saying, adding that a new prognosis should be published by end-July.</p>
<p>The firm lost 0.2 million zlotys in May and 0.1 million in June and earned 0.02 million zlotys in the first half against 1.9 million in first-half 1996. January-June sales are down slightly to 92.5 million zlotys from 95.3 million.</p>
<p>Szpyrkowska said reasons for the May and June losses included unfavourable currency fluctuations and lower than expected sales, in June partly due to changes in Pekpol's transport fleet. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
