<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748195" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intel to supply Pentiums to DEC.</title>
<headline>Intel to supply Pentiums to DEC.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intel Corp, which had threatened to cut off the supply of Pentium chips to Digital Equipment Corp after the third quarter, has agreed to continue shipments of the microprocessers in the fourth quarter, a Digital spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We recently got a commitment from Intel for Q4 supply,&quot; spokesman Dan Kaferle told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;They are going to supply us chips. We'll continue to develop Intel-based systems on par with market requirements.&quot;</p>
<p>Kaferle did not comment on the size of the fourth quarter shipments.  </p>
<p>In May, after Digital sued the chip manufacturer for allegedly stealing key semiconductor secrets and infringing on a handful of patents, Intel retaliated by threatening to cut off the supply of Pentium chips.</p>
<p>In 1996, Digital sold $2.2 billion worth of computers which use Intel chips, a major portion of its total product revenues of $8.4 billion for the year.</p>
<p>In two letters sent to Digital executives, Intel said Digital's current purchase order runs out in the third quarter. Digital said its product agreement with Intel ran through 1999 and it did not expect any interruptions.</p>
<p>Lawyers have said that any move by Intel to cut off supply could raise anti-trust troubles. Digital alleged in court papers filed earlier Wednesday that Intel wielded &quot;monopoly power&quot; to harm Digital for selling a competing microprocessor, the 64-bit Alpha chip.</p>
<p>((Michael Ellis, Boston bureau, (617) 367-4176))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
