<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748285" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: 3M sees 2nd-half EPS up 10 pct after forex.</title>
<headline>3M sees 2nd-half EPS up 10 pct after forex.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Minnesota Mining &amp; Manufacturing Co chief financial officer Giulio Agostini said Wednesday the company expects earnings per share, after currency effects, in the second half of the year to be up about 10 percent over the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Speaking at a company conference for analysts, Agostini said the company expects second-half earnings per share to be up well in excess of 15 percent, excluding currency effects.</p>
<p>The diversified manufacturer, based in St. Paul, Minn., reported earnings in the second half of 1996 of $1.85 per share on a continuing operations basis.  </p>
<p>&quot;Forecasting currency exchange rates is difficult, if not impossible. But, at today's levels, currency will have a larger impact on earnings in the second half than in the first six months of this year,&quot; Agostini said.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate the second-half effect will be about $0.15 a share, which would bring the impact for the full year to $0.25 a share,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>3M on Wednesday reported first-half 1997 earnings of $1.99 per share, up from $1.78 per share in the year-ago period. Revenues for the half were $7.53 billion, up from $6.99 billion in the first half of 1996.  </p>
<p>&quot;We recognize that comparisons become more difficult in the second half, and that there is the possibility of a slowdown in the U.S. economy,&quot; Agostini said.</p>
<p>&quot;Even so, we expect our solid top-line growth to continue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that 3M expects capital spending to total about $1.4 billion for 1997, slightly higher than earlier estimates.</p>
<p>Shares in 3M were off 1-11/16 at 98-5/8.</p>
<p>((--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
