<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74835" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Coffee epidemic threatens Central Africa - expert.</title>
<headline>Coffee epidemic threatens Central Africa - expert.</headline>
<byline>Julia Meehan</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A British pathologist said on Wednesday that Central African coffee production could be crippled if an epidemic which has already shaved output in some affected areas by more than 50 percent is not contained.</p>
<p>&quot;Wilt is a major disease in Central Africa at the moment. If steps are not taken to stop or contain it, the whole of coffee production in Central Africa is under threat,&quot; Julie Flood, tropical plant pathologist at the International Mycological Institute, said.</p>
<p>Flood said wilt, or tracheomycosis, which strips coffee trees of their leaves and attacks the base through fungal spores, is most critical in northeastern Zaire but has now spread to neighbouring Uganda, Africa's largest grower.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to act quickly...What is required in the short-term is a fire fighting excercise to eradicate the disease to uproot and burn diseased trees,&quot; Flood told Reuters in an interview during a break in a meeting of the International Coffee Organization (ICO).</p>
<p>Flood said Zaire has suffered production losses of as much as 56 percent in affected areas since 1986.</p>
<p>While Zaire's coffee production is only a fraction of Uganda's, with average annual exports of some 4.0 million 60-kg bags, some 20 percent of its population or some 8 million could lose their livelihood.</p>
<p>&quot;This disease is a reality. Twenty percent of Zaire's population live off coffee,&quot; Noel Munaga, President of Zaire's Coffee Board said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If the disease continues to spread, some eight million people are condemned to unemployment,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Flood said that eradicating the disease in the long-term needs effective breeding programmes for resistant strains.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the only practical and sustainable way of controling wilt disease,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>If not contained, the disease, which can be transmitted through winds or rain splash carrying the inffected spores, could even spread to leading coffee producers in South and Central America.</p>
<p>&quot;It could in theory (spread) but only if there was a transfer of material from Central Africa to Southern America...But I think the threat is more reasonably within Africa,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Further research is also needed to define the cause of this new wilt epidemic after the disease was successfully eradicated in Zaire in the 1950s through resistant breeding.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to find out whether this epidemic has been caused by the pathogen mutating to a more aggressive strain, in which case this is very, very serious,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CEAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
