<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748421" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-PALACE SAY LOMBARDO DEAL LOOKS DOUBTFUL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PALACE SAY LOMBARDO DEAL LOOKS DOUBTFUL.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crystal Palace manager Steve Coppell said on Wednesday that talks to sign Italian winger Attilio Lombardo from Juventus had hit an obstacle.</p>
<p>&quot;My gut feeling at the moment is that the deal looks like its going to break down,&quot; Coppell told the English premier league side's clubcall telephone information service.</p>
<p>Newly-promoted Palace had agreed the transfer with Italian champions Juventus last week but said the player had not yet agreed personal terms and had not flown to London as expected.</p>
<p>Coppell said that he could not put a timeframe on the 2.1 million pound ($3.5 million) transfer for the 31-year-old international.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still in discussions although we do seem to be some way off,&quot; he said. &quot;The total package is a lot of money and possibly too much for us at this present stage.</p>
<p>&quot;But it never ceases to surprise me how deals can spring back into life,&quot; Coppell said.</p>
<p>Lombardo, who played for Sampdoria before moving to Turin, was almost signed by Sheffield Wednesday last year but that deal also foundered on the player's wage demands.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
