<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748531" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Ireland arms compromise ends in failure.</title>
<headline>N.Ireland arms compromise ends in failure.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Protestant unionists dealt a blow to the troubled Northern Ireland peace process on Wednesday by voting down an Anglo-Irish plan to separate talks on an overall settlement from the disarming of republican guerrillas.</p>
<p>The pro-British unionists feared the plan would allow Sinn Fein, the political arm of Irish Republican Army guerrillas who want to end British rule in Northern Ireland, a seat at the talks with a secret army at its back.</p>
<p>The 'no' vote robbed the talks of a compromise backed by Britain, Ireland and the United States to get unionists and Sinn Fein to negotiate together for the first time in a conflict that has killed 3,200 people since 1969.</p>
<p>In Washington, U.S. State Department spokesman James Foley said: &quot;We regret that vote. &quot;I think the important point, though, is that the process will continue.</p>
<p>&quot;The British and Irish governments have expressed commitment to this process leading to a negotiated settlement. We don't see this vote as an end of that process,&quot; Foley said.</p>
<p>After the vote, the talks' chairman, former U.S. senator George Mitchell, announced that one more session would be held on Monday before the talks were adjourned until September, when the British government hopes to begin substantive negotiations.</p>
<p>Two unionist parties quit the talks altogether in protest at what they said were plans to appease Sinn Fein. They called on Britain to find another process to reconcile rival Protestant loyalists and Catholic Irish nationalists.</p>
<p>&quot;We have now left this particular process because there is nothing in it for unionists...and those who believe in law and order. The gunmen have taken over the process,&quot; Ian Paisley, leader of the Democratic Unionist Party, told reporters.</p>
<p>The DUP and the UK Unionist Party both walked out of the troubled year-long negotiations after Wednesday's vote, which capped 14 months of deadlock on the disarmament issue.</p>
<p>But the key Ulster Unionist Party (UUP) of David Trimble stayed on at the negotiations despite voting against the plan, which both London and Dublin said they would not abandon.</p>
<p>Britain's Northern Ireland Secretary, Mo Mowlam, said the governments would stick to a target date of September 15 for the start of substantive negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks process goes on. Both governments are firmly committed to substantive political negotiations on 15 September. We will hold to that and will take all necessary steps to ensure that that happens,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Irish Foreign Minister Ray Burke, sitting alongside her at a joint news conference, said they would meet again on Tuesday to start preparing for September 15.</p>
<p>Mitchell, speaking four days after the IRA's declaration of a new ceasefire, said the province was closer to peace than when his talks resumed after a six-week recess in June. But he acknowledged the vote was a blow.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clearly a setback, but I don't think it's a long-lasting setback,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mitchell said his staff would discuss with Sinn Fein on Thurday whether he would meet Sinn Fein president Gerry Adams.</p>
<p>Mitchell had proposed the &quot;parallel decommissioning&quot; plan to break a deadlock between unionists, who wanted IRA disarmament before the talks, and Sinn Fein, which wanted it only as part of the final agreement.</p>
<p>Under his compromise, pro-Irish republicans and pro-British loyalists should surrender some arms as the talks went on, and that the topic would be referred to a special commission.</p>
<p>Unionists say that until Sinn Fein agrees to hand over arms, the IRA truce will seem a ploy to get Sinn Fein into the talks.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein will be allowed to join the negotiations in six weeks if the ceasefire by the IRA, which has fought for 28 years to end British rule in Northern Ireland and merge the province with neighbouring Ireland, is judged genuine.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
