<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748588" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE high sulphur fuel up, low sulphur fuel soft.</title>
<headline>NWE high sulphur fuel up, low sulphur fuel soft.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>NWE high sulphur fuel oil was steady to firmer on Wednesday amid strong bidding on the barge market, traders said.</p>
<p>High sulphur barges were traded at $89.50 and $90 a tonne fob ARA in the morning and then at $90.50, before the offer slipped back to around $90.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked cargoes were notionally slightly firmer but fixed price talk was scarce. One regular seller said traders were bidding at around $2 over the high of published cif quotes.</p>
<p>Some players felt fixed prices should be around $84 cif NWE.</p>
<p>Others said this represented a differential with barge prices that was too large, and pegged prices closer to $86.</p>
<p>A Spanish refiner was heard to have bought an M-100 cargo from Klaipeda at around $6.50 over the mean/mean of published quotes. This follows the sale by a trader of another M-100 cargo on Monday at the same level.</p>
<p>Low sulphur markets were slightly softer amid a perception that Italian fuel oil buying would be muted for the time being.</p>
<p>Two or three prompt cargoes were thought available in NWE, and offers were talked at around $96 fob NWE.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 8167 (c) Reuters Limited 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
