<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748630" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar pauses in late Europe after dash to highs.</title>
<headline>Dollar pauses in late Europe after dash to highs.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar was off its early 71-month peak in late Europe, but analysts said the weak-mark story which has catapulted it higher was set to run and run.</p>
<p>The dollar was also cheered by Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan, who painted an upbeat picture of the U.S. economy in his closely-watched Humphrey Hawkins testimony last night and sent U.S. stocks and bonds soaring.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's been very pleased by Greenspan's comments generally and that contrast with what's happening in Europe means the dollar is a great thing at the moment,&quot; said Elizabeth Legge, chief economist at Bankgesellschaft Berlin in London.  </p>
<p>The U.S. unit hit a new peak of 1.8325 marks in early Europe, way up from late Tuesday's level of 1.8168/78. By 1525 GMT it had slipped back to 1.8255/60, stung partly by a comment from Fed Vice Chair Alice Rivlin that the dollar may not get much stronger.</p>
<p>Earlier, Rivlin warned the House Banking Committee of the risk of higher inflation and said the decision on whether to raise interest rates further was a &quot;tough call&quot;.</p>
<p>Though that unsettled the asset markets, traders said the dollar was unfazed by the prospect of higher U.S. rates, which would increase its appeal in terms of yield.  </p>
<p>There was also little forex reaction to assertions by the Fed's Laurence Meyer and William McDonough that the U.S. central bank should take preemptive action against inflation.</p>
<p>The ever-growing conviction that European monetary union will be launched on time by a wide group of countries -- ushering in a weak euro -- saw the mark sold heavily again, especially for currencies perceived as non-EMU safe havens.</p>
<p>The mark dived to more than seven-year lows against sterling, its weakest level against the Swedish crown since December 1992, and an 11-month low against the Swiss franc.</p>
<p>Analysts foresaw precious little respite for the mark.  </p>
<p>&quot;As long as the market perceives the euro's going to be soft, this trend is going to continue,&quot; said Nick Stamenkovic, economist at DKB International here.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there's much the authorities can do to change the mark's downward trend against the dollar.&quot;</p>
<p>Mark/yen slumped to a two-year low of 62.93 during the session, down from late Tuesday's 63.56/58, but recovered to an intraday high of 63.45/48 by 1541 GMT.</p>
<p>Traders said that hauled dollar/yen up too, to trade at 115.74/84 versus yesterday's close of 115.52/57. But dollar/yen remains sidelined by what is basically a mark-led move.  </p>
<p>Although speculation of central bank intervention to brake the mark's decline circulated in the market, traders said it was less prevalent than last week, when dollar/mark was hovering near 1.80.</p>
<p>There was some talk in the market that the Bundesbank might revert to a variable-rate repo after Thursday's regular council meeting, offering support to the mark by flagging the prospect of higher German rates.</p>
<p>But analysts were doubtful, and some said even a switch to a variable repo would have limited impact since EMU, not German interest rate levels, had been the principal mark-negative.  </p>
<p>The mark's slide against the Swiss franc helped dollar/Swiss climb to an over four-month high of 1.4900 during the session. It stood at 1.4840/50 at 1609 GMT versus late Tuesday's 1.4803/08.</p>
<p>-- Abigail Levene, London Newsroom +44-171-542-8968</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
