<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748680" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TransCanada says Express pipe still behind.</title>
<headline>TransCanada says Express pipe still behind.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The new Express crude oil pipeline to the United States from Alberta is still operating well below its capacity and TransCanada PipeLines Ltd does not expect &quot;meaningful&quot; earnings from it until next year, TransCanada officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Longer than expected refurbishment of the Platte pipeline, which ships oil to southern Illinois from the end of the new line in Wyoming, was keeping volumes around the project's break-even rate, said Stephen Letwin, president of TCPL unit TransCanada Energy USA.  </p>
<p>In energy processing, the company's acquisition of Enron Corp's Louisiana gas liquids operations in January this year had not produced the targeted eight to 10 percent this year, Hodgins said.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point, we don't think we can reach that level,&quot; he said. &quot;If product prices move up, we expect we will be earning a full return on these assets beginning later this year.&quot;</p>
<p>TransCanada said last week it modified its 1998 Canadian natural gas mainline expansion plans in a move that would see it construct lower cost low-pressure pipeline facilities resulting in lower tolls for shippers.</p>
<p>The 456 million cubic feet a day expansion, originally estimated to cost C$1.1 billion, is now estimated at C$877.6 million.</p>
<p>An application for a new two billion cubic feet a day line to Emerson, Manitoba from Empress, Alberta -- which would connect with the proposed Viking Voyageur pipeline to serve U.S. Midwest markets -- was expected to be filed with Canada's National Energy Board later this year.</p>
<p>Hodgins said the C$225 million reduction in spending for 1998 facilities would reduce TransCanada's planned equity issue next year by about C$70 million to about C$350 million.</p>
<p>((Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
