<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748724" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ETHIOPIA: OAU hails Liberia poll as free and fair.</title>
<headline>OAU hails Liberia poll as free and fair.</headline>
<dateline>ADDIS ABABA 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Organisation of African Unity (OAU) on Wednesday hailed the presidential election in Liberia as free, fair and peaceful.</p>
<p>A statement issued by OAU headquarters in the Ethiopian capital Addis Ababa said a 15-member OAU observer mission had visited a cross-section of polling stations in Liberia and were unanimous that the process was free of intimidation.</p>
<p>&quot;The OAU observer group found that the electoral proccess in Liberia was transparent and that the procedures were adequately implemented,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Partial results announced on Tuesday night gave former warlord Charles Taylor an unassailable lead of more than 75 percent over 11 rivals, assuring him the top job he failed to win by the gun.</p>
<p>The conduct of the election, Liberia's first since 1985, also received unanimous endorsement from more than 500 foreign monitors and over 1,000 local observers.</p>
<p>Liberia's election was held after a bitter seven-year civil war launched by Taylor that devastated the West African nation and killed more than 150,000 people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADDIS ABABA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ETHIOPIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
