<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748878" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: European flood disaster costs billions of dollars.</title>
<headline>European flood disaster costs billions of dollars.</headline>
<byline>Nigel Stephenson</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two weeks of devastating floods that have submerged large areas of central and eastern Europe have caused billions of dollars of damage -- and the bills are still rising.</p>
<p>As floodwaters begin to subside in parts of the worst hit regions of Poland and the Czech Republic, governments, farmers and businesses are beginning to count the cost of some of the worst floods this century.</p>
<p>But with the Danube not expected to peak in Hungary before Wednesday evening and flood defences still giving way on the Oder River in eastern Germany, experts say it is too early to calculate the total losses.</p>
<p>In human terms, more than 100 people have died in the past two weeks, with most deaths concentrated in Poland and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>In terms of economic losses, German reinsurance giant Munich Re said on Monday that early estimates of damage in Poland and the Czech Republic put insured losses at 1.3 billion marks ($714 million).</p>
<p>But authorities in the flood-hit nations say the total cost of destroyed homes, roads, railways and bridges, lost industrial production and damaged harvests will cost billions of dollars.</p>
<p>This is how each country sees the damage:</p>
<p>CZECH REPUBLIC</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Josef Lux said at the weekend the damage could be between 50 billion and 100 billion crowns ($1.45 and $2.9 billion).</p>
<p>But economists are still tallying the cost of the damage and Finance Minister Ivan Pilip was quoted on Wednesday as cautioning against overestimating the cost.</p>
<p>&quot;It is necessary to expect several estimates will have minimal or no relation to reality,&quot; he was quoted as saying in the Mlada Fronta Dnes daily.</p>
<p>The daily said a survey of individual ministries had put the damage at 50-60 billion.</p>
<p>Expandia Finance chief economist Miroslav Singer told Reuters that, assuming one to two weeks of lost production in the affected area, annual industrial output could be cut by one percentage point.</p>
<p>Major industrial installations, including steel mills and coal mines, are located in the flood-affected regions.</p>
<p>Apart from lost production, disruption to road and rail links means deliveries, and ultimately the Czech trade balance, are likely to be affected, analysts say. Thousands of homes have destroyed or damaged.</p>
<p>The Agrarian Chamber, an agricultural industry association, said on Monday that 130,000 hectares (312,000 acres) of crop land had been hit.</p>
<p>Association Secretary Jan Zahorka forecast the floods could cut the grain harvest by at least 500,000 tonnes from the June estimate of seven million tonnes.</p>
<p>Industry and Trade Minister Karel Kuehnl said last week the damage to manufacturing would be about 25 billion crowns.</p>
<p>POLAND</p>
<p>The Polish government, which on Tuesday approved a broad reconstruction plan for the flooded areas, has yet to give its official financial estimate of the total damage.</p>
<p>&quot;The estimate of property threatened by total or partial damage may be around eight billion zlotys ($2.3 billion) in the macro scale, including about five billion in company property losses,&quot; said Jan Chaladaj, deputy economy minister in charge of the ministry's flood relief effort.</p>
<p>The ministry figures do not include the cost of destroyed bridges, roads and other infrastructure, nor farm production losses.</p>
<p>The government's crisis committee estimated that more than 5,000 sq km (1,900 sq miles) of southern and southwestern Poland had been inundated, with about 1,280 cities, towns and villages hit by the region's worst flooding in centuries.</p>
<p>The agriculture ministry estimates grain losses at 500,000-800,000 tonnes, putting total 1997 output at the low end of the ministry's earlier forecast of 23.6-24.7 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The ministry's veterinary department said the loss of livestock was moderate at 2,000 cattle, more than 6,000 pigs lost and about 1.1 million chickens killed.</p>
<p>The floods are expected to cut rapeseed crops by 100,000-150,000 tonnes to 300,000-350,000 tonnes, which will force Poland to import oilseeds.</p>
<p>The most recent estimates from four leading Polish insurers of payouts totalled about 600 million zlotys, but the government's insurance supervising body estimated the eventual total would amount to one billion zlotys.</p>
<p>GERMANY</p>
<p>In Germany, insurers and local authorities were waiting to see the extent of a second wave of floods this week before making a final assessment of damage in the eastern state of Brandenburg, where the flooding has been concentrated.</p>
<p>Evacuations of villages and small towns on the German side of the swollen River Oder, which marks part of the border with Poland, started on Tuesday as water began breaching defensive dikes.</p>
<p>Hundreds of east German homes have already been hit by the floods, which have resulted in power cuts and widespread disruption of the sewer system. Farmers have already been told to remove thousands of livestock from the danger zone.</p>
<p>Allianz AG, Germany's largest insurer and the firm with greatest exposure in the Oder valley region, said it believed flood claims could amount to hundreds of millions of marks.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect considerable costs. But the full damage can only be appraised when the water level has fallen back,&quot; a spokesman for the Munich-based company said.</p>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl, visiting flood victims on Tuesday, pledged full federal government support for the region and said he wanted soft government loans to be made available to flood-hit businesses there.</p>
<p>HUNGARY</p>
<p>Experts said it was too early to estimate Hungary's damage as the main cause was not the heavy rains, which only partially affected Hungary, but the still rising Danube river.</p>
<p>The Danube will only rise to its peak of around 7.40 metres (24 ft) in Budapest on Wednesday evening. The worst flooding was in 1965 when the river rose to 8.95 metres.</p>
<p>Material damage has been confined to the flood plains between dikes, especially on the wetland region of Szigetkoz which straddles the Slovak border.</p>
<p>&quot;No one can give real estimates because we don't have satellite scanning but we can say the waters did not go over the dikes,&quot; said Laszlo Nagy, counsellor at the National Water Management Directorate.</p>
<p>SLOVAKIA:</p>
<p>Slovak Deputy Agriculture Minister Marian Lipka said that rains and floods have caused damage to property, crops and production estimated at 2.327 billion crowns ($68 million) and that rain was delaying the harvest.</p>
<p>&quot;So far less than 10 percent of the grain crop has been harvested,&quot; he told journalists. &quot;On the other hand we don't expect this to threaten the domestic grain supply.&quot;</p>
<p>($ = 34.45 Czech Crowns)</p>
<p>($ = 34.53 Slovak Crowns)</p>
<p>($ = 3.457 Polish Zlotys)</p>
<p>($ = 1.820 German Marks)</p>
<p>($ = 195.2 Hungarian Forints)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
