<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="748825" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>LITHUANIA: Lithuanian shares close easier, major banks steady.</title>
<headline>Lithuanian shares close easier, major banks steady.</headline>
<dateline>VILNIUS 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lithuanian shares closed slightly down in sluggish trade on Wednesday and dealers said the market's direction was unclear.</p>
<p>Official list shares slipped 1.92 points to 944.80 points, while the broader group A index eased 1.61 points to 1824.46 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is giving no clear signs,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>The market, which lacks a big institutional presence, remains largely divorced from the bullish trends elsewhere in Europe.</p>
<p>Brokers said it had even failed to be moved significantly by a spate of positive interim results from the five leading blue chip listings.</p>
<p>Rokishkis Cheese, which announced on Monday that its net profit for the first six months of the year rose to almost 9.5 million litas from 1.25 million litas in the same period last year, eased to 41.50 litas from 42.00.</p>
<p>Key banking shares, widely regarded by Lithuania's cautious investors as the safest bet in town, remained steady.</p>
<p>Hermis Bank held at 215 litas on the central market, turning over 302,000 litas, compared to total central market turnover of 482,000 litas.</p>
<p>&quot;At this price, I would assume the (Hermis) shares might stay active for another week,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Vilniaus Bank shares stayed steady but not very active at 245 litas on the central market, where they turned over only 10,000 litas.</p>
<p>-- Burton Frierson, Vilnius newsroom + 370 2 22 35 18</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VILNIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LITHUANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
