<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="749073" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru rejects claims of phone tapping, press abuses.</title>
<headline>Peru rejects claims of phone tapping, press abuses.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru's government rejected on Tuesday accusations that it was involved in wire-tapping and attempts to clamp down on the freedom of the press.</p>
<p>Government ministers summoned to Congress to answer questions on scandals which have sent President Alberto Fujimori's popularity to an all-time low, said the allegations were motivated by a desire to tarnish the government's image.</p>
<p>&quot;This government, which was elected by popular vote, is a fervent believer in the freedom of press and expression, which it not only promotes but defends,&quot; Prime Minister Alberto Pandolfi read from a prepared address to a packed Congress.</p>
<p>Public concern over revelations of torture and phone- tapping by security agents turned to outrage last week when the government revoked the citizenship of an Israeli-born businessman just an hour before his television station aired a report on systematic phone tapping by security agents.</p>
<p>Opinion polls published in Lima dailies in recent days show less than one in five Peruvians approve of the president, who is perceived as authoritarian and subordinate to the military.</p>
<p>Education Minister Domingo Palermo said the government was totally opposed to phone tapping and that the evidence presented so far was of recordings from cellular telephone conversations which could be intercepted with unsophisticated equipment.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Alfredo Quispe said Frecuencia Latina network owner Baruch Ivcher had been stripped of his Peruvian citizenship not because of the allegations aired by the station but because he had not complied with a requirement to renounce his Israeli citizenship.</p>
<p>&quot;This (case) has nothing to do with the freedom of the press in Peru,&quot; Quispe said.</p>
<p>Opposition legislators, in a first round of questions, slammed the ministers' statements as evasive and misleading.</p>
<p>&quot;Ivcher's nationality was taken away because he had started to criticise the government,&quot; said Carlos Chipoco of the Union for Peru (UPP) party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
