<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="749014" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Late Mexican capo worked with Cali cartel - reports.</title>
<headline>Late Mexican capo worked with Cali cartel - reports.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Late Mexican drug lord Amado Carrillo Fuentes worked closely with Colombia's Cali cartel to transport cocaine from South America to the United States through Mexico, media reports said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Mexican newspapers said testimony this week from an ex-top Cali official in a U.S. court in Miami helped confirm what U.S. officials long believed -- that the Colombians relied heavily on their upstart Mexican counterparts in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>Guillermo Pallomari, the Cali cartel's self-confessed accountant who surrendered to U.S. authorities last year, testified to the court in the case against two U.S. citizens who allegedly worked as Cali lawyers, newspapers Reforma and Universal said.</p>
<p>According to the reports, Pallomari said Carrillo Fuentes, who died mysteriously earlier this month, became a partner for the Cali cartel from late 1992 to early 1994 -- when the two sides had a falling out over money.</p>
<p>Pallomari reportedly said Cali chief Miguel Rodriguez Orejuela began courting Carrillo Fuentes after the Colombian cartel found it increasingly difficult to continue transporting drugs through traditional Caribbean routes.</p>
<p>The Colombian cartel's troubles deepened in early 1992 when their leading distributors in Miami were arrested, Pallomari reportedly said.</p>
<p>&quot;It came as a shock, it was serious. (Rodriguez Orejuela) became sick at the news and ordered a meeting of the cartel and its lawyers,&quot; Reforma quoted Pallomari as saying.</p>
<p>As heads of a cartel believed to account for as much as 80 percent of the world's cocaine traffic, Rodriguez Orejuela and his brother Gilberto were arrested in mid-1995 and are both now in jail in Colombia awaiting trial.</p>
<p>Pallomari's comments backed up testimony by U.S. customs agent Eduard Kacerosky in another drug case in April, when the U.S. government brought drug charges against Carrillo Fuentes in a bid to pressure the Mexican government to extradite him.</p>
<p>The fate of that case is in the air after Carrillo Fuentes' death on July 4 following plastic surgery in Mexico City to change his appearance. Officials have said Mexico's most wanted trafficker may have been murdered through a drug overdose.</p>
<p>But the revelations have backed up allegations by U.S. drug enforcement officials that Mexican cartels had become as important as their Colombian counterparts in the mid-1990s. Among the rising stars was Carrillo Fuentes, who was known as the &quot;Lord of the Skies&quot; for his tactic of flying commercial aircraft laden with cocaine from Colombia to Mexico.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
