<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="749157" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: INTERVIEW - Angang sees steady growth.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Angang sees steady growth.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Angang New Steel Co Ltd said the poor reception of its Hong Kong initial public offering of H-shares is due to investors' misunderstanding of its business' prospects but it expects to see steady growth in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;Some investors, especially the Hong Kong public, do not have a thorough understanding of China's steel industry and they do not see how our company is different from other steel companies,&quot; Mu Shicheng, Angang's deputy chairman, told Reuters in an interview on Wednesday.</p>
<p>After reorganistion Angang, a unit of China's Ministry of Metallurgical Industry, holds the most profitable operation of the Angang Holding group to focus on the production of cold rolled sheet, wire rods and thick plates.</p>
<p>&quot;These lower stream steel products are in good demand in China given the nation's high economic growth,&quot; Mu said.</p>
<p>The China steel producer recently offered 890 million H-shares at a price of HK$1.63 each in an international placement and public offering in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>But the Hong Kong offering of 89 million H-shares, or Chinese enterprises shares listed in Hong Kong, was just 99.7 percent subscribed.</p>
<p>Analysts expected the shares to post a weak trading debut on Thursday due to the poor response in the Hong Kong offering.</p>
<p>They said investors perceived the company's prospects as unexciting because Angang is susceptible to fluctuations in steel prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors may need some time to understand but as part of the management team we are confident about the quality of the company,&quot; Mu said.</p>
<p>Angang was not affected by the overall weak trend in China's steel market, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices for our products are expected to be steady to slightly higher in the second half of the year,&quot; he said, addding the prices were basically unchanged in the first half of 1997 from the same period last year.</p>
<p>China's steel prices in June fell an average 7.2 percent from the same period last year, the Shenzhen-based Securities Times reported earlier this week.</p>
<p>Demand for lower stream steel products in China was relatively high despite the industry as a whole facing over supply and keen competition, he said.</p>
<p>The overall consumption growth in steel in China was expected to grow by 5.6 percent per annum during 1996 to 2000, according to the Ministry of Metallurgical Industry's forecast.</p>
<p>But Wu saw consumption of cold rolled sheet rising by 10 percent and thick plates by 14.2 perecnt but wire rods by 1.9 percent per annum in the same five year period.</p>
<p>The gross profit margin for the company in the first half of the year rose to 14.2 percent from an average of 13.5 percent in 1996, the deputy chairman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering the performance of the company in the first half, we are confident that we can achieve the profit forecast set in the prospectus,&quot; Wu said.</p>
<p>It forecast a rise in net profit of 18 percent to 480 million yuan for the year ending December 31, 1997 from 407 million the previous year.</p>
<p>He said net profit for 1995 dipped to 192 million from 392 million in 1994 because the implementation of a production expansion programme caused wire rods production to be suspended for four months.</p>
<p>Production capacity of the company would be expanded to 2.70 million tonnes in 1999 from 2.20 million in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate the production for the year to rise to 2.4 million tonnes,&quot; Mu said. -- Alison Leung (852) 2843 6369</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
