<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="749192" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan accounting change seen affecting earnings.</title>
<headline>Japan accounting change seen affecting earnings.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>An expected change in Japan's accounting standards to adopt the mark-to-market accounting method will sharply affect earnings of Japanese corporations, according to a study by Daiwa Institute of Research (DIR).</p>
<p>Japan is expected to introduce mark-to-market accounting from fiscal 1999/2000 as part of its Big Bang financial reforms.</p>
<p>However, the implementation of the new accounting measure is likely to be gradual, with mark-to-market accounting expected to be applied to just short-term securities initially, said Wakako Komatsu, a DIR analyst.</p>
<p>In mark-to-market accounting, the value of a position is calculated based on the daily closing price, thereby reflecting unrealised profit or losses on an outstanding position.</p>
<p>In Japan, companies currently appraise the value of their holdings in financial products such as stocks and bonds based on the price at the time of purchase, not the current market value. Gains or losses need to be calculated only when positions are closed.</p>
<p>According to a DIR study, securities holdings by 365 Japanese companies which list their shares on the first section of the Tokyo Stock Exchange (TSE) totalled about 53 trillion yen on a book value, accounting for 17 percent of their total assets at the end of March, 1997.</p>
<p>The market value of those securities holdings at the end of March totalled 83 trillion yen.</p>
<p>Therefore if share prices move 10 percent in a year, the companies may be forced to post appraisal losses or profits of nearly 8.3 trillion yen under mark-to-market accounting.</p>
<p>This appraisal loss or profit accounts for some 90 percent of their parent current profit of 9.2 trillion yen in the last 1996/97 business year.</p>
<p>The study said the 365 firms held a total of 24 trillion yen in short-term securities holdings, defined as securities to be sold within one year.</p>
<p>&quot;The impact of share price fluctuations on corporate earnings will not be small even if the new accounting method is introduced for short-term securities holdings only,&quot; Komatsu said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
