<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="749266" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New York jury deliberates reputed mob case.</title>
<headline>New York jury deliberates reputed mob case.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal jury ended its first day of deliberations on Wednesday without reaching a verdict in the murder and racketeering trial of accused New York City mob boss Vincent &quot;The Chin&quot; Gigante.</p>
<p>The jury deliberated four-and-a-half hours before retiring for the day. The panel is weighing 21 murder, racketeering and other charges against Gigante, the reputed head of the Genovese crime family.</p>
<p>He was accused of ordering seven murders, plotting to kill three other people, rigging business bids and extortion.</p>
<p>The jury heard testimony from six mob informants and a dozen law enforcement agents during almost four weeks in Brooklyn federal court before Judge Jack Weinstein.</p>
<p>Deliberations were scheduled to resume on Thursday.</p>
<p>During its first day of deliberations, the jury asked to be read back testimony from two of the informants who testified -- Peter &quot;Big Pete&quot; Chiodo and Salvatore &quot;Sammy the Bull&quot; Gravano.</p>
<p>Chiodo, a former Lucchese crime family captain, testified that Gigante was boss of the Genovese family. So did Gravano, who testified that as Gambino underboss he met Gigante.</p>
<p>Testimony by Gravano was key in the 1992 murder and racketeering conviction of Gambino godfather John Gotti, who is serving life in prison without possibility of parole.</p>
<p>Gigante's defence attorneys argued the informants were witnesses willing to modify their testimony to suit the government. They also argued that Anthony &quot;Fat Tony&quot; Salerno was convicted of being the Genovese crime family boss in 1986.</p>
<p>They said Gigante -- who earned the nickname &quot;The Oddfather&quot; for wandering the neighbourhood around his Greenwich Village apartment in a tattered bathrobe -- was incapacitated by mental illness.</p>
<p>But prosecutors said Gigante feigned illness for years to avoid prosecution.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
