<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74931" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST - SAfrica rates seen down over next 12 mths.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - SAfrica rates seen down over next 12 mths.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African interest rates over the next 12 months were likely to move sideways for the remainder of the year before moving lower, WorldGroup Software (WGS) said in its latest survey of eight economists.</p>
<p>It said the prime overdraft rate, which will be reduced by 0.25 percentage points to 19.25 percent on October 1, will fall by at least one percentage point and could fall as much as three percentage points over the next twelve months.</p>
<p>&quot;The expectations are for prime to be at least one percent lower in 12 months from now. This downward movement can be anything up to three percent over this 12-month time horizon,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The possibility of a one-point reduction in prime within the next three months was 16 percent but increased to 66 percent over the next six months and to 93 percent over a year, it said.</p>
<p>The chance of a two-point cut was 58 percent over a twelve month time horizon.</p>
<p>WGS noted that while a number of negative factors were still present in the South African economy, positive factors were beginning to emerge.</p>
<p>&quot;Negative factors like the high crime rate, (labour federation) Cosatu's resistance against privatisation, high corporate taxes and the overspending by government are being addressed,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Issues such as high money supply and bank credit growth will also be addressed, WGS said.</p>
<p>&quot;This still leaves us with serious problems in terms of the balance of payments, a sluggish economy with high unemployment, political and social instability, a low savings rate, high direct and indirect personal taxes as well as negative foreign perceptions about South Africa.&quot;</p>
<p>These problems would only be addressed over the longer term if government showed the necessary dedication and will power, WGS said.</p>
<p>It forecast key interest rates as follows:</p>
<p> (pct)	  Basis rate   3 months   6 months   12 months</p>
<p> Prime	  19.50	  19.25	18.75	17.75</p>
<p> 3-month BA   15.40	  15.00	14.50	13.65</p>
<p> 12-month BA  16.20	  15.65	14.95	14.30</p>
<p> Eskom 168    15.40	  14.85	14.40	13.95</p>
<p>The eight economists who took part in the forecast were Nedcor's Dennis Dykes, Transnet's Ulrich Joubert, Adam Jacobs of Absa, Smith Borkum Hare's Jos Gerson, Johan Rossouw of Huysamer Stals, Edwin Basson from Iscor, Helmo Preuss of Forecaster Ecosa and Louis Fourie from JMM Beleggingsdienste.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
