<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74933" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Rwanda tribunal meets on defence request.</title>
<headline>Rwanda tribunal meets on defence request.</headline>
<dateline>ARUSHA, Tanzania 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The court at the International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda opened on Wednesday to hear a defence request that Georges Rutaganda, a Rwandan Hutu charged with genocide and crimes against humanity, be released due to illness.</p>
<p>An official at the tribunal told Reuters the hearings, being held in camera, started at 9 a.m. (0600 GMT).</p>
<p>&quot;The proceedings have started,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Rutaganda's Belgian lawyer Luc de Temmerman said last week his client was seriously sick but declined to give details. Tribunal officials confirm he is ill.</p>
<p>The tribunal, created by the United Nations in late 1994, is supposed to start its first trial on Thursday with the case of Jean Paul Akayesu, aged 43 and another accused of involvement in the 1994 genocide in which up to a million people were slaughtered in a three month period.</p>
<p>But Akayesu's lawyers have filed their own requests for an adjournment, on procedural and other grounds, and that application will be heard on Thursday.</p>
<p>Rutaganda, a former agricultural engineer and businessman, is accused of being the second vice-president of the national committee of the Interahamwe, a militia group which played a leading role in the 1994 genocide.</p>
<p>He was charged in Arusha in late May with eight counts of genocide, crimes against humanity (extermination), crimes against humanity (murder) and violations of Article 3 of the Geneva Conventions.</p>
<p>Rutaganda, like two other accused held at Arusha, pleaded not guilty last May when he carried a bible into court. His trial date was originally set for October 3 and later postponed to October 17.</p>
<p>Rutaganda is accused of arming Hutu extremists in April 1994 and ordering the murder of Tutsi civilians with machetes, guns, grenades and by drowning. The prosecution alleges some of the victims were forced to dig their own graves before being killed.</p>
<p>Rutaganda, a Hutu, is also charged with distributing guns and other weapons to Interhamwe militia in Nyarugenge commune and stationing militiamen near his office in Kigali to catch ethnic minority Tutsis.</p>
<p>He is charged with participating in an attack on a technical school where thousands of unarmed Tutsi men, women and children were sheltering and taking part in a second attack on those who survived.</p>
<p>The six-page indictment against him says that in June 1994 Rutaganda ordered people to bury the bodies of victims in order to conceal his crimes from the international community.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARUSHA, Tanzania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
