<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="749344" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spending hotel dollars where you made a reservation.</title>
<headline>Spending hotel dollars where you made a reservation.</headline>
<byline>Judith Schoolman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>August is prime vacation time but even though you may have a reservation at a hotel or motel, beware -- some hotels may take your reservation but when you arrive tell you there's no room at the inn.</p>
<p>Rather than be left out in the cold at a hotel, travel experts say that knowing what can potentially go wrong will help prevent problems from occurring in the first place. Your travel dollars will be spent where you want them, rather than at some &quot;better than nothing&quot; dump down the road.</p>
<p>Not all &quot;guaranteed&quot; reservations are: Some hotels intentionally overbook, as do some airlines, assuming that the number of no-shows will take care of the excess. While airline overbookings are allowed under federal laws, though penalties apply, they are not permitted at hotels.</p>
<p>&quot;That would mean they've sold you something they don't have, and they can't do that,&quot; said Stephen Colwell, co-author of &quot;Trouble-Free Travel,&quot; (Nolo, 1996), in SmartMoney magazine's August issue.</p>
<p>To avoid being a victim of overbooking, get your reservation confirmed in writing.</p>
<p>The first quoted price is never the best: Hotels set a range of prices, usually topping out when select events, such as the Olympics or World's Fair, are in town. Let the hotel know you are shopping around for the best price, mention association ties or frequent flyer programme memberships. You could get a 10 percent to 30 percent discount, SmartMoney said.</p>
<p>Also, ask if there are any package rates. It pays to assume the hotel has discounts.</p>
<p>Make sure there are no hidden extras on your bill: Some hotels, unbeknownst to the guest, tack on charges for use of the in-room coffee maker, add a cleaning fee for travelers with pets in tow, or tack on a surcharge for trade show attendees. When booking, and again at check-in, ask specifically what charges are not included.</p>
<p>Remember, those little bottles in the hotel room refrigerator are not free!!</p>
<p>If you do not plan to use your reservation, cancel it: Many hotels, because of high occupancy rates, are charging no-shows as if they were shows. So, if you reserve a hotel room with a credit card, didn't show up and didn't cancel the reservation, some hotels will bill you anyway.</p>
<p>This takes a chunk out of your pocket, but double lines the pockets of the hotel.</p>
<p>Chances are, however, credit card companies will come to a guest's rescue in such a case. To avoid any hassles, try whenever possible to call the hotel (many have toll-free phone numbers) and cancel.</p>
<p>Make sure the hotel is actually where you think it is: Some hotels, for the sake of image, might call themselves something that they are not. Best to ask, &quot;Where exactly are you located?&quot; so the hotel you think is &quot;downtown&quot; isn't actually located at the airport.</p>
<p>Don't expect the hotel to be totally liable in the case of theft: Many hotels are liable up to $1,500 if something is stolen from your room, but that might not cover the full amount of the items.</p>
<p>SmartMoney says &quot;In general, the off-premises theft coverage under your homeowner's insurance policy will cover you if your personal property is stolen.&quot;</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Long car rides can be boring, especially for small children. A good way to keep World War III from breaking out in the back seat is to keep children occupied and amused.</p>
<p>Dr. Toy, a.k.a. Dr. Stevanne Auerback, a San Francisco-based expert in the field of child development, has compiled a list of suggested toys that are especially suitable for travelling.</p>
<p>These toys are culled from among 138 toys made by 100 companies that she recommends in her list of the best children's vacation products for 1997.</p>
<p>Here are some toys that might work well for car or plane trip entertainment:</p>
<p>Eyeball drawing pad (Accord Publishing, ages 5-12, $15.95)</p>
<p>Felt mosaics (Alex, ages 7-10, $8)</p>
<p>Are we there yet? (game) (Are we there yet?, ages 6-12, $14.95)</p>
<p>Rush Hour (puzzle) (Binary Arts, ages 8-12, $15)</p>
<p>Be a dinosaur finder (electronic game) (Cloud 9 Interactive, ages 6-12, $29.95)</p>
<p>Mini Calin in Suitcase (doll) (Corolle Dolls, ages 3-5, $50)</p>
<p>Tricky Triangles (puzzle) (DaMert, ages 6-12, $4)</p>
<p>Busy Board (Do-A-Dot Art!, ages 6-12, $5.99)</p>
<p>Beth Manners' Fun French (audio tape) (Future Boomers, ages 2-6, $9.98)</p>
<p>Felt Kids (Learning Curve Toys, ages 3-8, $24.99)</p>
<p>Trip Tracker (book) (Rand McNally, ages 8-12, $16.95)</p>
<p>U.S.A. Colour A Mat (Straight Edge, ages 6-12, $5)</p>
<p>For more information write to Dr. Toy, Institute for Childhood Resources, 268 Bush Street, San Francisco, Calif. 94104-3524. She asks that you send a stampled self-addressed business-sized envelope. Information is also available on the Internet at http://www.drtoy.com.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Have a question or solution to make your money go farther? Write to Judith Schoolman c/o Reuters, 199 Water Street, 10th floor, New York, N.Y. 10038, or e-mail to JUDITH.SCHOOLMAN(at)REUTERS.COM. She regrets she cannot answer letters personally but will try to address them in future columns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
