<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="74951" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Local Bosnia polls could affect NATO deployment.</title>
<headline>Local Bosnia polls could affect NATO deployment.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Any delay in the Bosnian municipal elections scheduled for November could affect the number of NATO troops deployed here after the December end of the alliance's current mission, NATO said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If municipal elections were postponed until April it would not affect the 53,000 or so NATO troops currently on the ground. They would still withdraw based on the December 20 timetable,&quot; said NATO spokesman Major Brett Boudreau.</p>
<p>&quot;What it might affect is the number of troops in a reconstituted NATO follow-on force, if one were agreed upon.&quot;</p>
<p>Boudreau said municipal polls would place an even greater demand on NATO troops in Bosnia than September 14 national and regional ones, which saw virtually the entire NATO-led peace force involved in providing logistics and security support.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we could really nail down a precise figure with respect to how much would be required to support the elections,&quot; Boudreau told reporters in Sarajevo.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly for the national elections we said that the majority, some 50,00-plus troops, were engaged one way or the other in support of those elections.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;For the municipals it will be perhaps a little more challenging than the presidential elections in the sense that voting will take place over a three-day period, so that will add a different security dimension to it,&quot; he said, adding that the Balkan winter would be a further problem.</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) is charged with staging elections in Bosnia under a mandate provided by the Dayton peace agreement.</p>
<p>Municipal elections were originally planned to be held along with the September 14 poll, but voter registration irregularities led to them being postponed until late November.</p>
<p>The OSCE's independent election monitor on Tuesday urged that the municipal elections be postponed until next spring, insisting that months of remedial effort are required to create credible voting conditions.</p>
<p>Although NATO's current mandate in Bosnia expires on December 20, 1996, a follow-on force of some significance is expected to be agreed after U.S. elections in early November.</p>
<p>NATO defence ministers meeting in Bergen, Norway on Wednesday confirmed as much without specifying the size or composition of the force, or its mission.</p>
<p>The OSCE could still decide to proceed with municipal elections in November, in which case all of NATO's current combat-ready troops would be available for support duty.</p>
<p>But if the vote were postponed until next spring, the follow-on force would have to be big enough to handle election duties.</p>
<p>The general assumption is that NATO's task would be even more difficult and demanding than it was on September 14, especially if large numbers of refugees try to cross de facto ethnic boundaries to cast votes, as is expected.</p>
<p>Boudreau said NATO was still working on the assumption of a November date for municipal elections.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not really looking at any contingencies for a spring election,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
