<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="749844" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Bunds retreat from highs but remain cheery.</title>
<headline>German Bunds retreat from highs but remain cheery.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>German debt prices enjoyed an early rally on Wednesday, cheered by a relatively tame speech by Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But after the September DTB Bund future powered to a new contract high at 103.58 in early trade, prices settled back slightly in later trade with the contract at 103.21, up 21 basis points, by 1512 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was very strong after Greenspan, but things have calmed down a bit now,&quot; said one Frankfurt-based trader.</p>
<p>Analysts said inflation data from three west German states had taken a bit of the shine off the debt price rally.  </p>
<p>The states of Hesse, Bavaria and North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany's most populated states, all said the cost of living had increased in July.</p>
<p>Prices in all three states were up 0.5 percent on the month, while year-on-year rates ranged from up 1.7 percent to up 2.1 percent.</p>
<p>But despite the rise, which some analysts said was partly fuelled by mark weakness, economists said there was no reason to fear a monetary tightening from the Bundesbank.</p>
<p>The central bank holds it regular fortnightly meeting in Frankfurt on Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is no need to panic,&quot; said Holger Fahrinkrug, senior Germany economist at UBS in Frankfurt. &quot;The Bundesbank will do nothing for some time to come.&quot;</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of 10 economists showed that not one expects a change in key Lombard, discount or repo rates at the meeting.</p>
<p>But some traders said that another sharp downwards move in the mark's exchange rate versus the dollar might fuel renewed speculation further that the Bundesbank might consider moving to a variable repo rate or even raising the rate.</p>
<p>&quot;With the mark taking a beating, people will be looking at whether the Bundesbank might moveon the repo,&quot; said one.  </p>
<p>The mark traded as low as 1.8325 to the dollar on Wednesday after Greenspan's speech boosted Wall Street and prompted enthusiasm for U.S. assets.</p>
<p>By 1552 GMT the German currency was in slightly better shape, trading at 1.8235 to the dollar.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Bund market might be slightly unsettled by the currency's weakness in the coming sessions, but would continue to be well-supported by firmer U.S. markets.</p>
<p>-- Kate Kelland, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
