<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="750250" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UAW strikes GM Michigan plant.</title>
<headline>UAW strikes GM Michigan plant.</headline>
<byline>Todd Nissen</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Auto Workers union members struck a General Motors Corp. engine component plant in suburban Detroit at midnight Tuesday after talks failed to produce a new contract by the 11:59 p.m. deadline.</p>
<p>UAW Local 909 Financial Secretary Jim Marcum said pickets will start going up shortly outside the transmission plant in Warren, Michigan. The facility employs about 2,800 hourly workers.</p>
<p>&quot;When it's time to go, it's time to go,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Talks continued at a GM Delphi Interior &amp; Lighting plant in Anderson, Indiana. Bargainers there were attempting to reach a new settlement before a strike deadline of 12:59 a.m. EDT.</p>
<p>&quot;They're still in negotiations,&quot; said Fred Haney, a spokesman for Local 663 in Anderson. He declined to provide further details.</p>
<p>A strike at either plant could quickly disrupt GM's North American production. Two strikes during the second quarter have already cost the No. 1 U.S. automaker $490 million in lost profits.</p>
<p>The Warren factory produces four-speed automatic transmissions for cars and light trucks, including GM's brisk-selling minivans. The Anderson plant has about 2,500 workers who produce tail lamps and brake lights for nearly all of GM's North American vehicles.</p>
<p>Earlier Tuesday, a recorded message at Local 663 said progress was made during talks over the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;The pace of the negotiations picked up considerably over the weekend and significant progress was made,&quot; the message said, adding that &quot;much work&quot; still needs to be done.</p>
<p>The Warren and Anderson strike deadlines are the most recent skirmishes between GM and the UAW. Union resistance to GM's efforts to cut its workforce and send more work to outside contractors has lead to a rancorous year of labor negotiations, including five strikes and numerous strike deadlines.</p>
<p>GM says it requires fewer workers to produce its newest generation of vehicles, and needs to slash overall manufacturing costs to stay competitive. Union leaders insist GM add more staffing to reduce overtime burdens and improve health and safety. The union also wants to bolster job security by forcing GM to limit how much work it sends to outside contractors.</p>
<p>Last Friday, 5,850 workers from UAW Local 594 approved a settlement with GM, ending a strike at the Pontiac, Mich., full- size pickup truck plant that began April 22.</p>
<p>As part of the new accord, GM agreed to add 557 new production and skilled trades workers and pay a total of $9.5 million to settle grievances and cover missed holiday pay.</p>
<p>A new national contract between GM and the UAW was signed last November. But the conflicts over staffing and outsourcing has lead to slow bargaining progress. Of GM's 105 UAW locals, about 10 still do not have new contracts.</p>
<p>By contrast, the other members of Detroit's Big Three, Ford Motor Co. and Chrysler Corp., had their local contracts wrapped up months ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
