<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="750416" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Nationwide members reject market float.</title>
<headline>Nationwide members reject market float.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of the mutually-owned Nationwide Building Society, Britain's largest, on Wednesday rejected a move to float the Society on the stock exchange when they supported existing board members in an election.</p>
<p>The defeated five members were in favour of the society giving up its mutual status and becoming a bank, which would have led to windfalls of at least 1,000 pounds per member, in a float worth at least 7.0 billion pounds.  </p>
<p>Nationwide members voted to re-elect five existing directors -- Stuart Bernau, retail operations head; Philip Williamson, marketing and commercial director; and three non-executive directors, Jonathan Agnew, Alison Carnwath and John Engestrom.</p>
<p>The society said it received 1.35 million votes out of a total membership of around 3.5 million. It said on average, the directors received 70 percent of the votes cast.</p>
<p>Nationwide chief executive Brian Davis told reporters the election had been highly disruptive to the Society's business. Its chairman, Charles Nunneley, said the society was delighted by the very strong show of support but admitted some surprise at the result in the light of the huge publicity about windfalls.</p>
<p>&quot;We now plan to return to our normal position on account opening balances and especially look forward to welcoming new small savers as soon as possible,&quot; Davis said. Nationwide suspended new account openings earlier this month.</p>
<p>- Joe Ortiz, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8864.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
