<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="750515" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Calif. Housing Agency LOC Aa3/VMIG1 by Moody's.</title>
<headline>Calif. Housing Agency LOC Aa3/VMIG1 by Moody's.</headline>
<text>
<p>MOODY'S INVESTORS SERVICE RATES LETTER OF CREDIT BACKED ISSUE</p>
<p>FOR CALIFORNIA HOUSING FINANCE AGENCY</p>
<p>California Housing Finance Agency</p>
<p>LOC: CREDIT SUISSE FIRST BOSTON AND MORGAN GUARANTY TRUST</p>
<p>COMPANY OF NEW YORK</p>
<p>Fully Supported</p>
<p>California</p>
<p>Moody's Rating</p>
<p> Issue			1997 Series C (AMT)</p>
<p> Rating		     Aa3/VMIG 1 1</p>
<p> Sale Amount		$31,295,000.00</p>
<p> Expected Sale Date     07/23/97</p>
<p> Rating Description     Revenue Bonds</p>
<p>1 Rating expires on February 22, 2002 or earlier termination of the letter of credit.</p>
<p>NEW YORK, July 22, 1997 -- Moody's has assigned a rating of Aa3/VMIG 1 to California Housing Finance Agency Multifamily Housing Revenue Bonds III 1997 Series C(AMT). The rating is based on the letter of credit provided by Credit Suisse First Boston and Morgan Guaranty Trust Company of New York, the structure of the transaction, which ensures timely debt service and purchase price payments to investors, and Moody's evaluation of the creditworthiness of the banks issuing the letter of credit. Each letter of credit provider covers fifty per cent of the total amount of principal, interest and purchase price. Since each bank is only responsible for fifty per cent of the total letter of credit obligation, the rating tracks the ratings assigned to the lower rated bank if the bank ratings differ. Moody's rates Credit Suisse First Boston Aa3 for long-term bank deposits and P-1 for short-term deposits. Moody's rates Morgan Guaranty Trust Company of New York Aa1 for long-term bank deposits and P-1 for short-term deposits.</p>
<p>DESCRIPTION OF BONDS</p>
<p>The bonds will initially bear interest at a weekly rate of interest and pay interest on the first business day of each month. Upon conversion, the bonds will be subject to mandatory tender at a price of par plus accrued interest.</p>
<p>The letter of credit is to be drawn on to make timely payments of principal or interest to the extent that the trustee does not possess sufficient available money. The trustee will make drawings under the letter of credit to pay purchase price to the extent remarketing proceeds are insufficient.</p>
<p>Bondholders can tender their bonds during a weekly mode on any business day with seven days prior notice; during a daily mode on any business day; during a monthly mode on any interest payment date with seven days prior notice; and during the semiannual mode upon the commencement of the next interest rate period with adequate notice. Bonds which are purchased by either bank due to a failed remarketing may not be released by the trustee unless they have received confirmation that the letter of credit has been reinstated in the amount of purchase price drawn for such bonds.</p>
<p>Substitution of the letter of credit is permitted, so long as Moody's confirms that the rating will not be reduced or withdrawn, otherwise the bonds are subject to mandatory tender prior to the effective date of a substitute letter of credit. Bondholders will be notified of any substitution of either letter of credit provider.</p>
<p>The bonds will be subject to mandatory tender not less than five days prior to the expiration of the letter of credit unless extended or substituted with rating confirmation. The bonds are subject to mandatory tender at the direction of either bank due to an event of default under the indenture. The bonds are also subject to mandatory tender at least eight days prior to a letter of credit termination date due to an event of default under the reimbursement agreement leading to a nonreinstatement of interest for the letter of credit.</p>
<p>LETTER OF CREDIT</p>
<p>The letter of credit, which is sized for full principal plus 58 days of interest at the maximum rate on the bonds, will provide sufficient coverage for bonds while they bear interest at the daily, weekly or monthly modes. The initial letter of credit does not currently cover bonds in the flexible, semiannual, long or fixed modes.</p>
<p>Conforming draws received by the banks by 11:30 a.m., New York City time, will be honored by 2:30 p.m., New York City time, on the same day. Draws for interest will be automatically reinstated unless the trustee receives written notice to the contrary on or prior to the eleventh day after the draw. Non-reinstatement of interest under the letter of credit results in the mandatory tender discussed above.</p>
<p>The letter of credit expires upon: (1)February 22, 2002; (2)date trustee surrenders letter of credit for cancellation; (3)twenty days after the effective date of an alternate letter of credit; (4)first business day that is twenty days after the trustee's receipt of a bank termination notice; (5)date there is no remaining amount available to be drawn under the letter of credit.</p>
<p>OUTLOOK:</p>
<p>Moody's rates Credit Suisse First Boston Aa3 for long-term bank deposits and P-1 for shot-term bank deposits. The rating outlook is stable. Moody's rates Morgan Guaranty Trust Company of New York Aa1 for long-term bank deposits and P-1 for short-term bank deposits. On February 7, 1996, Moody's revised the rating outlook from stable to negative.</p>
<p>ANALYSTS:</p>
<p>Maureen Babis, Analyst, Public Finance Group, Moody's Investors Service</p>
<p>Gail Sussman, Director, Public Finance Group, Moody's Investors Service</p>
<p>CONTACTS:</p>
<p>Journalists: (212) 553-0376</p>
<p>Research Clients: (212) 553-1625</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
