<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="750647" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Partisan fight snarls US House on ag funding bill.</title>
<headline>Partisan fight snarls US House on ag funding bill.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Short-tempered Republicans and Democrats in the U.S. House threatened another round of acrimony in a row that prevented any votes on a $49.6 billion agriculture spending bill Tuesday.</p>
<p>In an attempt to break the impasse, the Republican-run Rules Committee approved debate guidelines that would limit debate on amendments to 10 minutes in most cases and 30 minutes on proposals to curtail sugar, tobacco and peanut supports. Those amendments could be called on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lawmakers ended 90 minutes of debate on the fiscal 1998 agriculture appropriations bill after learning of the Rules Committee action. Wisconsin Democrat David Obey said it would lead to &quot;more acrimony.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;For the last two days, the House has been in a procedural impasse,&quot; Obey said. He blamed it on Republican unwillingness to let Democrats offer important amendments on other bills.</p>
<p>Last week, Democrats repeatedly used parliamentary tactics to interrupt debate on the appropriations bill and finally forced the House to adjourn the for weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody wants to talk about everything but agriculture,&quot; responded James Walsh, New York Republican, who accused Democrats of &quot;dilatory tactics... You reap what you sow.&quot;</p>
<p>Farm-state lawmakers waited most of Tuesday evening before the appropriations bill could be called for debate at 10 p.m. (2200 GMT). At the same time that debate started, the Rules Committee began drafting the debate &quot;rule&quot; that would limit the time spent on each amendment.</p>
<p>The House adjourned without voting on an amendment to trim $23 million from crop insurance sales commission to increase funding for the Women, Infants and Children feeding program. It was the first major amendment on the bill.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
