<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75078" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish coalition meeting fails to settle row.</title>
<headline>Polish coalition meeting fails to settle row.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's two ruling leftist parties emerged unreconciled on Thursday from a nine-hour crisis meeting on a share-out of power in a coming cabinet reshuffle, one grouping's official said.</p>
<p>Aleksander Bentkowski, a senior parliamentarian of the Polish Peasant Party (PSL), again threatened his group would quit a partnership with the larger Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) if the SLD again ignored it in crucial decisions. @</p>
<p>&quot;Appointing another minister without consultations will be an evident violation of the coalition agreement and I think... the coalition would end,&quot; private Radio Zet quoted Bentkowski as telling reporters in parliament.</p>
<p>A coalition breakdown would pave the way for early parliamentary elections, otherwise not due until late next year, with no alternative parliamentary majority in sight.</p>
<p>A crisis between the two parties erupted three weeks ago when the ex-communist SLD's Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz abruptly sacked Peasants' official Jacek Buchacz over alleged irregularities in his foreign trade ministry.</p>
<p>The dismissal, apparently without any consultations, aggravated a dispute between the two parties over a forthcoming cabinet reshuffle aimed at streamlining cabinet decision-making.</p>
<p>The rift mainly concerns appointments in three key economic ministries, first of which -- the treasury portfolio -- is to be created in October.</p>
<p>Bentkowski said the two parties were unlikely to hold talks on cabinet reconstruction unless Prime Minister Cimoszewicz openly acknowledged that the sacking of Buchacz violated the coalition pact and promised not to do it again.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is no point in meeting for the second time until the premier clearly states he has broken the coalition agreement and he will not break it again,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>The liberal SLD and the populist, rural Peasant party, both rooted in the communist era before 1989, have survived several crises over policy differences and cabinet posts since they won elections in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
