<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="750997" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - French N-plant stirs Channel island health fears.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - French N-plant stirs Channel island health fears.</headline>
<byline>Lee Yanowitch</byline>
<dateline>ALDERNEY, Channel Islands 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Luscious green cliffs and translucent waters make the tiny, idyllic English Channel island of Alderney a popular hideaway for holiday-makers across Europe.</p>
<p>But behind Alderney's peaceful and unspoiled facade lurk fears that its residents are vulnerable to often-fatal illnesses that may be due to radioactive waste discharged from France's La Hague nuclear reprocessing plant, just eight miles (12 km) away on the Normandy coast near Cherbourg.</p>
<p>Those islanders willing to speak about the issue -- and there are not many -- say the political establishment wants to keep nuclear concerns under wraps for fear it will damage tourism, the pillar of its economy.</p>
<p>Stuart Syvret, a young, outspoken senator on the nearby island of Jersey, has led a lone campaign to open a public dialogue on the potential danger of the radioactive wastes.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly when you are discharging nuclear waste into the sea and pumping radioactive gases into the air, statistically you will induce an increase in cancer instances and cancer mortalities. I think that's beyond dispute,&quot; Syvret told Reuters.</p>
<p>A mainstay of France's powerful lucrative nuclear industry, La Hague is run by the state nuclear company Cogema, reprocessing several tonnes of spent nuclear fuel, such as plutonium, each year from countries including Britain, Germany and Japan.</p>
<p>NUCLEAR WASTES SPEWED INTO SEA, AIR</p>
<p>Waste products created in the reprocessing are spewed into the sea from an underwater discharge pipe or belched into the air from its chimneys.</p>
<p>At least two men on Alderney have died of brain cancer in the last three years. Though no direct connection has been proven, both men cultivated land on the southern cliffs affected by fumes from La Hague's chimneys when the wind is blowing from the southeast.</p>
<p>Cogema says it has brought the levels of radioactivity released into the atmosphere down to negligible levels.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't deny the danger linked to radiation in general. But what we are saying is that our contribution is absolutely minimal compared to what you are naturally exposed to,&quot; said Jean-Pierre Laurent, Cogema's director of environment.</p>
<p>Last month, divers from the Greenpeace environmental group conducted tests in the waters off La Hague. They said they found &quot;stupefying&quot; radioactivity levels -- above those allowed by the European Union -- in the sludge near the discharge pipe.</p>
<p>The sludge contained cobalt, americium, barium, antimony, europium and other radioactive isotopes.</p>
<p>Cogema said the findings were not representative because the samples were taken too close to the pipe.</p>
<p>Guernsey's director of public health began recording cancer cases a year ago, and then only after the media took an interest in the problem. It is too early for conclusive data.</p>
<p>Doctor Patrick Quanten, one of two general practitioners on Alderney, feels the problem is not taken seriously enough by local officials because economic interests are at stake.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's pretty silly to pretend that there's an iron curtain around the factory and nothing goes through it, so it doesn't affect its surroundings. It's as of it wasn't there.&quot;</p>
<p>Quanten does not think there is a higher rate of cancer on Alderney than elsewhere in Britain, but he has seen many strange cancers, particularly for a population of only 2,300 people.</p>
<p>Besides brain cancer, Quanten cited several cancers of the respiratory tract -- the throat, the oesophagus, and even the bottom part of the mouth.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that was something strange. I'm not saying it's any stranger than anywhere else. But it's just that, looking at the whole bag, there are a few bits in there I wasn't expecting to find when I first started,&quot; he said, carefully weighing his words.</p>
<p>CANCER DEATHS ON RISE OVER PAST DECADE</p>
<p>Chris Busby, a radiation health scientist from North Wales who is a consultant to the European parliament committee on radiation risk, conducted a study on cancer rates and radioactivity levels on Alderney last year.</p>
<p>Busby, who found average annual cancer mortality on Alderney had about doubled in the past decade, said he was obstructed by local officials in his research and refused access to public records, such as electoral lists.</p>
<p>&quot;Radiation is known to be the cause of all types of cancer. If we're talking about gases from La Hague, it could be associated with upper respiratory tract cancers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kay Mouat, who has been Alderney's president for more than 20 years, denies La Hague poses a health risk for residents.</p>
<p>&quot;It's seven or eight miles (11 or 14 km) away and one of the strongest currents in Europe passes between France and Alderney. So if anyone is going to get it, it would be Dunkirk or Jersey...,&quot; he said sweeping his hand in an arc from side to side.</p>
<p>It is hard to loosen tongues on Alderney when it comes to discussing fears of radiation from La Hague.</p>
<p>&quot;The ordinary people are reluctant to speak publicly about this issue because they are scared that retributive action will be taken against them by the establishment,&quot; said Syvret, who says he himself has been a victim of harassment.</p>
<p>&quot;For example, people will find their cars getting booked all the time, or they'll receive much higher tax bills than expected. Things of that nature, you know,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But there are those who have nothing to lose, like John Sugden, a taxi driver on Alderney.</p>
<p>Sugden's wife Gay died in 1992 of a lung tumour, aged 39, leaving him with five sons, the youngest only three years old.</p>
<p>&quot;My wife loved the sea and she used to be in the water four to six hours at a time with the children. I used to have suspicions about Cap La Hague and I still do. When there's a shark in the water, you can fight it off, but plutonium -- you can't see it,&quot; Sugden said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALDERNEY, Channel Islands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
