<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75098" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Sept 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Sept 25.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>BURSA</p>
<p>- Commodity exchange in Black Sea port of Constanta to open new office in Israel.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Big trade unions plan nationwide protest rallies on Thursday to protest against government's plans for 5.0 percent wage indexation.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Agriculture Ministry appeals to commercial banks to give financial support to animal farms.</p>
<p>AZI</p>
<p>- Romania's foreign debt amounts to $6.0 billion.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Despite promises, the government seems unable to recover old credits extended to African countries, the paper says.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- Most of the whiskey sold in Romania is smuggled in.</p>
<p>- Haul of 4.5 tonnes of hashish captured at Episcopia Bihor rail station near the Hungarian border came from Russia.</p>
<p>- Miron Cosma, leader of vigilante Jiu Valley coalminers, has registered his bid for a seat in the upper Senate house in the November 3 polls.</p>
<p>- Journalists will quizz Gyorgy Frunda, contender for the Hungarian Democratic Union (UDMR) in November 3 presidential race in commercial television Antena 1 talk show on Wednesday.</p>
<p>- Parliament commission is discussing ban by CNA broadcast media regulator which prevents cable operators, reaching one million subscribers, from programming electoral shows.</p>
<p>- Emil Constantinescu, presidential candidate for opposition Democratic Convention (CDR) bloc, visited Bucharest's RATB utility plant on electioneering trail, telling workers that neither he nor CDR is pro-monarchy.</p>
<p>- CDR will sign accord with former Prime Minister Petre Roman's USD alliance and with ANL Liberal alliance on monitoring fairness of November 3 elections.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Parliament mediation commission on Tuesday adopted text voted by upper Senate on homosexuality, which only provides jail sentences if homosexual relations cause &quot;public scandal.&quot;</p>
<p>- Star gymnast Nadia Comaneci has been named honorary president of the Romanian Gymnastics Federation at ceremony marking 90 years since its creation.</p>
<p>- World Health Organisation warning about meningitis epidemic in Romania scared off fans of Germany's Borussia Dortmund due to meet Steaua Bucharest on Wednesday.</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Civil Alliance political group has lodged appeal against ruling by constitutional court on President Ion Iliescu's right to run for a new term in office.</p>
<p>- CDR's presidential candidate Emil Constantinescu has urged his supporters to go on missionary campaign to villages.</p>
<p>- Romanian institute of labour and social welfare issued first study on post-communist sexual harassment.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Newspaper prints list of candidates selected by ruling Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) for the Novmeber 3 parliamentary polls.</p>
<p>- Nicu Ceausescu, youngest son of Romania's late Stalinist dictator, to be flown back home from Vienna hospital soon after second surgical operation due on Friday.</p>
<p>- Traian Chebeleu, President Ion Iliescu's spokesman, to be appointed ambassador to Britain.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Romania is only eastern European country operating soccer bookmaking offices.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>- &quot;Romania never sent one single Jew to (Nazi) death camps,&quot; professor Alfred Harlaoanu says in interview.</p>
<p>- Virgil Magureanu, head of the Romanian Intelligence service (SRI) to appear today before parliament commission in probe over alleged illegal phone tapping.</p>
<p>JURNALUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- BNS labour unions expect 10,000 workers to attend Thursday's protest rallies in Bucharest and 13 towns across Romania over demands of 10 percent wage indexations, double the government's offer. -- Bucharest newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
