<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="750902" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: T-bonds mark time in London after Greenspan boost.</title>
<headline>T-bonds mark time in London after Greenspan boost.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries treaded water in London on Wednesday, digesting hefty gains overnight prompted by Federal Chairman Alan Greenspan's Humphrey-Hawkins testimony.</p>
<p>Investors were ready to take their cue from New York where long-bond prices jumped more than a point and a half on Tuesday on a benign inflation picture painted by Greenspan for the short term.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just a question of marking time as people work out what the implications of Greenspan's speech are,&quot; said Nick Benton, trader at BankAmerica in London.</p>
<p>The 30-year bond was quoted at 102-21 in London, yielding 6.42 percent, compared with 102-23 in Tokyo and 102-24 in New York at the close. September T-bond futures were up 5/32 on the day at 115-13 in automated trade.</p>
<p>Greenspan said in his semi-annual testimony that the economy's growth was slowing for now and that inflation in 1997 would be quite modest.</p>
<p>He said the Fed expected a core inflation rate of 2-1/4 to 2-1/2 percent for 1997 as a whole, &quot;significantly better&quot; than the 2-3/4 percent consumer price inflation foreseen in February.</p>
<p>But as the dust settled, economists pointed at some of Greenspan's remarks which suggested inflation would pick up in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;There were some warning signs in the speech which the markets have just decided to ignore, that the tightening bias is still in place,&quot; said Ian Morris, international economist at HSBC James Capel in London.</p>
<p>&quot;We think some of the economic indicators are starting to show some strength again, showing a third quarter bounce back in consumer activity, and we would suggest that Treasury yields will begin to head back up again,&quot; said Morris.</p>
<p>On technical grounds also the market looked overbought, he said.</p>
<p>Morris said the current euphoria over low inflation growth could push the long bond yield to 6.35 percent, but it was bound to crawl back up again to 6.75 in the next month or so.</p>
<p>Economists say the most important data to watch for now is the second quarter employment cost index due on July 29. Any big rises here could set the stage for profit taking in Treasuries.</p>
<p>Before that, there are weekly jobless claims on Thursday, June durable goods orders and existing home sales on Friday.</p>
<p>Next Wednesday new home sales for June could also show a significant rise, Morris said.</p>
<p>Meantime, the Treasury market could muster further strength, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are looking for 117-00 on the (futures) contract,&quot; said Benton.</p>
<p>For Wednesday investors were also awaiting the outcome of a five-year T-note auction worth $11.5 billion.</p>
<p>-- Clelia Oziel, International Bonds +44-171-542 8663</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
