<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75105" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - Sept 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - Sept 25.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Sarajevo press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>OSLOBODJENJE</p>
<p>- OSCE coordinator of international monitoring said on Tuesday that he would recommend certification for Bosnia's September 14 elections although they were neither fair nor free.</p>
<p>- The forensic team of the International Tribunal for war crimes for the former Yugoslavia, that has been working at a mass grave site near the eastern Bosnia village of Pilice, will soon leave, the U.N. said.</p>
<p>- Heavy rainfall over the last couple of days has caused floods in most of Bosnia and claimed one victim.</p>
<p>DNEVNI AVAZ</p>
<p>- The United States suspended arms deliveries to Bosnia's Moslem-Croat Federation because the two federal partners have failed to form a joint Ministry of Defense and a joint command for the Federal army.</p>
<p>- An explosive device was thrown into the garden of a local Croatian official in Bihac on Thursday.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVINE</p>
<p>- The United States Agency for International Development awarded a 900,000 German mark loan to the Sarajevo textile producer Alhos on Tuesday. The loan will create jobs for 70 employees.</p>
<p>-- Sarajevo newsroom, +387-71-663-864.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
