<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="751049" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Placer 6-month net profit US$32 mln.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Placer 6-month net profit US$32 mln.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Placer Dome Inc said on Wednesday it recorded a net profit of US$32 million for the six months to June 30 compared with a loss of $24 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>Net earnings for the three months to June were $19 million compared with a loss of $32 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>The Canadian-based gold miner released its results in Australia, where its shares are also listed.  </p>
<p>Sales revenue for the first half of the year totalled $599 million compared with $562 million in the year earlier period.</p>
<p>Placer Dome said the year earlier losses mainly reflected the cost of environmental remediation at its Marcopper operations in the Philippines.</p>
<p>Mine operating earnings for the latest half were $118 million against $108 million while cash flow from operations amounted to $119 million compared with $116 million.</p>
<p>Operating earnings from gold were $101 million in the first half compared with $88 million a year earlier.  </p>
<p>Placer Dome said its price hedging position provided for the sale of about one-third of planned gold production to the year 2001 at prices in excess of $475 an ounce, which enabled the company to realise $379 per ounce, $32 more than the average London market price of $347 in the half year period.</p>
<p>This compared with a price realisation of $407 an ounce and an average London market price of $395 an ounce a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;If the gold price remains at the current level of about $330 an ounce, the corporation expects to realise prices of about $365 an ounce for the second half of 1997,&quot; Placer Dome said.  </p>
<p>Placer Dome said the company's average cash production cost for its share of gold production for the six months was $214 an ounce compared with $246 an ounce in the 1996 half year.</p>
<p>In the second quarter, it was $205 an ounce compared with $246 an ounce a year earlier.</p>
<p>The company said its share of gold production in the second quarter was 633,000 ounces, bringing production for the first half of 1997 to 1,168,000 ounces, up 25 percent year on year.</p>
<p>&quot;For the full year, the corporation expects to produce 2.4 million ounces for its account at an average cash production cost of about $215 an ounce,&quot; Placer Dome said.  </p>
<p>Placer said its share of half-year output from the half owned Porgera mine in Papua New Guinea was 192,000 ounces, up from 98,000 a year earlier, when it held a direct 25 percent.</p>
<p>It said new production from the 68 percent owned Musselwhite Mine in Canada and 60 percent owned Pipeline project in the United States added 74,000 ounces to the gold production share.</p>
<p>&quot;With the completion of the sale of two mines in Canada expected in the third quarter, 10 of the 12 gold mines operated by the corporation continue to be profitable at current market prices for gold and with the protection of price hedging programmes,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>Placer Dome said its most profitable mines in the half were Campbell and Dome in Canada, Granny Smith in Australia, Cortez in the United States and Porgera in Papua New Guinea.</p>
<p>It said total proven and probable reserves at Porgera were now estimated at 82.6 million tonnes of ore grading 4.4 grams of gold per tonne containing an estimated 11.6 million ounces.</p>
<p>This is 1.2 ounces more than the June 1996 estimate.</p>
<p>Placer Dome said its copper operations in Australia and Chile contributed $10 million to operating earnings in the half compared with $12 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
