<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="751109" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: TIFFE euroyen ends with healthy gains in Tokyo.</title>
<headline>TIFFE euroyen ends with healthy gains in Tokyo.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>July 23 settlement  prev settlement</p>
<p> TIFFE Euroyen 3M (H)     99.06		   99.02</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The key March three-month Euroyen futures contract ended with healthy gains on Wednesday on Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's remarks suggested no near-term credit tightening, a successful JGB auction and weak Tokyo stocks, traders said.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan showed an unexpectedly accommodative stance this morning by leaving the market with about a 300 billion yen surplus after its regular money market operations.  </p>
<p>Greenspan said in his semi-annual Humphry-Hawkins report to Congress on Tuesday that the central bank must be ready to react if necessary to head off inflation as the economy strains at its limits but for now growth seems to be slowing.</p>
<p>&quot;Given no rate move likely in the U.S., both long- and short-term Japanese interest rates fell this morning, causing a rise in futures prices,&quot; said a city bank dealer.</p>
<p>Chart-wise, traders are watching whether the March's high of 99.06 on Wednesday would become a triple top or the March will be able to extend gains to challenge the next resistance of 99.08 and 99.10.  </p>
<p>The new 10-year JGB auction held on Wednesday was successful, producing the lowest price of 100.60.</p>
<p>The good auction cheered the yen debt market across the yield curve, pushing up the euroyen contracts, traders said.</p>
<p>The Tokyo stock market weakness also added to the bullish sentiment. The key overnight call rate fell to 0.48 percent from Tuesday's 0.50 percent.</p>
<p>The ample fund supply helped increase the amount of new issues of the benchmark three-month certificates of deposit (CD), a major fund-raising tool banks use to cover the end-September interim fiscal year-end, traders said.  </p>
<p>About 300 billion yen of the three-month CDs were issued at 0.67 percent, up from Tuesday's 0.66. About 40 billion yen of one-month CDs were issued at 0.59 percent, unchanged from Tuesday.</p>
<p>The key overnight call rate fell to 0.48 percent from Tuesday's 0.50 percent.</p>
<p>The three-year interest rate swap rate was quoted at 1.38/1.42 percent at 0716 GMT, down from Tuesday's 1.42/46 percent.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-8676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
