<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="751309" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Product Swap - Gas oil steady in quiet trade.</title>
<headline>Asia Product Swap - Gas oil steady in quiet trade.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore gas oil swaps were steady at midday in quiet trade as the market consolidated its early week gains following unexpectedly strong physical buying support, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Gas oil is hovering at the higher level right now after the big gains earlier in the week,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>August swaps were last quoted at $22.15/$22.25 per barrel, up marginally from Tuesday's $22.10/$22.20 per barrel, brokers said.</p>
<p>The market is currently up about 60 cents from its quotes of $21.55/$21.65 on Monday morning.  </p>
<p>Traders said the increase in prices are due to the renewed buying interest from several players in the belief that supplies are tightening from natural demand and a cut in output.</p>
<p>Lower supplies were attributed to cuts in refinery runs in Singapore, maintenance shutdowns in Indonesia and reverse arbitrage exports from the region to the West.</p>
<p>The shutdown of Shell Singapore's 82,000-barrel-per-day gas oil unit for a 21-day maintenance in early August will also help in reducing high domestic supplies, traders said.  </p>
<p>Singapore's weekly middle distillate stocks for the week ending July 16 was down 849,000-barrels to 10.615 million barrels which others said is still high compared to the usual six to eight million barrels.</p>
<p>In the physical market on Tuesday, a buyer emerged for a cargo that was offered at $21.50 per barrel free-on-board Singapore basis but no deal was concluded due to operational differences.</p>
<p>The buying level was 30 cents above Monday's highest traded price.  </p>
<p>On Monday, four deals totalling 670,000 barrels were done between $20.90 and $21.20 per barrel on a free-on-board Singapore basis.</p>
<p>The fuel oil market is steady with August last quoted at $98.50/$99.50, brokers said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
