<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="751568" id="root" date="1997-07-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - July 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - July 23.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- It may take a year for U.S. food and drug administration to approve food group Raisio's Benecol product offically as cholesterol- cutting agent, FDA official says.</p>
<p>- Wood and Allied Workers union representative says main focus in pay talks will be to improve employment -- says he believes in a broad pay deal despite paper workers' abstention.</p>
<p>- Next state budget is three billion markka below earlier estimates.</p>
<p>- Finance Ministry budget plans to combine lowest rates of value added tax, six and 12 percent, cut tax on medicines, books and movies, but raise tax on public transport.</p>
<p>- Crime, especially assaults, continuing to grow, statistics show.</p>
<p>- Finnish researchers found effective treatment for adult diabetes.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- Centralisation of food retailers has put heavy pressure on farm product prices: farmers should unite to resist, says Central Union of Agricultural Producers and Forest Owners (MTK).</p>
<p>- British oil service station chain Station 1 starts competing in Finland: market is worn out by competition already, Finnish sector representative says.</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- Parliament speaker Riitta Uosukainen apologizes &quot;for existing&quot; in row over presidential powers.</p>
<p>- Finnish weather prophet, frog-owning professor Taisto Heikkila, plans to retire with his frogs: says ageing frogs start getting delirious and you cannot really rely on their weather forecasts.</p>
<p>TURUN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Finland has more more Internet users than any other country, and growth has amounted annually to 100 percent.</p>
<p>- European Commission has agreed to discuss Finland's special farming conditions -- problems from unfavourable climate for agriculture and high producer costs -- next autumn.</p>
<p>- Finland will announce its official stand on EU enlargement next autumn, says EU Minister Ole Norrback.</p>
<p>-- Nora Hallberg, Helsinki Newsroom +358-9-680 50 292</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
