<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="751651" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks set new records on profit reports.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks set new records on profit reports.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto stocks scaled new heights for a second straight day on Thursday, buoyed by favorable corporate earnings reports.</p>
<p>The TSE 300 Composite Index overcame early profit-taking to end up 19.99 points at a record close of 6785.15.</p>
<p>Almost 93 million shares were traded, worth C$1.76 billion ($1.2 billion).</p>
<p>The key index also set an intraday high of 6787.37.</p>
<p>&quot;We had the makings of a significant deterioration earlier today. But the market was fueled by excellent earnings reports,&quot; said Ira Katzin, an investment advisor with RBC Dominion Securities.</p>
<p>Communications, conglomerates and transportation led gains in 10 of 14 sub-groups. The weak side included financial services, precious metals, utilities and pipelines.</p>
<p>Advancing stocks outpaced declines 516 to 448, with 321 issues unchanged.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Canadian National Railway Co. ended up 2.70 at 69.80 after earlier soaring to a 52-week high of 73.50. The railway firm reported a 74 percent jump in second-quarter net income late on Wednesday. Canadian National pushed the transport group up 123 points or 1.5 percent.</p>
<p>* Canadian Pacific Ltd. added 1.20 to close at 43.30 after earlier reaching a 52-week peak of 43.45. CP reported sharply higher second-quarter earnings on Wednesday. The stock powered a 200-point gain in the conglomerates group on Thursday.</p>
<p>* BioChem Pharma Inc. rose 2.50 to 40.50 after a U.S. analyst raised his earnings estimates for the biotechnology player based on &quot;spectacular&quot; second-quarter results.</p>
<p>* Airline operator Air Canada led heavy traders, adding 0.35 to 11.90 on 2.5 million shares.</p>
<p>* Methanex Corp. improved 0.30 to 13.10. The world's biggest methanol producer said on Thursday it was cash rich and would have the means to fund a major project or distribution to shareholders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
