<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75197" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's Bancomext sees $2 bln bond issues next yr.</title>
<headline>Mexico's Bancomext sees $2 bln bond issues next yr.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kozak</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican trade development bank Banco Nacional de Comercio Exterior (Bancomext) may return to the international bond markets next year to raise about $2 billion, the bank's assistant director general of finances said.</p>
<p>The bond issues would be part of its overall financing program, including lines of credit and commercial paper, that could total as much as $10 billion over the course of 1997, Julio Mendez Rubio told Reuters in an interview.  </p>
<p>&quot;It depends a lot on what demand is. If demand for the financing is concentrated more in the long term, then we would be calculating that it (bond issuance) will be about $2 billion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The lion's share of next year's financings will be in short-term loans and commercial paper. Some of that will be rolled over as the paper comes due during the year, bumping up the overall year total, he said.</p>
<p>The bank's lending programs, which determine the amount it must borrow, are still under discussion with other sectors and departments of the government.  </p>
<p>Bancomext is Mexico's second-largest development bank after Nacional Financiera (Nafin), and promotes and finances foreign trade. Exports have been one of the hottest sectors of the Mexican economy since the 1994 devaluation of the peso and the ensuing economic crash.</p>
<p>With its trade-linked advantage, Bancomext was able to lead Mexican borrowers back to the global markets after the crash. In June 1995, the development bank placed a $300 million floating-rate note, up from the initial $200 million on offer, a placement which is credited with paving the way for Mexico to start floating more issues.  </p>
<p>Mendez said one of his overriding considerations in deciding where to borrow is where to get the cheapest funds.</p>
<p>&quot;One thing that exporters have to take into account is the cost of financing, and we have to try to supply that financing at the cheapest rate possible...,&quot; he said. &quot;We have to be aggressive in terms of pricing for the outside funds that we arrange in order to lend them here to exporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The strategy is to go where the funds are the cheapest, whether that be in the German market, or in Japan, or in the Yankee market...,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>For example, over the last year the development bank has placed issues in yen and German marks.</p>
<p>In May, it placed a 10-year bond for $250 million in the United States and Europe to help finance a dam project, marking one of the first 10-year bonds to be placed by Mexico.</p>
<p>One of its main sources of short-term funds is from lines of credit, or trade lines, with a large number of international banks, he said.  </p>
<p>The bank also has a European global commercial paper program, its Euro medium-term notes program, worth about $2.5 billion. That complements its investment-grade commercial paper program in the United States, worth $300 million, and lines of credit with various export banks.</p>
<p>Mendez said Bancomext's access to markets has rebounded to where it was before the crash, even if spreads on longer-term paper are still slightly above pre-crash levels.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of access to the markets, I think that we are practically equal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of cost, we are a little above what we paid before the crisis for long-term (financing), but for the short-term, we are below the costs that we paid before the crisis. With each placement, we have fortunately been able to reduce the cost of our funding,&quot; Mendez said.</p>
<p>In September, Bancomext officials said that they expected to grant about $9.0 billion in credits for 1996.</p>
<p>-- Mexico City newsroom (525) 728 9559</p>
<p>E-mail at robert.kozak@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
