<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752206" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Scots ignore campaign against parliament plan.</title>
<headline>Scots ignore campaign against parliament plan.</headline>
<byline>James Forrester</byline>
<dateline>EDINBURGH 1996-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A campaign to launch opposition to the Labour government's plan for a devolved parliament in Scotland won little response from Scottish shoppers and homeward-bound workers on Thursday.</p>
<p>An open-topped bus festooned with balloons and &quot;Vote NO, NO&quot; posters drew barely a second glance as it toured the Scottish capital's main shopping street and back to the proposed site of parliament.</p>
<p>A handful of activists on the open upper deck were outnumbered by cameramen and reporters. Cries urging Scots to vote against a parliament in a September 11 referendum were largely lost in traffic hubbub or drowned by bagpipers vying for tourist attention.</p>
<p>The &quot;Think Twice. Vote NO NO&quot; bus took to the road after Scottish Secretary Donald Dewar gave the United Kingdom parliament details of plans to put a devolved parliament in place on January 1, 2000 if Scottish voters vote &quot;Yes&quot; in a two-question referendum.</p>
<p>&quot;We are remaining firmly involved in the United Kingdom,&quot; said Dewar. &quot;We are taking a mass of domestic legislation under democratic scrutiny in Scotland.&quot;</p>
<p>The 129-member parliament would control and legislate on all Scotland's domestic affairs, except a few specifically reserved to the U.K. parliament, and would have power to vary the basic rate of income tax by three percent.</p>
<p>Defence, Foreign, and European Union Affairs would remain with the U.K. government.</p>
<p>The plan was generally welcomed across the political spectrum -- though ordinary voters questioned seemed rather more muted -- but there was criticism of some details and the opposition Conservative party denounced it as a step towards breaking up the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>Conservatives lost all their Scottish seats in the May 1 general election and do not control any local authorities in the country.</p>
<p>Canon Kenyon Wright, an Episcopal clergyman who acted as co-chairman of the non-party Scottish Constitutional Convention (SCC), said it was a historic moment for Scotland. &quot;The government has firmly followed, and improved, the scheme agreed by the convention,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It can't be anything but good,&quot; said SCC member Moira Craig. &quot;It's much better than we would have had from the failed 1979 referendum. That would only have given Scotland an assembly, not a parliament.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's what we've been waiting and working for for more than a century,&quot; Scottish Liberal Democrat leader Jim Wallace said.</p>
<p>&quot;This parliament will give us the opportunity to take responsibility for our own education, transport, health and many other services. We can devise Scottish solutions for Scottish problems.&quot;</p>
<p>Scottish Nationalists welcomed publication of the plan and said extensive consultations would take place. The party's stance would be finalised at a national council meeting on August 2.</p>
<p>&quot;Independence in Europe would be the best and clearest solution,&quot; said deputy leader Allan Macartney.</p>
<p>Bill Anderson of the Small Business Federation said they were neutral as far as political aspects were concerned but everyone should vote in the referendum.</p>
<p>&quot;We are relieved that tax-raising power is limited to the basic rate of income tax. Our biggest concern was that it would apply to the gross profits of an unincorporated business, not just to income taken.&quot;</p>
<p>The Scottish region of the Confederation of British Industry said the detailed proposals needed careful study before comment.</p>
<p>If given the go-ahead in the referendum being held on the 700th anniversary of the defeat of King Edward's English army by Scotland's hero William Wallace, elections for the Scottish parliament will be held in the first half of 1999.</p>
<p>Scottish residency will be the main qualification, with Commonwealth and European Union citizens eligible to vote if resident in Scotland. Peers, peeresses and ministers of religion banned from U.K. elections will all be able to vote.</p>
<p>Voting will be for 73 constituency members, with a further 56 chosen from party lists by proportional representation. Elections will be held every four years.</p>
<p>The 72 Scottish members in the UK parliament will be cut when the Boundary Commission reviews constituencies to equalise the size of each electorate. Present rules mean Scotland must have not less than 71.</p>
<p>Though Scottish Conservatives oppose devolution, they pledge to contest elections if a parliament is set up.</p>
<p>Brian Meek, a former Scottish Conservative vice-chairman, said he believed the people of Scotland would vote overwhelmingly in favour of a parliament. His biggest political mistake was not taking part in the Constitutional Convention, Meek said in the Herald newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;Tories (Conservatives) like me ought have been there,&quot; he said. &quot;You can't have any influence from outside. We need more prominent Conservatives to take part, fewer telling the people they've got it wrong.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EDINBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
