<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752308" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Taylor gets mandate to rebuild wrecked Liberia.</title>
<headline>Taylor gets mandate to rebuild wrecked Liberia.</headline>
<byline>John Chiahemen</byline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former warlord Charles Taylor won a landslide victory in in Liberia's post-civil war presidential election, according to final results declared on Thursday.</p>
<p>Liberians, looking for strong leadership, turned to the gritty Taylor as the man most able to stand up to other warlords and prevent a return to the bloodletting that shattered Africa's first modern republic.</p>
<p>Taylor reciprocated the popular gesture, extending an olive branch to other converted warlords in the faction-ridden West African state.</p>
<p>&quot;To all ex-combatants...I say I am now your president. I am not going to be a wicked president, but I will not be a weak president,&quot; Taylor declared, reading from a victory statement.</p>
<p>&quot;To all the faction leaders I extend my hand of friendship to you. Come and help in rebuilding this republic for the new millenium.&quot;</p>
<p>Final results announced by Independent Elections Commission chairman Henry Andrews at a formal ceremony earlier showed Taylor, candidate of the National Patriotic Party, polled 468,443 votes or 75.3 percent of ballots.</p>
<p>The runner-up, former United Nations executive Ellen Johnson-Sirleaf, received 59,557 votes or 9.6 percent. None of the 10 other candidates attained 10 percent.</p>
<p>After a brief session of the elections commission, Andrews formally read out a motion declaring Taylor &quot;duly elected&quot;.</p>
<p>Taylor's victory came almost on the eve of the 150th anniversary on July 26 of the founding of Liberia by freed American slaves.</p>
<p>He becomes the first descendant of freed slaves to lead the country since soldiers led by Sergeant Samuel Doe ended the 133- year, one-party rule of the True Whig Party in 1980.</p>
<p>The last Americo-Liberian president, William Tolbert, was executed in that coup along with several of his aides.</p>
<p>The October 1985 election was widely believed to have been rigged by Doe and triggered a coup attempt a month later which he crushed, leading to a ferocious seven-year civil war.</p>
<p>Doe was captured in Monrovia in September 1990 and tortured to death by a breakaway faction of Taylor's National Patriotic Front of Liberia. The NPFL started the war with an invasion by 150 fighters from Ivory Coast.</p>
<p>The 16-member Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS), breaking new ground in regional peacekeeping, sent in a Nigerian-led multinational force which policed Liberia. It disarmed guerrillas and provided security for the elections.</p>
<p>The war killed more than 150,000 people and uprooted more than half the pre-war population of 2.5 million. The economy, which was based iron ore, diamond, rubber and timber exports, is ruined.</p>
<p>Andrews put turnout on polling day at just under 90 percent of some 700,000 registered voters, which he said far surpassed that in 1985.</p>
<p>He cited Liberians who rose hours before dawn to cast their ballots to show their rejection of rule by the gun.</p>
<p>&quot;If we truly love our country...we will at this moment take a cue from the man in the street. This is the plea of the commission to the nation,&quot; Andrews said before announcing the final results.</p>
<p>Several of the 11 candidates who competed for president with Taylor attended the ceremony inside a ground-floor hall of the elections commission headquarters.</p>
<p>Johnson-Sirleaf was absent as was Alhaji Kromah, one of two warlords who vied with Taylor for president. The second, George Boley, was present and joined the other candidates in congratulating Taylor as his victory was announced.</p>
<p>Taylor, sporting his trademark cream safari suit, smiled broadly. Thousands of his supporters sang and danced in the streets and packed the forecourt of his party headquarters.</p>
<p>Voters also elected 26 senators and 64 lower house deputies in the poll based on proportional representation. The distribution of seats among parties will be announced later.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
