<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752417" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanian parliament lifts state of emergency.</title>
<headline>Albanian parliament lifts state of emergency.</headline>
<byline>Marko Bello</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's parliament on Thursday lifted a state of emergency and curfew introduced on March 2 after an armed uprising broke out in response to the collapse of pyramid investment schemes.</p>
<p>All 104 deputies attending the session voted in favour of the measure, which takes effect immediately, ending a nationwide 10 p.m. to 5 a.m. curfew.</p>
<p>Deputies of parliament's new Socialist majority said the move got their government off to a good start.</p>
<p>&quot;The Socialist Party does not wish to elect the new president with the law on the state of emergency in force,&quot; said Pandeli Majko, head of the Socialist parliamentary group.</p>
<p>Socialist Party leader and prime minister designate Fatos Nano said: &quot;We should replace the emergency of the destruction of our institutions with the emergency of their construction.&quot;</p>
<p>The session then began debate on a new president, expected to be Socialist secretary-general Rexhep Mejdani. Outgoing president Sali Berisha resigned hours before the new parliament opened on Wednesday to take a seat as an opposition deputy.</p>
<p>Small changes introduced by parliament's commission on mandates on Thursday morning left the Socialists and their coalition allies with 119 seats in the 155-seat parliament, while the Democrats were reduced to 27. Seven deputies are</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
