<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752418" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Europe and CIS port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>Europe and CIS port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>BULGARIA, July 21 - Varna - East - 2 Vessels loading at berth, 5 discharging at berth, 3 waiting at anchorage to load, 2 waiting at anchorage to discharge. West - 10 Vessels loading at berth, 3 discharging at berth, 2 waiting at anchorage to load. Bourgas - East - 15 Vessels due, 2 loading at berth, 1 discharging at berth, 9 waiting at anchorage to load, 1 under repair/drydock. West - 1 Vessel loading at berth, 1 tanker in port. Bourgas - Four vessels operating of which 3 loading, 1 general, 1 steel, 1 ammonia nitrate, 1 vessel discharging paper. 4 Vessels waiting in roads for loading of 1 cars, 1 gasoil, 1 benzene, 1 tanker. 8 Vessels due of which 5 to load, 3 steel, 1 clinker, 1 ammonia nitrate, 3 to discharge iron ore.</p>
<p>Varna - 36 Vessels operating of which 23 loading, 1 tsp, 1 cellulose, 1 paper, 1 plywood, 1 edc, 7 soda, 4 cement, 1 cigarettes, 2 clinker, 1 kaoline, 1 sas, 1 urea, 1 quartz sand. 4 Discharging, 1 coal, 1 soya fodder/maize, 1 coke, 1 general. 1 Discharging/loading soya fodder/frozen chickens. 8 Discharging/loading 3 trucks/containers, 5 containers. 18 Vessels due of which 4 to load, 1 general, 2 cement, 1 clinker. 1 To discharge coal, 5 to discharge/load containers, 8 cargo not nominated.</p>
<p>CYPRUS, July 22 - Limassol - Vessels due on 23/7, 5 containers, 2 conventional vessels, 5 passenger vessels. No delays expected. 7 Container vessels discharging/loading at berth, 2 conventional vessels discharging at berth, 2 ro-ro vessels discharging/loading at berth, 1 vessel waiting at anchorage to discharge/load. Larnaca - Vessels due on 23/7, 1 container vessel, 1 conventional vessel. No delays expected. 5 Containers discharging/loading at berth, 2 conventional vessels discharging at berth.</p>
<p>ESTONIA, July 22 - Tallinn - City port - 3 Vessels due, no delays expected. 1 Vessel loading timber at berth, 1 liner vessel. Kopli - 7 vessels due, no delays expected. 1 Vessel loading fertiliser at berth, 1 vessel discharging frozen meat at berth. Parnu - 1 Vessel due, no delays expected. Loading at berth, 5 timber, 1 peat moss. Muuga - 7 Vessels due, no delays expected. Loading at berth, 1 fuel oil, 1 timber, 1 scrap, 1 fertiliser. Discharging at berth, 1 frozen meat, 1 container vessel, 1 liner vessel.</p>
<p>ITALY, July 22 - Naples - One bulk carrier in port. Gaeta, Salerno - No vessels in roads. Genoa commercial port - No vessels in roads, no delays. 32 Vessels berthed, 2 in drydock. Multedo oil harbour, Civitavecchia, Gaeta, Naples, Salerno, Palermo, Ancona/Falconara, Venice - No vessels in roads, no delays. Savona - One vessel in roads, no delays, 3 vessels berthed. Vado Ligure - No vessels in roads, no delays, 1 vessel berthed. La Spezia - No vessels in roads, no delays, 7 vessels berthed. Leghorn - No vessels in roads, 15 berthed. Augusta oil harbour - Three vessels in roads, 4 berthed. Syracuse oil harbour - One vessel in roads, 1 berthed. Sarroch - Four vessels in roads, 6 berthed. Taranto - No vessels in roads, 2 berthed, no delays. Ravenna - No delays. Trieste - Commercial port - No vessels in roads, no delays. Siot oil terminal - 2 Vessels berthed, 2 in roads, no delays.</p>
<p>LATVIA, July 23 - Riga - 17 Vessels operating of which 3 timber loaders, 2 container loaders, 1 tanker loader, 2 steel loaders, 1 fertiliser loader, 2 frozen food discharger, 2 awaiting operations, 2 sugar dischargers, 2 general cargo. No delays, 18 vessels due. Ventspils - Two vessels operating of which 1 steel loader, 2 awaiting operations. No delays, 10 vessels due.</p>
<p>LITHUANIA, July 21 - Klaipeda - Vessels loading, 2 fertiliser, 1 oil, 1 metal, 2 cement, 2 steel coils, 1 pig iron. Discharging, 6 fish, 1 sugar, 1 stuffing, 1 fertiliser, 2 fish powder, 1 sunflowerseed, 1 malt. 1 Vessel in roads, 26 due.</p>
<p>POLAND, July 22 - Gdynia - Eight vessels operating of which 5 loading at berth (1 coal, 4 bulk). 2 General cargo discharging at berth, 1 waiting at anchorage to discharge, 7 under repair/drydock. 27 Vessels due. Gdansk - Eight vessels operating of which 6 loading at berth (4 bulk, 1 general cargo, 1 tanker). 2 Discharging at berth of which 1 general cargo, 1 bulk. 20 Vessels due. Szczecin - July 23 - 57 Vessels due, 26 loading at berth, 31 discharging at berth, 1 waiting at anchorage to discharge, 13 under repair/drydock.</p>
<p>PORTUGAL, July 21 - Lisbon - 34 Vessels due, 83 in port, 4 loading at berth, 19 unloading at berth, 5 loading and unloading at berth, 4 loading at anchorage, 1 unloading at anchorage. 3 Bunkering, 20 under repair/drydock, 4 awaiting orders, 23 miscellaneous craft. July 22 -Setubal - Vessels in port, 4 loading at berth, 5 discharging at berth, 5 under repair/drydock. Vessels due, 5 for discharging, 2 for loading, 1 for repair/drydock. Sines - One vessel discharging coal, 1 vessel awaiting orders to discharge propane. Vessels due, 3 to discharge crude, 2 to discharge coal, 1 to discharge butane, 1 to load unleaded gasoline.</p>
<p>ROMANIA, July 21 - Constanta - 31 Vessels operating of which 16 generals loading, 10 bulkers (5 loading, 5 discharging), 2 bagged cement loading, 1 tanker loading, 2 containers (1 loading, 1 discharging). 6 Vessels waiting in roads of which 5 loading generals, 1 bulker loading. Constanta Sud (Agigea) - Five vessels loading generals. Mangalia - One vessel loading generals, 2 discharging. Midia - Five livestock carriers loading.</p>
<p>RUSSIA, July 21 - BALTIC PORTS - Kaliningrad - Commercial sea port - 8 Vessels operating of which 6 loading (2 ferro alloys, 1 fertiliser, 3 coal). 2 Discharging (1 cars, 1 wheat flour). 2 Vessels waiting, 7 due. Fishery port - 4 Vessels operating of which 3 discharging frozen fish, 1 loading fertiliser. 4 Vessels due. St. Petersburg - July 22 - 23 Vessels operating of which loading 3 non-ferrous, 3 steel, 8 fertiliser, 1 container vessel. Discharging, 2 frozen chicken, 1 rice, 2 container vessels, 1 fertiliser, 1 bagged sugar, 1 general cargo. 8 Vessels awaiting operations, 11 due. Kaliningrad - 10 Vessels operating, no delays, 5 vessels due. Vyborg - Three vessels operating. No delays. 4 Vessels due.</p>
<p>BLACK SEA - Novorossiysk - 15 Operating of which 11 loading, 2 coal, 1 cement, 5 steel, 1 scrap, 1 paper, 1 saltpetre. 4 Discharging, 3 sugar, 1 various. 15 Vessels waiting in roads of which 8 to load, 2 coal, 3 steel, 1 urea, 1 aluminium, 1 cast iron. 7 To discharge, 2 sugar, 3 rice, 1 frozen poultry, 1 luggage. 34 Due of which 20 to load 1 cement, 3 scrap, 1 cast iron, 9 steel, 1 tin, 1 aluminium, 1 copper, 1 copper cathodes, 1 coal, 1 cellulose. 12 To discharge, 5 sugar, 2 rice, 1 citrus, 1 soyoil, 1 general, 1 zinc concentrate, 1 luggage. 2 To discharge/load containers. Oil terminal - 3 Vessels berthed to load crude oil, diesel oil, fuel oil. 1 Berthed to deballast. 1 Crude oil tanker waiting in roads, 8 tankers due to load of which 5 crude oil, 1 diesel oil, 2 fuel oil.</p>
<p>July 21 - Northern Basin - Murmansk - Four vessels operating of which 1 apatite, 1 alumina, 1 steel scrap, 1 non-ferrous metal. No vessels waiting. Vessels due during the week, 4 loaders (3 apatite, 1 iron pellets). 2 Dischargers (1 alumina, 1 general cargo).</p>
<p>SLOVENIA, Koper - 14 Vessels berthed, 2 containers loading/discharging, 4 general cargo vessels loading sawn timber, pipes, steel, 2 bulk carriers loading coal, 2 bulk carriers discharging chrome ore, bauxite, 1 livestock carrier loading bulls, 1 reefer discharging bananas, 1 discharging vegetable oil. 1 Spanish navy vessel on courtesy visit. 7 Vessels due during next 2 days of which 3 containers to load/discharge, 1 car carrier to load cars, 1 general cargo to load sawn timber, paper, 1 ferry to load/discharge, 1 chemical tanker to discharge acids. No delays expected in port.</p>
<p>SPAIN, July 22 - Cadiz - 15 Vessels operating of which 3 ro-ro, 1 sugar, 1 semolina, 1 wood, 1 oil, 2 shipbuilding material, 1 sand. 5 Under repair, no delays.</p>
<p>TURKEY, July 21 - Istanbul - Haydarpasa - 6 Vessels operating of which 2 containers, 2 dry cargo, 2 ro-ros. No berthing delays. Galata 11 Cargo/passenger vessels operating. Port congested. Ambarli - 12 Vessels operating, no berthing delays. July 22 - Mersin - Nine vessels awaiting orders. 14 Operating of which loading, 2 legumes, 1 cement. Discharging, 2 bulk oil, 1 bulk wheat, 1 paraxylene, 1 pvc, 1 bulk rice. Loading/discharging, 2 vehicles, 2 container vessels, 1 vehicle/containers. No vessels in free zone piers. Seka - No vessels in port.</p>
<p>UKRAINE, July 21 - Mariupol - Nine vessels operating of which 8 loading, 7 steel, 1 wire rods/debars, 1 discharging equipment. 8 Vessels waiting in roads of which 6 to load, 2 steel, 1 sulphur, 1 urea, 1 coal, 1 fire clay. 1 To discharge urea, 1 to discharge/load containers. 30 Vessels due of which 22 to load 2 urea, 3 map, 7 steel, 3 ammonia sulphate, 1 sulphur, 4 fire clay, 1 kaolin, 1 sulphate. 5 To discharge, 2 ammonia sulphate, 1 clay, 1 alumina, 1 building materials. 2 To discharge/load containers. 1 Cargo not nominated. Odessa - 10 Vessels operating of which 6 loading, 3 metals, 1 oil, 2 fuel oil. 2 Discharging/loading containers. 1 Passenger vessel, 1 under repair. No vessels in roads, 23 due of which 19 to load, 16 metals, 1 oil, 1 equipment, 1 urea. 3 To discharge, 1 general, 1 diesel, 1 bananas, 1 to discharge/load containers.</p>
<p>Ilyichevsk - 10 Vessels operating of which 8 loading  4 steel, 2 pig iron, 1 spirit, 1 potash. 2 Discharging/loading containers. 3 Vessels waiting in roads of which 2 to load steel, 1 to discharge soybean. 13 Due of which 7 to load, 5 steel, 1 debars, 1 pig iron. 3 To discharge oil, 3 to discharge/load containers. July 22 - Odessa - Steel cargo loading. 6 Vessels alongside. 9 Vessels due. Containers, 1 vessel alongside, 1 due. Tanker loading, 2 tankers alongside, 1 tanker discharger due. General cargo, 3 vessels due. Fertiliser, 1 due. Ilyichevsk - Steel cargo loading, 5 vessels alongside. Containers, 1 alongside. Fertiliser, 1 vessel alongside.</p>
<p>Mariupol - Nine vessels loading at berth (metal products, clay, sulphur, coal), 1 container vessel discharging at berth. 6 Vessels waiting at anchorage to load,(urea, coal, fertiliser, sulphur, metal products. 1 General cargo waiting at anchorage to discharge, 1 reloading urea to sea-going vessel. 8 Floating storehouses (fertiliser, sulphur). 29 Vessels due for discharging and loading (fertiliser, clay, metal products, alumina, general cargo, containers). Kerch - Two vessels under repair/dry-dock, 2 due to load ore. Berdiansk - Two vessels loading at berth of which 1 fertiliser, 1 metal products, 1 due to load coke.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
