<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752448" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Merger could still be on time-Polifarb W.</title>
<headline>Merger could still be on time-Polifarb W.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The planned merger between Polish paintmakers Polifarb Wroclaw and Polifarb Cieszyn might still take place by the end of September as planned despite flooding at Wroclaw, Wroclaw's president said.</p>
<p>Andrzej Platek told Reuters on Thursday that the merger might see no delay despite a statement by Cieszyn's spokesman that the need to appraise flood damage at Wroclaw could push back the merger by at least a month.</p>
<p>&quot;The merger can be delayed if the KPW does not accept the submitted prospectus and current remarks added to it,&quot; Platek said, referring to the Securities Commission and an issue prospectus linked with the merger.</p>
<p>Trade in Polifarb Wroclaw has been suspended since July 11 when floodwaters inundated the factory, a fact Cieszyn spokesman Jacek Nagorniewicz said could delay the merger.</p>
<p>&quot;Currently we expect that the whole procedure can be drawn out for at least another month,&quot; PAP news agency quoted Nagorniewicz as saying from the southern town of Bielsko Biala.</p>
<p>No one at Cieszyn was immediately available for comment. @</p>
<p>Platek said that damage at Wroclaw would likely be appraised by Monday by the firm and its insurer, PZU SA, after which the company would await a bourse decision concerning its suspension.</p>
<p>He said that after the damage appraisal is sent to the Securities Commission the firm would submit the merger prospectus, which the KPW would likely examine on August 7.</p>
<p>Earlier this week the firm resumed sales and production, which would gradually be expanded.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
