<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752546" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Milosevic move is chance to fix US ties, ally says.</title>
<headline>Milosevic move is chance to fix US ties, ally says.</headline>
<byline>Gordana Filipovic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top Yugoslav official on Thursday urged the United States to end sanctions against Belgrade and said the election of Slobodan Milosevic as Yugoslav president was an opportunity to improve strained ties.</p>
<p>Relations remain at a low ebb over Belgrade's reluctance fully to implement the Dayton peace accord, which Washington says is a pre-condition for Yugoslavia to resume membership of the United Nations and international financial bodies.</p>
<p>Zivorad Jovanovic, vice-president of Milosevic's ruling Socialist Party of Serbia, criticised the Clinton administration's stance.</p>
<p>&quot;It is counter-productive to implement pressure and conditions against Yugoslavia. Instead of such negative, restrictive measures, one should foster a constructive approach and see what good and positive effects can be achieved in cooperating with Yugoslavia,&quot; Jovanovic told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said Milosevic's move on Wednesday from the Serbian presidency to the presidency of the Yugoslav federation -- comprising Serbia and the smaller Montenegro -- could put relations on a new footing.</p>
<p>&quot;With President Milosevic elected Yugoslavia's president the United States will have a stable partner...and in that respect opportunity for relations between Yugoslavia and the United States to improve,&quot; said Jovanovic, also one of the assistant ministers who rank below the deputy foreign minister.</p>
<p>Washington insists Yugoslavia must cooperate with the international war crimes tribunal in The Hague before it can return to the United Nations and international financial bodies.</p>
<p>And it says Belgrade must show it respects human rights in its mostly ethnic Albanian province of Kosovo, and make progress on dividing former Yugoslavia's assets.</p>
<p>Milosevic's switch to the Yugoslav presidency, hitherto a relatively unimportant post, is widely interpreted in Serbia itself as a tactic to remain the political supremo in Belgrade and power broker in the crisis-ridden Balkans.</p>
<p>Jovanovic insisted political ties between Belgrade and Washington had already been improving.</p>
<p>&quot;Political dialogue between Yugoslavia and the United States progresses and shows continuity and an upward trend which is frequently neither spectacular nor obvious but undoubtedly positive,&quot; said Jovanovic, also vice-president</p>
<p>He said Yugoslavia and the United States were sure to normalise relations at some stage, but declined to predict when.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important that Yugoslavia is fully open and interested as a traditional ally and partner to America in normalising and restoring tranditional cooperation based on mutual recognition, friendship and common interests,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
