<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752530" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin aides defend anti-corruption campaign. [CORRECTED 13:35 GMT]</title>
<headline>Yeltsin aides defend anti-corruption campaign. [CORRECTED 13:35 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Oleg Shchedrov</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aides to President Boris Yeltsin said on Thursday many top officials had ignored his orders to declare their property and income under an anti-corruption drive.</p>
<p>But they told a news conference there were few legal means of prosecuting saboteurs and setting tough moral standards for Russian politicians in the near future.</p>
<p>&quot;More than 63 percent of Russia's regional leaders failed to meet the July 20 deadline for filing their declarations,&quot; Yeltsin's deputy chief of staff, Yevgeny Savostyanov, said. &quot;The situation is too bad with the regional leaders.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There are no articles in the criminal code to punish the saboteurs,&quot; he added. &quot;So they could only be punished (corrects from &quot;published&quot;) administratively in a way the president will decide.&quot;</p>
<p>Yeltsin, 66, ordered top officials to make their incomes public as part of a drive to root out the age-old scourge of corruption, which he says is an obstacle to economic reforms.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has declared his own income, as have Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin and other ministers.</p>
<p>Alexander Livshits, a Kremlin economic aide, said the first experience of declaring property and incomes by officials had proved confusing but had played a positive role.</p>
<p>Critics have said many officials have seriously distorted the price of property they own in a mockery of the whole idea.</p>
<p>One official put the price of his smart Lincoln Towncar as &quot;less then 120 million roubles&quot; ($20,000).</p>
<p>&quot;Sell it to me for $30,000 and I will resell it for $60,000 the next day,&quot; one reporter shouted out at the news conference.</p>
<p>Livshits argued that the problem was not that the official had any wicked intentions but that it was difficult to assess the values of possessions in many areas of the nascent Russian market.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course some of the values cited in the declarations may look funny but this does not matter,&quot; Livshits said. &quot;The main thing is that now we have some starting point.&quot;</p>
<p>Savostyanov said that although imperfect, the mechanism of property declarations still encouraged public servants to make honest statements and would help trace some corrupt officials.</p>
<p>&quot;It is as simple as that. If an official fails to declare some sources of income or property he will some day find himself cornered,&quot; Savostyanov said.</p>
<p>The decision to expose some facts in the personal lives of civil servants attacks the foundations of the carefully preserved ivory tower in which bureaucrats have lived since Tsar Peter the Great in the early 18th century.</p>
<p>Political advisor Georgy Satarov said the concept of a &quot;public figure&quot; -- an official more exposed than others to public scrutiny and judged by higher moral standards than others -- was still alien for Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;We must look at this concept from the historical point of view,&quot; Satarov said, noting other countries had moved slowly towards accepting the idea.&quot;Russia is an exception because it is moving towards a civilised order at great speed.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Give us another 150 years and we will settle the problem,&quot; Savostyanov interfered jokingly.</p>
<p>&quot;No, I think we will come to this faster,&quot; Livshits replied.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
