<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752661" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Priebke lawyer to challenge Argentine return ban.</title>
<headline>Priebke lawyer to challenge Argentine return ban.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Argentine lawyer of former SS captain Erich Priebke said on Thursday that he would challenge Argentina's ban on the ex-Nazi's return after he has served out his prison sentence in Italy.</p>
<p>Priebke lived openly in Argentina from 1948 until 1995, when he was extradited to Italy to face trial for his part in Italy's worst Second World War atrocity, the massacre of 335 men and boys at the Ardeatine Caves outside Rome in 1944.</p>
<p>Priebke, 83, and ex-SS major Karl Hass, 84, were convicted on Tuesday for the massacre, in which many Jews were murdered. But the military court conceded mitigating circumstances which reduced the sentences to freedom for Hass and five years for Priebke.</p>
<p>Priebke has already served 3-1/2 years' arrest so he will only spend 18 months in an Italian jail, after which he wants to return to his wife in the Andean ski resort of Bariloche.</p>
<p>However, Argentine President Carlos Menem ordered a ban on Priebke's return last August, after a first Italian military trial briefly declared Priebke a free man.</p>
<p>The ex-Nazi's Argentine lawyer, Pedro Bianchi, told Reuters in a telephone interview that he would appeal the order.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe it is an arbitrary and unfounded decree for someone who lived in Argentina for 50 years,&quot; said Bianchi, who was due to travel to Italy on Thursday to see Priebke.</p>
<p>He accused Menem of &quot;wanting to look good with the Jewish community in Argentina&quot; by banning Priebke's return.</p>
<p>The head of Argentina's large Jewish community, Ruben Beraja, said on Wednesday the government had promised him Priebke would not be allowed back into the country.</p>
<p>Priebke and Hass have both admitted shooting two people each at the Ardeatine caves, but said they would have been shot themselves if they failed to follow orders. Priebke said he ticked names off a list as victims arrived at the caves.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
