<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752610" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - July 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - July 24.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 7142 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>***GENERAL***</p>
<p>- The parliamentary group of opposition Christian Democrat party will oficially cease to operate on Friday.</p>
<p>- An eight-member interministerial commission will oversee women's rights.</p>
<p>- The government is expected to discuss measrues to improve the situation of the Gipsy minority.</p>
<p>- The Hungarian consulate has reopened in the Transylvanian town of Cluj.</p>
<p>- Germany will not issue further work permits for Poles and Hungarians.</p>
<p>- The first Hungarian of a dormant Swiss bank account was identified on Wednesday.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>***BUSINESS***</p>
<p>- Hungary's GDP edged up 1.2 percent in the first quarter compared with the same period of 1996.</p>
<p>- Building industry output grew 1.1 percent year-on-year in the January-May period.</p>
<p>- The crawling peg forint devaluation couyld be reduced again in September, Finance Minister Peter Medgyessy said in Beijing.</p>
<p>- The board of state privatisation agency APv Rt has approved an asset swap between APV and Postabank.</p>
<p>- The CEO of national airline MALEV has rejected anonymous charges that the $8.5 million paid by the Italian airline Alitalia for a minority stake.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>- Privatisation agency APV has approved the sale of the remaining 25 percent state stake in the country's largest bank, OTP Bank.</p>
<p>MAGYAR HIRLAP</p>
<p>- Pension funds will end the dominance of foreign investors in Hungary's capital markets.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
