<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752655" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Menem ex-wife camps out in police HQ protest.</title>
<headline>Menem ex-wife camps out in police HQ protest.</headline>
<byline>Jason Webb</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's former first lady Zulema Yoma on Thursday continued for a second day her sit-in at police headquarters, where she passed the night on a sofa bed in protest at an alleged cover-up of her son's death.</p>
<p>Yoma accuses her ex-husband President Carlos Menem's government of trying to disguise what she alleges was the murder of their son Carlos Jr., who died at 26 when the helicopter he was piloting hit a power cable in 1995.</p>
<p>She is refusing to leave police headquarters until they release a report which she says will show the helicopter crashed after being hit by sniper fire.</p>
<p>The original Air Force report into Carlos Jr.'s crash wrote it off as an accident. It said the president's son was flying his chopper low along a highway when he hit a power cable, killing himself and a friend flying with him.</p>
<p>Yoma alleges it was a political murder being covered up by security services. Various newspapers have carried alleged leaks of the police report on the case showing that the helicopter wreckage bore the traces of four bullet holes.</p>
<p>Visitors reported that aides brought Yoma pizza, sandwiches and soft drinks for her first supper on Wednesday night in the police reception room she has taken over. They brought her a portable bed and made her a cup of tea in the morning when she awoke.</p>
<p>Yoma is also demanding that her former husband come to police HQ and make them hand over the report.</p>
<p>But Menem's lawyer Ricardo Klass said the president was concerned both by the probe into his son's death and by his ex-wife's actions, but was going to stay away from Yoma.</p>
<p>Menem &quot;is completely informed of what is going on and has a great interest in this situation being cleared up as soon as possible, as it is causing him deep grief,&quot; Klass told local radio.</p>
<p>The report was due to be released on Thursday but was delayed after Menem's lawyers requested that investigating Judge Carlos Villanueva send for technical information from U.S. firm Bell Helicopters, who made his son's chopper.</p>
<p>One of Yoma's aides, Roberto Lockler, told the private DyN news agency that the move by Menem's lawyers could delay the report by months.</p>
<p>The 67-year-old president was devastated by the death of his son. But he does not support Yoma's theory, calling it the product of a mother's grief.</p>
<p>Yoma, who divorced Menem after being thrown out of the palace in 1990, has ignored dismissals by senior officials that she is hysterical and has lobbied tirelessly against what she says is a murky plot involving politics and drugs.</p>
<p>She has had the body exhumed for a second autopsy and has managed to get the word &quot;accident&quot; removed from the file.</p>
<p>The former first lady's conspiracy theory is gradually gaining acceptance and even the public prosecutor in charge of the case, Amalia Sivori, told a newspaper this week that she was investigating &quot;a possible double homicide.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
