<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752678" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Lima shares end down on political risk worries.</title>
<headline>Lima shares end down on political risk worries.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-06-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares on the Lima stock exchange closed down Thursday as investors continued to worry about the country's political risk following a series of scandals hounding President Alberto Fujimori, brokers said.</p>
<p>Players were largely expected to stay on the sidelines Friday as political fears were seen dragging prices down again, they added.</p>
<p>Thursday, the General Index fell 1.90 percent to 2,894.1 points, while the blue-chip Selective Index dropped 1.68 percent to 2,032.9 points, according to preliminary figures.  </p>
<p>In a total of 1,632 trades, volume was 34.0 million soles ($12.8 million), brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The political blunders of the government have made the market jumpy,&quot; said Alberto Giha of local brokerage 4G. &quot;Investors ... are taking the sensible route by sitting tight until President Fujimori's (July 28 State of the Nation) address.&quot;</p>
<p>Fujimori's popularity in the polls has fallen to its lowest point during his seven years in office as Peruvians have become increasingly hostile to his perceived authoritarian style.  </p>
<p>Last week, media allegations of phone tapping by the secret services and the government's attempt to annul the Peruvian citizenship of an Israeli-born television station owner led to violent protests against Fujimori.</p>
<p>Commentators have predicted Fujimori will use the July 28 speech to announce measures aimed at stopping the slide in his popularity.</p>
<p>Benchmark Telefnica del Per fell 1.10 percent to 6.27 soles on volume of 1.9 million shares.  </p>
<p>Cement company Cementos Lima suffered the biggest drop among leaders, falling 8.77 percent to 5.20 soles on low volume of 25,000 shares.</p>
<p>Peru's largest brewery group Unin de Cerveceras Peruanas Backus y Johnston SA closed at 2.19 soles with a 4.78 percent fall on volume of 2.2 million shares.</p>
<p>Miner Atacocha registered the biggest rise among leaders, climbing 1.15 percent to 2.65 soles and a volume of 250,000 shares.</p>
<p>((-- Eduardo Orozco, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-06-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
