<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75263" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Nicaragua prepares anti-drug money laundering law.</title>
<headline>Nicaragua prepares anti-drug money laundering law.</headline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nicaraguan officials are taking steps to control money laundering and the entry of drug money into its election campaign, a top official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to introduce a bill into the National Assembly next week to regulate the laundering of money from illegal activities such as drug trafficking,&quot; Vice Interior Minister Frank Cesar, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Cesar said Nicaragua, a growing transshipment point for cocaine being smuggled from Colombia to the United States, is one of the few Latin American countries without a law against money laundering.</p>
<p>&quot;We can identify money launderers but there's no legal mechanism to punish them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nicaragua also has little control over the money entering the campaign chests of its political parties, making it easy for drug money to influence the election process, as has happened in Colombia and Panama, he said.</p>
<p>Both Colombian President Ernesto Samper and Panamanian President Ernesto Perez Balladares have been rocked by charges drug cartels donated money to their election campaigns.</p>
<p>&quot;If it happened in Colombia and Panama, countries with a history of democratic government, it could happen in Nicaragua, which is new to democracy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cesar said the bill could become law before Nicaragua's Oct. 20 elections, or before a possible run-off vote in December, and be applied to this election campaign.</p>
<p>While the amount of money laundered in Nicaragua is minor compared to other Latin American countries, the proposed laws are designed to nip the problem in the bud, he said.</p>
<p>The law proposes sentences of four to 25 year for people convicted of money laundering, and politicians accepting drug money in their campaigns will have to pay fines of double the amount of money received, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
