<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752680" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONDURAS: Catholic bishop to run Honduran police force.</title>
<headline>Catholic bishop to run Honduran police force.</headline>
<dateline>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The archbishop of Tegucigalpa has been tapped by Honduran President Carlos Roberto Reina to run the country's national police force while it undergoes a transition from military to civilian control, a legislator said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Monsignor Oscar Rodriguez will head a special board that will oversee the transition, Raul Pineda, leader of the opposition National Party in Congress, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an agreement in the Congress that the temporary board presided over by Monsignor Oscar Rodriguez will assume control of the police and moreover, will carry out the evaluation and purification of the police corps,&quot; Pineda said.</p>
<p>In the meantime, the Congress will work on a law outlining a new police structure in this Central American country.</p>
<p>The national police force of about 6,500 officers has been under military control since 1963. Since then, human rights organisations have accused police of widespread human rights abuses, abuse of power, corruption and ties to organised crime.</p>
<p>&quot;This will eliminate the rotten fruit that has compromised the prestige of the Honduras police,&quot; Pineda said of the reforms.</p>
<p>Reina has made curtailing the vast powers of the military a central theme of his presidency. Among other measures, he has removed the police from army control and eliminated the military draft.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONDURAS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
