<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752638" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ECUADOR: Ecuador rating to boost investment, help IMF talks.</title>
<headline>Ecuador rating to boost investment, help IMF talks.</headline>
<dateline>QUITO, Ecuador 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The B1 credit rating assigned to Ecuador's long-term foreign currency debt Thursday will help investment in the country and boost talks with the International Monetary Fund, Ecuadorean officials said.</p>
<p>Danilo Carrera, president of the country's policy setting monetary board, told journalists the rating &quot;will serve to help in the talks with the IMF and with international banks on the necessary issues of international financing.&quot;</p>
<p>Moody's Investors Service assigned a B1 rating to Ecuador Thursday, putting it at the same level as Argentina and Brazil. It is Ecuador's first ever rating.</p>
<p>The rating &quot;has important immediate positive effects for trade in Ecuadorean debt, for new loans and for new investments,&quot; Carrera added.</p>
<p>The ratings news coincided with a visit to the country by an IMF mission that arrived Monday to study the progress of Ecuador's economy with emphasis on its fiscal accounts.</p>
<p>&quot;The strengths of the (government's) macro-economic program have been analyzed by the IMF mission...this opens the possibility of arriving at an understanding with this important international organization,&quot; Central Bank General Manager Fidel Jaramillo told reporters.</p>
<p>((--Franz Bastidas, Quito Newsroom, 5932 258429))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUITO, Ecuador"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ECUADOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
