<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752742" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's leader chastizes controversial minister.</title>
<headline>Brazil's leader chastizes controversial minister.</headline>
<byline>Michael Christie</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO, Brazil 1997-07-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian President Fernando Henrique Cardoso on Wednesday chastised a cabinet member for criticising his political allies and moved to quell a potentially destabilising rebellion among his supporters.</p>
<p>Ordering his ministers to keep their personal opinions to themselves, the reformist president said none of his government ministers was exempt from possible dismissal.</p>
<p>&quot;Certain issues regarding private opinions should not be debated in public. That goes for all ministers,&quot; Cardoso said at a previously unscheduled news conference.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day Cardoso managed to head off the resignation of the government's chief whip in the lower house, Deputy Luis Eduardo Magalhaes, an immensely powerful figure in Brazilian politics often tipped as a future president.</p>
<p>Brazilian stock prices tumbled when rumours of Magalhaes' possible resignation hit local news wires.</p>
<p>Magalhaes was furious over a Veja magazine interview given by controversial Communications Minister Sergio Motta in which Motta blasted virtually every government ally in Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;He's as sackable as any other,&quot; Cardoso said of Motta when asked if the minister had survived the furore his interview provoked because he was considered indispensible.</p>
<p>But he also stressed Motta's important role in the $70 billion privatisation of Brazil's telecommunications industry.</p>
<p>In the past Motta has criticised the president's wife, Ruth Cardoso, who heads a government social welfare programme, for carrying out &quot;sociological masturbation.&quot;</p>
<p>But Motta is also a close friend of Cardoso's and often regarded as playing the bad cop role in government. The two are joint owners of a farm in central Brazil.</p>
<p>News reports said Magalhaes had agreed to stay on only if Cardoso publicly rebuked Motta and affirmed his faith in the parties that make up the governing coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no grounds for government ministers to criticise Congress' performance,&quot; Cardoso said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO, Brazil"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
