<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752851" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Debt wallows in currency mire.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Debt wallows in currency mire.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian debt markets wallowed in the mire on Thursday as continued currency volatility sidelined all but the most intrepid of debt issuers.</p>
<p>Even AAA-rated Singapore found its currency sliding to 32-month lows against the U.S. dollar, plunging to levels not seen since November 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;The currency market is very volatile,&quot; said one banker, asked why new issues were so scarce.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, the Hong Kong dollar strengthened, and the swap market steadied, but fluctuating interest rates ruled out the thought of new issues.</p>
<p>Bankers were focusing on the default by Thai property firm Somprasong Land on a euroconvertible bond, and its implications for holders of Asian bonds.</p>
<p>Somprasong missed a US$3.1 million interest payment on a US$80 million euro-convertible bond in February, and bondholders have rejected a settlement offer, opting to call a default.</p>
<p>&quot;Being the first default by a Thai company on an international security, it will be monitored very carefully, and it certainly doesn't do any good for sentiment,&quot; said one banker based in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Thailand's Alphatec Electronics Plc eurobond-holders are to meet in Zurich in early August after Alphatec failed to meet a July 7 payment deadline.</p>
<p>The Alphatec bondholders exercised a put option on US$43.68 million of the firm's total US$45 million euroconvertible.</p>
<p>The decision by Bankers Trust, the bond's trustee, means Alphatec does not have to make a payment until bondholders have met and decided what to do.</p>
<p>Bankers said the market was eager to see a satisfactory agreement between a defaulter and bondholders.</p>
<p>&quot;If it is a reasonable settlement, it may help them to regain investor confidence,&quot; a banker in Hong Kong said.</p>
<p>The Asian currency volatility is not deterring Hutchison Whampoa Ltd, which is launching a US$1 billion global bond which bankers said could be increased to US$2 billion.</p>
<p>They said Hutchison's A3/A-plus rating and high rate of return compared to similarly-rated corporates should guarantee an enthusiastic response from investors.</p>
<p>&quot;An A3/A-plus rated company paying 85 basis points to 90 basis points for a 10-year (over U.S. treasuries) is cheap,&quot; one banker close to the deal said.</p>
<p>He said the alternative was taking 70-75 basis points for a U.S. corporate with the same rating.</p>
<p>In other news, Hopewell Holdings Ltd declined to comment on reports it was seeking to raise U.S. dollars to help finance the Bangkok road/rail rapid transit system in Bangkok.</p>
<p>A Chinese commercial bank is seeking approval for a five year floating rate certificate of deposit (FRCD) or floating rate note (FRN) featuring puts and calls, bankers said.</p>
<p>They said Taiwan's Hua Nan Commercial Bank expected to award a mandate for its US$150 million FRN by the end of July.</p>
<p>Development Bank of the Philippines is talking to investors about a possible six year samurai issue, bankers said.</p>
<p>Sean Kennedy (852) 2843 6321</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
