<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75294" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Quake rocks central NZ but no damage.</title>
<headline>Quake rocks central NZ but no damage.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>An earthquake measuring 6.2 on the Richter scale was felt across wide areas of New Zealand's North and South Islands late on Wednesday but there were no reports of damage.</p>
<p>In the capital, Wellington, the quake shook windowpanes and rattled houses. It appeared to come in two waves, lasting up to a minute in total.</p>
<p>Seismologist Ken Gledhill of the Institute of Geological and Nuclear Sciences told Reuters it measured 6.2 on Richter and was centred about 40 km (25 miles) north of the North Island town of Wanganui.</p>
<p>Gledhill said the quake occurred at great depth -- about 250 km (155 miles) below the earth's surface -- and therefore would have caused little damage, although it was widely felt.</p>
<p>Radio New Zealand said it shook towns from Taranaki on the west coast of the North Island to Christchurch on the east coast of the South. While some people said they felt two distinct earthquakes, Gledhill said these were actually two waves of the same tremor.</p>
<p>New Zealand is part of a band of earthquake activity around the Pacific Rim and on average experiences one quake a year measuring higher than 6.0 on Richter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
