<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75299" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Lion Nathan confirms market share fall.</title>
<headline>Lion Nathan confirms market share fall.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lion Nathan Ltd chief executive Douglas Myers confirmed on Wednesday the brewer's market share had declined in its largest sphere, Australia.</p>
<p>Myers said market share had dropped to 42.0 percent from 43.1 percent in February, as reported in the Australian media. &quot;The figures are accurate,&quot; Myers said in an interview.</p>
<p>Myers said he still expected solid profits from Australia but not a lot of profit growth.</p>
<p>But he said the market, not market share, was more of a factor as Australia and New Zealand followed the worldwide trend of declining beer consumption.  </p>
<p>&quot;The dynamics of losing a point or a fraction of a point of market share, up or down...is relatively much less worrying to both brewers.&quot;</p>
<p>Lion competes against Fosters Brewing Group Ltd in Australia and DB Group Ltd in New Zealand.</p>
<p>Myers said changes in drinking patterns were behind its shift toward cost reduction and diversification into China.</p>
<p>Market share for Lion's Pepsi franchise in Australia was still low but improving.</p>
<p>&quot;Costs are down, market share is up, our actual trading performance has improved and I think we are feeling very much better about the future, but it is a very tough business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
