<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="752956" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FBI says Cunanan contacted associate after murder.</title>
<headline>FBI says Cunanan contacted associate after murder.</headline>
<byline>James Vicini</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Andrew Cunanan contacted an associate, right after fashion designer Gianni Versaci's murder, about getting false identification and a passport so he could flee the United States, a top FBI official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>FBI Deputy Director William Esposito also told a news conference the FBI had located in Las Vegas the owner of the Miami Beach houseboat where Cunanan, suspected of murdering Versace and four other men, killed himself.</p>
<p>Esposito said the German houseboat owner was being cooperative. &quot;He is probably being interviewed as we speak,&quot; the FBI official said, adding that he was unaware whether the owner and Cunanan had a prior relationship.</p>
<p>Asked whether Cunanan had AIDS or the virus that causes the disease, as has been widely speculated, Esposito said, &quot;We have no information on that. We have asked the medical examiner for blood and hair samples.&quot;</p>
<p>Esposito said Cunanan, from the south Florida area, telephoned the unidentified associate within 48 hours of Versace's murder July 15. He said they discussed individuals on the East Coast who might have a passport.</p>
<p>The FBI learned about the conversation when contacting Cunanan's associates to determine if he had been in touch and to warn them. When the associate was asked why he did not call the FBI with the information, &quot;he declined to comment,&quot; Esposito said.</p>
<p>The FBI official said the associate described Cunanan as &quot;agitated and nervous.&quot; Cunanan did not admit killing Versace during the call, Esposito said.</p>
<p>The FBI now will conduct a &quot;follow-up investigation&quot; to &quot;tie up a lot of loose ends,&quot; Esposito said. He said he would have preferred that Cunanan be captured alive so the suspected serial killer could &quot;tell us why he did the things he did.&quot;</p>
<p>In all, nearly 1,000 FBI agents nationwide took part in the search for Cunanan in what Esposito called a manhunt as intense as the one for the deadly serial bomber known as the Unabomber.</p>
<p>He said an FBI hotline received more than 1,000 calls, and that 500 of the tips had been followed up on. Esposito said all FBI offices had been ordered to follow up on any leads about Cunanan within an hour of getting the information.</p>
<p>But asked if the FBI during the manhunt had any idea of Cunanan's exact whereabouts, Esposito acknowledged, &quot;We had no clue at all as to where he was located.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
