<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="753054" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mallinckrodt says deal will hurt earnings, stock drops.</title>
<headline>Mallinckrodt says deal will hurt earnings, stock drops.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Medical products company Mallinckrodt Inc. said Thursday that its $1.9 billion purchase of Nellcor Puritan Bennett Inc., a maker of respiratory equipment, would hurt its earnings in the current fiscal year, and its stock fell.</p>
<p>The St. Louis-based maker of X-ray media and other products for hospitals said the deal announced late on Wednesday would dilute earnings by 15 percent in its fiscal year ended next June, excluding one-time charges.</p>
<p>Mallinckrodt stock lost $1.25 to $38.50 in consolidated trading at midday on the New York Stock Exchange. Nellcor Puritan stock soared $7.125 to $28.06 on Nasdaq. The cash offer is equal to $28.50 a share.</p>
<p>The deal would create one of the world's leading medical products suppliers and is the latest in the rapidly consolidating health care field. As hospitals have merged and become more involved in managed care, they have squeezed suppliers to lower costs.</p>
<p>Mallinckrodt said it expected one-time charges of between $325 million and $600 million from the deal in fiscal 1998 and $100 million in costs savings in its fiscal year ending in 1999, when the acquisition would start to boost earnings.</p>
<p>But investors focused on the short-term hit to Mallinckrodt's results and its increased debt load after the transaction. Mallinckrodt said it would use proceeds from asset sales over the past year and $1.2 billion in new borrowings to finance the acquisition.</p>
<p>Nellcor Puritan, based in Pleasanton, Calif., is one of the leading makers of products to monitor, diagnose and treat patients with respiratory conditions, including oxygen monitors, ventilators and anaesthetic gases.</p>
<p>Mallinckrodt also makes devices for diagnostic imaging and monitoring temperature, as well acetaminophen and narcotic painkillers.</p>
<p>Mallinckrodt Chief Executive Ray Holman said the acquisition would expand the merged company's role in medical and hospital supply, but that it was based on cost savings and not big sales growth.</p>
<p>The combined company will have sales of about $2.4 billion, Mallinckrodt said in announcing the deal Wednesday. The announcement came after the stock market had closed.</p>
<p>Holman, who made his remarks to Wall Street analysts Thursday, also said the companies do not expect any antitrust issues to block the transaction.</p>
<p>&quot;There is virtually no competition between the two companies,&quot; he said, adding that the product lines are complementary but do not overlap.</p>
<p>Mallinckrodt Chief Financial Officer Michael Rocca said the company expects charges of $325 million to $600 million in fiscal 1998 from the transaction. Excluding the charges, the deal is expected to dilute earnings by 15 percent in fiscal 1998 and boost earnings 10 percent to 15 percent in fiscal 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
