<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="753276" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Battle rages over U.S. Second World War monument.</title>
<headline>Battle rages over U.S. Second World War monument.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Wilson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fifty-two years after the end of the Second World War, official Washington on Thursday waged a battle of aesthetics and architecture over plans for a memorial in the heart of the U.S. capital.</p>
<p>At stake was the integrity of the National Mall, a 2-1/2 mile (four kilometre) long grassy corridor lined by formal rows of elm trees, flanked by civic buildings and housing the soaring 500-foot (152 metre) Washington Monument and the neoclassical Lincoln Memorial.</p>
<p>The protagonists faced off at a public hearing on a proposed monument to honour American service and sacrifice in the Second World War, the only conflict without a specific memorial among 11 already scattered about the Mall.</p>
<p>The prizewinning design by Austrian-born architect Friedrich St Florian -- planned for a 7.4 acre (three hectare) site at the east end of a reflecting pool in the centre of America's town green -- must be approved by a bevy of bureaucracy including the Commission of Fine Arts (CFA), the National Capital Planning Commission and the Interior Secretary.</p>
<p>The open-air plaza, combining gently sloping floral landscapes, waterfalls and two colonnades of 25 columns each 35 feet (10.5 metres) tall, won considerable praise from CFA members, veterans' groups and design professionals who contended it would not visually intrude on the Mall's symmetry or vistas.</p>
<p>&quot;The central location of this memorial affords it the preeminenmce it deserves,&quot; said CFA chairman J. Carter Brown. &quot;There is no reason why further consideration of other locations or designs should be undertaken.&quot;</p>
<p>But the senses of many have been offended by the proposed memorial. The New York Times in an editorial declared &quot;hallowed ground in jeopardy&quot; and pleaded &quot;keep the Mall as it is.&quot; Environmentalists called for a study of its impact on the surrounding landscape as well as traffic and visitor volume.</p>
<p>Sen. Bob Kerrey, who lost a leg during the Vietnam War and holds the nation's highest military award for valour, the Congressional Medal of Honour, led 18 of his colleagues in seeking a halt to the approval process.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision the commission must finally make, cannot and must not be based solely on emotion,&quot; the Nebraska Democrat told the hearing.</p>
<p>While neither he nor others disagreed that a monument to the Second World War was long overdue, Kerrey said the proposed structure  -- four times the size of the Lincoln Memorial -- would &quot;permamently and irrevocably&quot; change the nature of the Mall.</p>
<p>He noted its location was the site of many significant national gatherings including Dr Martin Luther King's &quot;I Have a Dream&quot; speech, and said the area provided uninterrupted, quiet space for visitors to reflect &quot;on the meaning of the ideas that underlie our nation's founding and survival.&quot;</p>
<p>But Ohio Democratic Representative Marcy Kaptur, who introduced legislation in Congress in 1987 to create the memorial, pointed out that in the past 200 years the Mall had served as a cow pasture, a slaughtering site, a civil war hospital, a railroad station and a trash-filled and stagnant canal.</p>
<p>&quot;Little did I know a decade ago how many hurdles lay in wait and that it would take us longer to build the memorial than fight the war,&quot; she told the hearing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
