<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="753325" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cooper says electrical products helped Q2.</title>
<headline>Cooper says electrical products helped Q2.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cooper Industries Inc said Thursday its second quarter earnings are the result of continued strong momentum in its electrical products business, and a rebound in the performance of its Tools &amp; Hardware segment.</p>
<p>The company also said its automotive products business is &quot;holding its own in a very difficult worldwide market.&quot;</p>
<p>The company said it made a decision during the second quarter to exit certain lower-margin product lines, which it said it expects will lead to significant margin improvement in its automotive products segment.</p>
<p>The company also said that in its electrical products segment, its power systems business will benefit from the recent acquisition of Kearney Co and the a major restructuring of distribution transformer manufacturing processes.</p>
<p>The company reported fully diluted earnings per share of $0.86 compared to $0.77 for the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>Revenues for the electrical products segment were up 8 percent during the quarter, and revenues for the automotive products segment were down 2 percent in the quarter.</p>
<p>The company said automotive products revenues reflected, among other things, generally weak demand for wiper and temperature control products.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32870">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
