<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="753396" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Witness accuses Democrats of searching for dirt.</title>
<headline>Witness accuses Democrats of searching for dirt.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Republican fundraiser testifying before the Senate committee investigating campaign finance scandals, accused Democrats Thursday of conducting an unwarranted search into his personal records.</p>
<p>Fred Volcansek raised a $2.1 million loan guarantee for a Republican think tank from a Hong Kong businessman in 1994. The money was transferred to the Republican Party just before the 1994 election.</p>
<p>In his opening statement to the Senate Governmental Affairs Committee, Volcansek said he recently became aware the Commerce Department had issued a worldwide bulletin requesting information about him from all places he visited as a department official from 1989 to 1992.</p>
<p>He said the request came from the committee's chief democratic counsel, Alan Baron.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly my service in the Department of Commerce had nothing to do with the 1996 election and I believe it is far outside this committee's mandate,&quot; Volcansek said.</p>
<p>His disclosure led to an angry exchange between committee chairman Fred Thompson of Tennessee and ranking Democrat John Glenn of Ohio.</p>
<p>Thompson said the committee had no business &quot;rummaging around prior activities&quot; and owed Volcansek an apology.</p>
<p>Glenn said the committee owed no apology and Baron was simply trying to gather relevant background information. He said Republicans were doing exactly the same to Democratic supporters.</p>
<p>The committee is investigating how foreign money flowed illegally to political parties in the 1996 campaign. At the centre of its probe is Asian-American John Huang, who worked in the Clinton administration at the Commerce Department and later solicited millions of dollars in illegal contributions from Asian business interests.</p>
<p>The committee was expected to hear testimony from former Republican Party chairman Haley Barbour later Thursday or Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
