<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="753304" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Harleysville reduces hurricane exposure.</title>
<headline>Harleysville reduces hurricane exposure.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Harleysville Group Inc said on Thursday it has taken steps to decrease its exposure to hurricanes, reducing the number of homeowners policies in coastal counties from Maine to Florida by 18 percent in the past 18 months.</p>
<p>Harleysville said it also added windstorm deductibles or exclusions to 34 percent of the remaining policies.</p>
<p>Harleysville reported second quarter operating earnings of $0.90 a share, in line with analysts' expectations.  </p>
<p>The statutory combined ratio, a key measure of underwriting profitability, was 102.6 percent in the second quarter compared with 102.3 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>For the six months, the statutory combined ratio was 104.5 percent compared with 108.1 percent in 1996. An underwriting profit occurs when the combined ratio falls below 100 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The improvement was due partially to this year's more normal winter weather, but, additionally, to an aggressive property reunderwriting and repricing program,&quot; Harleysville chief executive Walter Bateman said.  </p>
<p>However, he said, net written premium growth has been flat so far this year.</p>
<p>&quot;While we are encouraged by strong growth in certain territories -- particularly the Midwest -- the continuing soft market in commercial lines, mandated rate reductions for workers compensation insurance in some of our larger states, and our own ongoing efforts to reduce total property exposure along the Atlantic Coast have contributed to flat net written premium growth so far this year,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In light of the soft commercial lines marketplace, we will continue to emphasize responsible risk-based pricing and disciplined selection standards, favoring profitability over growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Bateman said the company expects to supplement its growth in the Midwest by seeking additional expansion opportunities there.</p>
<p>&quot;In the longer term, we expect our two new affiliates -- Insurance Management Resources L.P. and Harleysville Asset Management L.P. -- will generate more fee-based, non-underwriting income by offering insurance-related products and services to other companies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Harleysville Group Inc, based in Harleysville, Pa., is a regional holding company for eight property and casualty insurance companies whose marketing territory encompasses 24 states in the eastern half of the United States.</p>
<p>((Patricia Vowinkel 212-859-1716))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
