<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="753481" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Former Franco aide has dormant Swiss bank account.</title>
<headline>Former Franco aide has dormant Swiss bank account.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former foreign minister Ramon Serrano Suner, brother-in-law of the late Spanish dictator Francisco Franco, has appeared on a list of holders of dormant Holocaust-era Swiss bank accounts published this week.</p>
<p>Serrano, 96, was listed among the 1,840 dormant accounts cited by Swiss banks when they broke their strict code of secrecy in an effort to find the heirs of Holocaust victims and other owners of secret accounts.</p>
<p>Jewish groups have said Nazis and profiteers who looted victims' assets may also have sought to take advantage of Swiss banking secrecy laws and could appear on the list.</p>
<p>Serrano and his six children are listed among those who hold proxy powers over dormant accounts.</p>
<p>In an interview with Spanish newspapers published on Thursday, Serrano denied he had any dealings in money or property confiscated from Jews by Nazis during World War Two.</p>
<p>&quot;I never had anything to do with the matter of the Jews, I never received anything from them, nor did I give them anything,&quot; Serrano told the daily El Pais.</p>
<p>Asked about his appearance on the list of dormant Swiss accounts, Serrano denied he was a proxy for any person or institution. He said he maintained the accounts to pay educational and incidental expenses for his children and to deposit income from business dealings he had in Switzerland.</p>
<p>&quot;The explanation is quite clear. Those are accounts that I opened in Switzerland before the war in my name and the name of my six children. Then I didn't cancel them,&quot; he said. &quot;I never imagined that they would be made public some day.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the sums in his Swiss accounts were modest.</p>
<p>El Pais reported last February that it had discovered documents in the Spanish Foreign Ministry which show Serrano coordinated with France, Italy and Germany the transfer to Spain of three shipments of gold bought by Franco's government from the Swiss National Bank.</p>
<p>Serrano had denied the allegations.</p>
<p>Jewish organisations and a Spanish parliamentary commission are investigating shipments of looted Nazi gold to Spain during the war. Jewish groups have also said Spain was a conduit through which looted assets and escaping Nazis passed on the way to Latin America.</p>
<p>Serrano was a general of the Falangist faction which supported Franco during the Spanish Civil War from 1936-1939. After Franco's victory, he was appointed foreign minister, a post he held until 1942. He was considered an architect of the fascist regime.</p>
<p>Serrano, who was married to Franco's sister, was believed to have been influential in persuading Franco to remain neutral during the war instead of allying Spain with Nazi Germany.</p>
<p>At least 77 Spaniards appeared on the dormant list -- 55 as account holders and 22 as proxies, newspaper reports said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
