<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75365" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam rice market firm on strong export demand.</title>
<headline>Vietnam rice market firm on strong export demand.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong demand from abroad continued to underpin Vietnam's rice market this week, with a flurry of shipments heading for Africa, Latin America and the Middle East, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices for all grades are starting to firm up,&quot; said one trader. &quot;Sales have really been pretty strong this month.&quot;</p>
<p>Five-percent broken grade was quoted at $280-$283 a tonne and 10-percent at $265-$270, both little changed from last week.</p>
<p>Traders said Vietnamese exporters were benefiting from the fact that the Indian crop had not yet come into the market and from relatively low prices.  </p>
<p>Official media reports said this week that Vietnam's rice exports in the first nine months of this year were estimated at 2.15 million tonnes. For the whole of 1995, the country's exports came to 2.025 million tonnes.</p>
<p>They said that since the start of September, the Philippines, Sri Lanka and Senegal had between them ordered more than 50,000 tonnes of low quality rice from Vietnam.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected shipments to total around 300,000 tonnes this month.  </p>
<p>The Ministry of Agriculture has asked for the export quota this year to be increased to 2.3-2.5 million tonnes from two million in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not really a big problem,&quot; said one trader. &quot;If exporters want to sell more they'll get the quota.&quot;</p>
<p>Recent flooding in northern and central Vietnam submerged hundreds of thousands of paddy fields, but damage to crops was light because harvesting was almost over when the flooding hit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
