<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75363" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore oil products see firmer gas oil on IPE.</title>
<headline>Singapore oil products see firmer gas oil on IPE.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore oil products were mixed on Wednesday with gas oil riding on London IPE's gas oil rally, while jet fuel was under pressure amid plentiful supplies, traders said.</p>
<p>They said there was limited gas oil in Asia and prices here lagged way behind Europe. IPE gas oil hit a five-year of $228 a tonne in early trading before easing to $226. October gas oil swaps traded as high as $28.25 on the rally, 50 cents over Tuesday's deals. October traded lower late in the day at $27.93. Traders said regional demand focused on Indonesia and China's barge market. But China's demand was curbed by high prices.  </p>
<p>Physical gas oil was offered by a major at $28.00 for October 16-20 lifting fob, 15 cents over Tuesday's offer. Another offer for mid-October was seen at $28.10 but lowered to $27.90. India issued an import tender for 90,000 tonnes of 0.25 percent sulphur diesel for November delivery which closes Oct 4. Nepal also plans to issue a tender next week to buy a cargo each of gas oil and kerosene for November arrival.</p>
<p>A trader has jet fuel to offer to S. Korea and is seeking a $1.60-premium to Singapore quotes for mid-October lifting c+f. An offer of jet fuel at $29.70 for Oct 20-24 attracted two bids, traders said. An early October offer was made Tuesday at $29.80.  </p>
<p>Taiwan's CPC bought one unleaded cargo of 95-octane gasoline at around $23.80 per barrel for November 1-20 delivery, c+f. But traders said the awarded level was $23.96, which was close to the awarded level for 500,000 tonnes of unleaded gasoline for October delivery. Fuel oil was steady amid more MidEast supplies seen arriving in Asia and increased Chinese demand, traders said. At least four Kuwaiti cargoes are due to arrive in the next two weeks, on top of the usual Iranian cargoes, a trader said. Some traders said Chinese demand will not be strong enough to absorb the surplus as part of the demand has been met by S.Korean supplies. --Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
