<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75371" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan ministry reform plan seen as election ploy.</title>
<headline>Japan ministry reform plan seen as election ploy.</headline>
<byline>Yoko Kobayashi</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The parties of Japan's ruling coalition on Wednesday stitched together a plan to reform the powerful Ministry of Finance, but analysts called it a ploy to win votes in general elections expected next month.</p>
<p>The ministry, which is viewed as the pinnacle of Japan's elite bureaucracy, has come under fire for its handling of problems in the banking industry and its practice of trying to deal with banking crises internally.</p>
<p>The coalition plan calls for the establishment of an independent body to take over the exclusive supervisory and regulatory role through which the ministry has long exercised control over the financial industry.</p>
<p>But analysts said the plan failed to specify steps to implement the reforms under a new government after the elections, which are widely expected to be held on October 20.</p>
<p>&quot;The reforms were hammered out in haste to make it in time for the general elections. Although the three ruling coalition parties agreed on the plan, it may all change depending on the result of the elections,&quot; said Masaru Takagi, chief economist at Fuji Research Institute Corp.</p>
<p>Even if Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto, who is the leader of the dominant Liberal Democratic Party (LDP), retains his job after the elections, the reform plan could be derailed by strong opposition from Finance Ministry officials.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still up in the air whether the reforms can be carried out as planned,&quot; Takagi said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the coalition was unlikely to adopt its plan as a government plan ahead of the election -- which would be a way to guarantee its implemention under any government.</p>
<p>&quot;Most probably the Liberal Democrats want to make the new body a voter-attractive portion of their plan for administrative reform, one of the biggest issues in the upcoming election campaign,&quot; the Asahi Shimbun newspaper said in an editorial.</p>
<p>The coalition's reform plan calls for streamlining of the ministry's functions by merging its banking and securities bureaux into one. The international finance bureau would remain as it stands now, but the coalition suggested a part of its function should be shifted to the merged bureau.</p>
<p>The plan left the major issue of removing the ministry's budget-forming function for the next ruling party or parties to decide after the elections.</p>
<p>In an apparent protest at the coalition's move to set up the new independent body, Vice Finance Minister Tadashi Ogawa said the decision-making process might be slowed down if it involved large numbers of people.</p>
<p>Analysts said the coalition's proposals to beef up the independence of the Bank of Japan, now being debated by a study group to the prime minister, could suffer the same fate as those for the Finance Ministry.</p>
<p>The parties have suggested curbing the finance minister's power to fire senior central bank executives and to supervise the central bank's business by revising a 54-year-old law which maps out the status of the Bank of Japan.</p>
<p>The study group is due to come up with reform proposals covering the central bank in October, when the election campaign is expected to be at its height.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
