<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="753706" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France wants Aerospatiale in public sector - paper.</title>
<headline>France wants Aerospatiale in public sector - paper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>France wants to keep state-owned plane maker Aerospatiale in the public sector after linking it with warplane manufacturer Dassault Aviation, said Defence Minister Alain Richard on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The government hopes to convince Dassault Aviation that this linking of forces can take place while keeping Aerospatiale in the public sector,&quot; afternoon daily Le Monde quoted Richard as saying in an interview.  </p>
<p>The previous conservative government had planned to merge Aerospatiale and Dassault Aviation and privatise the new company.</p>
<p>Dassault Chairman Serge Dassault has said he would only agree to the merger if the resulting firm were privatised.</p>
<p>Richard said in the interview that France's overall strategy centred on a deeper European alliance in the civil aviation sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Our European partners have already realised synergies between their civil and military aeronautic sectors and that is a target for France as well, but without losing sight of the final result, which is European,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He repeated the government's position that they would not completely sell off defence electronics firm Thomson-CSF and said the company would have no problem finding European partners despite speculation that private companies would be reluctant to link up with a company heavily influenced by the state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
