<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="753876" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee called to open 3.00 to 4.00 lower.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee called to open 3.00 to 4.00 lower.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures were called to open 3.00 to 4.00 cents lower Thursday in a technical correction to their two-day rally, traders said.</p>
<p>In the past two consecutive sessions, September jumped 22.80 cents -- or more than 14 percent. While some traders said the run-up was a bit overdone, they noted sentiment had turned cautiously bullish.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market will dip this morning,&quot; said one trader. &quot;But I would not be surprised to see it go higher later on. People like it.&quot;</p>
<p>Wednesday, New York arabica futures soared to three-week highs, as speculators continued to buy heavily amid renewed near-term supply concerns. Spot September settled up 12.55 cents at 181.65 cents a lb after ranging from 184.50 to 167.50. December rose 6.40 cents to 158.15 cents, while the back months closed 1.75 to 4.25 higher.</p>
<p>The September/December switch, a barometer of nearby availability, ballooned to 23.50 cents compared with 17.35 cents at the close on Monday.</p>
<p>Technically, traders pegged September support at 176.00 cents. They said September would face some resistance at Wednesday's high of 184.50 cents, followed by 190.70 cents.</p>
<p>CSCE reported after Wednesday's close that certified coffee inventories rose by 3,666 60-kg bags as of July 22, to 90,897 bags. An additional 5,609 bags were pending grading, the exchange said.</p>
<p>On the weather front, Weather Services Corp said on Thursday that there is no damaging cold weather expected during the next seven days in Brazil's coffee belt, with low temperatures forecast mostly in the 50s (low to middle teens C).</p>
<p>London coffee futures were broadly higher early Thursday, but well below pre-opening expectation of up $130. At the midday break, September was $55 higher, at $1,615, after ranging from $1,617 to $1,590. November rose $57, to $1,608.</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
