<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75397" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai PM keeps nation guessing on replacement.</title>
<headline>Thai PM keeps nation guessing on replacement.</headline>
<byline>Rajan Moses</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The race to find a new prime minister for Thailand intensified on Thursday, with a senior aide saying Defence Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh was a front-runner.</p>
<p>Dej Bunlong, secretary-general to incumbent Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa, told reporters he expected Chavalit, who leads the New Aspiration Party (NAP), the second largest in the ruling coalition, to get the job.</p>
<p>&quot;I asked him (Banharn) this morning who is going to replace you and he said it was up to the six-party coalition to decide,&quot; Dej said. &quot;But the trend is towards Chavalit and most likely it will be Chavalit.&quot;</p>
<p>Banharn himself was tight-lipped about whether he would dissolve parliament and call snap elections as the tussle continued over the choice of his successor.</p>
<p>Banharn was forced by key partners in his six-party coalition to declare last Saturday that he would resign in seven days.</p>
<p>Politicians and analysts said the fact that coalition leaders had been arguing for five days over the succession and Banharn's silence indicated a hard bargain was being struck.</p>
<p>The coalition planned to meet later on Wednesday to discuss the issue, party sources said.</p>
<p>Elder statesman and former premier Prem Tinsulanonda and a top army officer separately urged the coalition to settle personal differences quickly in the national interest.</p>
<p>Besides Chavalit, other names being mentioned included a party elder in Banharn's core Chart Thai party, Pramarn Adireksarn, a rank outsider and former premier Chatichai Choonhavan, who leads the opposition Chart Pattana party, and possible compromise candidate Foreign Minister Amnuay Viravan, leader of junior coalition partner the Nam Thai party.</p>
<p>Chatichai could become premier by making his party a new member of the coalition, political sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is very confusing. It is full of rumours and no one can tell whether Chavalit, Pramarn or Chatichai or somebody else will be the next premier,&quot; said NAP spokesman Suraporn Danaitangtrakul.</p>
<p>The Bangkok Post newspaper, quoting unidentified sources, said on Wednesday that Chavalit, who engineered Banharn's downfall, would be named prime minister on Friday. It reported that Banharn had yielded to pressure from his own party to hand over the post to Chavalit.</p>
<p>However, the Nation newspaper said the opposite. It reported that Banharn's party had refused to endorse a plan by coalition partners to nominate Chavalit for the top post.</p>
<p>It quoted NAP sources as saying there was a strong possibility the party would be forced into opposition because Chavalit looked like he was not going to get the premiership.</p>
<p>&quot;Take your pick on rumours... every paper has a different story. There may be disinformation being put out as well,&quot; said Graham Catterwell, head of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>The Thai stock market slipped as it waited for a resolution of the protracted leadership crisis, brokers said. The index was down 10.71 points at 1031.50 at 0925 GMT.</p>
<p>Analysts said the chances of Banharn and his coalition coming back to power if a snap poll was held looked slim because his administration was being blamed by many for a current economic slowdown and other related problems.</p>
<p>Army commander General Pramon Phalasin urged restraint among politicians but said the military, which has staged 17 coups or coup attempts since 1932 when Thailand adopted parliamentary democracy, would not get involved in politics.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
