<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754058" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Delta Air names acting CEO, chairman.</title>
<headline>Delta Air names acting CEO, chairman.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Delta Air Lines Inc. said Thursday it named two acting officers to head the nation's third-largest carrier after the July 31 retirement of current Chairman Ronald Allen.</p>
<p>Delta said Mary Johnston Evans, a member of Delta's board since 1983, will serve as acting non-executive chairman. Maurice Worth has been named acting chief executive officer. Worth is currently the airline's executive vice president of customer service and acting chief operating officer.</p>
<p>Worth was named acting COO in May when Allen announced his retirement.</p>
<p>Allen's departure after 34 years with Delta surprised industry experts, who suggested at the time that his resignation followed a rift with the board about the company's strategic focus.</p>
<p>Delta said Worth will oversee the airline's daily worldwide operations, while Evans will handle board issues until a permanent chairman is named.</p>
<p>&quot;The entire board of directors feels a real sense of urgency about finding a new leader for Delta, but we don't feel rushed. We intend to find the very best person to lead Delta Air Lines. There is no self-imposed deadline,&quot; Evans said.</p>
<p>Worth has been with Delta for 36 years in operations, station management, personnel and executive management, the airline said.</p>
<p>Evans has served on a number of corporate boards, including Baxter International Inc., Dun &amp; Bradstreet Corp. and Household International Inc.</p>
<p>Evans also served as vice chairman of Amtrak from 1974 to 1979 and worked with the Citizens Advisory Committee on Transportation Quality and the Urban Transportation Advisory Council to the Secretary of Transportation.</p>
<p>Delta's stock was down 6 cents at $88.125 in consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
