<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754286" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Avon says profits up 11 percent.</title>
<headline>Avon says profits up 11 percent.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Avon Products Inc. said Thursday its earnings rose 11 percent in the second quarter, boosted by solid worldwide sales gains of beauty products.</p>
<p>It posted earnings of $95.2 million, equal to 72 cents a share, vs. year-earlier profits of $85.7 million, or 64 cents a share</p>
<p>Sales jumped to $1.23 billion from $1.13 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;We are well on our way to another year of solid profitable growth,&quot; said James E. Preston, chief executive officer.</p>
<p>&quot;Most international operations are performing strongly, with outstanding growth continuing in Mexico, the Philippines and the U.K., as well as in Russia and other developing markets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the United States, Avon's largest market, sales rose 5 percent from a year earlier, led by good gains in cosmetics, fragrance and toiletries sales, especially skin care and colour cosmetics. Jewelry and accessories reversed declining sales trends and delivered a solid increase, Avon said.</p>
<p>Total sales in the Americas rose 10 percent, and pretax profits were up 11 percent.</p>
<p>Mexico had strong sales, thanks to its continued recovery from the country's 1995 economic crisis, Avon said, but the gain was partially offset by Brazil, where sales and pretax profits fell due to softness in consumer spending.</p>
<p>In Europe, sales rose 8 percent, buoyed by upbeat results in Britain, Russia and Poland, with pretax profits up 18 percent.</p>
<p>Avon's stock was off 19 cents at $75.875 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
