<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754240" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Supersol faces slower Israeli economy.</title>
<headline>Supersol faces slower Israeli economy.</headline>
<byline>David Rosenberg</byline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Supersol Ltd, Israel's biggest food retailer, is bailing out of the loss-making office supply sector, but it remains committed to boosting its non-food sales to sustain growth.</p>
<p>President David Alphandary said Supersol will be opening its European-style hypermarket in Haifa at the end of the year -- a 7,200 sq metre (80,000 sq foot) monster store, with around half the floor space devoted to non-food items.</p>
<p>A second store, slated for Tel Aviv's northern suburbs, will open next year.</p>
<p>&quot;When we're talking about non-food...the object is to improve our mix and share of products within our large stores,&quot; Alphandary told Reuters.</p>
<p>Building up its non-food business is part of Supersol's strategy to increase sales and margins at a time when the rapid growth the Israeli economy experienced in the first half of the 1990s has cooled.</p>
<p>Immigrants from Russia streamed into the country, the economy grew at six to seven percent a year and Israelis switched to pricier prepared foods from basics. Israeli food retailers like Supersol had enjoyed growth of seven to eight percent annually in food spending in the first half the 1990s.</p>
<p>But immigration has slowed and Israel's output is forecast to grow just 2.5 percent this year, so that food spending growth is likely to slow to about four percent annually in coming years, estimated Supersol chief economist Hanna Guterman.</p>
<p>Alphandary aims to build on the slimmer growth by scratching out market share from the other chains as the industry undergoes a consolidation. In February it acquired 25 stores from Shekem and Alphandary is eyeing smaller chains.</p>
<p>Supersol is aggressively developing new outlets at a rate of six to eight annually, while expanding floor space.</p>
<p>More important, it is winning market share from corner groceries, open-air markets and other non-chain competition. Supersol and the other chains are gaining ground, but have a long away to go.</p>
<p>Stephen Levey, an analyst at Carnegie Emerging Markets in London, estimated only about 36 percent of Israeli food spending is done at chains, versus 70 percent in the United States.</p>
<p>Supersol is tapping into the ultra-orthodox population by buying and expanding the Birkat Rachel chain catering to their needs.</p>
<p>To capture some of the business of the kibbutzim, Alphandary said Supersol has begun to distribute food to and advise the collective farms' food distribution outlets. Supersol is even providing distribution services to small groceries.</p>
<p>This will be made easier by the company's new $50 million logistics centre in a Tel Aviv suburb. Its 25,000 sq metres (2,250 sq feet) of floor space will fully open by year end.</p>
<p>The new centre will act as a central drop-off point for suppliers, Alphandary said. From there the centre will provide Supersol's 120 outlets with just-in-time delivery of products for the shelves.</p>
<p>Stores will have fewer out-of-stock items, while inventory and delivery costs will fall, Alphandary said, adding the centre should enable him to win better terms from his suppliers. All that should help boost Supersol's tightening margins.</p>
<p>Levey sees Supersol boosting earnings per share (EPS) at least 10 percent this year and 22 percent in 1998, thanks to higher turnover. Shekem will help boost sales 27.5 percent this year, but same-store sales -- a better measure of growth -- should show surprisingly strong growth of five percent this year and next.</p>
<p>Lehman Brothers' analyst Elise Horowitz, whose EPS projections are more conservative, said Supersol's Tel Aviv-traded shares are a little expensive at about 19 times her 1997 estimated earnings, but justly so.</p>
<p>&quot;It is already trading at a premium to the stock market because it pays a good dividend and because of its strong growth record,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Supersol is planning to issue American depositary receipts (ADRs). &quot;We believe that if nothing changes in Israel or the U.S. market by the end of the year, we will accomplish the offering,&quot; says Alphandary.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.52 shekels)</p>
<p>-Jerusalem newsroom, 972-3-537-0502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
