<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754377" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton to name Berman to lead fast-track effort.</title>
<headline>Clinton to name Berman to lead fast-track effort.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Thursday will name Jay Berman, head of the Recording Industry Association of America, to lead the White House effort to win fast-track trade authority from Congress, the White House said.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry told reporters Clinton would make the announcement during a meeting Thursday morning with some two dozen Democratic congressman to discuss strategy for winning the authority.  </p>
<p>McCurry said Clinton would make the argument why he, like all recent presidents, should receive congressional authority to negotiate trade agreements with other countries without fear that they will be changed by Congress.</p>
<p>When Congress gives fast-track authority to a president it gives up the right to amend the resulting agreements and can only vote for or against them.</p>
<p>McCurry said the Clinton administration was optimistic about the chances of winning the authority.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of concerns that we have to address but given the strength of the economy, and the role that free trade plays in the strength of the economy, we think that we can win the argument at the end of the day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((--Washington Newsroom 202 898-8300))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
