<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754324" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fountain Oil reaches Ukraine oil sales agreement.</title>
<headline>Fountain Oil reaches Ukraine oil sales agreement.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fountain Oil Inc said Thursday that one of its associate companies has reached a reached an oil sales agreement with the Ukrainian state oil company.</p>
<p>In a press release, Fountain also said that the company has been exempted from certain taxes on the oil sales.</p>
<p>Kashtan Petroleum Ltd, in which Fountain Oil owns a 40.5 percent interest, has signed an oil sales agreement with Neftekhimik, a Ukrainian state owned trading company, for the sales of oil and condensate initially produced from the Lelyaki field, the company said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Prices will be based on Ukrainian spot prices, but the agreement includes a minimum guaranteed price of US$131.18 per ton (US$16.7 per barrel), including valued added tax (VAT).</p>
<p>&quot;Through this agreement, Kashtan has secured the sale of all 1997 production from the Lelyaki field up to a maximum of 30,500 tons (240,000 barrels) of crude oil,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>Kashtan has been exempted from the payment of approximately 26 percent in miscellaneous royalties based on gross revenue and the government also exempted VAT of 20 percent, subject to Parliament approval, Fountain said.  </p>
<p>There are currently three wells at various stages of production/development in the field and Fountain plans a total of 12.</p>
<p>Fountain Oil's President and CEO Nils N. Trulsvik commented:  &quot;This is a pioneering project that has taken more time than anticipated.  In a country undergoing a profound transition, we consider it quite an achievement to have succeeded both in starting technical operations and in establishing a solid commercial and fiscal basis for the activity.  The sales agreement at international price levels confirms the commercial attractiveness of the Lelyaki project.&quot;</p>
<p>((--New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1620))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
