<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75448" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Moroccan bourse ends session nearly unchanged.</title>
<headline>Moroccan bourse ends session nearly unchanged.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca bourse closed on Wednesday nearly unchanged due to the stagnation of blue chip stocks except for privatisation bonds, stockbrokers said.</p>
<p>The bourse all-share index closed at 431.25 points, up 0.01 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the surge in the privatisation bonds, the stock market remained globally unchanged, similar to Tuesday trading session,&quot; a stockbroker at Upline Securities said.</p>
<p>Banque Commerciale du Maroc, the bourse's largest capitalisation, remained unchanged at 685 dirhams.</p>
<p>First tranche of privatisation bonds  BDP.CS, which were issued in January, traded at 1,124 dirhams, up 24 dirhams on the previous session. The second tranche, which were issued in May, rose six dirhams to close at 1,076 dirhams.</p>
<p>Both bonds are negotiable on the market or can be converted into equity in future privatisations.</p>
<p>Wafabank, one of the market blue chips, made no change and closed at 505 dirhams.</p>
<p>ONA Group, Morocco's largest private group and one of the main market capitalisation companies, was also unchanged at 450 dirhams.</p>
<p>The bourse volume was estimated at 29.6 million, from an estimated 43.7 million dirhams on Tuesday.</p>
<p>($1= 8.7 dirhams)</p>
<p>Rabat newsroom (212-7) 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
