<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754447" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sharp drop in U.S. claims sign of tight labor mart.</title>
<headline>Sharp drop in U.S. claims sign of tight labor mart.</headline>
<byline>Jeff Coelho</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A drop in jobless claims data this week had been expected by many Wall Street analysts, but the sharpness of the decline shows that the U.S. labor market remains very tight, experts said.</p>
<p>The Labor Department reported new claims for state unemployment insurance dropped to 299,000 in the week ended July 19 against a revised 341,000 in the previous week. The level was the lowest since the week of July 27, 1996, when claims hit 297,000.  </p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters had called for a decline to 333,000 claims versus the original reading of 349,000 in the prior week.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that (claims) is under 300,000 underscores the point that we've got a nice healthy manufacturing sector with low unemployment,&quot; said Richard Berner, chief economist at Mellon Bank in Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>Many experts said the lofty levels in claims in past weeks were skewed due to temporary auto plant re-toolings.</p>
<p>&quot;We knew it was going to come down as soon as Detroit got back in business, so I think this signals that,&quot; Berner added.  </p>
<p>Some analysts said the numbers were not likely to change the market's sentiment about the overall economy, which many experts expect to continue to grow at a moderate pace.</p>
<p>A few experts said the modest increase in continued claims from the surveyed week last month -- 2.30 million from 2.26 million -- point to a strong labor market, but not as robust as in the previous quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;It's indicative of a labor market that is strong, but a little bit less hot than early in the second quarter,&quot; said Peter Kretzmer, senior economist at Nationsbanc Capital Markets Inc.</p>
<p>Kretzmer said he will likely call for a steady unemployment rate of 5.0 percent in July.</p>
<p>The U.S. Treasury market reacted swiftly to the report, as the long end fell a few ticks after the annoucement. But after traders had digested the numbers, T-bond prices rebounded as market players began buying on dips.</p>
<p>At 0940 EDT/1340 GMT, the benchmark 30-year Treasury bond was up 13/32 at 102-29/32 bid, yielding 6.40 percent.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
