<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754466" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Xerox Q2 revs up 3 pct after currency hit.</title>
<headline>Xerox Q2 revs up 3 pct after currency hit.</headline>
<dateline>STAMFORD, Conn. 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Xerox Corp said it second quarter revenues were up three percent to $4.4 billion, after the negative impact from currency due to the stronger dollar, which continues to adversely affect its results.</p>
<p>On a pre-currency basis, Xerox's revenues were up six percent. A year ago, Xerox reported $4.2 billion in revenues.</p>
<p>Xerox said that its revenue growth, before currency, was driven by strong growth in equipment sales and continued excellent growth in document outsourcing.</p>
<p>It reported second quarter fully diluted earnings of $0.94 a share. According to First Call, consensus was $0.89 a share.  </p>
<p>Xerox's second quarter results include $0.04 a share gain as a result of its acquisition last month of the Rank Group's remaining interest in Rank Xerox.</p>
<p>Xerox said that sales of its digital products grew 24 percent in the quarter, driven by excellent growth in color copiers and printers and strong growth in high-speed laser printers. The DocuColor 40, its 40-page-per-minute color document processing system, continued to contribute significantly to revenue growth.</p>
<p>Xerox said production publishing revenues showed good growth, despite some slowdown due to new product anticipation.  </p>
<p>Customers were anticipating the new 180-page-per minute DocuTech Production Publisher, which is now widely available.</p>
<p>Digital product revenues represented 34 percent of total second quarter revenues.</p>
<p>&quot;Customer acceptance of the digital black-and-white copiers we introduced in April has been excellent,&quot; said Paul Allaire, chairman and chief executive. &quot;Orders for these products have been more than double our expectations.&quot;</p>
<p>Allaire also said that the new digital production publishing and printing products that Xerox introduced in May have received excellent customer acceptance.  </p>
<p>Black-and-white light lens copier revenues, now 52 percent of total revenues, declined three percent in the quarter, reflecting pricing pressures and the impact of customers transitioning to Xerox digital technology.</p>
<p>As a result of the company's ongoing focus on productivity and expense controls, the ratio of selling, administrative and general expenses to revenues was 29.6 percent, an improvement of 0.5 percent points from second quarter 1996.</p>
<p>Xerox also said that prospective buyers continue to show interest in the three remaining insurance units of Talegen Holdings Inc.  </p>
<p>The previously announced sale of the industrial indemnity unit is expected to close this quarter.</p>
<p>Disposition of the remaining units should be substantially completed by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Even though the strengthening dollar continues to adversely impact Xerox's results, Allaire said that Xerox is maintaining its focus on profitable revenue growth and improved productivity to deliver double-digit earnings growth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STAMFORD, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
