<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754593" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Merger mania outshines glowing German bank profits.</title>
<headline>Merger mania outshines glowing German bank profits.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT, Germany 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rallying stock markets pumped profits into Germany's top banks in the first six months but investors are paying far more attention to the prospect of further mega-mergers.</p>
<p>This week's earnings releases by Deutsche Bank AG, Commerzbank AG and Bayerische Vereinsbank AG have been overshadowed by Monday's news of a Bavarian merger that will transform Germany's bank landscape.</p>
<p>Analysts say bank stock prices are being driven not by fundamentals, but by wild speculation about who will team up with whom in response to Vereinsbank's fusion with Bayerische Hypotheken- und Wechsel-Bank AG (Hypo-Bank).</p>
<p>&quot;Most people have stopped looking at earnings numbers,&quot; said Mark Hoge, an analyst at Credit Suisse First Boston.</p>
<p>Rolf Breuer, Deutsche's chief executive, acknowledged on Wednesday that his bank's shares rose more than 10 percent on that day not because of its good first-half earnings, but because of merger speculation, which he called overdone.</p>
<p>The lack of correlation between earnings and share prices was particular evident with Commerzbank, Germany's third-largest bank, on Thursday.</p>
<p>Its stock price had leaped 20 percent since last Friday on speculation that it faces a takeover or merger following the emergence of the Bavarian banking giant as the sector's new No. 2.</p>
<p>But the shares fell 4.6 percent on Thursday despite news that Commerzbank's pre-tax profit rose 24.7 percent to 1.65 billion marks ($905 million), well above expectations.</p>
<p>Deutsche also beat market forecasts, reporting on Wednesday a 27.5 percent jump in net income to 1.5 billion marks ($822 million), driven by strong growth in trading and commission income.</p>
<p>Vereinsbank's results slightly disappointed markets, raising its operating profit after risk provisions by a slightly lower-than-expected 15.2 percent to 765.7 million marks ($420 million).</p>
<p>Dresdner Bank AG and Hypo-Bank publish their results next Tuesday, July 29.</p>
<p>Analysts expect earnings growth at the banks to slow down during the second half, but said banks were still on course to post record profits this year.</p>
<p>Markets are unlikely to keep up the breakneck pace of the first six months, August is usually a quiet month due to summer holidays and the fourth quarter often sees banks raise their risk provisions ahead of the end-year accounts, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was only to be expected that with this kind of boom in the markets, the banks would do well,&quot; said Christine Winkler, an analyst at Hypo-Bank in Munich. &quot;Everyone has priced in a weakening on the financial markets in the second half. As long as there is not a total collapse, we should be looking for record results.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts now see investors focusing more heavily on the banks' ability to get their costs under control, particularly at Deutsche, whose administrative costs rose 26.7 percent in the first half, boosted by the weak mark.</p>
<p>But merger fever should remain on the boil as investors brace for a inevitable chain reaction to the Bavarian move.</p>
<p>Bankers have predicted change in the overbanked sector will come quickly once the first player makes a move, but there is no clear consensus on what the next step is likely to be and how soon it will come.</p>
<p>Analysts speculate that Deutsche, Dresdner or a foreign bank may merge with or buy Commerzbank, or that Dresdner may team up with the Bavarian group or with insurer Allianz AG .</p>
<p>Deutsche said Wednesday it saw no need to take any action in response to the merger and Commerzbank reiterated Thursday that it expected to remain independent.</p>
<p>Analysts are not so sure. The country's top bankers spent most of the last 12 months playing down the prospect of major merger activity in the private sector, but it happened.</p>
<p>The Munich merger shows German bankers are ready to make bold moves to stay competitive and cut costs, and analysts are convinced the top banks are dusting off their contingency plans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
