<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754585" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU says Boeing row strengthens case for WTO role.</title>
<headline>EU says Boeing row strengthens case for WTO role.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan said on Thursday that the row over the Boeing -McDonnell Douglas merger strengthened the case for the World Trade Organisation to be involved in anti-trust cases.</p>
<p>&quot;I have long believed that we need an international agreement on competition rules and smoother cooperation between national competition jurisdictions,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;There are bound to be more and more clashes when powerful competition authorities seek to deal with the same case, applying different rules.&quot;</p>
<p>The European Commission on Wednesday approved in principle a merger between the two U.S. aircraft manufacturers after Boeing agreed to last-minute concessions aimed at ensuring the company would not abuse its strong market position and would leave airlines the choice of buying rival planes.</p>
<p>The proposed merger sparked a furious transatlantic trade row with U.S. politicians saying the Commission had no right to block what was effectively an American affair.</p>
<p>The Commission argued that because the merger would leave the new company with a dominant market share in Europe, it had to intervene.</p>
<p>&quot;We have avoided a crisis this time but this is a problem that will not go away until there is an effective international agreement on the application of competition rules,&quot; said Brittan.</p>
<p>A ministerial meeting of the WTO in Singapore in December established a working group to look at trade and competition policy, but the committee has met only once since then.</p>
<p>&quot;Major mergers such as the Boeing-Mcdonnell Douglas ... inevitably arouse concern in several countries around the world.,&quot; Brittan said. &quot;Once again we have reached an amicable conclusion, but it is never easy. We need better safeguards against unnecessary conflict of interest. -- David Fox, Brussels Newsroom ++32 2 287 6832</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
