<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75466" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SEC sends Wells notices to two Merrill executives.</title>
<headline>SEC sends Wells notices to two Merrill executives.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Commission's staff has sent notices to two senior Merrill Lynch &amp; Co. executives, informing them that they may be charged in connection with the Orange County, Calif., bankruptcy, sources familiar with the probe said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The executives who received the so-called Wells notices were Richard Fuscone, a managing director who heads the firm's global debt markets and derivatives unit, and Robert Simonson, a managing director and the former top money-markets trader.</p>
<p>As reported last week, the brokerage firm itself has also received a Wells notice. A Wells notice informs its recipient that SEC staff intends to recommend enforcement action to commissioners.</p>
<p>The sources said the Wells notices take issue with the adequacy of the disclosures in official statements for several Orange County note offerings underwritten by Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>The SEC's office in Los Angeles declined to comment.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch spokesman Timothy Gilles also declined to comment on whether Wells notices were received.</p>
<p>In a statement issued late on Wednesday, Merrill Lynch said, &quot;As we have stated, we are very confident that our work on the Orange County note offerings was done professionally and properly and we have total confidence in the conduct of the employees involved in those offerings.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is important to understand that Merrill Lynch was one of several firms that underwrote Orange County offerings that are now under SEC review,&quot; Merrill Lynch said. &quot;In our opinion ... the risk disclosure on notes underwritten by Merrill Lynch was entirely appropriate, and, in fact, was more complete than in other Orange County offerings.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Merrill Lynch does not comment on any aspect of regulatory investigations, including Wells notices,&quot; Merrill Lynch said. &quot;However, it would be wrong and unfair for anyone to infer that receipt of a Wells notice by any institution or individual represents a conclusion that wrongdoing occurred or that charges are warranted.&quot;</p>
<p>The SEC staff has sent Wells notices to several municipalities as part of its Orange County probe, including the cities of Irvine and Anaheim, and several local school districts.</p>
<p>In addition, several firms besides Merrill Lynch have received Wells notices, including CS First Boston Corp. Jean Costanza, a partner with the law firm of LeBoeuf Lamb Greene &amp; MacRae, had also received such a notice.</p>
<p>Orange County filed for bankruptcy protection in December, 1994, after investment losses of more than $1.6 billion.</p>
<p>The county emerged from bankruptcy in June of this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
