<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754722" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Austrians hurt in Greek crash may be flown home.</title>
<headline>Austrians hurt in Greek crash may be flown home.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek and Austrian authorities were hoping to fly home home five Austrian tourists on Thursday who were hurt in a head-on car crash on the Greek holiday island of Rhodes.</p>
<p>A 17-year-old Austrian girl, Sylvia Bergsmann, and her mother Kornelia were among the tourists killed on Wednesday when their minibus collided with a pick-up truck on their way back from a day-trip to the ancient site of Lindos, 55km from Rhodes town.</p>
<p>Another five tourists including Bergsmann's father and seven-year-old sister were seriously injured. They were transferred by a Hellenic Air Force C-130 airplane to Athens hospitals on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>The Austrian embassy in Athens said it was conferring with doctors on whether they could fly the injured to Austria.</p>
<p>Austrian ambassador Hans Sabaditsch said two of the tourists were in &quot;not very good condition&quot; but that seven-year-old Julia Bergsmann was in &quot;pretty good shape for the circumstances&quot;. He gave no details on the condition of her father Alfred.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
