<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754766" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: PHILIPS Q2 EARNINGS MORE THAN DOUBLE.</title>
<headline>PHILIPS Q2 EARNINGS MORE THAN DOUBLE.</headline>
<dateline>EINDHOVEN, Netherlands 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philips Electronics NV said on Thursday net profit from ordinary operations more than doubled in the second quarter to 693 million guilders ($337.4 million) from 304 million in 1996.</p>
<p>It said profits were helped by sound earnings across virtually all its product sectors.</p>
<p>The results roundly outstripped analysts' forecasts, which had ranged between 429 and 540 million guilders.</p>
<p>Shares in the company opened strongly on the Amsterdam bourse, putting on 14.90 guilders -- more than eight percent -- to 177.00 guilders in busy early trade.</p>
<p>Analysts expressed surprise at the extent of the jump in earnings and most said they would be re-adjusting their earnings estimates for this year and 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;The results are much better than expected and what is surprising is the enormous improvement in Europe. The loss in the United States was to be expected. We will increase our earnings estimates for the company,&quot; Steven Vrolijk of ING Barings said in an initial reaction.</p>
<p>&quot;Better than expected, the only slightly disappointing segment was consumer products -- that's probably because of the start-up costs of mobile telephones etc,&quot; said Rene Verhoef of NIB Securities.</p>
<p>NIB would upgrade its per-share forecasts for this year and next, he added: &quot;A share price of about 200 guilders looks reasonable at the moment and 225 guilders in a year's time is possible.&quot;</p>
<p>Philips said total net profit in the second quarter jumped to 747 million guilders ($363.6 million), up from a loss of 456 million in the same period last year.</p>
<p>The company said the first half results indicated that the internal improvement programmes initiated in 1996 were on track.</p>
<p>It addded it remained committed to achieving its previously stated goal of double digit growth in operating income, a positive cash flow of over one billion guilders in 1997, and a 24 percent return on net assets in the longer term. ($ = 2.054 Dutch Guilders)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EINDHOVEN, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
