<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754801" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME prices stable in pre-market, spreads hold key.</title>
<headline>LME prices stable in pre-market, spreads hold key.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Base metals prices hovered near previous closing levels in a subdued pre-market on Thursday after London Metal Exchange (LME) stocks offered no surprises.</p>
<p>But traders said they were closely watching nearby spreads on copper, aluminium and zinc for direction on these markets.</p>
<p>Aluminium's solid gains on Wednesday sparked by speculators were expected to extend to $1,650 and then $1,670, traders said.</p>
<p>In the pre-market light speculative short covering was countered by profit-taking. Three months prices were last at $1,646/1,648 per tonne, versus $1,642 at the kerb close.</p>
<p>&quot;The 1,650 level has been hard to get through which encouraged some profit-taking. The market has paused but the spread is underpinning the rally,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>He was referring to growing tightness in nearby months, exacerbated by steadily declining stocks.</p>
<p>The cash/threes contango contracted to $8/$5 on Thursday morning, compared to around $20 earlier in the week.</p>
<p>Zinc, the star of the complex which marched to fresh seven-year highs on Wednesday, is also seen firmer.</p>
<p>But zinc is very oversold, with the 14-day RSI above the 80 level, and the market may need to consolidate gains around current levels before proceeding higher, traders said.</p>
<p>On the upside $1,580 and then $1,600 were targets.</p>
<p>Market sentiment was decidedly more bearish for copper, due to steady LME stock rises and a contracting backwardation.</p>
<p>For the time being, however, it was was firmer at $2,282/$2,285 per tonne against Wednesday's close of $2,273.</p>
<p>Cash to threes backwardation was at $60/$65, little changed from Wednesday afternoon but down sharply from last week's peak of $270 as recent tightness unwound.</p>
<p>LME stocks rose by 3,950 tonnes, bringing the total reported inventories to 204,900 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;People are looking for copper to go lower, but it doesn't look ready to break down just yet,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>In the other metals, nickel probed the $6,800 level early on, following overnight news of a breakdown in contract talks between nickel producer Falconbridge Ltd and a union representing 1,400 workers at its Sudbury, Onatrio operations.</p>
<p>The current contract expires at the end of the month.</p>
<p>But prices edged back down to $6,780/$6,790 little changed from the kerb close of $6,780.</p>
<p>Tin edged up by $10 to $5,380 while lead was quoted at $648/$650 versus $650.</p>
<p>Alloy was indicated unchanged at $1,465/$,1,470.</p>
<p>--Lida Poletz, London newsroom +44 171 542 2936</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
