<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754946" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: INSTANT VIEW - Australian Q2 wages data.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Australian Q2 wages data.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian average weekly ordinary time earnings rose 0.5 percent in the three months to May to show annual growth at 3.7 percent. Median forecasts had centred on a 0.8 percent rise for an annual rate of 4.1 percent. A selection of economists' immediate reactions the data follows.</p>
<p>JOHN EDWARDS, CHIEF ECONOMIST, HSBC MARKETS:</p>
<p>&quot;I think it clears the way for a rate cut which we continue to expect to most likely be announced at 9.30 a.m. (2330 GMT) tomorrow. It is an excellent result. We would be surprised to see that low level of wages growth being sustained.&quot;  </p>
<p>ROB HENDERSON, CHIEF ECONOMIST, DRESDNER</p>
<p>&quot;It's a fantastic number. I think it almost certainly cements low inflation over the next 12 to 18 months in our economy. From that point of view, we've got an extremely good inflation outlook on the back of a very, very good inflation performance already, so in terms of interest rates I think it's unlikely now that the Reserve won't cut. We'd have to concede and that it's a 90-percent chance I think now that they will cut.&quot;</p>
<p>DAVID DE GARIS, TREASURY ECONOMIST, ANZ BANKING GROUP</p>
<p>&quot;They are a very encouraging set of numbers as far as the Reserve Bank's inflation targets are concerned. We think that the Reserve Bank now has more than sufficient evidence on weaker-than-expected activity and lower-than-expected inflation on which to ease again.&quot;</p>
<p>BILL SHIELDS, CHIEF ECONOMIST, MACQUARIE BANK:</p>
<p>&quot;They were much lower than expected. In fact, lower than the market range even. It's a very low and obviously positive figure looking forward on inflation. That's the key issue. It tells you that inflation expectations are also probably coming down in line with yesterday's positive result on lower underlying inflation. That certainly builds the case for an interest rate cut. If for no other reason than perhaps to prevent real interest rates from rising as a consequence of lower inflation. So it certainly adds to the case for a rate cut.&quot;</p>
<p>PETER MUNCKTON, SENIOR ECONOMIST, BANKERS TRUST</p>
<p>&quot;It was very good. It does not matter how you print it, it shows wages is not a problem, yesterday it showed that inflation is not a problem, but unemployment is still a problem and that is why I think on August 6 they (RBA) will cut rates.&quot;  </p>
<p>MICHAEL BLYTHE, SENIOR ECONOMIST, COMMONWEALTH BANK:</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very inflation-friendly result. Essentially yesterday's data told us we had low inflation and today's data suggests we are going to keep it low for the next year or so. There doesn't seem to be anything standing in the way of another rate cut. With an unemployment rate of 8.5 percent it would seem to be a necessity rather than something that I would like to debate.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
