<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="754952" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Aristocrat to discuss suspension with ASX.</title>
<headline>Aristocrat to discuss suspension with ASX.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gaming machines operator Aristocrat Leisure Ltd said on Thursday it would meet with officials from the companies office of the Australian Stock Exchange to discuss the issues behind the company's suspension.</p>
<p>Aristocrat general counsel Louise Sexton told Reuters that she hoped the suspension could be lifted as soon as possible following the talks.</p>
<p>The ASX imposed the suspension before the start of Wednesday trading, seeking more information about the company's dispute with the Colorado Gaming Control Commission and the future of its licence in the U.S. state.  </p>
<p>The company said earlier this week that a number of allegations in the Commission's denial notice relating to its future licensing in the state were defamatory.</p>
<p>It said, however, that the Commission was concerned about who was in control of the company and their unsuitability, irregularity in sales to South American customers, and management and operational instability.</p>
<p>The company, which was founded by Len Ainsworth, would argue against the Commission's notice in a hearing to begin on August 29. Ainsworth's family has recently announced agreements not to exercise voting control.  </p>
<p>Sexton said Aristocrat had not been made aware of any concerns by the New South Wales Casino Control Authority, which regulates gambing in the state.</p>
<p>The Authority told The Australian newspaper that it was in contact with the Colorado Commission.</p>
<p>The company said earlier this week that it had reached an agreement to sell 830 machines to the Sydney Harbour Casino Ltd . </p>
<p>Aristocrat, which makes slot machines for casinos and licenced clubs and hotels, assembles its U.S. product in California and has a licence to operate in New Jersey which has the key gambing centre of Atlantic City.</p>
<p>It plans to seek a licence for its products in the other key state of Nevada later this calendar year. Las Vegas and Reno are located in Nevada.</p>
<p>Aristocrat said Colorado accounted for only five percent of its U.S. market but earlier told Reuters that it was concerned about potential flow-on effects.</p>
<p>-- Ian Pemberton, Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
