<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="755009" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Ekran to clarify Bakun terms with ABB.</title>
<headline>Ekran to clarify Bakun terms with ABB.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ekran Bhd said on Thursday said it was seeking clarifications over the terms of a contract to build the Bakun hydroelectric dam from ABB Asea Brown Boveri. </p>
<p>&quot;BHC (Bakun Hydroelectric Corp Bhd) is seeking clarification of some of the terms from ABB,&quot; an advisor to Ekran chairman Ting Pek Khiing told reporters at the company's headquarters.</p>
<p>Ekran, who was awarded the Bakun project, has given the $5.5 billion engineering, procurement and construction (EPC) contract to ABB and Brazil's Companhia Brasileria Projectos o Obras (CBPO).  </p>
<p>BHC, in which Ekran has a 32 percent stake, is the operating company of the project.</p>
<p>The advisor, speaking to reporters on the sidelines of a meeting between Ekran and ABB Brown Boveri, said the companies will return at a later date to clarify some of the outstanding issues on the EPC contract.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not something that can be resolved overnight,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Malaysia's Deputy Prime Minister and Finance Minister Anwar Ibrahim had said last week that there were &quot;major disagreements&quot; over the terms of the agreement between Ekran and ABB Asea Brown Boveri.</p>
<p>Anwar had said the disagreements were over &quot;major terms&quot; of the EPC contract, and could lead to a delay in the hydroelectric project, scheduled for completion by 2003.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said on Tuesday there was no dispute in the project, only differing personal opinions.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
