<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="755148" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan firms denies Oak patent charge.</title>
<headline>Taiwan firms denies Oak patent charge.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four Taiwan electronic companies on Thursday denied charges that they have infringed patents of U.S.-based Oak Technology Inc.</p>
<p>Oak said on Tuesday it had filed a complaint with the U.S. International Trade Commission against nine companies, alleging a violation of trade laws for importing and selling products that Oak believes infringe two of its patents.</p>
<p>Oak makes CD-ROM controllers used in computers.</p>
<p>Five of the nine firms are from Taiwan, including United Microelectronics, Winbond, Lite-on Group, Lite-On Technology, and Behavior Tech.</p>
<p>The first four firms denied the charges, while Behavior was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very surprised by Oak's move because we and Oak have reconciled in the case,&quot; United Micro vice-president J.S. Aur told Reuters. &quot;There must be some mistakes there, and I believe Oak will soon withdraw its charge against us.&quot;</p>
<p>Aur said United Micro produces only T$20 million worth of CD-ROM controllers a year, a small part of its 1996 sales of T$22.6 billion.  </p>
<p>A Winbond spokesman, who declined to be named, said the firm was unlikely to have infringed Oak's patents.</p>
<p>&quot;We contacted Oak in February, and the initial results showed that it's impossible we have infringed Oak's patents,&quot; the Winbond spokesman said by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;Still we have to wait for Oak's formal complaint documents, but it's unlikely we have infringed Oak's patents,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lite-On Technology and Lite-On Group said Oak's patent complaints would not affect its production and sales of CD-ROMs.</p>
<p>&quot;We are surprised to be involved in this because we bought CD-ROM parts from United Micro to produce CD-ROMs,&quot; said Lite-On spokeswoman Kuo Hsiu-chuan.</p>
<p>&quot;While United Micro told us that it had already reconciled with Oak, so we believe the case will be solved soon, and it should not affect our CD-ROM production and sales,&quot; Kuo said.</p>
<p>-- Taipei newsroom (886-2-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302004">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34532">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
