<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="755353" id="root" date="1997-07-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Tears flow in Rome as O'Dell executed in Virginia.</title>
<headline>Tears flow in Rome as O'Dell executed in Virginia.</headline>
<byline>Philip Pullella</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>While Joseph O'Dell was being put to death in Virginia, hundreds of Italians opposed to capital punishment held a countdown vigil in a Rome square hoping and praying to the last minute that he would be spared.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe the Pope will call the governor (of Virginia),&quot; one woman in the crowd said minutes before O'Dell was executed. &quot;That's the only thing that might save him at this point&quot;</p>
<p>But she and others in the small crowed broke into tears when, via a live television hook-up from Virginia, they heard a spokesman for Governor George Allen announce dryly:</p>
<p>&quot;The execution was completed at 9:16&quot; p.m.</p>
<p>O'Dell, a convicted murderer and rapist, was killed by lethal injection and died after saying he was innocent.</p>
<p>&quot;They killed a man who died proclaiming his innocence and above all a man who was very different than what he was 12 years ago when he was accused of killing the woman,&quot; said Alfredo Biondi, deputy speaker of the Senate and an ex justice minister.</p>
<p>The crowd gathered in Rome's Campo de Fiori square, around the statue of Giordano Bruno, the monk who was burned there for heresy in 1600 during the Counter-Reformation. They converged on the square after an earlier protest at the U.S. embassy</p>
<p>With many of them wearing T-shirts reading &quot;Don't kill for me. I don't support the death penalty,&quot; the crowd watched on two mega-screens as live television hook-ups with Italian correspondents kept them informed of the events in Virginia.</p>
<p>Italy, which has no death penalty in civilian criminal cases, is among the most vocal supporters of a worldwide ban on capital punishment.</p>
<p>The O'Dell case became a cause celebre, with Pope John Paul, President Oscar Luigi Scalfaro and Prime Minister Romano Prodi making appeals for clemency to Governor Allen.</p>
<p>O'Dell was convicted for the 1985 rape and murder of Helen Schartner but had appealed for new DNA testing he said would prove his innocence.</p>
<p>But earlier on Wednesday, a federal appeals court in Richmond turned down the DNA request, saying the claim was &quot;meritless.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Let's not let O'Dell die twice,&quot; former family affairs minister Antonio Guidi said in the crowd. &quot;Let's use this as an opportunity to spur us on to fight against capital punishment.&quot;</p>
<p>On a wall of one of the centuries-old buildings in the square, a bustling fruit market by day, hung a banner that read:</p>
<p>&quot;The hangman does not go on vacation&quot;. It included a list of death row inmates who are due to be executed in the United States in coming weeks.</p>
<p>Actor Vittorio Gassman who was once married to American actress Shelly Winters, told a reporter:</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the death penalty is a deterrent against crime and I am shocked that a people as generous as the Americans do not rise up against capital punishment.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;I have a daughter who is American and I think she would be happy to know that I am here.&quot;</p>
<p>Alfonso Pecoraro-Scanio, a parliamentarian of the Greens Party, urged Italians to boycott U.S. states were capital punishment is practised.</p>
<p>&quot;I urge Italians not to go on vacation in American states that have the death penalty. Go to states where it is not practised,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The O'Dell execution was carried out hours after the U.S. Supreme Court rejected an appeal 9-0.</p>
<p>Allen also denied O'Dell's last-minute plea for clemency, saying he saw &quot;no legitimate reason&quot; to justify overturning the judgement of a jury who heard the case.</p>
<p>O'Dell, 55, was married to his volunteer paralegal, Lori Urs, 41, in a midday wedding on Wednesday at the Greenville Correction Centre.</p>
<p>O'Dell was made an honorary citizen of the city of Palermo and has said he wanted to be buried there.</p>
<p>Luciano Neri, a parliamentarian of the Sicily-based La Rete party, said he visited O'Dell recently and that he asked that his grave in Palermo be made a monument against the death penalty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
