<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="755415" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AOL drops plan to share users' phone numbers.</title>
<headline>AOL drops plan to share users' phone numbers.</headline>
<byline>Jim Wolf</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>America Online Inc. said Thursday it was dropping plans to sell subscriber phone numbers to business partners for telemarketing purposes.</p>
<p>Responding to a mounting outcry from customers, privacy advocates and consumer leaders, AOL said it had never planned to make the phone numbers of its more than 8 million subscribers worldwide &quot;available for rental to telemarketers.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The only calls we intended for you to receive would have been from AOL and a limited number of quality-controlled AOL partners,&quot; the company said in a statement addressed to its subscribers.</p>
<p>&quot;However, upon further reflection, we today decided to change our plans. We will not provide lists of our members' telephone numbers even to our partners. The only calls you might receive will be from us,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>AOL reversed itself after a firestorm erupted over a planned change to its privacy policy that would have added phone numbers to the list of personal information, such as electronic mail addresses, it already sells to some marketers.</p>
<p>Moments before the AOL reversal, President Clinton's top aide on consumer affairs had urged the Dulles, Va., company to rethink the move as a threat to individual privacy.</p>
<p>Leslie Byrne, a special assistant to the president and former member of Congress, had said she would ditch AOL as her personal gateway to the Internet unless it reversed course.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they recognized it was bad business,&quot; Byrne, a former Democratic member of Congress from Virginia, told Reuters after AOL backed down.</p>
<p>She said her office had been reviewing surveys showing that personal privacy was a key concern for people using the Internet, the worldwide collection of computer networks.</p>
<p>&quot;For the integrity of the Internet and for people to really use the medium to its full potential means that companies like AOL have got to protect personal information,&quot; Byrne said.</p>
<p>Privacy advocates had voiced outrage at what they deemed woefully inadequate notice of the changes to AOL's &quot;terms-of-service&quot; agreement. As of early Thursday, no notice of the change had been provided on any of the screens a user sees when logging on and where new AOL features are typically announced.</p>
<p>The initial AOL plan had represented &quot;a quantum leap&quot; in the potential invasiveness of direct marketing, said David Sobel, legal counsel at the Electronic Privacy Information Center in Washington, a nonprofit research group that tracks privacy issues on the Internet.</p>
<p>At issue was more than the disclosure of just &quot;unadorned&quot; subscriber telephone numbers, Sobel said. He said he understood that AOL, using its ability to record every site  its members visit online, had been planning to add value to the telephone lists by breaking them out according to &quot;navigational&quot; and &quot;transactional&quot; preferences, such as where subscribers have gone or what they had bought through AOL.</p>
<p>The new policy, which had been outlined in AOL's revised user rules, was to have taken effect on July 31. It would have made telephone numbers available to direct marketers such as CUC International Inc. , which signed a $50 million marketing arrangement with AOL last month.</p>
<p>By killing the planned change quickly, AOL apparently hoped to avoid the kind of public relations nightmare sparked by widespread busy signals last winter and spring when it failed to anticipate the demand a flat-rate pricing plan would bring.</p>
<p>AOL, which bills itself as the world's most popular gateway to the Internet, did not immediately spell out what effect its reversal would have on marketing arrangements with partners such as CUC International</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
