<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="755412" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AirTouch profits jump 74 percent, stock hits record.</title>
<headline>AirTouch profits jump 74 percent, stock hits record.</headline>
<byline>Eric Auchard</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>AirTouch Communications Inc., the diversified cellular and paging operator, said Thursday its profits jumped 74 percent in the second quarter as revenues grew even faster despite rising competition.</p>
<p>The San Francisco-based company said its net income for the three months ended June 30 soared to $106 million, or 21 cents a share, from $61 million, or 12 cents a share.</p>
<p>The per-share results were far better than Wall Street had expected. The consensus had been for 14 cents a share, according to First Call, which tracks analysts' estimates.</p>
<p>The latest quarter included a gain of 3 cents primarily related to changes in accounting for taxes in prior years.</p>
<p>The company's stock shot up $3 to $31.50 on the New York Stock Exchange, where it was one of the most actively traded issues, setting a new year-high.</p>
<p>AirTouch said its revenues for the quarter raced ahead by 87 percent to $901 million from $481 million as it added 617,000 new customers.</p>
<p>&quot;Without a doubt this is the best quarter we've ever had,&quot; Chairman Sam Ginn said.</p>
<p>He added that based on the company's results so far this year, AirTouch was on track to meet or exceed its goal of $1.5 billion in cash flow for 1997, up from $1.1 billion in 1996.</p>
<p>Investors focus on cash flow as a measure of the earnings potential of wireless phone companies once they finish paying off substantial up-front investments that must be made for construction of cellular or paging networks.</p>
<p>Recognizing that the amount of revenues it derives from each customer is falling as prices for cellular phone service decline in the face of increasing competition, AirTouch has focused on controlling costs to offset revenue declines.</p>
<p>Ginn attributed the company's growth to its success in attracting and retaining customers, a crucial means of controlling expenses, which amount to $350 to add each new subscriber in the United States.</p>
<p>Ginn said that while revenue per customer declined 14 percent in the second quarter, costs per customer fell 22 percent in the same period, substantially boosting profits.</p>
<p>He also pointed to the success of the company's overseas operations, where revenues grew 92 percent in the second quarter compared with the same quarter of 1996. The company's international business accounted for 42 percent of its total revenues.</p>
<p>AirTouch said second-quarter profit margins in its U.S. cellular phone business rose to a record 49 percent of revenues -- up from 48 percent in the first quarter and 43 percent in year-ago quarter and well ahead of the industry.</p>
<p>While Ginn said it would be hard to sustain those record levels over time, he said margins would remain at or above industry levels. &quot;I see us operating in the 40's for the foreseeable future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Overall second-quarter operating cash flow profit margins grew to 35.6 percent from 30.8 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>AirTouch said the addition of 617,000 cellular, personal communications services and paging customers allowed it to reach more than 9 million customers, including its proportionate ownership in various domestic and international properties.</p>
<p>Ginn said he expected the company to meet or beat its goal of adding 1.6 million customers during 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;With our international start-ups reaching profitability and our U.S. cellular margins at an all-time high, we are well-positioned for the remainder of the year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Alex. Brown &amp; Sons analyst Brian Colemam said he upgraded AirTouch's stock to a strong buy rating and was planning to raise his earnings estimates for the rest of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This quarter really highlighted the size and scale benefits that are accruing to this company,&quot; Coleman said.</p>
<p>AirTouch serves more than 9 million customers in the United States and 11 other countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
