<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="755576" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US debt futures end off in quiet pre-weekend trade.</title>
<headline>US debt futures end off in quiet pre-weekend trade.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures ended lower in very quiet pre-weekend trade.</p>
<p>Traders said the market ground to a virtual stop by midday and key contracts remained locked in tight ranges in the afternoon.</p>
<p>With this week's abundance of economic stimuli behind them, players took to the sidelines ahead of an equally jam-packed line-up next week.</p>
<p>The market &quot;looks swell but it kind of lost its momentum right now and with all this news out next week people are probably going to sit back and prepare,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>Traders were especially keen for the second-quarter employment cost index, due Tuesday. The previous report showed an 0.6-percent gain. Also on tap are a quarterly refunding announcement, second-quarter gross domestic product, and July payrolls data.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be an active week,&quot; a Eurodollar trader said. He noted minor pre-weekend positioning early, and said many local traders left the pits by midday, leaving trade in the short end at a standstill late Friday.</p>
<p>Debt futures dipped to lows early on June durable goods orders, then turned up after existing home sales.  </p>
<p>June durable goods rose 2.3 percent, compared with a forecast for a 1.4 percent gain and an upwardly revised drop of 0.4 percent in May.</p>
<p>June existing home sales fell 2.6 percent to a 4.14 million annual rate, compared with a forecast for a 4.19 million rate.</p>
<p>Overall, traders said the market still holds a firm tone, and said the week's action remained bullish.</p>
<p>&quot;There are not really a lot of bad things you can say about the market,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>September Treasury bond futures achieved a new high for the year at 115-23/32 during the week and closed nearly a point above last week's 114-06/32 close.</p>
<p>At the close, September T-bonds were off 9/32 at 115-01/32, 10-year notes were down 5/32 at 110-00, muni-bonds fell 10/32 to 120-22/32, December Eurodollars gave up 0.015 to 94.125, and December T-bills ended flat at 94.815. ((DerivativesDesk(312)408-8750)) E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
