<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="755830" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IntraNet Solutions set $4 mln credit pact.</title>
<headline>IntraNet Solutions set $4 mln credit pact.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>IntraNet Solutions Inc said Thursday it has completed a $4 million private placement of convertible preferred stock.</p>
<p>According to a Securities and Exchange Commission ruling related to the financing, the company will take a non-cash charge totaling about $1.6 million. This non-cash charge will result in no net effect on total stockholders' equity since the charge, reflecting the approximate discount to market calculated at the date the preferred stock was issued, is offset in the company's balance sheet by a corresponding increase in additional paid-in-capital.</p>
<p>In the placement, IntraNet has issued 800,000 units, each consisting of one share of the $5.00 par value Series A five percent convertible preferred and a warrant to acquire one share of common stock at an exercise price of $5.18.</p>
<p>The Series A preferred stock converts into the company's common stock at 75 percent of market value at the time of conversion, with a maximum conversion price of $3.71 per share.</p>
<p>Robert Olson, chairman and chief executive officer, said, the financing will be used to expand its business. &quot;The proceeds bolster our capital base and provide the resources necessary to continue with the implementation of our strategic plans for the future, including the aggressive marketing and distribution of IntraNet's Intra.doc!(TM) Management System in both U.S. and international markets.&quot;</p>
<p>IntraNet provides services to manage and distribute information contained in documents, using Internet/intranet web technologies.</p>
<p>	     ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
