<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756178" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK surgeon in breakthrough on child heart surgery.</title>
<headline>UK surgeon in breakthrough on child heart surgery.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A cardiac surgeon based has pioneered a revolutionary procedure for child heart surgery, the Scottish-based HCI International Medical Centre reported on Friday.</p>
<p>Dr Tony Corno, director of the Centre's paediatric cardiac programme, has discovered children can endure heart surgery without having their body temperature lowered.</p>
<p>Traditionally, heart surgery on the young involves chilling sick and fragile children before operating, a technique known as hypothermia surgery. The problem is that a quarter of children undergoing such surgery suffer serious side effects.</p>
<p>Corno's method, which he calls normothermia, had astonished doctors around the world, HCI, which is located near Glasgow, said. He has performed the technique, operating on children without lowering their body temperatures or slowing metabolism and blood flow, in 60 cases since last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The benefits of the normothermic technique speak for themselves,&quot; Corno said. &quot;Although it means we have to work much faster, we are able to avoid the complications which can arise from deliberately chilling and re-heating the child.&quot;</p>
<p>Corno, 47, said most of his patients leave the HCI intensive care unit after 24 hours and return home after five to seven days. Under traditional methods, 11 days is more normal.</p>
<p>In addition, fewer children require inotropic drugs to maintain the heart's ability to pump blood after surgery, while complications such as respiratory disorders and blood, liver and kidney difficulties are significantly reduced.</p>
<p>All that adds up to a significant reduction in hospitalisation costs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
