<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756232" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lloyds TSB to star again in UK bank results.</title>
<headline>Lloyds TSB to star again in UK bank results.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lloyds TSB Group Plc, which reports its first half results next Friday, is set to retain its position as the best performer in the UK banking sector.</p>
<p>Pre-tax profits are set to rise by around one third to above 1.5 billion pounds, after 1.14 billion in the same period last year, while a dividend per share of 5.0p compared with 4.2p last time will give growth of 19 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It's again going to be the star performer,&quot; said Nikko Europe banking analyst Tim Clarke. &quot;But its rating is hugely expensive on all measure.&quot;</p>
<p>Lloyds looks set to report a hefty fall in costs, unlike most others, and its high ratings are easily justified by the quality of its earnings stream, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Lloyds has been the best performer in the sector, its highly cash-generative business will ensure it soon accumulates enough cash to make other, value-enhancing, deals,&quot; said UBS analyst John Aitken.</p>
<p>Costs are expected fall by at least five percent as the bank reaps the rewards of its merger with TSB and internal cost cutting.</p>
<p>In the banking business, the group is expected to have found it just as tough as its peers to increase income, however, with margins under pressure and fee income growth lacklustre.</p>
<p>Like the others, Lloyds will benefit from consumer credit growth with good growth, for example, in credit cards.</p>
<p>The market will be looking for some indication from chairman Brian Pitman and chief executive Peter Ellwood on where Lloyds TSB will go from here.</p>
<p>Its ability to generate cash means that a further value-enhancing merger or takeover must be a major possibility despite the fact that Pitman has said prices are too high.</p>
<p>Indeed, Nikko's Clarke says its is imperative that Lloyds pursues this strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;Lloyds TSB will only remain the leader if its goes for another merger,&quot; Clarke said.</p>
<p>- Joe Ortiz, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8864.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
