<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756210" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WORLD BONDS- NZ, UK offer real returns, with risk.</title>
<headline>WORLD BONDS- NZ, UK offer real returns, with risk.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Scott</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yield-hungry investors trying to eke out a decent real return in major bond markets face tough choices in the current low inflation world, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>In addition to lower real yields, currency risks in otherwise attractive markets such as New Zealand and Britain and a potential upside inflation bias in Germany from the weaker mark have clouded the issue, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The intelligent investor ought to be focusing on the issue of real yields,&quot; said Michael Derks, cross market fixed income strategist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;Real yields are compressed, so you need to ask whether real returns at these levels are going to be justified over time.&quot;</p>
<p>Derks said the market that really stood out at present in terms of a healthy real yield was New Zealand, which still has one of the highest yields and lowest rates of inflation in the world.</p>
<p>New Zealand's consumer price inflation was at 1.1 percent in June, while the 10-year bond yield, annualised for international comparison, is currently at 6.96 percent, giving a real yield of 5.86 percent.</p>
<p>That compares with a real yield of 3.87 percent in Germany -- based on 1.7 percent inflation and 5.57 percent nominal yield -- and 4.19 percent in Britain, which saw 2.9 percent inflation in June with a 7.09 percent 10-year yield.</p>
<p>But even in New Zealand, the case is not as clear-cut as it has been, since currency factors threaten to erode returns.</p>
<p>&quot;To the extent that real interest rates are very high, that has attracted a lot of investors to New Zealand,&quot; said Kirit Shah, chief strategist at Sanwa International.</p>
<p>&quot;My concern is not an inflation problem...But the currency is already falling versus the dollar which is putting some people off.&quot;</p>
<p>Shah said with a large chunk of foreign investment in New Zealand, a snap sell-off by overseas investors could send prices sliding.</p>
<p>He noted the real return in the UK was fairly healthy, but added that was just one factor in a number that influenced investment decisions.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not so sure people are buying bonds because of real yields only,&quot; he said. Sterling's relentless rise and fears of another interest rate rise have kept the big money at bay.</p>
<p>Stephen Englander, international economist and vice-president at Smith Barney in Paris, said despite that, yields in Britain were fairly attractive.&quot;Surprisingly, the UK isn't a bad place to be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're afraid the Bank of England may tighten a few more notches, but in terms of yields, levels are attractive.&quot;</p>
<p>Shah said potential inflationary pressures in Germany should be sounding alarm bells for Bund investors.</p>
<p>&quot;One has to be very careful in terms of import price inflation,&quot; he said, adding that if the mark kept on weakening at its recent pace, it could endanger Germany's impressive inflation record.</p>
<p>But Englander was more sanguine, saying the inflation risk in Germany was minimal at the end of the day. He said medium-term Italian paper looked pretty good in real yield terms.</p>
<p>Englander noted investors in search of serious yields would have to increasingly turn to emerging markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Convergence in Europe has brought down yields in absolute terms as well so there's only a few pockets left you can point to where you can earn a bit of money,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 8682</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
