<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756254" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Biocompatibles up in rebound from lows.</title>
<headline>Biocompatibles up in rebound from lows.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Britain's Biocompatibles Plc shot higher on Friday, recovering from recent weakness as a press report highlighted positive comment on the stock from Merrill Lynch, dealers said.</p>
<p>The shares were up 175p, or 17.9 percent, at 11.55 stg by 1046 GMT. On Thursday the stock fell to a low of 950p, its lowest since January.  </p>
<p>The Financial Times noted that Biocompatibles shares had been depressed recently by worries over an apparent delay to talks with Johnson &amp; Johnson, concerning Biocompatibles' &quot;stent&quot; products used to free blocked-up arteries.</p>
<p>However, the paper said Merrill analysts remained positive on the stock.</p>
<p>Nigel Barnes at Merrill told Reuters he believed worries over the Johnson &amp; Johnson talks had been overdone.</p>
<p>Barnes said the talks had been expanded from their initial aim of allowing J&amp;J to license Biocompatibles technology to use in its own products, to include the possibility of the U.S. firm directly marketing Biocompatibles products.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Biocompatibles said in a statement its talks with J&amp;J were continuing and a further announcement would be made once negotiations had been completed.</p>
<p>Dealers said the report had helped jerk the stock out of its recent slump. &quot;It has just been bombed out in the past few days,&quot; said one, adding that he was not aware of any other news in the market.</p>
<p>-- David Holmes, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4367</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
