<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756275" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: POLL-Gilts top the table in spread convergence.</title>
<headline>POLL-Gilts top the table in spread convergence.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Scott</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bond spreads will continue to converge over the next 18 months with the British gilt market topping the table of outperformance over Bunds, according to latest Reuter surveys.</p>
<p>French OAT yields will gradually inch up towards their German counterparts and by the second quarter next year, will be on a par.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the main movers on spreads is going to be gilts -- that'll be one to watch,&quot; said Sonja Gibbs, senior bond strategist at Nomura International in London.</p>
<p>Italian and Spanish bond markets will also stick firmly to the EMU convergence path, but the blistering pace set over the last month or so will inevitably slow, anlaysts said.</p>
<p>The rate at which BTP yields have swooped in on Bunds has outpaced all but the most extreme predictions in the polls so far, which together used 98 forecasts from banks, research firms and academic institutions around Europe. The polls were conducted between late June and mid-July.</p>
<p>The Italian/German gap has already reached levels which were not expected to be seen until the second quarter of 1998.</p>
<p>So while convergence trades will continue, their pace will abate and the expected low in the BTP/Bund spread will likely be reached quicker than most economists expected just a few months ago.</p>
<p>Graham McDevitt, head of bond strategy at Paribas Capital Markets in London, said he expected all the European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) country spreads to narrow in the next six months, despite the already substantial moves.</p>
<p>&quot;In six months' time we'll basically know if EMU is happening or not. So by spring next year, we'll know who is in, what the exchange rates will be and so on,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>McDevitt expected the BTP/Bund spread to come in to around 50 to 60 basis points in that time, with the Spanish/German gap at around 30 to 40 basis points.</p>
<p>That compared with a median poll estimate of 80 basis points for the BTP/Bund spread in six months' time -- which has already been reached.</p>
<p>Gibbs estimated a slightly lower premium of around 20 to 30 basis points on Spanish and Portuguese bonds over Bunds by the time EMU kicks off in January 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;There's more of a credit risk issue with Italy,&quot; Gibbs said, adding that a premium of 40 basis points was more realistic for Italy.</p>
<p>But Spain and Portugal, if they are part of EMU, will have less to distinguish themselves from core European countries other than their histories of less stable policies, she said.</p>
<p>The poll predicted a median Bono/Bund spread of 55 basis points by the end of this year, falling to 35 basis points by the second quarter of 1998 and a low of 20 basis points by the end of next year. On Friday, the spread was at 62 basis points.</p>
<p>The Portuguese/Bund gap was also seen falling to 20 basis points by Q4 1998 from around 70 now, broadly in line with the Bonos spread, according to the median estimate.</p>
<p>Gilts meantime will be unable to shake their premium to Bunds completely, although steady outperformance between now and Q2 1999 will take the 10-year spread below the 100 basis point level.</p>
<p>According to the poll, the gap -- currently at 155 basis points -- will narrow to 135 by the fourth quarter of this year and 103 by the third quarter of 1998. It will finally dip below 100 basis points by the end of next year.</p>
<p>Gilts, like other &quot;EMU outs&quot;, will have to rely on fundamentals for any spread convergence, analysts said.</p>
<p>McDevitt said Sweden may struggle to wrench its bond yields down to any substantial degree as political uncertainy keeps the market on tenterhooks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
