<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756242" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Granada rises as DKB repeats 'buy'.</title>
<headline>Granada rises as DKB repeats 'buy'.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in UK hotels to television company Granada Group Plc climbed on Friday, after analysts at Dresdner Kleinwort Benson (DKB) repeated their 'buy' recommendation on the stock.</p>
<p>Granada stock added 20.5p to 804.5p by 1115 GMT as some two million shares changed hands.</p>
<p>DKB analyst Paul Slattery said Granada's recent underperformance was not justified given the prospects for digital terrestrial television and its acquisition of Yorkshire-Tyne Tees Television.  </p>
<p>Granada shares have slipped from over 950p in mid-May.</p>
<p>Slattery said Granada's involvement in the British Digital Broadcasting (BDB) venture with fellow ITV broadcaster Carlton Communications Plc was the right kind of initiative for the company, although it would be a medium to long-term investment.</p>
<p>BDB has won licences to run digital terrestrial television services when they are launched in 1998.</p>
<p>It has strengthened its hand in the ITV network with the 700 million stg acquisition of northern neighbour Yorkshire-Tyne Tees.</p>
<p>Slattery said the return on that deal was likely to be lifted by plans to reform the licence fee system for ITV companies.</p>
<p>Proposals from the Independent Television Commission (ITC) envisage a cut in the fixed fee element of the payments, with a greater part of it based on advertising and sponsorship income.</p>
<p>Yorkshire, which handed over 56 million stg in fixed fees in 1996, has long been lobbying for a reduction in its payments.</p>
<p>-- Keith Weir, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8793</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
