<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756463" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAfrica's Nampo says white maize shortage persists.</title>
<headline>SAfrica's Nampo says white maize shortage persists.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's National Maize Producers Organisation (Nampo) said on Friday that despite a rise this week in the 1997 crop estimate, there would still be a 476,000 tonne shortage of white maize this season.</p>
<p>Japie Grobler, Nampo's chairman said in a statement that the price of white maize, which he said was currently around 550 rand a tonne to the farmer, would have to rise to 600 rand a tonne.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the latest crop estimate was raised by 300,000 tonnes (200,000 tonnes white and 100,000 tonnes yellow maize), consumer trends show that there is still a 476,000 tonne shortage of white maize on the domestic market,&quot; Grobler said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices will therefore have to move higher to encourage producers to sell their white maize,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The National Crop Estimates Committee this week increased its monthly maize forecast to 7.966 million tonnes from its 7.660 million tonnes in June. The crop was expected to comprise 4.333 million tonnes of white and 3.633 million of yellow.</p>
<p>Nampo urged farmers who had not yet entered into maize contracts to deliver their product to agricultural co-operatives to enable co-ops to have enough maize to operate in the market on behalf of producers.</p>
<p>Grobler said that estimates showed there would be a surplus of yellow maize in the domestic market which was being reflected in lower prices. Producers were encouraged not to sell their maize at too low prices and rather to use it as animal feed.</p>
<p>He said that yellow maize was currently trading at 480 rand a tonne to producers.</p>
<p>Grobler cautioned about the impact on next season's crop of the El Nino weather phenomenon, which has built up far quicker than usual this year and has previously caused devastating droughts in southern Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;It must be taken into account that El Nino will not only negatively impact on expected production (next season), but it will also have a dramatic effect on pasturelands and alternative food sources,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
