<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756441" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: FEATURE - Boom times bring top ad agencies to West Africa.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Boom times bring top ad agencies to West Africa.</headline>
<byline>Alan Raybould</byline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>When the owners of Awa, a brand of bottled drinking water in Ivory Coast, came to the fledgling advertising agency, Ocean, in 1988, they had a problem.</p>
<p>&quot;There were rumours going about that some children had died after drinking Awa, that people had arrived at the hospital in a coma,&quot; remembers Ocean's founder, Martine Coffi-Studer.</p>
<p>She told the owners they had to use sealed bottles. &quot;Until you've done that, there's no point in advertising.&quot;</p>
<p>A sealing machine would cost too much, the company said.</p>
<p>But within a year, as sales plummeted, it finally took Ocean's advice, and Awa's distinctive blue and red label is now visible everywhere, from the road-side kiosks to the expanding supermarkets, sitting alongside the fancy French brands.</p>
<p>Last month, Ocean lost the Awa account when the company changed hands, but Coffi-Studer can afford to be relaxed.</p>
<p>She has just negotiated an alliance with Ogilvy &amp; Mather, part of WPP Group Plc, an international giant in the industry.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Ocean's big local rival, Panafcom, is getting into bed with another world leader, Young &amp; Rubicam.</p>
<p>Ogilvy is taking an initial 25 percent stake in Ocean, while Young &amp; Rubicam will move in stages by 2000 to a 50 percent stake in Panafcom, which has been in existence since 1970.</p>
<p>&quot;With economic growth, with the boom in Ivory Coast, Ogilvy felt the need to have a presence in West Africa in order, quite simply, to respond to the demands of its (international) clients,&quot; Coffi-Studer told Reuters.</p>
<p>SPECIFICS OF THE AFRICAN MARKET</p>
<p>Ocean was chosen, she said, because of its &quot;African sensibility, something an agency like Panafcom does not have&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The management of Ocean is 100 percent Ivorian, I00 percent African...We know the local culture well, consumer trends, the local environment,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Panafcom founder Pierre-Daniel Brechat -- &quot;I wasn't born in Ivory Coast but I've been here 30 years&quot; -- also feels strongly about the specificity of the African market, and agrees the majors needed local alliances to get the client's message over.</p>
<p>&quot;It's palpable, even at the level of the countries of West Africa. Publicity produced in Ivory Coast is immediately recognisable as different from something done in Senegal.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;When people think of Africa, they tend to think of events in 'sensitive' countries, Zaire, Liberia and so on. But there are countries that are stable and developing, like Ivory Coast, Burkina Faso, Mali, Senegal,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Those four are members of the Economic and Monetary Union of West Africa, which groups 62 million people in eight states.</p>
<p>&quot;That's 62 million people who eat, who wash, who brush their teeth,&quot; Brechat said.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe for consumer durables, it's a bit limited, a bit early, although all those people aspire to have a television, a refrigerator, a car,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Niche markets for big ticket goods already exist.</p>
<p>A Panafcom campaign for Nissan Patrol 4x4 cars has helped sell 600 to well-heeled Africans and expatriates in the past three years, at a hefty 25 million CFA francs ($43,000) each.</p>
<p>Brechat estimated the size of the advertising market in Ivory Coast at some 15 billion CFA francs ($26 million).</p>
<p>&quot;Ivory Coast represents a crucial investment for us, our first venture in West Africa,&quot; Miles Young of Ogilvy's executive committee said last month, calling the country its &quot;strategic base&quot; for the whole of francophone Africa -- some 20 countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Ivory Coast has all the characteristics that allow you to predict big growth in publicity. The economy is stable and solid, with a low rate of inflation and high growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government has forecast seven percent growth in 1997, while inflation is currently around 5.0 percent.</p>
<p>Its privatisation programme has provided a lucrative area of work for Ocean, which has spearheaded an information campaign for the Privatisation Committee and the World Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;We were asked to look after a global budget of almost $1 million, to support the privatisation campaign,&quot; Coffi-Studer said, noting that this involved seminars and open days at companies, as well as traditional media campaigns.</p>
<p>Panafcom has done government work -- a film aimed at foreign companies, &quot;Invest in Ivory Coast&quot;, for example -- but missed out on the privatisations.</p>
<p>Brechat makes light of this, but he complains that the tender process for the advertising work was &quot;unsatisfactory&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Ocean makes no secret of its privileged relationship with the authorities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ocean did the advertising for the 1995 election campaign of President Henri Konan Bedie, as well as that of his predecessor, independence leader Felix Houphouet-Boigny, in 1990.</p>
<p>Both agencies advertise cigarettes and have few worries about a U.S.-style crackdown on such ads.</p>
<p>Brechat reckons health authorities in Africa have more pressing work, such as improving infant mortality rates by tackling malaria, dysentery and other mass killers.</p>
<p>&quot;Let them grow up first before you tell them to stop smoking,&quot; he said. ($1 = 585 CFA francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
