<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756401" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya moves to avert clashes in port of Mombasa.</title>
<headline>Kenya moves to avert clashes in port of Mombasa.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>MOMBASA, Kenya 1996-07-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya's government has acted to avert political violence in the tourism-rich port of Mombasa by licensing an opposition-backed rally planned for Saturday.</p>
<p>The move greatly reduced the chances of a repeat in Mombasa of clashes elsewhere in Kenya in June and July between riot police and demonstrators demanding constitutional reforms to ensure free and fair elections later this year.</p>
<p>Mombasa is the centre of Kenya's coastal tourism industry, the East African country's main employer and its largest earner of foreign exchange. It is also Kenya's second city and its main port.</p>
<p>At least nine people were killed on July 7 in Nairobi and several other cities and towns in battles between police and demonstrators in Kenya's worst unrest for seven years.</p>
<p>Leading Kenyan dissident Sheikh Khalid Balala was issued a permit for Saturday's planned rally when he visited a local administrator to inform him of the plan and ask that security be provided.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very shocked that a license has been issued in my name. I did not make an application and this license should therefore not be considered lawful,&quot; Balala told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't understand why the license is in my name when the government says I am not Kenyan in the first place.&quot;</p>
<p>Opposition-backed groups who called the rally had said they would not apply for any permits for their rallies on the grounds that the law requiring them was unconstitutional.</p>
<p>Kenya allowed Balala to return home on July 12 from three years of forced exile in Germany after granting him a new passport and dropping its argument that he was not a Kenyan citizen.</p>
<p>Balala is an Islamic preacher in Mombasa and perhaps the most outspoken critic in Kenya of President Daniel arap Moi.</p>
<p>The permit from District Commissioner Peter Olando asked Balala to ensure that law and order was maintained on Saturday.</p>
<p>Olando said Balala visited him at his office on Friday to tell him about the rally but had not requested a licence. But based on their talks, Olando decided it should be licensed.</p>
<p>On Friday, Kenyan Finance Minister Musalia Mudavadi and Central Bank Governor Micah Cheserem said foreign exchange and equity markets had recovered from a heavy beating they took after the wave of violence and that investor confidence was returning.</p>
<p>Moi said on July 16 that permits for rallies would automatically be granted except in exceptional cases. But rally organisers still had to apply for the licenses in advance.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Moi ordered police not to beat up ordinary protesters at rallies and &quot;even the offending people should not be beaten if they break the law, they should be arrested&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We now expect a very peaceful rally. There will be plenty of anti-government rhetoric but without police interference, there is little room for clashes,&quot; said an opposition politician in Mombasa.</p>
<p>Diplomats said on Friday that 22 foreign embassies and high commissions in Kenya had urged Moi in a letter to pursue dialogue with the opposition to avoid more political violence.</p>
<p>The reforms demanded by the opposition would cut the power of Moi, 73 and in power for 19 years. No date is set for presidential and parliamentary elections this year.</p>
<p>The National Convention Executive Council (NCEC), the alliance of Kenyan opposition parties, civic groups and other bodies demanding constitutional changes, had hoped for a peaceful rally in Mombasa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOMBASA, Kenya"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
