<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756480" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: U.S. soldier's car bombed, Czechs assaulted.</title>
<headline>U.S. soldier's car bombed, Czechs assaulted.</headline>
<byline>Dan De Luce</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. soldier's car was damaged in a firebombing outside his apartment in the Serb-controlled Bosnian town of Vlasenica early on Friday, the NATO-led peace force said.</p>
<p>No one was injured in the incident, the latest in a series of Serb retaliatory attacks over a NATO swoop on indicted war criminals earlier this month.</p>
<p>A &quot;Molotov cocktail-type&quot; bomb hit the civilian vehicle used by an American military observer at 4:10 a.m. (0210 GMT), setting the car ablaze, NATO said in a statement issued from a U.S. base in Tuzla.</p>
<p>The attack occurred in Vlasenica, some 15 km (nine miles) from Bosnian Serb army headquarters in Han Pijesak.</p>
<p>In the northwest town of Prijedor, also in Serb territory, Czech soldiers guarding the offices of international agencies had to run for cover twice when a car drove straight at them, Western officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>European Union monitors said Czech soldiers called in reinforcements and an armoured personnel carrier on Thursday evening after a Mercedes nearly ran them over twice.</p>
<p>The Czechs were standing guard in front of the local offices of the United Nations, the EU and the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe.</p>
<p>After reinforcements arrived, the Czechs stopped the Mercedes and detained the driver and a passenger. Western officials said the driver was carrying a pistol and wearing a police uniform.</p>
<p>No one has been killed in the wave of revenge bombings which have followed a NATO raid two weeks ago in Prijedor against two Serbs indicted for war atrocities.</p>
<p>One suspect was seized and extradited to face trial before the U.N. war crimes tribunal for former Yugoslavia, based in The Hague. A second suspect was shot dead after he opened fire on British soldiers trying to arrest him.</p>
<p>Ultra-nationalists who opposed Bosnia's 1995 peace treaty and are loyal to former Bosnian Serb president and indicted war criminal Radovan Karadzic are orchestrating the low-level violence in an attempt to discourage further arrest operations.</p>
<p>The NATO raid, which employed sealed, or secret, indictments has sent shock waves through the Serb leadership and throughout Bosnia. Powerful warlords and their henchmen may fear punishment for their actions during the 1992-95 war.</p>
<p>Several senior Western envoys visited Bosnia this month to assess the aftermath of the NATO swoop, which marked the first such operation since alliance-led peace force deployed in December 1995 to solidify the treaty.</p>
<p>The United States and European allies have vowed not to shrink from a tougher stance towards indicted war criminals despite the recent Serb violence and threats.</p>
<p>The U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, Bill Richardson, warned Serb authorities during a visit to Bosnia this week that retaliatory violence would not be tolerated.</p>
<p>Another senior American diplomat, human rights envoy John Shattuck, was expected to convey a similar message during a visit Sarajevo on Saturday.</p>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel, who travelled to Sarajevo on Friday, refused to rule out more arrests and said &quot;the clock was ticking&quot; for indicted war criminals if authorities failed to hand them over soon.</p>
<p>British Foreign Secretary Robin Cook is due to visit Bosnia next week.</p>
<p>In a statement issued in London on Friday, Cook promised to deliver a blunt warning to Bosnia's fractious ethnic leaders about lack of progress in implementing the 1995 Dayton peace accords.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect some frank exchanges -- particularly on the need for reintegration within the Dayton framework, but also on war criminals, corruption and media freedom,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
