<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756530" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine's Kuchma reshuffles cabinet to push reform.</title>
<headline>Ukraine's Kuchma reshuffles cabinet to push reform.</headline>
<byline>Rostislav Khotin</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma, trying to speed up sluggish economic reforms, reshuffled his government on Friday following the appointment of a pragmatic new prime minister earlier this month.</p>
<p>Issuing a string of decrees, Kuchma replaced ministers in charge of key areas of reform including the economy, industry and energy portfolios. It was the biggest shake-up since the president came to power three years ago.</p>
<p>But some analysts expressed doubts that the personnel changes would really give a push to free-market reforms. Many ministers were re-appointed and at least three former ministers returned to the cabinet after periods out of office.</p>
<p>&quot;The government reshuffle, together with the appointment of a new prime minister, were the result of the president's desire to accelerate economic reforms,&quot; Kuchma's spokesman Petro Ostapenko told Reuters.</p>
<p>Viktor Suslov, who headed the parliamentary banking and finance committee, was appointed economy minister, replacing Yuri Yekhanurov.</p>
<p>&quot;Suslov's appointment will boost the economic sector of the government,&quot; Anatoly Halchinsky, Kuchma's top economic adviser, told Interfax-Ukraine news agency.</p>
<p>&quot;Suslov is committed to economic reforms.&quot;</p>
<p>Kuchma also appointed Yuri Karasyk to head the agriculture ministry, a post he has held before, replacing Mykhailo Zubets.</p>
<p>Yuri Bochkaryov was sacked from energy and Yuri Rusantsov from the coal ministry. They were replaced by Olexiy Sheberstov and Stanislav Yanko -- both of whom had held the posts before.</p>
<p>Valery Mazur was dropped from the industry ministry and Kuchma also set up a new Ministry for Industrial Policy and named ex-defence industry minister Vasyl Hureyev to head it.</p>
<p>But some observers remained sceptical that the shake-up heralded a real move forward to a free market.</p>
<p>&quot;Kuchma could sack every minister -- and be right. He can also appoint any new minister and be wrong. Thinking that only personalities can improve the situation is wrong,&quot; said Serhiy Naboka, a leading Kiev political commentator.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem lies not in personalities but in the whole government structure, in the structure of power in Ukraine. Decisions have been taken slowly, usually they are not carried out in the end, the bureaucrats, some of whom have been there since the 50s, simply block reforms,&quot; Naboka said.</p>
<p>Mikola Dyvak, editor of Agriculture Magazine, said new farm minister Karasyk was seen as a conservative during a previous term in the post from 1992 to 1995. Agriculture is a key sector for Ukraine, breadbasket of the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>More new appointments, along with details of the structure of the cabinet, would be given later on Friday, Ostapenko said.</p>
<p>Serhiy Tyhypko, deputy prime minister in charge of reforms, retained his post, he said, as did the defence, interior and finance ministers.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Valery Pustovoitenko was appointed on July 16 following the resignation of Pavlo Lazarenko. Under Ukraine's constitution, Kuchma is obliged to form a new cabinet following the appointment of a new head of government.</p>
<p>The previous government, which struggled to push reforms through parliament, leaves an economy which shrank 7.5 percent in the first half after a 10 percent drop last year.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) recently decided not to grant a $2.7-2.9 billion three-year credit to Ukraine, faulting Kiev's failure to make tax reforms. For the time being the IMF is considering an interim standby loan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
