<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756527" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian T-bill yields slip in cash-poor market.</title>
<headline>Russian T-bill yields slip in cash-poor market.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yields on Russian government securities edged down in quiet trade on Friday in a market deprived of cash from banks, which had coughed up big deposits for the prominent Svyazinvest telecoms company auction.</p>
<p>Overnight credits, under strong upside pressure for several days, dropped as funds rolled in from the government securities market, dealers said.</p>
<p>*Average yield fell to 17.9 pct from 18.2 pct on Thursday</p>
<p>*Turnover fell to 3.35 trln roubles from 3.93 trln</p>
<p>*Central bank sold 79.0 bln roubles of T-bills</p>
<p>				  July 25		    July 24</p>
<p>    rouble/dollar	   midday	morning    close</p>
<p>    today settlement	5,801-02    5,801-02   5,791-93</p>
<p>    tomorrow settlement   5,799-800   5,800-01   5,899-00</p>
<p>    overnight credits (%)     4-8	   2-7	  8-13</p>
<p>According to the terms of the Svyazinvest auction, bidders had to deposit $400 million to participate. Losers will receive their money back within three banking days.</p>
<p>&quot;It is obvious that most people (bidders) deposited the funds in hard currency, and the money will not go to the forex market,&quot; said ING Bank dealer Alexander Lomakin.</p>
<p>&quot;It is logical to suppose that it will be sold for roubles to be channelled into T-bills, while some of the hard currency will be used to buy MinFin bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>Russian officials said on Friday Cyprus-registered group Mustcom, set up by Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, Russian investment bank Renaissance Capital and others, won the Svyazinvest stake for $1.875 billion.</p>
<p>Overnight credits fell sharply as fresh funds from the T-bill market returned to the market. The rouble slipped until it hit a resistance level of 5,802 per dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;Overnight roubles were practically free today, that is why roubles with today and tomorrow settlements opened at the same level,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;Later, people started buying the dollar, but at 5,802, level sellers appeared.&quot;</p>
<p>--Anna Smirnova, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
