<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756644" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks gains wiped out by Cemex upset.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks gains wiped out by Cemex upset.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks closed sharply lower on Friday, wiping out early gains after market heavyweight Cemex reported disappointing earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's case was clear, Telmex moved the market along with hopes for Cemex...then Cemex's earnings were not well received,&quot; said Diego Candano, research director at the Ixe brokerage.</p>
<p>The leading IPC share index ended down 40.23 points, or 0.85 percent, at 4,722.42, after reaching as high as 4,832.14 earlier.</p>
<p>On the broad market, sliders outnumbered gainers by 55 to 45 out of 116 stocks that traded, on moderate volume of 91.0 million shares.</p>
<p>Cement maker Cemex CPO shares reversed an early advance of 35 centavos (4.5 cents) to drop 1.55 pesos (20 cents) at the close to 37.80 pesos ($4.85).</p>
<p>Cemex posted a first-half earnings during the session that were down from year-ago figures in net and operating terms.</p>
<p>Telefonos de Mexico (Telmex) meanwhile cut back an early advance of 50 centavos (6 cents) to just 5 centavos (less than one cent), ending at 20.25 pesos ($2.60).</p>
<p>Candamo said the Mexican bourse would remain volatile during the earnings season.</p>
<p>&quot;It tends to open up on favourable reaction to earnings posted the night before...and then profit-taking following those gains,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For Geoffrey Dennis, emerging markets strategist at HSBC-James Capel, initial reaction to earnings had made for a rough ride, but not for any lasting fundamental setback.</p>
<p>&quot;The real issue at the moment is second-quarter earnings...and it is a mixed picture. They have been a touch disappointing in places,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nonetheless, there is a sense the economy is improving at the margin and that earnings momentum is picking up. So if there is weakness, I think investors will be prepared to buy on it,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
