<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756700" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: U.S. committed to Peru, Ecuador border mission.</title>
<headline>U.S. committed to Peru, Ecuador border mission.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States remains committed to its role as observer of a border peace mission between Peru and Ecuador, despite deciding to withdraw logistical support for the endeavour, top U.S. officer Gen. John Shalikashvili said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States is still participating in the mission and has no plans to terminate our mission,&quot; Shalikashvili, chairman of the U.S. Joint Chiefs of Staff, told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a prudent investment in peace and the absence of war,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Washington announced last year that it would withdraw logistical support, including helicopters and communications equipment from the mission overseeing the disputed border where the two Andean nations fought a brief war in 1995.</p>
<p>Ecuadorean officials have said the United States' role will be taken by Brazil.</p>
<p>The mission involves observers from the United States, Chile, Argentina and Brazil -- the four countries which guaranteed a 1942 agreement to settle the jungle border.</p>
<p>Shalikashvili was speaking during a two-day visit to Chile during which he held talks with acting Defence Minister Jose Miguel Insulza and Chilean armed forces chiefs.</p>
<p>His visit to Santiago was the last leg of the four-nation Latin American tour which included stops in Mexico, Brazil and Argentina.</p>
<p>While military relations with Latin America have improved in recent years, the United States has still not decided whether to lift a 20-year virtual ban on selling sophisticated military weapons to the region, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. government has decided to review the issue of conventional arms sales to see whether its policy up to now is still valid or requires adjustment. (But) the review has not concluded one way or the other,&quot; said Shalikashvili.</p>
<p>In April, President Bill Clinton authorised U.S. aircraft manufacturers to bid to sell jets to the Chilean air force, which is interested in buying Lockheed F-16 Falcon fighters as part of a plan to modernise the country's ageing air fleet.</p>
<p>The Carter administration imposed the ban on weapons sales to Latin America in 1977 when must of the region was under military rule.</p>
<p>But the return of democracy to most countries in Latin America has led to pressure from companies and governments on Clinton to lift the restrictions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
