<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756812" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Kiwi dollar ends turbulent week in good spirits.</title>
<headline>Kiwi dollar ends turbulent week in good spirits.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand dollar closed a turbulent week firmer and in reasonable spirits, despite drifting off from its intra-session highs.</p>
<p>Dealers expected further volatility from the currency, but said its recovery from a low on Tuesday of US$0.6450 to its close on Friday at 0.6546/53, up from 0.6538/45 at the open, had improved general sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;The kiwi's very volatile at the moment. We've had some big ranges -- it's up and down like a yo-yo,&quot; said a bank chief dealer.  </p>
<p>&quot;But I think overall it looks okay at the moment, particularly with no rate cut in Australia today and the Aussie holding here nicely above US$0.7390.</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect that the kiwi will remain volatile again tonight, but I think the downside should be limited to around 0.6525, with a move closer towards 0.6575 in the offing.&quot;</p>
<p>The New Zealand currency traded as high as 0.6565 this session but eased off towards the close.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the local trading market was probably a little long looking for a retry of the overnight highs and they just got filled in and it's drifted off,&quot; said the chief dealer at another bank.</p>
<p>&quot;But the volumes have been quite light. I would suggest that the general feeling is probably a little more upbeat, a bit more positive, given that kiwi's managed to recover nicely from its lows and really is closing pretty well bid,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the longer term trend, which has seen the kiwi fall from above 67.7 U.S. cents in a month, was still in place.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're just marking time and consolidating, because we saw some pretty considerable losses over a very short period of time,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;I think overall the trend still remains down.&quot;</p>
<p>The Trade-Weighted Index closed unchanged at 65.07.</p>
<p>--Matthew Brockett, Wellington Newsroom +64 4 4714 272</p>
<p>e-mail wellington.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
