<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75687" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Oct spot gas prices edge up, bidweek winds down.</title>
<headline>US Oct spot gas prices edge up, bidweek winds down.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot natural gas prices for October edged up Wednesday as bidweek drew to a close, with Gulf indices likely to come in about five cents over September levels, industry sources said.</p>
<p>But most agreed price direction next month will depend on weather, with values likely to soften as storage injections taper unless early heating load kicks in to pick up the slack.</p>
<p>&quot;Cash was up early, but next month, it all depends on the weather,&quot; said a cash trader, noting October Gulf Coast gas was talked in the low-to-mid $1.80s/mmBtu, up slightly on the day and more than five cents over September indices.  </p>
<p>September gas at the Gulf was up slightly to the high-$1.80s, more than 10 cents over Sept 1 levels.</p>
<p>October Midcon gas was talked in the low-to-mid $1.70s, up a couple of cents from Tuesday and almost 10 cents over Sept indices.</p>
<p>In west Texas, October gas on El Paso Permian was quoted in the mid-to-high $1.60s, up slightly on the day.</p>
<p>South Texas gas for October delivery edged up to the mid-to-high $1.70s, up a penny Wednesday and steady to slightly over index.</p>
<p>October New York city gate gas also firmed a couple of cents to the $2.07-2.10 area.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
