<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756884" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: ASEAN says good progress on regional free trade.</title>
<headline>ASEAN says good progress on regional free trade.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southeast Asian nations said on Friday there was good progress towards a free trade area that they expect to boost trade and investment among nearly 500 million people in the region.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministers of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) ended a two-day annual meeting expressing satisfaction at progress mid-way through a 10-year period in which most tariffs are being slashed to between zero and five percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We are at a point where we might be able to achieve the goals of AFTA (the ASEAN Free Trade Area) by the year 2000 instead of the year 2003,&quot; ASEAN Secretary-General Ajit Singh told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said that by 2000, more than 87 percent of tariff lines would have zero-to-five percent tariff rates.</p>
<p>&quot;That is no mean achievement for an organisation like AFTA,&quot; Singh said, adding that he counted it as one of the major achievements of his five-year tenure in office, which ends on December 31.</p>
<p>A communique at the end of the foreign ministerial meeting noted that the average tariff rates for products included in a common effective preferential tariff (CEPT) scheme had dropped to 6.38 percent from 12.76 percent in 1993.</p>
<p>Singh had told a pre-meeting news conference in Jakarta that intra-ASEAN exports of all products in the January-September period of 1996 had reached $56.1 billion, a 10-percent increase over the same 1995 period.</p>
<p>The communique said the ministers had &quot;emphasised the need to eliminate non-tariff barriers in ASEAN and noted the achievements in this area&quot;. These included removal of all customs surcharges at the end of 1996 and prioritisation of 20 product groups for harmonisation of standards.</p>
<p>The ministers reiterated their commitment to &quot;open regionalism and a rule-based multilateral trading system&quot;, the communique said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
