<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756993" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Burma forgotten man at ASEAN meeting.</title>
<headline>Burma forgotten man at ASEAN meeting.</headline>
<byline>Bill Tarrant</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burma has become the forgotten man at ASEAN's annual meeting now that the international spotlight has swung to Cambodia.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, Burma's sort of off the screen,&quot; said one U.S. diplomat who is helping President Bill Clinton's special envoy for Cambodia, Stephen Solarz, with his separate mediation effort in Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>Burma was admitted along with Laos as the eighth and ninth members of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) at a special ceremony on Wednesday before a glittering assembly of Malaysia's diplomatic community.</p>
<p>Notable in his absence was British High Commissioner David Moss, who boycotted the ceremony.</p>
<p>&quot;Bearing in mind the current state of relations between the United Kingdom and Burma, we considered it would send a misleading signal to have the high commissioner (ambassador) attend this ceremony,&quot; a British High Commission spokesman said on Friday.</p>
<p>Cambodian strongman Hun Sen's bloody putsch against First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh earlier this month forced ASEAN to postpone the country's admission.</p>
<p>Much of the discussion in the ASEAN meetings and on the sidelines has concerned efforts to mediate in the conflict.</p>
<p>But Burma will become a major talking point at the ASEAN Regional Forum, which brings the ASEAN foreign ministers together with 11 other Western and Asian powers for talks on Asian political and security issues on Sunday.</p>
<p>ASEAN Secretary-General Ajit Singh said on Friday problems had arisen with the European Union and the United States following Burma's admittance.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some technicalities we need to look at,&quot; he said, referring to a cooperation agreement between the ASEAN and the EU and whether it would be extended to Burma.</p>
<p>Western nations had lobbied hard against Burma's admission saying it should be isolated over its human rights record and crackdown on a pro-democracy movement led by Nobel peace laureate Aung San Suu Kyi.</p>
<p>But ASEAN contends that Burma, which shares borders with India, China and fellow ASEAN member Thailand, is strategically too important to isolate and is worried about Beijing's influence -- China is Burma's biggest arms supplier.</p>
<p>ASEAN -- which now groups Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, Vietnam, Brunei, Burma and Laos -- insists its policy of &quot;constructive engagement&quot; can reform Burma's military government from within the family.</p>
<p>Malaysian Foreign Minister Abdullah Badawi referred to that in his speech welcoming the two new members this week.</p>
<p>&quot;At times it may be necessary for ASEAN member countries to be a mirror for each other. Gentle reminders from fellow ASEAN brothers should be accepted in the spirit of maintaining the unity and credibility of ASEAN,&quot; Abdullah said.</p>
<p>But his gentle reminder to Burma's ruling generals during a visit to Rangoon last month to start a dialogue with Suu Kyi was firmly rejected.</p>
<p>Burmese Foreign Minister Ohn Gyaw made no mention of working with Suu Kyi's National League for Democracy, which won a 1990 general election later nullified by the military.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of us in the region of Southeast Asia are nations who all possess a chequered past of colonial legacies, with similar experiences in our nation-building endeavours,&quot; Ohn Gyaw said.</p>
<p>ASEAN said it was also reluctant to put pressure on its neighbours because that would contravene a cardinal principle of the group -- to avoid interference in the internal affairs of other members.</p>
<p>That policy, formed in 1967 when Southeast Asia was a cauldron of cross-border insurgencies and deep ideological divisions, was seen as a cornerstone of the group's thinking.</p>
<p>It also recognised the vast differences in types of governments in the region, which now range from a military dictatorship in Burma, to communist Vietnam and Laos, an absolute monarchy in Brunei and various kinds of democracies in the other members.</p>
<p>That policy has come under renewed scrutiny as ASEAN heads into the next millennium.</p>
<p>Malaysia's Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim has called on ASEAN to practise &quot;constructive intervention&quot;, citing Cambodia and Burma as examples.</p>
<p>Burma's admission capped a three-decade effort by ASEAN to get Rangoon into the group. Burma in the 1970s was so isolationist it walked out of the Non-Aligned Movement and twice refused ASEAN invitations to join the group.</p>
<p>ASEAN feared if it did not admit Burma now, Rangoon could travel down a new isolationist road and fall further into China's sphere of influence, diplomats said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
