<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="756955" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore to raise retirement age.</title>
<headline>Singapore to raise retirement age.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore will raise the retirement age to 62 in 1999 to boost its declining workforce and spur economic growth, Labour Minister Lee Boon Yang said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;With increasing life expectancy and declining birth rates, our population is ageing rapidly,&quot; Lee told parliament.</p>
<p>He said the extension of working life beyond the current 60 is was in line with the government's long term aim of raising the retirement age to 67.</p>
<p>He said the move was one of seven recommendations made by a committee comprising government officials, employers and trade unions.</p>
<p>The committee also proposed that further extension of the retirement age should depend on prevailing economic conditions and the experience gained from the latest move.</p>
<p>He said it now took eight economically active people to support one person over the age of 60 and if the retirement age were not increased, then by 2010 it would take four and by 2030 it would take 2.5.</p>
<p>&quot;This trend would result in fewer people at work to drive the economy and generate growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;A rapidly ageing population will not only adversely affect our economic competitiveness but will also have serious social repercussions.&quot;</p>
<p>The government first increased the mandatory retirement age in 1993 to 60 from 55 years.</p>
<p>Lee said the government will allow employers to cut costs by giving them the discretion to reduce wages by up to 10 percent for people over 60.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
