<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75717" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Heating oil price on political agenda in NE states. [CORRECTED 22:40 GMT]</title>
<headline>Heating oil price on political agenda in NE states. [CORRECTED 22:40 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Patrick Connole</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Politicians in the Northeast corridor of the United States have pushed heating oil prices onto the election-year agenda amid worries that a stocks shortage may spike home heating costs this winter.</p>
<p>U.S. gas marketers met Wednesday in Washington on the heating oil situation. President Bill Clinton was expected to weigh in on the issue this weekend when he campaigns throughout New England. (Corrects to show that the meeting was held by gas marketers and was not a congressional hearing)</p>
<p>Industry and government data this week showed stocks of distillates -- heating and diesel oil -- running some 30 pct below 1995 levels in the northeast U.S., the largest market in the world for heating oil. Overall, U.S. inventories are 15 pct below five-year averages for this time of year.</p>
<p>If cold weather dominates this winter, economic models predict distillate consumers could pay 20 cents per gallon more at the retail level, translating to a hit of $200 to the average user this winter.  </p>
<p>Last week, a group of 41 senators and congressmen from Northeastern and Midwestern states asked Energy Secretary Hazel O'Leary whether Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) crude could be sold to raise money to buy heating oil for future sales. But the Energy Department said it didn't want to interfere in the market.</p>
<p>Consumer activist groups are also calling for government action, noting the elderly and poor families would be hit hardest by price increases for heating fuel.  </p>
<p>A study released Wednesday by New York Attorney General Dennis Vacco on last spring's energy price jolts, called for federal investigations of potential &quot;collusion&quot; by national suppliers and wholesalers despite finding no price gouging by retailers during the time period studied.</p>
<p>Vacco's report said &quot;just-in-time&quot; inventory practices, cold temperatures and international political tensions resulted in the higher prices. The report also urged that federal minimum inventory standards should be studied, exploring state-directed futures purchases for home heating oil and encouraging conservation.  </p>
<p>Oil marketers came out last week against any government interference in the distillate markets. Officials from the Petroleum Marketers Association of America, who were to speak to the Congressional panel on Wednesday, said government purchases of heating oil would have the opposite effect intended and might exacerbate price hikes.</p>
<p>Heating oil prices already have soared in the past three months, with New York futures prices rising some 40 pct to 70 cents a gallon. But though a regional political hot potato, economists say the soaring heating costs will not be a factor in national inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;Heating oil has a relatively small weight in the Consumer Price Index, and of course the impact on consumers varies, since heat and diesel are used primarily in the Northeast,&quot; said Peter Jaquette, senior economist at the WEFA Group in Philadephia.</p>
<p>Latest statistics collected in 1993 showed only 10.2 million U.S. households using heating oil as their main source of heat, out of a total 96.9 million households, according to Energy Information Administration spokesman Tom Welch.</p>
<p>Natural gas and electricity combined for more than 75 million households in comparison, Welch noted.</p>
<p>--New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1828</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
