<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757159" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: ASEAN can only help stop interference, Hun Sen say.</title>
<headline>ASEAN can only help stop interference, Hun Sen say.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodian strongman Hun Sen said on Friday the only role ASEAN could play in his country's crisis was to prevent foreign interference and said his comments about mediation had been misinterpreted.</p>
<p>In a statement issued by his office ahead of a meeting with U.S. special envoy Stephen Solarz, Hun Sen reiterated earlier demands that the international community not involve itself in Cambodian affairs.</p>
<p>&quot;The internal problems of Cambodia must be solved by Cambodia itself in accordance with the principles of the Constitution and on the basis of the achievements of the Paris Peace Accords and the general election of 1993,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cambodia welcomes the role of ASEAN in contributing to stability and peace in Cambodia on the basis of respect for national independence and sovereignty through preventing the foreign interference into the internal affairs of Cambodia,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The 1991 Paris treaty officially ended the Cambodian war and paved the way for U.N.-supervised elections in 1993 which Prince Norodom Ranariddh and his royalist party won.</p>
<p>Ranariddh subsequently agreed to a power-sharing coalition with Hun Sen. Hun Sen overthrew Ranariddh on July 6 after two days of fighting in Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>Hun Sen said reports that he had changed his mind about refusing ASEAN's mediation efforts were a misinterpretation and insisted Cambodia must solve its own internal problems.</p>
<p>ASEAN groups Brunei, the Philippines, Burma, Vietnam, Thailand, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia and Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;A number of newspapers have misinterpreted statements made by... Hun Sen... on the role of ASEAN regarding the stability and peace in Cambodia... causing a misunderstanding among national and international public opinion,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The international community should allow Cambodia to solve its own affairs by itself and should not do anything as encouragement to cause a new war in Cambodia through providing weapons, ammunition, shelter etc to the opposition,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Ranariddh has called for resistance to Hun Sen and his forces have been fighting Hun Sen's troops in Cambodia's far north.</p>
<p>Solarz, who arrived in Phnom Penh on Thursday, did not talk to reporters as he arrived at the Council Of Ministers for talks with Hun Sen on Friday morning.</p>
<p>Solarz, on a whirlwind tour of Asian capitals seeking a solution to the turmoil in Cambodia, said earlier the United States hoped to work closely with ASEAN to try end the problem.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
