<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757265" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Jerusalem plan &quot;declaration of war&quot; - Palestinians.</title>
<headline>Jerusalem plan &quot;declaration of war&quot; - Palestinians.</headline>
<byline>Howard Goller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinians on Friday condemned an Israeli decision to build a Jewish settler enclave in the heart of Arab East Jerusalem as a &quot;declaration of war&quot;.</p>
<p>News of the decision by the Jerusalem municipality emerged late on Thursday, prompting Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to rush out a statement vowing to prevent the plan from going ahead now.</p>
<p>Israel's peace talks with Yasser Arafat's Palestine Liberation Organisation have been in crisis since March when Netanyahu broke ground on a Jewish settlement on a hilltop at the edge of Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Israel Television said the decision on Thursday granted a permit to Irving Moskowitz, a U.S. Jewish businessman who bankrolls Jewish settlement in occupied areas, to build for Jews in the 11,000-strong Arab neighbourhood of Ras al-Amoud.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a known declaration of war on the Palestinians in East Jerusalem, on the Palestinians in general, and a complete disregard of the spirit of the signed agreement,&quot; Arafat's adviser Ahmed Tibi told Israeli army radio.</p>
<p>Saeb Erekat, Arafat's senior negotiator, said the Palestinian Authority had protested to Netanyahu's office insisting that the plan be scrapped.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made great efforts to try to put the peace process back on track but Israel is insisting on destroying the peace process,&quot; Erekat told Reuters in Gaza.</p>
<p>Yossi Sarid, head of the leftist Meretz party in Israel's parliament, gave warning of a burst of violence over the project.</p>
<p>He likened the decision to Netanyahu's opening of a tourist tunnel entrance near Moslem holy sites in Jerusalem last September which sparked clashes and gun battles that took the lives of 61 Palestinians and 15 Israeli soldiers.</p>
<p>&quot;I am really certain that the building in Ras al-Amoud is the match that will light the great fire in the territories, a great fire that will burn lives of both Jews and Arabs,&quot; Sarid, a former peace negotiator, told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>Israel's Jerusalem municipal planning commission gave conditional approval last December to a plan for 132 settler homes in Ras al-Amoud. The plan required the approval of Interior Minister Eli Suissa but was later shelved.</p>
<p>Jerusalem Mayor Ehud Olmert said the plan approved on Thursday was for a scaled-down project on the same land east of Jerusalem's walled Old City. Israel Television said this apparently did not require ministerial approval.</p>
<p>&quot;We are fighting over Jerusalem here and one can imagine there are elements who don't like that,&quot; Olmert said.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's office voiced surprise at the decision.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister heard late at night from the mayor of Jerusalem on the decision taken on the issue...the prime minister is working to prevent implementation of the plan,&quot; his office said in a hastily prepared statement.</p>
<p>In a later statement, Netanyahu's office said the prime minister opposed the start of construction &quot;now&quot;, suggesting the timing was his biggest problem.</p>
<p>Miami-based Moskowitz is said to own the 3.5 acre (1.4 hectare) plot in Ras al-Amoud neighbourhood. The claim is disputed by Palestinian officials.</p>
<p>The status of East Jerusalem is one of the most volatile issues dividing Israelis and Palestinians. The PLO wants East Jerusalem as capital of a future Palestinian state.</p>
<p>Israel, which occupied East Jerusalem in the 1967 Middle East War, says both sides of the city form its &quot;united and eternal&quot; capital.</p>
<p>Palestinians say Israeli moves in East Jerusalem are aimed at pre-empting peace talks on the city's fate. There are now some 160,000 Jews in East Jerusalem and 155,000 Palestinians.</p>
<p>Olmert said he doubted Moskowitz would go ahead soon with the plan as approved because the American would fight to carry out the larger project.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
