<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757298" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt state re-offers investors three BOT airports.</title>
<headline>Egypt state re-offers investors three BOT airports.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Egyptian state re-offered private investors three airports under a build, operate and transfer (BOT) agreement as part of its privatisation-led economic reform programme.</p>
<p>In a published advertisement on Friday, the official Civil Aviation Authority said the airports were at the Bahariya and Farafra oases in the Western Desert and at El Alamein, site of a historic World War Two battle on the Mediterranean coast.</p>
<p>It said investors could buy the prospectus until the end of July and that it would open all bids on December 30, 1997.</p>
<p>The state offered investors the Alamein airport earlier this year and the deadline for bids was January 31.</p>
<p>The state had also set a May deadline for investors to bid for the Bahariya and Farafra airports as well as for three others, but lack of interest prompted the state to build two of the airports, at Dakhla and East Oweinat oases.</p>
<p>The status of the third airport project, at the Red Sea resort of Dahab, is not known.</p>
<p>The state is currently negotiating another BOT airport at Marsa Alam on the Red Sea with Kuwaiti firm Mohamed Abdulmuhsin Kharafi and Sons. Egypt has also offered private investors BOT roads and is considering drafting private investors to set up power stations under the same formula.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +202 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
