<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757244" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - July 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - July 25.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Manila newspapers on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- Vice President Joseph Estrada still leads among 10 other presidential aspirants, but his rating has leveled off, while those of Senators Miriam Defensor-Santiago and Raul Roco and Defense Secretary Renato de Villa keep rising. (PHILIPPINE DAILY INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- Members of the Integrated Bar of the Philippines and the Philippine Judges Association are considering a nationwide boycott of court sessions if the government fails to address their concern over the killing and abduction of judges and lawyers. (MANILA TIMES)</p>
<p>- Andrew Cunanan's run from the law ends when he kills himself in a houseboat on Indian Creek, a few miles from fashion designer Gianni Versace's mansion in South Beach. (ALL PAPERS)</p>
<p>- Two senators, formerly with the opposition party, have decided to join the administration party. (MANILA BULLETIN)</p>
<p>				 +++++++++</p>
<p>BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>- The central bank says it is comfortable with the present 28 pesos to $1 trading range prevailing at the Philippine Dealing System (BUSINESS DAILY)</p>
<p>- Banker and takeover specialist Edgardo Espiritu has bought a minority stake in oil and mining exploration firm Alcorn Petroleum and Minerals Corp. He has taken two seats on the company's seven-man board. (MANILA TIMES)</p>
<p>- Monetary authorities order banks to get clearance before they can enter into options to buy or sell dollars from non-resident clients (MANILA BULLETIN)</p>
<p>- The central bank is expected to keep its interest rates high in the near term as the foreign exchange market has yet to return to normal trading condition. (BUSINESSWORLD)</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8938</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
