<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757414" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. weekly cash lumber review - July 25.</title>
<headline>U.S. weekly cash lumber review - July 25.</headline>
<text>
<p>Random Lengths Gross List Cash Lumber Prices Quotes:</p>
<p>  (2x4 Std&amp;Btr)	     WEEKLY   MIDWEEK  PREV WK  YR AGO</p>
<p> Inland Hem-Fir		405	410	415	---</p>
<p> Southern Pine Westside    468	468	468	---</p>
<p> Western Spruce-Pine-Fir   346	352	355	---</p>
<p> Framing Lumber Composite  428	---	430	407</p>
<p>COMMENT - The downward drift in lumber prices continued, with Random Lengths Composite off $6 over the past four weeks. Southern Pine's upward course flattened, raising fears that a correction may be in the cards, Random Lengths said in its endweek review.  </p>
<p>Buyers and sellers agreed that wood was moving fine through the system, but that high output was generating more product than the market could absorb, the agency said.</p>
<p>Some traders reiterated the belief that slow offshore markets were contributing to the abundance of offerings. S-P-F traders worried that the full effect of Canadian mills returning from summer shutdowns had not been felt.</p>
<p>Many office wholesalers said they liked the market's pace, since they were able to counter at will to secure profits, yet move a fair volume of wood. Others countered that ready availability of stock has squeezed margins.  </p>
<p>Some said they anticipated a round of end-of-the month discounting next week. Those secondaries who owned wood concentrated on reducing inventories in case prices softened. A number turned bearish, shorting items they felt were out of line with competing product, Random Lengths said. Distributors stayed with their strategy of replacing one-for-one on the assumption that quick wood would remain available.</p>
<p>Labor negotiations in B.C. receded into the background. The quota system on Canadian lumber shipments to the U.S. was rarely mentioned, with buyers assuming that Canadian mills had worked around the barrier through various means.</p>
<p>Railcar shortages remained a problem across the U.S., but especially in the West. Hurricane Danny dumped rain in coastal areas of the mid-South early in the week, disrupting both production and consumption. Rain also dampened jobsite activity in the upper Midwest, the agency said.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
