<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757436" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: No appeal of lawyer dismissal in baby death case.</title>
<headline>No appeal of lawyer dismissal in baby death case.</headline>
<dateline>WILMINGTON, Del. 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Delaware Supreme Court late on Friday refused to consider an appeal of a lower court's decision dismissing the lawyer of a New Jersey teenager charged with the murder of her newborn son.</p>
<p>Amy Grossberg and her boyfriend Brian Peterson were charged with murdering their infant son last year and leaving the body in a motel dumpster near the University of Delaware.</p>
<p>Last month Judge Henry duPont Ridgely, of the Delaware Superior Court, removed Grossberg's attorney Robert Gottlieb from the case because his &quot;orchestration&quot; of Grossberg's interview with Barbara Walters on ABC's &quot;20/20&quot; show in May allegedly violated a court-imposed gag order.</p>
<p>In papers signed by chief justice Norman Veasey for the three-judge panel that considered the appeal request, the court said &quot;we have no jurisdiction to hear an interlocutory appeal in a criminal case.&quot;</p>
<p>The court added that &quot;the action of the trial court of which Mr. Gottlieb complains may be reviewable after the underlying criminal case has come to final judgment.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILMINGTON, Del."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
