<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757450" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NATO chief meets U.S. defense secretary Cohen.</title>
<headline>NATO chief meets U.S. defense secretary Cohen.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen held talks with NATO chief Javier Solana on Friday to work out preparations to expand the military alliance to former Cold War foes.</p>
<p>Cohen said before the meeting it was important that new members make a military contribution to the alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;NATO is, after all, firstly a military alliance and they must be able to make a military contribution to the alliance if they want to join,&quot; Cohen said.</p>
<p>NATO members agreed at a summit in Madrid on July 8 to allow Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic to join NATO, which currently has 16 member nations. The new members are expected to join in April 1999.</p>
<p>Cohen said a key step in the expansion plans would be talks this fall with the three countries on their obligations to achieve full membership.</p>
<p>During his four-day visit to the United States, Solana has worked hard to sell the merits of NATO expansion to lawmakers and the American public.</p>
<p>Earlier, Solana met an influential group of U.S. senators to win support for NATO's expansion plans. The expansion has to be ratified by the parliaments of all the current members.</p>
<p>There has been some opposition by lawmakers in the United States to expanding NATO, partly because of the costs of bringing in new members and because they fear U.S. troops may one day have to fight in Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>A NATO spokesman told Reuters that Solana had a fruitful meeting with the 28-member Senate NATO Observer Group.</p>
<p>&quot;The Secretary-General made it clear that in the view of the alliance the costs are manageable,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a need for modest increases but these are affordable, particularly when set against the political gains that enlargement will bring,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Cohen said his meeting with Solana would also cover recent developments in Bosnia. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>He reiterated the U.S. position that indicted war criminals would be arrested only when they entered the &quot;field of operation&quot; of international forces.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been no change in policy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Solana gave his personal commitment that indicted war criminals would face an international tribunal before the international community left the area.</p>
<p>He stressed, however, that arrests of indicted war criminals would be made by international forces in Bosnia only when tactically possible.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
