<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757541" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - T-bond vols climb ahead of busy week.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - T-bond vols climb ahead of busy week.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatility for September U.S. Treasury bond futures rose Friday as traders' focus turned to next week's heavy data lineup.</p>
<p>One options trader said volatility was attracting a bid before Tuesday's second-quarter employment cost index report.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't think why else we'd be up on a Friday when we haven't moved,&quot; the trader said in the afternoon, when the underlying futures were languishing at slightly lower levels.</p>
<p>Typically, traders discount volatility on Friday afternoon to allow for weekend time decay.  </p>
<p>However, the market is gearing up for a big week ahead. Also on the agenda are June new home sales Wednesday, second-quarter advance gross domestic product Thursday and July employment Friday.</p>
<p>Another trader said futures' late slide, back toward session lows at the close, may have contributed to the volatility uptick.</p>
<p>September bond volatility ended the session at 8.07 percent, up from 7.88 percent on the opening and from the previous settlement of 7.68 percent, according to one desk.</p>
<p>The futures contract ended at 115-01/32, down 9/32.  </p>
<p>Some sizable transactions were noted in the 114-00 puts. Early in the session, a dealer firm sold 2,000 of the puts covered against futures at 115-06. The dealer also sold 4,000 of the 114-00 puts and bought 2,000 of the 115-00 puts in a spread.</p>
<p>A second dealer bought 2,500 of the 114-00 puts, and a local house bought 1,000.</p>
<p>In general, out-of-the-money put premiums have been depressed by an imbalance of sellers due to the current rally in futures, the first trader said.  </p>
<p>At the short end of the curve, Eurodollar volatilities were flat to a touch firmer, with December pegged at 9.0 percent and March at 11.0 percent.</p>
<p>A Eurodollar options broker said good put buying interest continued for a second day.</p>
<p>He added the session's highlight was a trading firm's sale of 3,000 December 1998 straddles in the 93.75 strike around midday.</p>
<p>((Susan Kelly, Chicago Derivatives Desk (312) 408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
