<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757501" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Deaf Mexicans found as slaves in N.C..</title>
<headline>Deaf Mexicans found as slaves in N.C..</headline>
<byline>Knight Chamberlain</byline>
<dateline>SANFORD, N.C. 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Immigration and Naturalisation Service agents on Friday took into custody 16 Mexican immigrants, most of them deaf, who were held in servitude in North Carolina.</p>
<p>&quot;We executed two search warrants at two residences in Sanford, North Carolina. Taken into custody were 14 adult deaf-mutes from Mexico, two juveniles and one small U.S. citizen child,&quot; said Russ Parry, an INS supervisory special agent from Atlanta, who came to Sanford for the raid.</p>
<p>The raid came just a few days after the discovery that 60 deaf Mexicans were being held captive and treated as slaves in New York City. Parry said the North Carolina raid stemmed from information the INS obtained while investigating the New York case.</p>
<p>No charges had been filed, but Parry said one man taken into custody was believed to be one of the bosses of the operation. He said he expected that more Mexicans were being held in similar circumstances elsewhere in Sanford.</p>
<p>&quot;It's our understanding the modus operandi here is there was more than two residences in this Sanford, North Carolina area. And further information will continue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Parry also said the INS believed that Sanford was the centre for the group's operations through North Carolina, with immigrants living in the city branching out to peddle trinkets assembled in Sanford throughout the state.</p>
<p>In a scheme similar to that involving the Mexicans in New York, the Mexicans in North Carolina were believed to have been smuggled from their homeland. Once in the United States, they travelled around the state, using trinkets such as key rings and flag stickers, to beg for one- or two-dollar donations.</p>
<p>But at the end of each day, their earnings were taken from them by the bosses who ran their houses.</p>
<p>After the raid Friday morning INS agents took the 17 to a field office in Charlotte, North Carolina, where they were to be held at a hotel.</p>
<p>He said INS would interview the group and determine their immigration status. &quot;Over the course of the next two to three days, they will be interviewed as far as how they entered the United States and their bondage here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In New York, seven people have been arrested, including four members of one family. They are charged with conspiracy to transport and conceal illegal aliens. Authorities are still seeking the alleged ringleader, identified as Reinaldo Paoletti.</p>
<p>Authorities believe the ringleaders recruited their victims from homes and schools for the deaf and mute in Mexico, promising them a better life in the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANFORD, N.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
