<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757509" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Asian, Latam crudes take center stage in US Gulf.</title>
<headline>Asian, Latam crudes take center stage in US Gulf.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian and Latin American crudes took center stage in U.S. foreign crude trading on Friday amid the continued tight trans-Atlantic arbitrage, traders said.</p>
<p>A major U.S. refiner picked up Malaysian Tapis and Miri crudes from a European major at around 10 cents and 23 cents, respectively, over benchmark West Texas Intermediate/Cushing, traders said.</p>
<p>The deal extends a recent series of U.S. transactions involving Asian grades.</p>
<p>A Swiss trading company was still offering a small piece of prompt Indonesian Widuri crude on the U.S. Gulf Coast. Several refiners said the crude's high pour point would make it a hard sell in the U.S. market.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Ecuadoran state oil company Petroecuador raised the price differentials by 10 cents a barrel for Oriente for most customers effective August 1, a trade source said.</p>
<p>Only those price differentials that are based on WTI were affected, the source said.</p>
<p>The new fob formula prices are as follows:</p>
<p>						   New Price     Old Price</p>
<p>    US Gulf Coast/East Coast/Caribbean WTI -$5.20    WTI -$5.30</p>
<p>    Peru					 WTI -$4.76    WTI -$4.86</p>
<p>    Chile					WTI -$5.08    WTI -$5.18</p>
<p>    Argentina/Brazil			 WTI -$5.16    WTI -$5.26</p>
<p>The formula for the U.S. West Coast and Pacific Central America were unchanged at $2.56 and $2.51, respectively, under Alaska North Slope Long Beach. The formula for Asian customers was also unchanged at Oman minus $2.50 a barrel.</p>
<p>Separately, a U.S. refiner on Friday bought an Oriente spot cargo from a trader for September 1-10 at around $3.00 a barrel under WTI on a cif basis for the U.S. East Coast.</p>
<p>The same trader moved two more Oriente cargoes on Thursday, one for the U.S. Gulf at a $3.07 a barrel discount, and another for Peru at around $3.00-05 a barrel cif Peru.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the region, a U.S. major was heard to have sold part of a Canadon Seco cargo to a U.S. refiner for mid-September at around $1.40-50 a barrel under WTI.</p>
<p>--Patricia Garip-Bertuol NY Energy Desk ((+1 212 859 1620))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
