<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757522" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pfizer stock falls after company comments.</title>
<headline>Pfizer stock falls after company comments.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pfizer Inc stock on Friday fell after Henry McKinnell, president of its pharmaceuticals group unit, acknowledged at an analyst meeting that second half growth was likely to be in the single-digit range.</p>
<p>Shares were off 2-7/8 to 58-7/8, with analysts attributing the drop to McKinnell's response to a question posed by an industry analyst.  </p>
<p>The analyst pointed out that Pfizer showed earnings growth in the teens in the first two quarters of 1997, but noted the company was forecasting its earnings growth for the year would be at least 10 percent.</p>
<p>The analyst then asked, &quot;Are you suggesting you'll have a single-digit second half,&quot; to which McKinnell replied: &quot;Yes.&quot;</p>
<p>As its stock traded lower later in the afternoon, Pfizer released a statement saying the company did not say that earnings growth &quot;would be in the single digits&quot; in the second half.  </p>
<p>The company said it was reaffirming its statement from an earlier news release that Pfizer is &quot;targeting growth of at least 10 percent in revenue, net income, and earnings per share for the full year.&quot;</p>
<p>Later, company spokesman Andy McCormick said the quotes from the analyst and McKinnell -- on which Reuters based its story -- were accurate. He said it was a matter of &quot;semantics,&quot; adding Pfizer was concerned the market has misinterpreted McKinnell's comment and the Reuters story.</p>
<p>Smith Barney analyst Christina Heuer later Friday shaved her 1997 earnings estimate to $1.65 per share from $1.70, based upon slowing sales of two key Pfizer drugs, Norvasc and Zoloft.</p>
<p>((Ransdell Pierson, New York News Desk 212-859-1736))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
