<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757597" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republicans want to speed budget, Dems slow it down.</title>
<headline>Republicans want to speed budget, Dems slow it down.</headline>
<byline>Sue Kirchhoff</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Congressional Republicans tried to speed up sluggish balanced budget talks with the White House on Friday but Democrats applied the brakes, warning President Bill Clinton not to rush into a final deal.</p>
<p>Led by New York Sen. Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Democrats on the influential Senate Finance Committee asked Clinton to defer final action until the fall if necessary in order to work out legislation that met party priorities.</p>
<p>Republicans have set Aug. 1 as the deadline for passing final tax and spending blls to implement a five-year balanced budget pact with the White House. After that date, Congress is scheduled to adjourn for a month-long recess.</p>
<p>Administration officials and lawmakers have been closeted in meetings for several days. Aides said the two sides were beginning to make headway on some smaller issues, but were battling over big-ticket items.</p>
<p>&quot;If it is not possible by August 1 to produce legislation that Democrats can in good conscience support, then we urge that action be deferred until September,&quot; the Senate Democrats told Clinton in a letter.</p>
<p>They predicted the federal budget deficit could shrink to about $30 billion at the close of fiscal 1997, which ends Sept. 30. If current trends continued, the budget could be in balance next year without new action by Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;At a time when our economy is outperforming all expectations...it is incumbent upon the administration and Democrats in Congress to stand firm for our priorities,&quot; the Democrats said.</p>
<p>Republican lawmakers warned delay would only make it harder to get a final deal.</p>
<p>&quot;If there are differences, they are going to remain in September and the chances of passing (the budget bill) will be greatly diminished,&quot; said Senate Budget Committee Chairman Pete Domenici, a New Mexico Republican.</p>
<p>The White House and Republicans are trying to work out legislation cutting taxes by $89 billion over five years and a separate spending measure including $115 billion in Medicare reductions and about $15 billion in Medicaid cuts.</p>
<p>Sources said Republicans were moving toward the White House in several areas, including restoration of disability aid to legal immigrants who will lose benefits in the coming months under a new welfare law.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we're going to get this agreement,&quot; Clinton told an education group, speaking shortly after discussing current negotiations with top aides.</p>
<p>Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott wants to wrap up talks by the end of Friday to allow Congress time to vote on a budget bill next week. Negotiations may well go into the weekend, aides said.</p>
<p>Among major disagreements, the White House opposes a Republican tax plan indexing capital gains for inflation. Administration officials are also pushing to extend a $500-per-child tax credit to low-income workers.</p>
<p>Children's health is another simmering issue. Republicans have agreed to provide $16 billion to extend health care to many of the nation's 10 million uninsured children.</p>
<p>Clinton wants an additional $8 billion approved by the Senate as part of a 20-cents-per-pack increase in the cigarette tax. He also wants Republidans to tighten their plan to provide national, comprehensive insurance benefits.</p>
<p>Senate Democratic Leader Tom Daschle said he sensed a lightening up.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an attitude much more conducive to compromise than 24 hours ago,&quot; he said. &quot;I don't think there is anything I can point to. We're just friendlier towards one another.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
