<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757531" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reputed New York mob boss convicted.</title>
<headline>Reputed New York mob boss convicted.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A jury on Friday found Vincent &quot;The Chin&quot; Gigante guilty of racketeering, conspiring to murder other organised crime figures and being boss of New York City's Genovese crime family.</p>
<p>The jury deliberated for three days in Brooklyn federal court. Gigante, 69, considered the last of New York City's old-time mob dons, faces a possible sentence of life in prison.  </p>
<p>The jury found Gigante guilty, among other crimes, of plotting to kill Gambino mafia family godfather John Gotti. That killing was never carried out, and Gotti is now in prison for murder and racketeering.</p>
<p>The prosecution's case against Gigante relied heavily on the testimony of six former mobsters who became government informants, including Salvatore &quot;Sammy the Bull&quot; Gravano, whose testimony was critical in the 1992 Gotti conviction.</p>
<p>Gigante's defence attorneys, who did not call a single witness on his behalf, claim he is incapacitated by mental illness.</p>
<p>Gigante earned the nickname &quot;The Oddfather&quot; for his habit of wandering the neighbourhood around his Greenwich Village apartment in a tattered bathrobe and slippers, muttering to himself.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
