<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757696" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electricity seen higher, extends Thurs. rise.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electricity seen higher, extends Thurs. rise.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures were called to open higher Friday, extending Thursday's rise on shortcovering and steady prices in the western physical power market, market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have a shot to go higher...because of where the momentum is,&quot; a New York futures broker.</p>
<p>August Palo Verde (PV) futures, in over-the-counter trading, were quoted at $35.60-35.95 a megawatt hour (MWh) up from Thursday's settlement at $35.49, and August California-Oregon Border (COB) was talked at $21.00-21.50 a MWh versus yesterday's close at $21.10.</p>
<p>Despite expectations of rising supply in the Southwest, PV futures were able to maintain within the upper end of their trading range ahead of August's expiration.</p>
<p>Both August PV and COB futures will expire Monday, and August power options are scheduled to go off the board today.</p>
<p>PV's strength helped stablize to COB following a downtrend that began July 10.</p>
<p>The 1,070 MW unit 2 and 1,080 unit 3 at the San Onofre nuclear power station in San Clemente, California, were at 97 percent power as of early Friday, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission said.</p>
<p>The Western Systems Coordinating Council approved a final summertime capacity for the Pacific Intertie transmission system of 6,900 megawatts (MW). The new rating will replace an interim summer cap of 6,300 MW which took effect July 1.</p>
<p>The 1,221 MW unit 2 at the Palo Verde nuclear complex near Phoenix, Arizona was set Sunday to begin slowly ramping down to between 60 and 80 percent power by September 6, when it was scheduled to shut for refueling.</p>
<p>In the next six to ten days, forecasters called for temperatures to average normal across most of the Southwest and above normal in the Pacific Northwest.</p>
<p>Coastal cities from Seattle to Los Angeles were expected to see readings in the 70s-80s F, while interior centers like Phoenix and Las Vegas would continue to experience seasonal triple-digit heat.</p>
<p>((--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
