<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757852" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Buba seen pulling punches on mark intervention.</title>
<headline>Buba seen pulling punches on mark intervention.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bundesbank may have broken its silence on the continuing fall of the mark, but economists on Friday cautioned that there is little concrete action the central bank can take to reverse the decline.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now seeing verbal intervention, the Bundesbank has threatened a little bit by leaving open what it may do on short-term rates over the summer...but I do expect the markets will realise there is little the Bundesbank could do to back up threats,&quot; said Gerhard Grebe, chief Germany economist at Bank Julius Baer in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>After keeping largely quiet on the mark's six percent fall against the US dollar over the past 10 days, three Bundesbank officials spoke out late Thursday and early Friday on the state of the currency.</p>
<p>Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing told German television late on Thursday that he &quot;could not say that he was not worried&quot; over the speed and size of the mark's drop, but was reluctant to say what the most appropriate level for the mark might be.</p>
<p>In an interview published in Belgium on Friday but conducted in mid-July, Vice president Johann Wilhelm Gaddum said the dollar was slightly overvalued.</p>
<p>Finally, council member Reimut Jochimsen told German newspaper Handelsblatt: &quot;Normally we stress that we do not follow an exchange rate-oriented policy. Now we want to make people aware that we are driving carefully, making sure we can see the road clearly.&quot;</p>
<p>While economists agreed that the inflation-conscious Bundesbank was now clearly concerned about the weaker mark and its longer term effect on prices, they also said the central bank had only a few tools to stop the dollar's rise.</p>
<p>One of the cheapest, and so most preferred, methods to check a currency's rapid rise or fall is so-called verbal intervention, where policy-makers warn markets of how hard they could be hit if rates were to be raised.</p>
<p>But aggressive currency traders were hardly intimidated by this relatively mild-mannered talk, realising Germany lacks a clear policy on where it wants the mark to be -- a fact which is forcing the Bundesbank to pull its punches.</p>
<p>Although the weaker mark could ultimately send local inflation rates higher, Germany's largely export-driven economy is relishing the chance to sell its cheaper goods abroad.</p>
<p>An interest rate hike to support the currency would hit growth on two fronts -- by boosting the currency and potentially dampening domestic demand.</p>
<p>&quot;Bonn actually seems to be enjoying the fact that a weaker mark could boost German economic growth and I hardly think the Bundesbank is so disloyal that it would raise rates now,&quot; Baer's Grebe said.</p>
<p>Other analysts said that a premature rate hike could stifle the country's fragile economic recovery and virtually ensure that Germany would not meet the entry criterion for currency union, throwing the entire project into disarray.</p>
<p>&quot;There would have a very negative domino effect and the Bundesbank would again be blamed for messing everything up,&quot; Grebe said, noting Frankfurt's central bankers are desperately trying to avoid bad press.</p>
<p>One final option for the Bundesbank to rein in the dollar would be to intervene in the open market, an option that several economists have termed as increasingly likely.</p>
<p>By ambushing the market with some targeted dollar sales, possibly with the aid of other central banks, the Bundesbank could succeed in unnerving the markets, economists said.</p>
<p>But UBS economist Holger Fahrinkrug noted it might be difficult to convince European nations like France and Italy to join in any intervention, leaving the Bundesbank to go it alone.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
