<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757824" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Fininvest to make OPA for Standa share.</title>
<headline>Fininvest to make OPA for Standa share.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silvio Berlusconi's Fininvest Spa media group said it was launching a public buy offer (OPA) for all ordinary and savings shares in Italian retail chain Standa held by minority shareholders.</p>
<p>Fininvest said in a statement the operation for 5.35 million ordinary shares and 6.7 million savings shares would cost a total of 144.56 billion lire.</p>
<p>Each ordinary share would be valued at 20,000 lire which Fininvest said represented a premium of 34 percent over the average price in the last month, and 32 percent over the average price over the last six months or 38 percent over the last year.  </p>
<p>Each savings share would be valued at 5,600 lire, which represented a premium of 44 percent over the average price in the last month, it said.</p>
<p>Fininvest said the OPA was conditional on a minimum take-up rate which would give the media group 90 percent of the retail chain's share capital when added to those shares already in Fininvest's possession. But it said it reserved the right to carry out the OPA even if the minimum level was not reached.</p>
<p>&quot;The offer is part of a wide programme of rationalisation of the Fininvest group's activities, with a widening of control over Standa's activities,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>It said the operation also aimed to allow a relaunch of the business some time in the future and a strengthening of its capital either through accords with other operators in the sector, reorganisation or mergers with non-listed companies in the Fininvest stable.</p>
<p>Conditional on approval by stock market authorities, the operation was expected to start in August. Fininvest is being advised by Banca Commerciale Italiana.</p>
<p>Standa shares were suspended on the bourse on Thursday and Friday pending an announcement. Ordinary shares last stood at 19,000 lire.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau 39 2 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
