<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="757916" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FOCUS-EU bullish on steel output, prices in 1997.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-EU bullish on steel output, prices in 1997.</headline>
<byline>Fredrik Dahl</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission issued a bullish 1997 outlook for the European Union's steel industry on Friday, saying increasing output should help boost profitability.</p>
<p>In a report on the steel market, the EU executive even forecast that the downward trend in employment in the industry should level off in 1997 and 1998, except in Germany and Spain.</p>
<p>The industry, often in crisis over the last 25 years, would benefit from stronger economic growth in the 15-nation bloc, increasing demand for steel, especially in the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;On the Community steel market, the improvement noted at the end of 1996 is being increasingly confirmed, due in particular to high levels of exports, increasing domestic demand and less pressure from imports,&quot; the Commission said.</p>
<p>Total steel output may rise by some 6.5 percent to 157 million tonnes in 1997, exceeding even the &quot;outstanding level&quot; reached in 1995, when output amounted to 155.7 million tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;The business upswing for the main steel consuming industries, which need to build up stocks of finished products to meet both increased domestic demand and export commitments, points to faster growth in Community steel production over the coming months.&quot;</p>
<p>EU steel output stabilised in the last three months of 1996 after a sharp decline earlier in the year. Still, total output last year was 5.3 percent down from 1995.</p>
<p>In the first few months of 1997, however, production started to rise due mainly to rebuilding of stocks and export demand.</p>
<p>&quot;The gradual restoration of a more satisfactory steel production rate will no doubt help to improve the utilisation rate of capacity and improve operating profits, which is highly desirable if Community producers are to be more efficient.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, the trend towards stabilisation of EU steel prices observed in the last months of 1996 was confirmed from the beginning of this year.</p>
<p>But the recovery in prices had only partly offset losses of the earlier period. &quot;Moreover, Community steel prices are still much lower than those on the world market.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Internal prices should therefore rise further in the coming months with the better prospects of growth for the second half of 1997 in the EU and the probable maintenance of the current rate of the dollar which favours Community exports.&quot;</p>
<p>However, it also sounded a note of caution, saying the current recovery should not induce producers and dealers to unduly increase supply on the EU steel market, &quot;the balance of which is extremely fragile.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The rapid alternation of business cycles, with situations of oversupply of steel and the consequent sharp fall in prices followed by periods when one or other product is in short supply, should therefore make Community producers and dealers act with caution, in order to ensure long-term stability on the Community steel market.&quot;</p>
<p>The EU's trade surplus in steel reocovered significantly in 1996, but the Commission warned that it was possible that steel imports, attracted by the price upswing, could buck the trend in the second half of 1997. -- Brussels newsroom +32 2 287 68 11</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
