<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75817" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Christopher disturbed by alleged S.Korea spy case.</title>
<headline>Christopher disturbed by alleged S.Korea spy case.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary of State Warren Christopher said on Wednesday he was very disturbed by the arrest of an alleged spy for South Korea and said Washington had been in touch with South Korean officials over the case.</p>
<p>A computer specialist with access to top secret U.S. naval intelligence was arrested at a diplomatic reception at Fort Myer, Virginia, on Tuesday on charges of spying for South Korea, the FBI said in Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been very disturbed by the reports that I have received of that arrest and the incident itself,&quot; Christopher told reporters before talks in New York with Mexican Foreign Minister Jose Angel Gurria.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been in touch with the South Korean officials about it. Because this is a matter that's an ongoing criminal investigation, you'll understand why my comments will be very limited.&quot;</p>
<p>Christopher met on Tuesday afternoon with South Korean Foreign Minister Gong Ro-mung but State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said the matter had not been raised.</p>
<p>Christopher said &quot;the arrest wasn't made until last night,&quot; implying it came after his meeting with Gong.</p>
<p>Arrested was Robert Kim, 56, a Korean-born U.S. Citizen and 19-year government employee who worked at the U.S. Navy intelligence offices in Suitland, Maryland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
