<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758184" id="root" date="1997-07-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Media-buying business rises after yrs on sidelines.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Media-buying business rises after yrs on sidelines.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Adler</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The media buying and planning business -- long treated as the ugly stepchild of the advertising industry -- has finally come into its own, driven by a proliferation in media and a trend by advertisers toward globalisation.</p>
<p>As a result, advertising industry executives say they expect consolidation in the sector to meet the trend.</p>
<p>Media planning and buying involves determining a strategy for what media to use for an advertising campaign and the actual purchase of advertising space and airtime. It is handled by both companies solely devoted to that business, known as media independents, and by advertising agencies.</p>
<p>&quot;Five, 10 years ago, if you wanted to reach your consumer you booked a 30-second spot on 'Coronation Street' and you reached 30 percent of the (UK) population,&quot; Crispin Davis, chief executive of Aegis Group Plc, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Today that's no longer the case,&quot; said Davis, whose company is the parent of Carat International, Europe's largest media independent.</p>
<p>The soap opera &quot;Coronation Street&quot; may still be Britain's most popular television show, but, like other countries around the world, Britain no longer has just a handful of TV channels and the viewing audience is much more fragmented.</p>
<p>The explosion of cable and satellite television, as well as the move toward privatisation of state-operated TV networks, is but one factor making media more complex around the world.</p>
<p>&quot;There are more media avenues open to advertisers now,&quot; said Davis. &quot;It's not just traditional forms of television, print, press and radio. You've got sponsorship. You've got programming. You've got two-way communication. You've got the Internet.&quot;</p>
<p>BUSINESS TRANSFORMED</p>
<p>The realisation that planning media usage for advertising campaigns is no longer is easy business has transformed the status of the business.</p>
<p>Although the purchase of media has always represented about 85 percent of the total cost of an advertising campaign -- compared to the 10 to 15 percent of budget for the creation of the ads, the media side for years had little status in the glitzy world of advertising agencies.</p>
<p>&quot;The media department was always downstairs next to the boiler room,&quot; said Chris Ingram, chairman of CIA Group Plc, Europe's second largest independent media buyer.</p>
<p>&quot;Up until recently it was bean-counting work and everyone had access to the same stuff. Media planning and buying tended to be a commodity business,&quot; Alasdair Ritchie, president of advertising agency TBWA International, told Reuters.</p>
<p>LARGE MEDIA OWNERS POSE NEW CHALLENGE</p>
<p>Just as the growing complexity of the media business has raised its stature, the rise of increasingly large media owners has caused ad agencies to wake up to a new challenge.</p>
<p>The concentation of large parts of media around the globe in the hands of owners such as Rupert Murdoch has meant that media owners have more control over advertising than the ad agencies.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to wrest that (control) back,&quot; said Ritchie. &quot;That is why you have such a big interest from Omnicom and the other agencies, like WPP and Interpublic.</p>
<p>TBWA International, for instance, said in early July that it would not renew its contract with media independent Carat to service its clients in Europe. The move was in preparation for plans by its parent company Omnicom to consolidate its worldwide media operations.</p>
<p>In June, WPP, the world's largest advertising and marketing group, acquired 7.8 million CIA Group shares, representing a 12.5 percent stake.</p>
<p>WPP chief executive Martin Sorrell has been one of the advertising industry's most vocal people in stressing the mistake of ceding control of the media side.</p>
<p>&quot;Why is it that Carat and CIA have grown in Europe?&quot; Sorrell told a meeting with staff of WPP's Ogilvy &amp; Mather ad agency. &quot;Because the people who ran advertising agencies did not think it (media) was important.&quot;</p>
<p>Ogilvy &amp; Mather and J. Walter Thompson, also owned by WPP, have been considering merging their media operations.</p>
<p>Renewed competition from so-called full-service advertising agencies -- those that offer a full menu of creative and media services to clients -- is not expected to diminish.</p>
<p>&quot;There's going to be more competition from the full-service agencies,&quot; said Aegis' Davis.</p>
<p>Davis, who was adamant that Carat can stand up to any competition from ad agencies, said size will be increasingly important.</p>
<p>&quot;Size is going to be important,&quot; Davis said. &quot;I think you're going to see further consolidation in the industry over the next three to five years. ... It is important that you have a full-service (media) network so you can service clients all across Europe, and I think that's going to move globally.&quot;</p>
<p>GLOBAL APPROACH DEMANDED</p>
<p>Because companies are moving more and more toward a global approach, they demand the same of their media service.</p>
<p>&quot;Clients are more and more global,&quot; said TBWA's Ritchie. &quot;When they want a media platform for a product in terms of advertising,...they don't want to do it bit by bit. They want to do it globally.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Just as clients want international ad agencies with offices as far away as Vietnam, Delhi and Iceland, they want the same thing in media,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kellogg Europe in May consolidated its media buying into a new agency that is part of J. Walter Thompson, after previously using six different media buying agencies across Europe. Kellogg Europe, part of U.S.-based Kellogg Co, said the consolidation would facilitate more effective communication across its European operations.</p>
<p>Earlier in May, the Ford Motor Co consolidated its $1.1 billion U.S. media buying account into a new U.S. subsidiary of J. Walter Thompson, instead of remaining spread across five different media buyers.</p>
<p>As a result of globalisation, TBWA's Ritchie said, big media players will become bigger. &quot;The pace of acquisition will increase,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Consolidation in the media business is expected to concentrate in Europe and Asia before moving to the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;In America you don't have the number of (media) independents you have in Europe,&quot; said Ritchie, because the number of large advertisers have demanded that ad agencies be able to handle all their creative and media needs under one roof.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8395451">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
