<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758246" id="root" date="1997-07-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: HORSE RACING-SWAIN SPRINGS 16-1 SURPRISE.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-SWAIN SPRINGS 16-1 SURPRISE.</headline>
<byline>Dave Thompson</byline>
<dateline>ASCOT, England 1997-07-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swain, ridden by John Reid, sprang a 16-1 surprise to win the King George VI and Queen Elizabeth Diamond Stakes on Saturday.</p>
<p>The race featured a clash of international champions Singspiel, Helissio and Pilsudski but Swain, the outsider of four horses running for Sheikh Mohammed, stole the show.</p>
<p>Swain, trained in France last year but now in England under the care of Saeed Bin Suroor, took the running with 300 metres left in the 12 furlong (2.4 km) showpiece.</p>
<p>The colt battled on well to hold off Pilsudski (6-1) ridden by Michael Kinane and Helissio, the 11-10 favovourite, partnered by Cash Asmussen.</p>
<p>The result was an interesting contrast to last year's Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe when Helissio trounced Pilsudski with Swain in third place.</p>
<p>Heavy rain during the morning had altered the Ascot going to soft and resulted in a plunge in the betting on Helissio.</p>
<p>The change in the ground favoured Swain, who outlasted  the opposition in fine style to underline the horse's top-class credentials.</p>
<p>Jockey Reid, winner of the King George back in 1978, had never sat on Swain before but knew the horse would stay the distance well.</p>
<p>&quot;I wanted it to be a test of stamina,&quot; the Northern Irishman said.</p>
<p>Helissio cut out the early running along with Kingfisher Mill, the mount of British champion Pat Eddery, in second and Swain in third ahead of Pilsudski and Singspiel, ridden by Frankie Dettori.</p>
<p>Helissio led into the straight with Swain by his shoulder just ahead of Pilsudski. In a battle royal to the line, with four champions giving their all, Swain held on by a length with a length and a quarter separating second and third.</p>
<p>Singspiel finish fourth just ahead of Shantou with Kingfisher Mill fading into last of the eight runners.</p>
<p>Swain, now a five-year-old, has twice been placed in the Arc and also finished third in last year's Breeders' Cup Turf to Pilsudski.</p>
<p>Godolphin racing manager Simon Crisford said: &quot;We thought there was a good race in him but maybe the Man of War or the Turf Classic at Belmont (in the U.S. later in the year). We are delighted with his performance today...He's a really serious top-class race horse.&quot;</p>
<p>Sheikh Mohammed, who won the Dubai World Cup and the Japan Cup with Singspiel, felt the changed ground was the key to Swain's success.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a long final two furlongs,&quot; said the Sheikh, previously successful in the King George on Lammtarra in 1995, King's Theatre (1994), Opera House (1993) and Belmez (1990).</p>
<p>Races on the agenda for Swain now include another shot at the Arc and the Breeders' Cup.</p>
<p>Michael Stoute, trainer of Singspiel and runner-up Pilsudski, said of the latter: &quot;You've got to pleased with a performance like that. He's a real brave horse who tries his best and I am sure he has been beaten by a champion.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ASCOT, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
