<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758316" id="root" date="1997-07-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Volcker says suit could hurt Swiss bank cooperation.</title>
<headline>Volcker says suit could hurt Swiss bank cooperation.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A lawsuit that seeks to recover assets of Holocaust victims held by Swiss banks could hamper investigations by an independent committee, the commission's head, Paul Volcker, said in a letter filed in federal court, the New York Times reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>In the nine-page letter, Volcker, a former chairman of the U.S. Federal Reserve, said he was afraid Swiss bankers and other sources might stop cooperating with the commission if the lawsuit resulted in U.S. legal orders to disclose documents and sources, the Times reported.</p>
<p>The suit could have a &quot;strongly adverse impact&quot; on the commission's inquiries &quot;potentially to the point of ineffectiveness,&quot; the Times quoted Volcker as saying in the letter dated July 24.</p>
<p>Last week, Swiss banks published an unprecedented three-page list of names on dormant accounts in newspapers in 28 countries and on the Internet, breaking with a tradition of secrecy after criticism by Jewish groups.</p>
<p>In the published lists, owners or heirs were urged to come forward to five global contact offices and file claims that will be decided by a panel of arbitrators. The 1,800 accounts hold a total of 61 million Swiss francs ($40.2 million).</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps the greatest potential damage to the committee's investigative audit,&quot; the Times quoted Volcker as saying in the letter, &quot;would be the possibility of public disclosure of the documents from Swiss banks collected by the auditors.</p>
<p>&quot;Such a possibility will most likely result in a reluctance of Swiss banks .... to cooperate with the work of the committee,&quot; the Times reported.</p>
<p>U.S. District Court Judge Edward Korman is to hear arguments in Brooklyn, New York, on Thursday on a demand by Swiss banks that the suit be put on hold, the newspaper reported.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
