<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758361" id="root" date="1997-07-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Mahathir blames George Soros for attack on ringgit.</title>
<headline>Mahathir blames George Soros for attack on ringgit.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad on Saturday named U.S.-based financier George Soros as the man responsible for the current attack on the Malaysian ringgit currency, the national Bernama news agency reported.</p>
<p>&quot;...Today, I am confirming that George Soros is the man that I was talking about,&quot; Mahathir said with reference to his remarks in recent days that a certain foreign financier has been manipulating currencies in the region for his own political agenda.  </p>
<p>Mahathir, who also accused Soros on Saturday of upsetting other regional currencies, said the American had even used his clout to try to block Burma's entry into the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN).</p>
<p>&quot;He (Soros) was also known as the man who...tried to use his financial clout in the United States to block Myanmar's (Burma) admission into ASEAN,&quot; Mahathir said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very difficult to separate the right hand and the left hand and sometimes you don't even know what your right hand is doing. But in this case, it is quite obvious there is a convergence,&quot; Mahathir said.</p>
<p>ASEAN this week admitted Burma and Laos to the grouping, which also includes Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Vietnam, Singapore, Thailand.  </p>
<p>ASEAN foreign ministers, holding their annual convention in Kuala Lumpur this year, issued a communique at the end of their meeting on Friday, lambasting currency speculators for trying to destabilise their economies.</p>
<p>The Thai baht, the Philippine peso, Indonesian rupiah and ringgit have all come under strong speculative pressure since early July, forcing the region's governments to mount various rescue bids to save their currencies.</p>
<p>Mahathir first lashed at the speculators when opening the ASEAN meeting, calling them &quot;rogues&quot;, &quot;robbers&quot;, &quot;anarchists&quot; and &quot;brigands&quot;.</p>
<p>He did not name Soros then, but said the one financier he was referring to liked to project to the world that he was a charitable person.</p>
<p>The New York-based Soros Fund Management runs a philanthropic organisation called the Open Society Institute, which aims to promote democracy and provide financial help to certain countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We have worked 20 to 40 years to develop our countries to this level and along comes the man with a few billion US dollars and within a period of two weeks, he has undone almost the work we have done,&quot; Mahathir said on Saturday. &quot;Who is helping who...I would like to know that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
