<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758365" id="root" date="1997-07-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Peru's Fujimori not born in Japan, says uncle.</title>
<headline>Peru's Fujimori not born in Japan, says uncle.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>An uncle of Peruvian President Alberto Fujimori on Saturday angrily denied media reports in Lima that the head of state was born in Japan.</p>
<p>The Peruvian constitution requires presidents to be born in Peru.</p>
<p>&quot;I was surprised at the reports,&quot; Kiyoshi Minami, one of Fujimori's uncles, told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Why do they have to fabricate stories and slander him?&quot; said the 83-year-old uncle, who lives in Ube, western Japan.</p>
<p>The Peruvian weekly magazine Caretas questioned the authenticity of documents stating Fujimori -- the 58-year-old son of Japanese immigrants -- was born in Peru and whether he was born in Japan.</p>
<p>The Caretas report, based on a four-year investigation, showed documents which allegedly altered information on Fujimori's birthdate and suggested he may have entered Peru from Japan after he was born.</p>
<p>Minami said Fujimori's father, Naoichi, &quot;temporarily&quot; returned to Japan in 1934 to seek a bride.</p>
<p>&quot;He visited Japan in 1934 to get married to Mutsue Inomoto from Kumamoto. The couple left Yokohama port for Peru in August of the same year,&quot; Minami said.</p>
<p>&quot;I stayed with the couple at an inn for one night in Yokohama just the day before their departure by ship for Peru,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is crystal clear that they did not have a baby or child at that time,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said neither Fujimori's father nor mother had returned to Japan until after the end of World War Two.</p>
<p>In Lima on Friday, Fujimori's family lawyer Sandro Fuentes also said the president was born in Peru, on July 28, 1938.</p>
<p>Fujimori authorised an investigation examining documents that local opposition media claimed had been altered to change the name of the president's birthplace, Fuentes said.</p>
<p>The former head of Fujimori's election campaign, Francisco Loayza, claimed Montesinos knew the president was born in Japan and used the information to blackmail him into granting increased powers to the security forces.</p>
<p>After riding a crest of public approval at the end of Lima's four-month hostage crisis, Fujimori's popularity has plummeted in recent weeks with a series of scandals involving alleged abuses of power by the security forces which sparked violent street protests.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
