<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758357" id="root" date="1997-07-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: China's Qian says deeply concerned over Cambodia.</title>
<headline>China's Qian says deeply concerned over Cambodia.</headline>
<byline>Ian MacKenzie</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>China is deeply concerned at recent events in Cambodia and wants the conflicting parties to settle their differences peacefully, Chinese Foreign Minister Qian Qichen said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;China is deeply concerned about what recently took place in Cambodia,&quot; Qian told a joint news conference with U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright.</p>
<p>&quot;Cambodia already achieved national reconciliation and had established a coalition government, so we do not wish to see the eruption of armed conflict and bloodshed after all that.</p>
<p>&quot;Although between the different parties and between different leaders they might have contradictions and disagreements, we hope they can resolve their disagreements through peaceful means,&quot; Qian said.</p>
<p>Albright said Cambodia was one of the topics she would discuss with Qian during a meeting which followed the 30-minute news conference.</p>
<p>They are in Kuala Lumpur to attend the annual ASEAN Regional Forum (ARF) security conference on Sunday and hold meetings with the various ASEAN members and other major Asian and Western states.</p>
<p>ASEAN, the Association of South East Asian Nations, comprises Malaysia, Singapore, Thailand, Indonesia, Brunei, Vietnam, the Philippines and newly-joined Burma and Laos.</p>
<p>Cambodia had been due to join ASEAN this week, but its entry was postponed after Second Prime Minister Hun Sen ousted First Prime Minister Norodom Ranariddh early this month, plunging the country into fresh turmoil.</p>
<p>The Chinese foreign minister did not directly answer a question as to whether Beijing could work with Hun Sen, a former Vietnamese protege.</p>
<p>&quot;Our consistent position is not to interfere in other countries' internal affairs, but we wish to see that they (the Cambodians) will be able to work out their problem through peaceful means,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Cambodian issue dominated the two-day annual meeting of ASEAN foreign ministers on Thursday and Friday, and they have sought a clear policy statement from Hun Sen on his attitude towards an ASEAN mediation mission after confusing reports from Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>Three ASEAN foreign ministers led by Indonesia's Ali Alatas visited Beijing, where Cambodia's King Sihanouk is undergoing medical treatment, after the decision to postpone Cambodia's admittance to the group.</p>
<p>They also met Ranariddh in Bangkok and had talks with Hun Sun in Phnom Penh last weekend, at which he had rejected ASEAN mediation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
