<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758407" id="root" date="1997-07-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Rainstorms raise fears of new floods on Oder River.</title>
<headline>Rainstorms raise fears of new floods on Oder River.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>HOHENWUTZEN, Germany 1997-07-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of German soldiers laboured into the early hours on Saturday to stave off one of the worst floods in memory as rainstorms raised fears the river dividing Germany and Poland would rise higher.</p>
<p>In a westward bend in the Oder river, the village of Hohenwutzen looked more like a battlefield than an agrarian community located at the northern end of the Oderbruch plateau, laid dry in the 18th century by Frederick the Great.</p>
<p>The plateau was the breadbasket of the region during Prussian times and later in communist East Germany, cut off from the west by the Cold War divide.</p>
<p>But now floods that have left around 100 people dead in past weeks in neighbouring Poland and the Czech Republic were causing the Oder dikes to crumble and threatened to flood the fertile plain with unforeseeable consequences for the region.</p>
<p>Faded green army tents dot the fields and floodlights glare into the night as nearly one thousand soldiers, hundreds of aid workers and local villagers furiously stuffed sandbags to plug each new leak as it appeared.</p>
<p>Fewer than 500 residents from a population of some 5,000 in the Oderbruch plains remained in their homes. The rest were evacuated to neighbouring towns to stay with friends and family or find refuge in public shelters.</p>
<p>After working throughout the day, soldiers had plugged the most vulnerable spots in the dikes.</p>
<p>But then it started raining. In the distance lightening flashed orange in the sky, lighting up tree-tops that stood submerged in the river.</p>
<p>Villagers felt betrayed, recalling how communist leadership failed to heed warnings in the 1980s and declined to reinforce the Oder dikes. The flood now seemed certain to destroy what progress had been made in the seven years since German unity.</p>
<p>&quot;Now it's raining again,&quot; sighed Torsten Gauert, staring defeated at the muddy river and cradling his six-month-old baby. &quot;It can't hold. During the times of the (communist) East Germany nothing was done. There's no way the dike can stand this pressure for so long.&quot;</p>
<p>About 1,500 German border guards helped emergency operations with 65 helicopters and 100 boats. A further 5,400 soldiers were in the region to help out -- the German army's largest peacetime operation since World War Two.</p>
<p>Germany has so far has escaped the worst of the region's flooding, the most serious in centuries.</p>
<p>Military officials rushed about barking orders to subordinates as truckload after truckload of sand was driven up to the critical spot in the bend of the Oder that officials were uncertain would hold overnight.</p>
<p>Earlier, First Lieutenant Joerg Kiefel described how the soldiers hoped they could hold back the flood, the worst in some 50 years, by erecting a secondary dike behind the weak points in the sagging wall.</p>
<p>He pointed out over the plains that stretch several kilometres to the next dike and spread out south another 50 kilometres and said: &quot;If we are not able to stop the water here then all of this area will be flooded.&quot;</p>
<p>Should the dike break, there would be nothing to stop the river from rushing into the plains, overrunning farms and villages until, some 12 kilometres (seven miles) westward, the tide reaches the outskirts of Bad Freienwalde, a city with 16,000 residents.</p>
<p>Further south, water submerged two villages after dikes holding back the Oder burst in two places.</p>
<p>As the water rushed into Wiesenau, south of Frankfurt an der Oder, only the tops of houses were left above the waterline and local residents reluctantly gave in to the flood.</p>
<p>&quot;We are saying to farewell to our farm, that's the way it is,&quot; said Jorg Boettke.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOHENWUTZEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
