<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758528" id="root" date="1997-07-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: ROMANIA TAKES IN 42 PERCENT OF WHEAT CROP.</title>
<headline>ROMANIA TAKES IN 42 PERCENT OF WHEAT CROP.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania has taken in more than 40 percent of its 1997 wheat crop and figures show yields exceeded initial estimates, the ministry of agriculture said on Friday.</p>
<p>Ministry data showed the harvest on 1.02 million hectares, or 42 percent of the total 2.38 million hectares under wheat, produced 3.226 million tonnes of wheat.</p>
<p>Average yield per hectare was 3,157 kg, higher than initial estimates of 2,963, data also showed.</p>
<p>The ministry expects a total wheat crop of 7.07 million tonnes, almost double the level last year while exports are seen at over two million tonnes.</p>
<p>Officials have denied suggestions that adverse weather which in recent weeks affected eastern European countries, could have an impact on Romania's wheat crop.</p>
<p>Agriculture Ministry officials and top parliamentarians have described the incoming crop as &quot;excellent,&quot; discounting media reports that rains had damaged the quality of the wheat, especially in western counties.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the independent daily Adevarul said it had reservations over the ministry's estimates for the 1997 bumper crop as recent rains had delayed harvesting and most farms operated with only half the equipment needed for a smooth harvesting.</p>
<p>Adevarul said it feared further delays and a strong growth of weeds due to rains might cause significant losses.</p>
<p>&quot;The officials in the farming sector will realise that by estimating big crops they did nothing but sell the bearskin while it was still running through the woods,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>-- Adrian Dascalu, Bucharest Newsroom +401 312-0264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
