<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75852" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German corruption wave prompts action.</title>
<headline>German corruption wave prompts action.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT, Germany</dateline>
<text>
<p>A stream of corporate corruption scandals in Germany has dented its self-image as a by-the-rules player and spurred a fresh drive to clamp down on malpractice.</p>
<p>The government plans to introduce tighter penalties for corruption -- doubling the maximum prison term for convicted civil servants to 10 years -- and is considering blacklisting errant companies from public service contracts.</p>
<p>Public prosecutors are pushing to be allowed to use more powerful methods to crack major corruption rings, such as tapping telephone lines and offering informants the incentive of a reduced or waived sentence.</p>
<p>Corruption has become a hot topic in Germany in recent years but public consternation reached new heights last summer when prosecutors revealed a probe into more than 200 people at 40 companies, among them 65 past and present staff at General Motors Corp. subsidiary Opel.</p>
<p>A second big scandal emerged this year as work ended on Frankfurt Airport's second terminal. Prosecutors mounted a massive investigation into a suspected corruption network of up to 50 managers, including airport staff and 20 contractors.</p>
<p>Experts say corruption has always played a quiet role in German business, but the stakes have risen dramatically, especially in the battle for major public service contracts.</p>
<p>While a fur coat or expensive dinner might have bought success in a public bid in the 1970s, prosecutors say some government officials are now demanding cash payments of thousands or even millions of marks (dollars) just for information.</p>
<p>Reliable figures are hard to find, but prosecutors estimate the annual cost of corruption in the public building sector alone at 5 billion to 10 billion marks ($3.3 billion to $6.6 billion) -- a figure which gives the cash-strapped government an added incentive for a clampdown.</p>
<p>In the state of Hesse, which includes the business capital of Frankfurt, systematic bribery costs the state finances between 120 million marks ($79 million) and 170 million marks ($113 million) a year.</p>
<p>&quot;Compared with France or Italy, for example, the situation is fairly limited. But that doesn't change the fact that the level of corruption here -- for our society and with our legal system -- is dramatic and emotionally unacceptable,&quot; said Frankfurt senior public prosecutor Wolfgang Schaupensteiner.</p>
<p>Schaupensteiner heads a nine-year-old specialist corruption task force -- Germany's first ever -- and says he is deluged with work. His division has probed 1,700 corruption cases to date and brought around 340 to court.</p>
<p>&quot;We have over 300 cases pending,&quot; he said in an interview. &quot;Every time one of our investigators clears up one case, it leads to dozens more, like an avalanche. That shows just how widespread corruption is.</p>
<p>&quot;In most cases this is not just the site foreman getting a backhander. There are top level people, right up to management board level, dealing very personally with bribery,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt airport case alone, where losses on overpriced contracts and payments for non-existent deliveries are estimated at tens of millions of marks (dollars), is so much broader than it seemed at first that investigations will drag on at least until 1998, Schaupensteiner said.</p>
<p>The scandals, continually highlighted in the media, have exploded Germany's belief that its public servants and business executives were above the kind of wheeling and dealing more associated with their more chaotic Mediterranean neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;Controls must be sharpened if the state is not to suffer lasting damage ... But the roots are in society's moral code ... If it is viewed as chic to bribe here and cheat a bit there, a corruption-free society remains a dream,&quot; the Berliner Morgenpost newspaper said in a recent editorial.</p>
<p>The German cabinet in June approved a draft corruption law making price-fixing deals between firms bidding for contracts a criminal offence punishable with up to five years' prison.</p>
<p>The proposals also raise the penalty for bribery in business to five years from one year and impose a maximum 10 years for giving or accepting bribes in the public service sector. Prosecutors welcome what they say is overdue action from Bonn but say the government should take a tougher line.</p>
<p>Prosecutors and other justice officials have also called for reduced sentences for individuals who inform on a corruption ring, an almost unheard of occurrence at present because of the danger of prosecution.</p>
<p>&quot;Principles like free competition are also at stake here, not just state funds. We have to stop corporate crime and corruption from gaining a stronger foothold here,&quot; said Schaupensteiner.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
