<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758540" id="root" date="1997-07-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: GEORGIA, ABKHAZ PLEDGE TO AVOID CONFLICT.</title>
<headline>GEORGIA, ABKHAZ PLEDGE TO AVOID CONFLICT.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-07-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Officials from Georgia and its rebel province Abkhazia have reaffirmed pledges not to use force or threaten force against each other, the United Nations said on Saturday.</p>
<p>They also agreed that disputes, rooted in longstanding frictions dating back to the Soviet period, would be settled &quot;exclusively by political means&quot;, a U.N. statement said.</p>
<p>It was issued by Liviu Bota, new special representative for Georgia under Secretary General Kofi Annan, who chaired three days of talks between the two sides with four Western powers and Russia sitting in.</p>
<p>The two sides, who waged war in 1992-93 which left 10,000 dead and drove 250,000 ethnic Georgians from their homes in Abkhazia, &quot;reaffirmed their commitment to the non-use of force or threat of the use of force against each other&quot;.</p>
<p>But Bota, a former Romanian diplomat and long-time U.N. human rights official, told reporters the discussions had not brought any breakthrough on political problems between the two or any specific accord on peacekeeping in the area.</p>
<p>He said he would call another meeting in Geneva some time in September.</p>
<p>The statement said Bota, envoys of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) and the four Western powers -- the United States, Britain, France and Germany -- had urged Russia and Georgia's two sides to work for agreement on maintaining the present Russian peacekeeping operation.</p>
<p>Georgian President Eduard Shevardnadze has been seeking outside support for the force, which is nominally a Commonwealth of Independent States force but entirely composed of Russians, to be transformed into an international operation.</p>
<p>But Abkhaz leader Vladislav Ardzinba has flatly rejected the idea, and said his forces would repel any incursion.</p>
<p>The mandate for the present force runs out at the end of the month and Georgia has said the Russians, patrolling a border zone to which some 50,000 Georgian refugees have returned, must go if there is no accord on a new-style force.</p>
<p>Georgian parliament speaker Zurab Zhvania told Russia's NTV television after a meeting with Shevardnadze and other officials on Saturday that it would be some days before Georgia took a final decision on its ultimatum to the Russian peacekeepers.</p>
<p>Diplomats close to the talks in Geneva said they did not see a crisis looming. Moscow says it will pull troops out if both sides ask for it.  The Russian force commander told Reuters in the zone this week that war would likely break out if they left.</p>
<p>Ardzinba told Interfax news agency in his capital Sukhumi the Geneva accord &quot;gave reason to suggest&quot; that the Russian presence in the buffer zone would be prolonged. If it were not, he added, Abkhaz forces would occupy the zone.</p>
<p>Saying neither side wanted war, Ardzinba forecast talks &quot;may be complex and lengthy, but there is no alternative&quot;.</p>
<p>After a trip to Washington and the U.N. headquarters in New York to seek support for a wider force, Shevardnadze said many Western leaders had urged him to let the Russians stay on.</p>
<p>The former Soviet foreign minister recognises any further conflict could scare away foreign investment, diplomats say.</p>
<p>The U.N. said maintaining the peacekeepers would help &quot;secure favourable and peaceful conditions for the continuation of negotiations to achieve a comprehensive settlement&quot;.</p>
<p>Abkhazia initially sought full independence during and after the 1992-93 conflict. But it won no international recognition.</p>
<p>Negotiations under Russian and U.N. auspices since then have focused on agreeing a new status that would give the region, once a Soviet tourist destination and the Colchis of ancient Greek mythology, a large degree of autonomy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GRGIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
