<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758600" id="root" date="1997-07-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia Grain - Wheat's wild ride expected to last.</title>
<headline>Australia Grain - Wheat's wild ride expected to last.</headline>
<byline>Michael Byrnes</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A roller-coaster ride for Australian grain prices in the past week is likely to leave the market volatile as weather drives the market, traders believe.</p>
<p>Last week began with South Australian growers saying their 1997/98 wheat and grains production looked like falling by at least 40 percent because of El Nino drought. Wheat prices rose.</p>
<p>The week ended with private forecasts of rain headed toward southern parts of the grainbelt. Prices crashed.</p>
<p>Hard heads in the industry are standing back while the markets toss and turn.  </p>
<p>Australian Wheat Board (AWB) chairman Trevor Flugge, in several public appearances during the week, declined to forecast the crop, citing weather uncertainties. Xavier Martin, chairman of the New South Wales Farmers' Association grains committee, described the 1997/98 crop as &quot;on a knife-edge&quot;.</p>
<p>Grains Council of Australia president Brendan Stewart, addressing a conference in Sydney, stood by the Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE) forecast of 16.3 million tonnes, down from 23.5 million tonnes.  </p>
<p>In Stewart's view, El Nino was affecting only a small part of Australia, with good opening rains in most of Western Australia (WA), Queensland and much of New South Wales (NSW).</p>
<p>In contrast, Martin described rain as &quot;desperately needed&quot; in much of NSW.</p>
<p>Uncertainty at this level caused prices to swing stongly over the week.</p>
<p>Physical market prices tailed futures prices, which jumped in comparatively heavy volume from Monday through to Thursday. This took settlement prices for market leader January 1998 to A$202.00 on Thursday from A$186.50 on Monday.  </p>
<p>Forecasts on Friday that rain was headed for southern parts of Australia cut the January 1998 settlement price back to A$193.50. The settlement price of nearby September 1997 fell by A$13.50 to A$201.00.</p>
<p>Bill Mitchell of New England Agricultural Traders now sees Sydney as over-bought and likely to decline further, while Chicago seems set to rally a little higher.</p>
<p>&quot;We may just see them moving in different directions, it wouldn't surprise at all,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Guy Allen of GrainCorp remains sceptical of doomsday views.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's as bad as they're painting the picture. They typically kill the wheat crop two or three times,&quot; he said. &quot;I think we're going to see more of this volatility in the next six weeks, until we get through until about October.&quot;</p>
<p>World wheat markets seem unlikely to be affected by the Australian wheat outcome, despite the high degree of uncertainty surrounding the 1997/98 crop.</p>
<p>Brendan Hillary of ANZ Futures estimates Australia would have to produce less than 11 million tonnes for it to have a big impact on world prices.  </p>
<p>And the AWB's Flugge is quite optimistic about the world market overall.</p>
<p>He sees significantly higher prices at the end of the year, buoyed by strong demand.</p>
<p>The AWB's view of the wheat world in 1997/98 is for Egypt to increase its imports by 300,000 tonnes to 6.9 million tonnes, Pakistan to increase its imports by two million tonnes to five million tonnes, India to boost its imports by a further 1.4 million tonnes to three million tonnes, and Iraq to increase its imports by 1.8 million tonnes to three million tonnes.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
