<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758606" id="root" date="1997-07-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CONSENSUS-Australian economic forecasts.</title>
<headline>CONSENSUS-Australian economic forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following Australian economic</p>
<p>indicators and events are scheduled for this week.</p>
<p>  DAY  TIME   Indicator		 Period   Forecast   Previous</p>
<p>  Tue  0130  Goods/services balance   Jun	n/a    +A$873 mln</p>
<p>  Wed  0130  Building Approvals	 Jun     -1.5	+2.2 pct</p>
<p>  Thu  0130  Retail Trade		 Jun     +0.4	+2.9 pct</p>
<p>  Thu  0130  Retail Trade		 Q2	+0.1	+2.2 pct</p>
<p>  Thu  0230  Treasurer Costello at Economic Society, Melbourne</p>
<p>------------------Calendar for August 4 week--------------------</p>
<p>  Tue	  RBA board meeting	  Aug</p>
<p>  Tue  0130  Housing material prices  Jun</p>
<p>  Tue  0130  Building material prices Jun</p>
<p>  Thu  0130  Employment		   Jul		  +11,900</p>
<p>  Thu  0130  Unemployment		 Jul		    8.5 pct</p>
<p>  Fri  0130  Housing finance	    Jun		   -8.4 pct</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>    QUESTION OF THE WEEK - Following this week's benign</p>
<p>inflation report for the second quarter, which saw the policy</p>
<p>sensitive annual underlying rate fall below the Reserve Bank's</p>
<p>2.0-3.0 percent target at 1.7 percent, economists were asked</p>
<p>when would it get back to the danger level of 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>    The June quarter reading was yet another factor suggesting</p>
<p>that the Reserve Bank would ease policy again and the markets</p>
<p>have largely factored in an easing of 50 basis points from the</p>
<p>current level of 5.5 percent after the August board meeting.</p>
<p>    The jury is still out as to whether this will be the last in</p>
<p>the cycle, although this week's data showing a fall to 3.7</p>
<p>percent in the annual rate of wages growth does suggest that a</p>
<p>low inflation environment is entrenched for now.</p>
<p>    And given economists' forecasts for future inflation growth</p>
<p>it looks as if the RBA will have little to worry about over</p>
<p>inflation pressures in the near future and policy could be on</p>
<p>hold for some time once interest rates have bottomed.</p>
<p>    Forecasts were generally fairly evenly spread over 1999,</p>
<p>although some estimates were looking towards the end of 1998</p>
<p>with the stimulus from the RBA's current easing bias beginning</p>
<p>to impact on economic growth going into 1997 year-end</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>	    *Trade    Building   Retail    Sales    Inflation</p>
<p>	    surplus   Approvals   sales     Q2	at 3.0 pct</p>
<p>Access	  n/f	  n/f	 n/f     flat	Q1-99</p>
<p>AMP	    1.0 bln    +3.0	+0.5     +0.2	Q2-99</p>
<p>ANZ Bank     2.1 bln    -3.0	+0.5     +0.2	H2 99</p>
<p>ANZ Secs     2.2 bln    -2.0	+1.0     +0.7	Q4 99</p>
<p>Axiom	  1.315 bln  +3.0	+1.5     +0.8	Q3 98</p>
<p>BT	     1.5 bln    -2.0	flat     -0.2	mid-99</p>
<p>BZW	    2.048 bln  -1.1	+0.3     -0.1	Q3 98</p>
<p>Citibank    *300m	 -5.0	flat     flat	Q1-99</p>
<p>Col State    1.6 bln    +3.5	+0.4     +0.1	Q1-99</p>
<p>Comm Bank    1.6 bln    +2.0	-0.5     -0.1     late 99</p>
<p>County	 n/f	  -2.0	+0.5     +0.5     late 98</p>
<p>DMG	    1.7 bln    -2.5	-1.5     -0.4     late 99</p>
<p>Dresdner     2.2 bln    -2.0	-0.5	n/a not before Q1-99</p>
<p>GIO	   *887 mln    +1.1	+0.4     +0.2	H1-99</p>
<p>HSBC	   1.9 bln     n/a	 n/a	n/a	1999</p>
<p>JP Morgan    2.0 bln    -2	  flat     flat	H2-99</p>
<p>Merrill	2.1 bln    -2.7	-0.2     flat	1999</p>
<p>Macquarie    1.8 bln    -1.5	+0.5     +0.1	1999</p>
<p>Nat Mutual   1.5 bln    +6.0	+0.8     +0.6	 NF</p>
<p>Nomura	 n/f	   n/f	-0.2     -0.3	Q2-99</p>
<p>Pru Bache   *350 mln     n/a	+0.6     +0.1     late 98</p>
<p>Rothschild  *520 mln    -1.5	+0.6     flat	Q3-98</p>
<p>SBC	    2.0 bln    -4.0	-0.5     +0.4     mid-99</p>
<p>Soc Gen	n/a	  flat	flat     -0.5     mid-99</p>
<p>Schroders    n/a	  flat	+0.5     flat	1999</p>
<p>UBS	    1.2 bln    -5.5	+0.3     +0.1	H2-99</p>
<p>Westpac	1.0	  +5.0	+0.5     -0.5	1999</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>    Low	see	  -5.5	-1.5     -0.5</p>
<p>    High     note	 +6.0	+1.5     +0.8</p>
<p>    Average  n/a	  -0.6	+0.2     +0.1</p>
<p>    Median   n/a	  -1.5	+0.4     +0.1</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>    *Forecasts do not include any estimate for gold sale effect</p>
<p>    BALANCE OF GOODS AND SERVICES - Estimating the June figures</p>
<p>with any confidence is almost impossible since the Bureau of</p>
<p>Statistics is including part of the Reserve Bank's sale of gold</p>
<p>in the data as an export, and no forecast has been given as a</p>
<p>result. The exact sum is not known but the RBA has said some 125</p>
<p>tonnes of gold had been sold forward for June delivery and</p>
<p>another 42 tonnes spread over August and September.</p>
<p>    Thus should ensure the largest goods surplus on record</p>
<p>although analysts are unclear how the sale will be accounted for</p>
<p>since the RBA used the funds received to buy foreign bonds of an</p>
<p>equal amount, thus implying little net change in reserves.</p>
<p>    It was likely the gold sale would boost the net export</p>
<p>contribution to GDP, but be exactly martched by a corresponding</p>
<p>fall in stocks which would detract from growth.</p>
<p>    There was also some uncertainty over the underlying position</p>
<p>with some economists expecting a hefty rise in imports of up to</p>
<p>15 percent which would have produced a deficit without the gold</p>
<p>impact. Analysts also believed there were planes worth around</p>
<p>A$200 million in imports and noted a ship worth A$500 million</p>
<p>had inflated exports in May.</p>
<p>    BUILDING APPROVALS - This series has also been complicated by the inclusion of the Olympic Village in the May figures which substantially boosted the measure -- excluding this approvals would have fallen around 12 percent instead of rising 2.2</p>
<p>percent. A rise in June, therefore, would imply a substantial bounce back in normal approvals, that is not tied to a special project, of around 1,500 units. Even a modest fall would not be that weak so interpreting the figures will take some tact.</p>
<p>    RETAIL SALES - Probably the most important release of the week given the very erratic performance of sales in April and May -- a 1.7 percent fall followed by a 2.9 percent rise -- and the market's obsession with interest rates just now. The wide range of forecasts reflects this volatility as well as uncertainty about the state of consumer demand in general.</p>
<p>    Analysts noted vehicle sales were up very strongly in the month -- registrations were at a record high -- and consumer sentiment looked to have improved following the cut in official rates of May 23.</p>
<p>    A rise on the month would be a firm result given May's jump but it would have to be strong indeed to make the market re-think its expectation of an official rate cut in the near future. Sale volumes in the quarter should be supported by the very low level of the retail trade deflator, but not be enough to see much a real rise on top of the hefty 2.2 percent gain recorded in Q1.     -- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800 (c) Reuters Limited 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
