<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758683" id="root" date="1997-07-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran inaugurates $2 billion Bandar Abbas oil refinery.</title>
<headline>Iran inaugurates $2 billion Bandar Abbas oil refinery.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-07-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani on Saturday inaugurated the country's eighth oil refinery, located near the Gulf port of Bandar Abbas.</p>
<p>Calling it &quot;the largest heavy crude refinery in the world,&quot; Iranian state television said the $2 billion plant would produce oil products worth $5.5 million a day.</p>
<p>It said investment in the plant had included $1.5 billion in hard currency and 1,600 billion rials ($530 million).</p>
<p>Iran's Oil Minister Gholamreza Aghazadeh said at an OPEC meeting in June that the plant's full capacity of 232,000 barrels per day would be reached in September.</p>
<p>The refinery will be export-oriented but will also supply middle distillates to the growing domestic market.</p>
<p>Bandar Abbas director Ibrahim Zamanzadeh was quoted this month as saying that Iran would not need to import gasoline, kerosene and diesel fuel after March 1998, when the plant's two distillation units are expected to be running at full capacity.</p>
<p>Officials have said the refinery would produce 46,100 bpd of gasoline, 36,200 barrels of kerosene and jet fuel, 69,500 barrels of gas oil, 66,500 barrels of heavy fuel oil, 7,100 bpd of liquefied petroleum gas, 5,000 barrels of tar and 124 tons of sulphur a day.</p>
<p>The Middle East Economic Survey newsletter said this week that the National Iranian Oil Company had begun to offer fuel oil export cargoes from the new refinery after testing one of the plant's two crude distillation units.</p>
<p>Iran's Ettelaat daily said on Saturday the plant created jobs for 1,200 people. The paper said that in addition to the refinery, a large project had been completed to provide water from the sea to the refinery.</p>
<p>Iran, a member of the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries, ranks after Saudi Arabia and Norway as the world's largest crude exporter,with an OPEC quota of 3.6 million bpd.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
