<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758755" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks seen trending higher at open.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks seen trending higher at open.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>CHANGE				     CHANGE</p>
<p>TSE(CLS)  6780.27   -4.88   HI 6803.71	    LO  6773.66</p>
<p>DJI(CLS)  8113.44   -3.49   GOLD (LONDON)   US$325.40  +1.30</p>
<p>FTSE	4855.50   +4.00   GOLD (COMEX)    US$326.10  -0.40</p>
<p>NIKKEI   20575.26 +185.72   LME CASH NICKEL US$7150	0.0</p>
<p>CANDLR     1.3850	     LME CASH ALUM   US$1689.5  +71.5</p>
<p>CAN 30-YR  120.04   -0.05   BRENT CRUDE     US$18.63   +0.10</p>
<p>---------------------MARKET COMMENT--------------------------</p>
<p>Toronto stocks were seen headed higher at Monday's open after closing mixed on Friday as investors eye a big week for economic news. * Second quarter earnings seen wrapping up.  </p>
<p>Toronto's key stock index was seen firming at Monday's open, with investors expected to forsake the formerly high-flying interest-sensitive equities in favor of resource-based issues, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the overall market in Toronto will still do a little better,&quot; one trader said. &quot;There's going to be value-pickers out there and it'll lean into resource-based stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>As second quarter earnings wind down this week, market players will focus on a slew of U.S. and Canadian economic earnings, staring on Tuesday, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think we'll start to focus again on economics and this week will be a good week,&quot; another trader said. Tuesday's statistics include the U.S. second quarter employment cost index and Canada's Industrial Product Price Index for June.</p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange's 300 Composite Index slipped 4.88 points to 6780.27 by Friday's close, snapping a three-day winning streak based on rallying bank issues. But it still managed to set an intraday and life-time high of 6803.71 points.</p>
<p>Golds and forestry issues are expected to pick up where banks left off, the first trader said.</p>
<p>--- STOCKS TO WATCH ---</p>
<p>* Despite a slackening in the pace of quarterly earnings, the Western world's largest nickel miner Inco Ltd is expected to report second quarter earnings today. Analysts forecast a profit of US$0.16 a share versus year-earlier US$0.47</p>
<p>* Financially troubled Repap Enterprises Inc said early on Monday that its second quarter loss widened to C$0.39 a share, including a C$30.3 million charge for discontinued operations, from C$0.35 a year ago.</p>
<p>The paper maker also said it would issue 625 million common shares to repay its US$130 million 8.5 percent convertible debentures due August 1. Repap currently has about 123 million common shares outstanding.</p>
<p>* Gulf Canada Resources Ltd on Monday announced it would acquire Stampeder Exploration Ltd in a friendly stock-swap worth about C$1.0 billion.</p>
<p>Also, analysts said interest would shift to natural resource sectors after last week's rally on the back of interest-sensitive issues including banks.</p>
<p>Ten of Toronto's 14 sub-sectors took the higher road, led by golds, base metals, media and pipelines.</p>
<p>The weaker groups included conglomerates and oils.</p>
<p>At the open winning issues outpaced decliners 208 to 197 while 199 traded flat.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Energy firm Stampeder Exploration Ltd jumped 1 to 6.70 on 2.5 million shares after it said on Monday that it would be acquired by Gulf Canada Resources Ltd in a friendly stock-swap worth about C$1 billion.</p>
<p>Gulf said it would offer 0.69124 of a share for each Stampeder share for a value of C$7.50 a share. Gulf slipped 0.80 to 10 in heavy trading.</p>
<p>* Money-losing Repap Enterprises Inc fell 0.075 to 0.195 after reporting its second quarter loss widened to C$0.39 a share, including a C$30.3 million charge for discontinued operations, from C$0.35 a year ago.</p>
<p>* Gandalf, which was re-opened for trading after Friday's halt, dropped 0.51 to 0.47 following last week's news that it filed for creditor protection and would reorganize.</p>
<p>((Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8109))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
