<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="758858" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Andrx says product launch to boost earnings.</title>
<headline>Andrx says product launch to boost earnings.</headline>
<dateline>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pharmaceutical company Andrx Corp on Monday said its first product launch, due to occur in the latter half of this year, should be accretive to earnings.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, Dr. Elliot Hahn, president of Andrx, said he did not want to assign a numerical amount to the projected earnings increase, but the product launch would &quot;definitely&quot; boost earnings. The product he was referring to is a version of Dilacor XR, a drug licensed to Watson Pharmaceuticals Inc and used to treat hypertension and angina.  </p>
<p>Andrx said it is currently developing generic versions of some brand name pharmaceuticals while also developing its own brand name formulations of certain existing drugs that it believes may be improved through its own drug delivery technologies. Andrx researches controlled-released drugs and distributes generic drugs produced by third parties.</p>
<p>The company said it had created the manufacturing and sales infrastructure needed to support the Dilacor XR product launch and it had also raised additional capital to &quot;aggressively pursue our product development activities and future growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Andrx posted a second quarter loss of $0.16 per share for the second quarter of 1997, compared with a loss of $0.10 per share for the year-ago period.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
