<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759008" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Indexes quiet ahead of data.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Indexes quiet ahead of data.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading in major U.S. index options slowed on Monday as traders awaited the week's line-up of economic data that culminates Friday with the July employment report.</p>
<p>&quot;It is quiet. For a change,&quot; one S&amp;P 500 .SPX and S&amp;P 100 .OEX options trader in Chicago said. He noted that through midsession, S&amp;P 500 futures had traded in a relatively narrow range.</p>
<p>By about 1150 CST/1650 GMT, September S&amp;P 500 futures were up 1.90 at 946.80. It traded between 943.80 and 949.35.  </p>
<p>The spot SPX was up 2.41 at 941.20 and the OEX added 2.67 to 920.49. The Dow industrials .DJI were up 35 at 8,148.</p>
<p>Traders will be watching the second quarter employment cost index and some retail sales reports scheduled for Tuesday, followed by June new home sales on Wednesday and the Chicago purchasing managers survey on Thursday.</p>
<p>The July jobless report is scheduled for Friday, when June personal income and consumption data are also due.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be interesting,&quot; Jay Shartsis, head of options trading at R.F. Lafferty &amp; Co, said of the market's reaction to the jobs report.  </p>
<p>Economists on average expect a rise in payroll employment of 193,000, compared with 217,000 in June.</p>
<p>The unemployment rate is expected to drop to 4.9 percent from 5.0 percent and average hourly earnings are forecast to be up 0.2 percent against the 0.3 percent rise in June.</p>
<p>Traders said few index trades were noteworthy, with volatilities generally holding firm but not moving much with the market chopping around in tight ranges.</p>
<p>The index trader added, however, that the ranges could widen in the afternoon as has been happening frequently. That would expand volatilities.  </p>
<p>Jerry Hegarty, an options analyst at Thomson Financial Services, said he expected the market's roller coaster action to continue through Wednesday.</p>
<p>Shartsis said one potential sign the market may be set for a correction was the action in Dell Computer Corp, which was down sharply on its first post-split session.</p>
<p>Dell was off 1-1/2 at 80 after falling to 77. The stock closed at 163 last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;When the split (stocks) start acting badly, watch out,&quot; Shartsis said. &quot;They have been the leading edge&quot; of the market's rally.</p>
<p>((Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
