<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759091" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: SOCCER-FIFA GIVES CHECKS TO GUATEMALA SOCCER VICTIMS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FIFA GIVES CHECKS TO GUATEMALA SOCCER VICTIMS.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The families of 78 Guatemalans crushed to death in an overcrowded soccer stadium last year received a check for $6,500 each on Monday from FIFA, the international soccer authority.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want tragedies. But whenever they happen in World Cup football (soccer) we feel we should indemnify the victims and their families,&quot; said Jack Warner, a FIFA vice president who travelled from New York to distribute the checks.</p>
<p>Overcrowding triggered a human avalanche in the cheap seating section of Guatemala City's Mateo Flores stadium on October 16 just minutes before a World Cup qualifying match between Costa Rica and Guatemala.</p>
<p>It was the worst tragedy in the history of soccer's World Cup competition.</p>
<p>Warner said the extent of the tragedy affected him deeply.</p>
<p>&quot;I spoke to one family today who lost five members. A few thousand U.S. dollars could never pay for that. The mother was crying. She was still burdened. After it I couldn't continue, I had to excuse myself,&quot; Warner said.</p>
<p>The checks may seem small by the standards of developed nations, but many of the families who lost people in the tragedy were very poor and $6,500 could represent more than double the yearly income of one person.</p>
<p>Warner said the money for the families came out of a &quot;fair play&quot; fund that pools fines against members for penalties and rule infractions.</p>
<p>He said 25 families didn't show up on Monday for checks, but local sports authorities have six months to find them and give them their checks.</p>
<p>Despite Monday's check-giving, the families will continue to seek undetermined damages from the government and sports authorities blamed in the tragedy.</p>
<p>&quot;This is humanitarian aid from FIFA and it is completely separate from the compensation we've asked for from the courts,&quot; said Rene Cordoba, the attorney representing most of the families in a civil suit against the state and soccer event organisers.</p>
<p>A presidential commission investigated the tragedy and found extreme overcrowding, no emergency plan and no crowd control devices led to the worst tragedy in World Cup history.</p>
<p>FIFA ordered the stadium closed after the tragedy but in April granted permission for reopening after the Guatemalan Soccer Federation made changes to guarantee security for fans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
