<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759071" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RUGBY UNION-SMITH CHANGES HIS MIND ON KNOX.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-SMITH CHANGES HIS MIND ON KNOX.</headline>
<byline>Robert Galvin</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia on Monday recalled veteran fly-half David Knox to their squad for this weekend's Tri-Nations rugby union test against South Africa in a remarkable change of heart by coach Greg Smith.</p>
<p>Knox will interrupt a playing stint with South African province Natal to join a 22-man Wallaby squad for Saturday's Brisbane test after Tim Horan was ruled out with a broken hand.</p>
<p>Australia are to make at least two other changes from the side beaten 33-18 by New Zealand in a Tri-Nations test on Saturday after dropping back rower Michael Brial and losing full-back Matt Burke to injury.</p>
<p>Smith has repeatedly cited Knox's lack of defensive strength as the reason behind his decision to ignore the ACT Brumbies' goal-kicker this season.</p>
<p>But in a sudden turnaround on Monday, Smith said in a statement: &quot;With the injury to Tim Horan's hand, Knox is an automatic choice for the Wallaby fly-half position.&quot;</p>
<p>Yet in comments reported in The Australian newspaper earlier in the day, Smith said selecting Knox would prove too great a risk because of his supposed defensive weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we can afford to (select Knox). He's a non-tackler,&quot; Smith was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>The 33-year-old goal-kicker last played for Australia on the tour to Britain late last year but had failed to earn a place in any of Smith's squads for tests against England, France and New Zealand so far this season.</p>
<p>Brial's demotion appeared inevitable from the moment Smith singled out the back rower for blame after the All Blacks demolished the Wallabies in Melbourne to lift the Bledisloe Cup.</p>
<p>Veteran Troy Coker was expected to come into the side at number eight, with Stephen Larkham replacing Burke at full-back.</p>
<p>In justifying his previous selection decisions, Smith has repeatedly argued that Knox's acknowledged attacking talent did not compensate for his defensive frailty.</p>
<p>Smith, under intense pressure to keep his job next season, looked instead to Horan's tackling strength and ability to run directly at defenders.</p>
<p>But the selection policy caused widespread misgivings, with critics questioning Horan's suitability by citing concerns about the slow speed of his passing and the lack of a kicking game.</p>
<p>Knox, 33, a proven goal-kicker, enjoyed an outstanding season for ACT Brumbies in the Super 12 competition, helping the province to a losing final against Auckland in May.</p>
<p>Both South Africa and Australia lost to New Zealand in their opening Tri-Nations matches.</p>
<p>Australia squad:</p>
<p>Forwards - Richard Harry, Michael Foley, Marco Caputo, Andrew Heath, Andrew Blades, Garrick Morgan, John Eales (captain), Matt Cockbain, Brett Robinson, David Wilson, Daniel Manu, Troy Coker.</p>
<p>Backs - George Gregan, Sam Payne, David Knox, Elton Flatley, James Holbeck, Jason Little, Joe Roff, Ben Tune, Mitch Hardy, Stephen Larkham.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
