<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759110" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SOCCER-L.A. GALAXY WIN FIFTH CONSECUTIVE GAME.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-L.A. GALAXY WIN FIFTH CONSECUTIVE GAME.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER, Colorado 1997-07-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Harut Karapetyan broke a 1-1 tie with five minutes remaining to lift the surging Los Angeles Galaxy to their fifth consecutive win, a 2-1 victory over the Colorado Rapids in Major League Soccer action on Sunday.</p>
<p>Brazilian Welton also scored for the Galaxy (9-11), while Chris Henderson converted a penalty kick for the Rapids (10-12).</p>
<p>In East Rutherford, New Jersey, Colombian international Antony De Avila set up the equaliser and scored the game-winner with eight minutes remaining to give the New York/New Jersey MetroStars (7-12) a 2-1 victory over D.C. United (14-7).</p>
<p>U.S. national team captain John Harkes had given United a 1-0 lead in the 60th minute, but Venezuelan forward Giovanni Savarese tied it 11 minutes later.</p>
<p>In Columbus, Ohio, the Tampa Bay Mutiny (12-10) survived a scoreless tie in regulation and a shootout with the Columbus Crew (8-12) to register a 1-0 win. The Mutiny outscored the Crew in the tie-breaker, 3-1.</p>
<p>In other weekend action, in Washington, D.C., Bolivian international midfielder Marco Etcheverry scored his first goal of the year, with two minutes remaining in regulation, and converted a shootout attempt as United snapped a two-game losing game with a 2-1 win over Columbus.</p>
<p>Kris Kelderman and Roy Wegerle also scored in the tie-breaker as goalkeeper Scott Garlick made one save. Raul Diaz Arce had his MLS record point streak snapped at 10 games.</p>
<p>Pete Marino scored the lone goal for the Crew, who have lost nine of their last 11 games.</p>
<p>In Dallas, Ecuadoran Eduardo Hurtado scored twice in the second half to spark the Los Angeles Galaxy to their fourth consecutive victory, a 3-0 triumph over the Dallas Burn (12-10), who had their four-game winning streak snapped.</p>
<p>El Salvadoran Mauricio Cienfuegos scored the Galaxy's first goal, and Mexican goalkeeper Jorge Campos set up Hurtado's first score, knocking down a cross and dribbling to midfield before he gave the ball to Hurtado, who fired in a 30-yard shot.</p>
<p>In San Jose, California, former U.S. international defender Steve Trittchuh and Mexican David Patino scored early and late in the opening half, respectively, to give the Colorado Rapids a 2-1 win over the San Jose Clash (7-15).</p>
<p>El Salvadoran Ron Cerritos extended his point streak to eight games by assisting on a goal by Clash teammate Chris Sullivan. The Clash, who have the league's worst record, have dropped four straight matches.</p>
<p>In Kansas City, Missouri, the Wizards (14-7), who were stunned by the third division San Francisco Bay Seals in the third round of the U.S. Open Cup on Thursday, managed to rebound with a 1-0 shootout victory over the New England Revolution (12-9).</p>
<p>The Wizards won the tie-breaker, 4-3, after playing to a scoreless tie in regulation. Matt McKeon, Mark Chung, Paul Wright and Preki converted their shootout chances.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER, Colorado"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
