<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759215" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Guatemala debut bond priced at tight end of range.</title>
<headline>Guatemala debut bond priced at tight end of range.</headline>
<byline>Hayley Pienaar</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Guatemala on Monday launched its first international bond issue and impressed market participants by obtaining a lower spread level than veteran borrowers like Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;The Guatemala pricing is right on the button,&quot; an emerging markets debt trader said, adding investors were eager to buy longer-dated paper.</p>
<p>The $150 million 10-year bond was priced to yield 240 basis points over U.S. Treasury notes, at the tighter end of the indicated 240-250 b.p. range.</p>
<p>Bankers in the syndicate group said the bond was almost three times oversubscribed following successful roadshows in Europe and the U.S.</p>
<p>BankBoston is lead manager of the transaction.</p>
<p>Dealers said it was unusual that a debut transaction should be priced tighter than where similarly rated 10-year paper for Mexico and Venezuela traded in the secondary market.</p>
<p>But the rarity of Guatemala's paper, the limited amount of fresh supply at present, the country's status as a large central American economy and optimism about prospects after the end of a civil war boosted demand.</p>
<p>Added to this, the relatively small size of the transaction enabled it to achieve cheaper funding levels, bankers said.</p>
<p>Guatemala is rated Ba2 by Moody's Investors Service which the ratings agency said reflected the country's improved macroeconomic outlook and its low external debt levels, as well as positive effects from completion of the peace agreements.</p>
<p>Mexico's 9.875 percent 10-year bond (rated Ba2) was priced to yield 335 b.p. over U.S Treasury notes in January and was last trading around 255 b.p, dealers said.</p>
<p>Venezuela's 9.125 percent 2007 bond (rated Ba2) was bid at around 272 basis points on Monday, versus a launch spread of 265 b.p. in June, dealers said.</p>
<p>Panama's (rated Ba1) 7.875 percent 2002 bond was trading at around the February launch level of 175 b.p. over, while Argentina's 11.0 percent 2006 bond (rated B1) was trading around 249 b.p. over on Monday versus a 445 b.p. launch spread in October last year.</p>
<p>Guatemala's debut bond will not be increased in size. Last week Guatemalan officials said the country planned to use revenues from the bond to finance government investment programs.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7718</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
