<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759389" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Officials keep eastern Germany on evacuation alert.</title>
<headline>Officials keep eastern Germany on evacuation alert.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BLEYEN, Germany 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eastern Germany's flood-threatened Oderbruch farming region was kept on red alert for possible evacuation on Monday but many residents vowed to stay put.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is in no way stable and the dangers aren't over by a long way,&quot; said Manfred Stolpe, the premier of Brandenburg, the German state worst hit by the floods.</p>
<p>Some of central Europe's worst floods this century have claimed 55 lives in Poland and 49 in the Czech Republic so far this month. Germany has so far escaped the worst of the disaster and has so far suffer no loss of life as a result of the floods.</p>
<p>On the other side of the Oder from Germany in Poland, where the river is known as the Odra, officials said the town of Slubice, from which 15,000 people were evacuated at the weekend as a surge approached, had survived the onslaught. But they added that a fresh surge was expected soon.</p>
<p>Farther south in the Czech Republic, officials said floodwaters were receding and little rain was forecast for the first part of the week.</p>
<p>Germany's Oderbruch basin is particularly vulnerable as it lies below the level of the swollen Oder, protected only by a 70 km (45 mile) section of dike. Officials said the water level there was rising by between one and two centimetres (less than an inch) per hour.</p>
<p>Nearly 5,000 people were evacuated from the most endangered area near the German village of Hohenwutzen at the north end of the region on Friday, and 9,000 were &quot;sitting on their suitcases&quot; in 24 villages which have been put on alert for possible evacuation.</p>
<p>A fresh wave of high water was expected to roll down the Oder, which forms part of Germany's border with Poland, in the course of the day. But residents said they planned to stay in their homes.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not leaving. Where am I supposed to bring all my animals?&quot; said Waltrud Wassenberg, who was walking a German shepherd dog through her fields to view a large lake where water had seeped through the dike just a few hundred metres (yards) from her home.</p>
<p>Other residents in the village of Bleyen said water cresting near the top of the dike was not unusual in this area.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been living here for 30 years. The water levels are normal,&quot; said Rudi Goellnitz, one of the many dike inspectors who walk up and down the dam placing yellow flags in the ground where water is seeping through so that soldiers and civilian emergency workers can spot areas that need reinforcing with sandbags.</p>
<p>Goellnitz said the only people to have left his village was a young couple who hadn't lived in the area very long.</p>
<p>In the nearby village of Genschmar, people also seemed reluctant to go and accused the media of over-dramatising the situation. &quot;I'm going to stay as long as I can,&quot; said Helga Mehding, who moved to the village from Berlin four years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I have nowhere else to go,&quot; she said. &quot;Everything I own is here. Where else should I go?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The main task at the moment is to build up defences and to deploy all forces to prevent the worst happening,&quot; Brandenberg state's Stolpe told German Radio. Thousands of soldiers have already been deployed in the country's biggest post-World War Two relief operation.</p>
<p>Seven years after German unification, officials say flood damage could destroy many eastern Germans financially, just as they are starting to get on their feet.</p>
<p>Large sections of the dike protecting the Oderbruch have collapsed over the past few days. A 30 km (19 mile) section between Kienitz in the south and Hohenwutzen is particularly threatened.</p>
<p>The highest water levels in Oderbruch were registered in 1940, when measuring stations in Hohensaaten, near Hohenwutzen, reported 7.78 metres, (25.51 Feet) compared to 6.94 metres (22.76 feet) now.</p>
<p>Farther south, there have been three breaks in the dike over the past few days, flooding towns. The worst hit areas in Germany were Brieskow-Finkenheerd, Wiesenau and Ziltendorf.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLEYEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
