<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759477" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Unibanka stays in focus on mixed Latvian bourse.</title>
<headline>Unibanka stays in focus on mixed Latvian bourse.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading bank Unibanka maintained its dominance on the Latvian bourse on Monday and dealers expect it to remain the focus of attention in the wake of the auction of one million of the state's shares in the bank.</p>
<p>Other shares were mixed and dealers said the market's direction was unclear.</p>
<p>Overall market volume was 72,000 lats and the Rietumu index slipped 0.47 percent to 148.94.</p>
<p>Three of the six official list stocks gained and three held steady.</p>
<p>Unibanka rose to 3.21 lats from 3.19 lats in trade of 33,300 lats.</p>
<p>Dealers expect it to rise further after one million of the state's shares in the bank were auctioned at 3.22 lats per share on Monday. &quot;Its real price is 3.40 lats to 3.50 lats,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>On the secondary list, Jekabpils Sugar, which leapt last week on the strength of its unexpectedly high half year profit figures, eased to 66 santimes from 70 santimes.</p>
<p>Given the seasonal nature of the sugar industry, dealers do not expect its second half results to be as impressive.</p>
<p>Valmiera Glass Fibre factory eased to 1.36 lats from 1.37 lats in trade of 10,500 lats.</p>
<p>The bourse announced on Monday that Valmiera's net profit was 416,050 lats but dealers said it would not have much impact on its price.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the result) won't push its price up very much...much of its profit is being reinvested into construction and it is not expected to pay dividends this year,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>-- Ed Stoddard, Riga newsroom +371 722 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
