<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="75940" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: Business quietens at Malta exchange.</title>
<headline>Business quietens at Malta exchange.</headline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading was quiet on the Malta Stock Exchange on Wednesday, although the share index rose by 2.52 points to reach 1003.70.</p>
<p>Turnover slumped to Lm185,000 in the once-weekly trading session from Lm948,000 the week before.</p>
<p>Business in equities amounted to just over Lm50,200, with 43,264 shares changing hands. Of these, 25,013 were Bank of Valletta shares which were sold in 20 deals for an average of 129.9 cents, unchanged from last week.</p>
<p>Mid-Med Bank shares continued their rise, with 600 shares selling for an average of 151.8 from 150.6 cents the week before.</p>
<p>There were two deals in Lombard Bank Malta with 2,219 shares selling for an average 139.5 cents, unchanged. Four deals were struck in Middle Sea Insurance with 6,440 shares selling at an average 121.2 cents, up slightly from 120.6 last week.</p>
<p>Simonds Farsons Cisk saw 6,800 ordinary shares sold for an average 55 cents per share, unchanged. In the Farsons 8.5 percent preference shares 1996-99, 2,192 shares traded at an average price of Lm1 per share, the same price as when last traded on July 10.</p>
<p>In the government bond market, 11 issues were dealt in, turnover reaching Lm124,908. Business was mainly in the 7.25 percent MGS 2006 (II).</p>
<p>In corporate bonds, there were two deals in the Mid-Med Bank 7.25 percent unsecured loan stock 2005 amounting to Lm1,881 and two in the 6.5 percent Gasan Bonds amounting to just over Lm7,923. (One Maltese lira = $2.76)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
