<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759542" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - ROMANIA - JULY 28.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - ROMANIA - JULY 28.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>BURSA</p>
<p>- A decision on privatising the Bacau-based Rafo oil refinery will be made next month, the newspaper says.</p>
<p>- Wheat has been harvested only on 42 percent of the planted area, down from estimates that the whole wheat crop would be taken in by end July, the newspaper quotes a farming ministry survey as showing.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Mircea Ciumara submitted a first draft of the planned budget revision to a cabinet meeting on Friday, the newspaper says. The government is expected to discuss the revised budget at a meeting on Monday.</p>
<p>- Starting in September, telephone charges will undergo quarterly adjustments for inflation, the newspaper quotes a communications ministry official as saying.</p>
<p>- Rain and chronic shortages of combine harvesters, delayed wheat harvesting, the newspaper says.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- Romania's Petrom oil authority wants to use the commodities exchange to trade domestically-produced oil, the newspaper says.</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Andrei Dimitriu, chairman of the Romanian Development Agency, says in an interview that Romania's plans to draw in foreign investments would be jeopardised if the agency were scrapped.</p>
<p>- A German bank branch will soon open in the Transylvanian city of Sibiu, the newspaper says.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>- ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Cluj police identified three workers employed by local public utilities as the persons who removed the flag from the Hungarian consulate in the city, the newspaper says.</p>
<p>- Romania has turned into a conduit for illegal immigrants, says a newspaper report.</p>
<p>- The northeast city of Iasi is hosting the first pan-European meeting of Non-Smokers held in an East European ex-Communist country. Iasi has been picked up because its mayor has banned smoking in all public buildings, the newspaper says.</p>
<p>- With a delay of one year and a half, the scaffolding on the Hotel Athenee Palace, taken over by Hilton, comes down today.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- After Poland and the Czech Republic, floods also threaten Romania, the newspaper says, reporting that 1,000 hectares have been flooded in the western Arad county.</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Romanian truckers' STAR labour federation will stage protests in Bucharest Wednesday. The protesters plan to drive their trucks, horns blaring, across the capital from 9 a.m. to 1 p.m. to protest against a new road tax.</p>
<p>-- Bucharest Newsroom, 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
