<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759693" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine bonds rangebound in muted trading.</title>
<headline>Argentine bonds rangebound in muted trading.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine bonds were little changed in quiet trading Monday, with players awaiting the release of a slew of U.S. economic indicators starting Tuesday, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;So far things have been very quiet because everyone's waiting for the U.S. data,&quot; a dealer at a leading foreign bank said. &quot;Prices are underpinned by the prevailing optimistic trading environment in New York and strength in the local futures market.&quot;</p>
<p>Argentina's FRB Brady bond due 2005 was flat at 95-1/4 while the dollar-denominated Bocon Previsional 4 due 2002 dipped $0.10 to 118.65.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the U.S. indicators, starting with the release of the Employment Cost Index tomorrow, will be good,&quot; another dealer said. &quot;U.S. long bond yields are likely to stay below 6.5 percent this week, guaranteeing strong liquidity in the local markets.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. new home sales numbers were also due out Tuesday while gross domestic product estimates will be released Wednesday and July nonfarm payrolls Friday.</p>
<p>Traders said no new local news was affecting the market although the strong performance of the Argentine economy in the second quarter remained a key positive factor.</p>
<p>((-- Carmen Pignotti, Buenos Aires Newsroom 541 318-0657))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
