<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759662" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Steady path seen at Banco de Mexico with new chief.</title>
<headline>Steady path seen at Banco de Mexico with new chief.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kozak</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The two most widely mentioned front runners to replace the present governor of Banco de Mexico would bring only subtle changes to central bank policy, economists said.</p>
<p>Current governor Miguel Mancera -- according to some the world's longest-serving central banker -- retires at the end of the year, and one of his two deputies, Francisco Gil Diaz or Jose Sidaoui, is widely expected to take over.  </p>
<p>&quot;The two front runners are Gil Diaz and Sidaoui and they would not signal much of a change,&quot; Mexico City economist Jonathan Heath said.</p>
<p>Analysts expect Mancera to have a strong influence on his replacement, but the final decision will come from President Ernesto Zedillo, himself a former central bank economist.</p>
<p>The choice will then have to be ratified by the Senate, which is controlled by his long-ruling Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI).  </p>
<p>Central bank watchers say that Sidaoui is perceived to have the strong support of the Finance Ministry and is believed to be close to Zedillo, while Gil Diaz has the benefit of many years at the central bank and is considered a hard-core monetarist and inflation hawk.</p>
<p>Sidaoui was originally hired at the central bank in 1979. He became a deputy governor in January this year, moving over from the Finance Ministry where he was deputy finance minister from late 1994.</p>
<p>Analysts say the intention may have been to put him in a position to be promoted to the bank's top slot.  </p>
<p>&quot;The most probable replacement is Sidaoui. My feeling is that he is a close friend of Zedillo,&quot; said ING Barings economist Sergio Martin, adding that it would be very difficult for someone to come in from outside the bank.</p>
<p>Gil Diaz has a doctorate from the University of Chicago. He has held several high-level posts at the central bank as well as posts at the Finance Ministry, both in economic studies and in the revenue sector.</p>
<p>He is seen as being closely identified with Mancera, which analysts say may be detrimental if Zedillo is looking to make a statement that he wants a change at the central bank.  </p>
<p>Economists say that the bank will continue focusing on keeping inflation under control, but with subtle differences.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that Mancera has favored the strong peso with monetary policy, and Gil Diaz is behind that, and on the other side you could have a new trend of favoring a less strong peso,&quot; Martin said.</p>
<p>&quot;That doesn't mean a weak peso, but a less strong peso, and therefore a less strong hold on lowering inflation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>If there are any differences in the running of monetary policy, they would be nuances.  </p>
<p>&quot;The perception is that Sidaoui is seen as the more pragmatic and not quite as dogmatically monetarist. So there could be a little more flexibility in the monetary program,&quot; said Banker's Trust economist Denis Parisien.</p>
<p>&quot;Sidaoui is more identified with Hacienda (the Finance Ministry), which could perhaps be looking for more growth, while Gil Diaz is very strongly independent. But both are very well versed and know what to do,&quot; Mexico City's Heath said.</p>
<p>Among other rumoured replacements is widely respected deputy bank governor Jesus Marcos Yacaman, who is known as a first-rate economist. Analysts speculate he could take the prize should a deadlock develop over Sidaoui and Gil Diaz.</p>
<p>Other outside candidates have been tipped, some of whom have worked at one time or another at the central bank. But analysts downplay that possibility and say it would send a bad signal to bring in an outsider, particularly if it were done for political reasons.</p>
<p>Central bank watchers add that one possible consideration is that with their age differences, Gil Diaz, 53, could be named governor this time and Sidaoui, 43, later. ((-- Mexico City newsroom +525 728 9559</p>
<p>E-mail at robert.kozak@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
