<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759788" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: ASEAN sees Ung Huot's nomination as credible.</title>
<headline>ASEAN sees Ung Huot's nomination as credible.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>ASEAN views as credible the nomination of Cambodian Foreign Minister Ung Huot for the post of first prime minister of the war-torn country, Indonesian Foreign Minister Ali Alatas said on Monday.</p>
<p>Asked whether he regarded the nomination as credible, Alatas told reporters: &quot;It's...a credible form in parliament, certainly.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There were 97 members of parliament in all, and I think the quorum was only supposed to be 84 to 86,&quot; said Alatas, one of ASEAN's three mediators in the Cambodian conflict.</p>
<p>He added, however: &quot;I don't know how it'll be when it comes to confirming (Ung Huot's) election.&quot;</p>
<p>Ung Huot was nominated as first prime minister by the Cambodian National Assembly in place of Prince Norodom Ranariddh, ousted in a July 5-6 putsch by coalition colleague and Second Prime Minister Hun Sen.</p>
<p>His nomination came despite an announcement by Ranariddh on Sunday that he had temporarily expelled Ung Huot from his royalist FUNCINPEC party.</p>
<p>Hun Sen, who originally put Ung Huot's name forward to replace Ranariddh, attended the assembly session. Assembly officials, however, said voting for the post could be held only in a week due to administrative delays.</p>
<p>Asked if he had been in touch with Ung Huot, Alatas said: &quot;Yes, on the phone.&quot;</p>
<p>Alatas together with the foreign ministers of the Philippines and Thailand make up a team formed by ASEAN to mediate a solution to the Cambodian crisis, sparked by Hun Sen's ouster of Ranariddh.</p>
<p>The crisis kept Cambodia from joining ASEAN on schedule last week and the ministers remain in limbo, awaiting a clear word from Hun Sen on whether he will accept their mission.</p>
<p>Alatas is attending an annual series of meetings of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) together with major Asian and Western powers which have demanded a free and fair election of the new first prime minister as a key to the settlement of the crisis.</p>
<p>They have also endorsed ASEAN's leading role in helping bring peace and stability to the country.</p>
<p>ASEAN comprises Brunei, Burma, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
