<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759747" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thailand gets IMF advice, studying credit line.</title>
<headline>Thailand gets IMF advice, studying credit line.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai Finance Minister Thanong Bidaya said on Monday he was meeting officials of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) this week in Bangkok to seek advice on ways to revive the country's battered economy.</p>
<p>Thailand would also study if a standby IMF credit line was necessary to help overcome the country's worst financial crisis in more than a decade.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been in consultation with the IMF for the past month...we should be able to wrap it up (the meeting with the IMF team) within one week,&quot; Thanong told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The question of whether we need a standby IMF credit line will be included in the package,&quot; he said, without saying how much credit would be needed.</p>
<p>Officials in Washington, where there has been concern that a financial crisis in Thailand could spill over into other emerging market economies, welcomed news of the talks.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the dialogue between Thailand and the International Monetary Fund as a constructive step and will be following it closely,&quot; U.S. Deputy Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers said in response to enquiries.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States has a strong stake in financial stability and growth throughout the developing world.&quot;</p>
<p>An IMF spokesman said its team had arrived in Bangkok during the weekend. &quot;An IMF team...has initiated policy discussions with Thai officials,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Officials in Bangkok, guarding their independence jealously, had been wary of approaching the IMF for help because of the tough conditions likely to be attatched to any IMF loan.</p>
<p>But Bank of Thailand Governor Rerngchai Marakanond told reporters that Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh and Thanong had agreed in principle since July 22 to tap loans from the IMF.</p>
<p>&quot;No specific figures had been agreed. We only discussed it in broad principle,&quot; Rerngchai told reporters in the first statement from the authorities signalling that Thailand had decided privately to accept IMF loans.</p>
<p>He said any loan from the IMF would be used to assist the whole economy and not to bail out any specific sector.</p>
<p>IMF funding could open the door to a broader support package for Thailand, estimated by analysts to need about $10-20 billion to help it overcome its financial problems.</p>
<p>Rerngchai said a much-awaited economic rehabilitation package, drawn up by Thanong, was being vetted by ministers and needed to go the cabinet for approval by August 5.</p>
<p>Thanong said his package would include fiscal and monetary measures as well as deal with the question of what should be an appropriate level for the embattled baht.</p>
<p>&quot;The package will involve finding systematic measures to shore up the economy,&quot; he said. &quot;At this time, we need to set the priorities on how to tackle problems and set our targets. Once confidence of investors is restored funds will flow back automatically (to Thailand).&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The current liquidity problem can be compared to a leaking barrel. No matter how much we fill it in, it keeps leaking out. But if we plug the holes, it can stop the leak and liquidity can be refilled easily,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thanong said moves such as allowing the managed float of the baht and policies to allow foreign investors to take more than a 25 percent stake in Thai financial institutions had been implemented in consultation with the IMF.</p>
<p>&quot;The IMF has a job to help and advice on how to resolve these (Thai) problems systematically...we need their expertise and we want the correct approach extended by the international community,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
