<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759715" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: INSIGHT-Aussie support stays true,reinforces range.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT-Aussie support stays true,reinforces range.</headline>
<text>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>AUS$ S/Term range  *Support *Restnce *RSI-14 *MA-10  *MA-20</p>
<p>US$ *0.7310/0.7430 *0.7330  *0.7385  *38.41  *0.7376 *0.7408</p>
<p>--------------VIEWS FROM THE MARKET - July 29 ------------------</p>
<p>*Offshore range roughly US$0.7335/7381</p>
<p>*AUD survived another brush with the downside as good support at $0.7330 forced short covering in a distracted market</p>
<p>*Bounce turned technicals positive near term for rise to $0.7420, but longer term remains bearish while under $0.7475</p>
<p>*Weak Kiwi a drag, but sentiment aided by CRB rise, stg fall</p>
<p>*June trade balance at 11.30 am should show record surplus  </p>
<p>By 8.15 am (2215 GMT) the local dollar had edged up to US$0.7364/69 from a US$0.7335 low, to be steady on Monday's late US$0.7360/65. It had met first line resistance at US$0.7385 and there was talk of fresh offers around 74 cents, so further gains would not come easily.</p>
<p>Most chart analysts were not yet convinced the dollar's four month-old downtrend had bottomed and saw a real risk of a break below the 1996 trough of US$0.7305 leading to US$0.7250 and eventually the 1995 low of US$0.7070.</p>
<p>Traders, however, were inmpressed by the resilience of support in the face of intense rate cut speculation.  </p>
<p>The rally from 18-month lows around US$0.7310 last week had convinced many a 50 basis point easing had been fully priced in and the currency could actually recover once the cut was made and the uncertainty dispelled.</p>
<p>Today's data on the international balance of goods and services should not alter those expectations, although they are likely to show the largest trade surplus on record.</p>
<p>This is because almost all the gain reflects the inclusion of the Reserve Bank's sale of gold reserves rather than an improvement in the underlying trade position. Forecasts are clustered around A$1.7 billion but stretch up to A$2.2 billion.  </p>
<p>That would be way up on May's A$873 million, which itself was boosted by the sale of a A$500 million frigate, and imply a hefty contribution to Q2 GDP from net exports. However, the effect of the gold sale would be largely negated as it implied a corresponding fall in stocks which would detract from GDP.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the Commodity Research Bureau index rose 2.70 points to 241.18, extending a recovery from a two year low of 232.01 from July 7 and confirming a break of 236.00 resistance.</p>
<p>On the crosses, the A$ was buoyed by heavy profit taking on long sterling positions, but tainted by concerns over the sliding Kiwi. -- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
