<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759849" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Former South Vietnam soldier elected to assembly.</title>
<headline>Former South Vietnam soldier elected to assembly.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Edwards</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam announced on Monday that three independent candidates including a former soldier in the army of U.S.-backed South Vietnam had been elected to the communist country's National Assembly.</p>
<p>Election officials told journalists at a news conference that Tran Thanh Trai, now a prominent southern doctor, was elected with a huge 83.91 percent share of votes in the Binh Thanh and Phu Nhuan area of Ho Chi Minh City.</p>
<p>The figure was the most votes for any of the 25 candidates in the former Saigon, other than deputy prime minister Phan Van Khai.</p>
<p>It is also the first known time that a soldier in the former South Vietnam army has been elected, and the first time that a self-nominated candidate has won a place in a legislature traditionally seen as the domain of loyal party members and other handpicked deputies.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to emphasise that it (the general election) has been successfully and beautifully conducted,&quot; said an official as the news conference got underway. &quot;Tran Thanh Trai was elected ... regardless of his previous record.&quot;</p>
<p>The full results of Vietnam's election showed that all but 108 people in the 450-seat legislature were elected for the first time. Nearly 120 are women, 78 are from ethnic minority groups and 384 are members of the ruling communist party.</p>
<p>Among them was a prominent and outspoken lawyer, Ngo Ba Thanh. Others included an 86-year-old Catholic Bishop, Vuong Dinh Ai, in central Nghe An province.</p>
<p>All politburo candidates who stood for election succeeded, as expected, including National Assembly Chairman Nong Duc Manh who received 93.29 percent of his constituent's votes.</p>
<p>But while the personnel make-up of Vietnam's parliament may have changed since the last polls in 1992, there was little to indicate other differences.</p>
<p>The new assembly will still have only minor ability to influence decisions made at the higher levels of the political establishment. It will meet for the first time on September 18, but won't pass any laws until its second session next year.</p>
<p>Officials said revised turnout figures showed 99.59 percent of Vietnam's 43,672,683 voters made it to the polls on July 20, despite flooding in some areas. They also advised journalists against casting doubt on the level of success.</p>
<p>&quot;Journalists sometimes want to exploit the figures, but the elections were held in a very democratic way so your reports should not be misleading,&quot; Assembly Office Chairman Vu Mao said.</p>
<p>Vietnam's National Assembly is traditionally seen as compliant, but observers say it has begun to flex muscle of its own in recent years.</p>
<p>One of its first tasks in September will be to ratify the appointment of a new president and prime minister. The current incumbents, Le Duc Anh, 76, and Vo Van Kiet, 74, are stepping down.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
