<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759950" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT asks immediate CFTC approval on corn/soy plan.</title>
<headline>CBOT asks immediate CFTC approval on corn/soy plan.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) on Monday asked the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to approve the exchange's revised delivery terms for corn and soybean contracts without further delay.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission's prolonged inaction is inexcusable, all the more so given the urgency with which the Commission demanded that we revise our delivery terms in the first place,&quot; CBOT president Thomas Donovan said in a letter to CFTC chairwoman Brooksley Born and released by the exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;The time has come for the Commission to approve our application without further delay and to remove the legal uncertainty that has become an obstacle to legitimate hedging uses of certain listed products,&quot; Donovan said.</p>
<p>He said the CBOT, for its part, had come up with the revised terms in April following an order December 19 for the exchange to produce a revised delivery plan within 75 days.</p>
<p>The CFTC told the exchange its delivery terms for corn and soybean contracts were no longer suitable due to dwindling warehouse capacity.</p>
<p>The plan, designed by a CBOT-appointed Task Force, sets sets delivery points along the Illinois River from Pekin to Chicago and at Burns Harbor, Indiana.</p>
<p>But it also calls for eliminating St Louis and Toledo as delivery sites, a move that has prompted vocal protests from some politicans, farm groups and commercial firms.</p>
<p>The CBOT membership approved the proposal by a 2-to-1 margin in April. The CBOT has repeatedly asked for approval of the plan and CBOT chairman Pat Arbor said the exchange would take the Commission to court if the plan was not approved.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission, bowing to the pressures of a comment campaign organized by certain narrow special interests, even extended the public comment period twice,&quot; Donovan said.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, having acted quickly at the Commission's insistence, we find ourselves in the untenable situation of having our proposal trapped in regulatory limbo,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8750))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
