<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="759922" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Regulators probe News Corp. plan to buy Heritage.</title>
<headline>Regulators probe News Corp. plan to buy Heritage.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Justice Department is investigating potential antitrust implications of media giant News Corp.'s planned acquisition of Heritage Media Corp., a Dallas-based mass marketing company, the companies said Monday.</p>
<p>The probe is concentrated on the coupon operations of both companies, said News Corp. spokesman James Platt.</p>
<p>News Corp., which announced the proposed acquisition in March, operates a business that provides merchandise coupons in newspapers, as well as a smaller business that provides coupons found in grocery stores.</p>
<p>Heritage also has an in-store coupon operation.</p>
<p>&quot;Our argument is that the market is broader than the way they describe it,&quot; said Platt. News Corp.'s empire also includes the Fox television network, Fox movie studios, the New York Post and The Times of London</p>
<p>The deal originally was valued at $754 million in stock. The terms also call for News Corp. to assume $600 million in Heritage debt.</p>
<p>The companies said in a statement that the department's antitrust field office in San Francisco has recommended that the department challenge the deal. The companies said they were told of the San Francisco field office's position after the close of U.S. stock market trading on Friday.</p>
<p>The companies have granted the regulators more time to either challenge the transaction or approve the deal. The government already had issued a &quot;second request&quot; for more information that was set to expire later this week, Platt said.</p>
<p>The companies said they would &quot;vigorously pursue the approval&quot; of the transaction.</p>
<p>Heritage stock tumbled $2.19 to $17 per share in late consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
