<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760000" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Probe, new CEO could slow Columbia growth.</title>
<headline>Probe, new CEO could slow Columbia growth.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Columbia/HCA Healthcare Corp may face slower growth in the near-term due to a broad federal investigation of its business and the less aggressive style of its new chairman and chief executive.</p>
<p>&quot;Columbia is now in damage control mode,&quot; said Merrill Lynch healthcare analyst Margo Vignola, who added that growth would likely stall at the largest U.S. hospital company after the resignation Friday of long-time CEO Richard Scott.</p>
<p>The Nashville, Tenn.-based company has always relied on acquisitions to fuel its voracious appetite for revenue growth. But incoming chief executive and chairman Dr. Thomas Frist appears to be putting the company on a diet. In a televised interview Monday, Frist said: &quot;I don't think we can afford to look at any further mergers.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares in Columbia closed Monday off 1-10/16 at 34-5/16, while shares in Tenet Healthcare Corp closed off 12/16 at 29-13/16 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Columbia and Tenet have been rumored to be in merger talks, but in the wake of Scott's departure, the rumors have cooled -- at least, for now.</p>
<p>&quot;Our prediction: COL will operate independently for some time under Dr. Frist's leadership. Eventually, however, we believe that a combination with another healthcare entity is a strong possibility,&quot; said Robertson Stephens healthcare analyst Sheryl Skolnick.</p>
<p>Columbia is set to report quarterly results Wednesday and Wall Street will be watching closely to see if the company's many problems are beginning to damage its business.</p>
<p>Estimates for second-quarter earnings per share are firm at the First Call consensus of $0.62 per share, up from $0.54 per share a year ago, according to analysts' reports.</p>
<p>But behind the bottom line, analysts said they will be scrutinizing key signs of growth momentum, such as same- hospital revenues, same-hospital admissions, capital spending, share repurchases and merger strategy.</p>
<p>Columbia historically has enjoyed same-hospital revenue growth of seven to 11 percent year-over-year, versus the industry average of about five percent.</p>
<p>All signs are that growth in high single digits will be maintained this quarter, but at least one analyst has proposed a slow-down scenario assuming growth nearer the industry average in the near term.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe it is reasonable to consider the possibility that same-hospital operating trends could slow down under the weight of the investigation,&quot; said Bear Stearns healthcare analyst Albert Rice in a recent report.</p>
<p>Columbia has typically reported same-hospital admissions growth of two to five percent, said another analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;You can go back a long way and it's always between two and five. They've got a quarter coming out on July 30. It needs to be within that range,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Columbia announced a $1 billion share buyback on April 15. The recent decline in its stock price may prompt the company to extend that program, which could help boost earnings per share during a slowdown, analysts said.</p>
<p>The federal government is investigating laboratory billings, home healthcare operations and possibly other business practices at Nashville, Tenn.-based Columbia.</p>
<p>In the past two weeks, federal agents have seized files from 35 Columbia facilities in six states and subpoenaed five mid-level managers in Florida to testify to a grand jury. Under pressure from Columbia's board, long-time chief executive Richard Scott resigned Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to wonder at what point does this investigation begin to impact morale at the facilities to the point that they're...spending more time making sure they're not the next target at the local level, rather than growing the business,&quot; said one analyst who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Added Skolnick: &quot;In the meantime, expect competitors of COL to work very, very hard to take share and acquisitions away from COL during this time.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
