<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760041" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. phone companies object to US budget provision.</title>
<headline>U.S. phone companies object to US budget provision.</headline>
<byline>Roger Fillion</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Local telephone companies warn that budget legislation in the midst Monday of winning final passage in the House and Senate could force up phone rates for rural and other out-of-the-way communities.</p>
<p>House and Senate budget negotiators also agreed to tighten proposed terms under which television broadcasters could keep a valuable airwave license after the transition to digital TV.</p>
<p>And they agreed to waive curbs against media companies owning more than one TV station in markets with cities of more than 400,000 viewers, as well as curbs against such companies owning a broadcast station and a newspaper in such a market.</p>
<p>House and Senate commerce committee negotiators have approved the legislation containing the measures and it is being signed by budget committee lawmakers as part of the overall balanced-budget legislation, sources said.</p>
<p>The phone provision would delay spending of billions of dollars for a fund that keeps rural phone rates affordable.</p>
<p>To help balance the budget, payments to the government's &quot;universal service&quot; fund would be postponed until fiscal year 2003 from 2002. The amount could range from $2 billion to $5 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;What the budget conferees are proposing is a dramatic rate increase for millions of rural Americans,&quot; David Zesiger of the Independent Telephone and Telecommunications Alliance charged.</p>
<p>Others agreed with the alliance, which is made up of 15 mid-size phone companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Delaying expenditure of universal phone service support funds will make the system insufficient to preserve universal telephone service as mandated in the 1996 Telecommunications Act,&quot; said Roy Neel, president of the United States Telephone Association, made up of the the regional Baby Bells and other local carriers.</p>
<p>The digital-TV language attached to the same legislation would tighten previous conditions under which TV stations could keep their old analog licenses, as well as their new digital licenses to transmit programs in high-definition format.</p>
<p>The legislation is slated to raise more than $20 billion through federal airwave auctions.</p>
<p>TV stations would be allowed to keep their analog licenses after 2006 -- the return date mandated by the Federal Communications Commission -- if:</p>
<p>-- One or more network-affiliated stations in the local market do not broadcast in digital format.</p>
<p>-- Or set-top converters to receive digital signals that generally are unavailable.</p>
<p>In markets where neither condition applies, TV stations could keep the analog license if 15 percent of the households in their local viewing area:</p>
<p>-- Do not subscribe to a cable or satellite-TV system that carries the digital signals of at least one local station.</p>
<p>-- And do not have either a digital TV set or an analog set equipped with a set-top converter.</p>
<p>The legislation would make it tougher for TV stations to keep their analog licenses after 2006 than legislation that cleared the House and Senate earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;Without a doubt,&quot; said Gigi Sohn of the Media Access Project, a public-interest law firm.</p>
<p>But Sohn is not thrilled.</p>
<p>&quot;I really belive that, in 2006, there will still be at least 15 percent of the population that will not make the change to digital TV unless they absolutely have to,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
