<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760276" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures closing report.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures closing report.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's debt market closed lower after a thin, apathetic session lacking impetus, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The correction could continue given the Treasury's auction of medium and long-term paper later this week,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Germany's Ifo research institute said today that Italy may hit the EMU deficit target but should be kept out of the first round of euro members because it lacked the sustainability required for monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true that the structural reforms are still lacking but the Ifo criticisms could have a positive effect in keeping the pressure on for serious welfare state reform,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi himself warned against excessive euphoria at the weekend and said Italy could face a difficult autumn, although he said that the country's sacrifices for EMU were nearly over.</p>
<p>On the cash market, dealers noted sell orders this morning for paper to be offered on Wednesday, the May 1, 2004 CCT and the July 1, 2007 Btp, and on Thursday the May 15, 2000 and 2002 Btp. &quot;Then we saw some short-covering,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The Feb 1 2007 Btp lost 56 basis points to close at 102.70, yielding 6.46 percent. The 10-year Btp/Bund spread widened to 90 bps from an early 85.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129589</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
