<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760363" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's ICICI Q1 97/98 bad loans rise.</title>
<headline>India's ICICI Q1 97/98 bad loans rise.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Industrial Credit and Investment Corp of India Ltd (ICICI) said its non-performing assets (bad loans) rose to 7.8 percent as on June 30, 1997, from 6.8 percent on March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This is attributable primarily to the fact that there was a bunching of cases which were added to the list in the first quarter of the current financial year, which may otherwise have been spread more uniformly throughout the entire financial year as the asset base increases,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said ICICI recorded a growth fo 107 percent in loan approvals and 32 percent rise in disbursements during the firt quarter of 1997/98 (April-March), compared to the corresponding period of the previous financial year.</p>
<p>&quot;The growth was largely fuelled by the introduction of yield curve-based pricing. The medium-term prime rate announced in April 1997 received an enthusiastic response from the industry.&quot;</p>
<p>To move towards comprehensive yield curve-based pricing, ICICI has since announced a short-term prime rate which is also the benchmark for floating interest rate loan products, it said.</p>
<p>ICICI said profit for the first quarter at 2.23 billion rupees was arrived at in accordance with accounting principles as applied for the compilation of annual accounts.</p>
<p>ICICI, India's second largest term-lending bank, announced the results after a board meeting on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;While the classification of assets has been done in accordance with RBI guidelines, write-offs and provisions have been pro-rated for the quarter,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>ICICI said comparison with first quarter 1996/97 results may not be strictly appropriate. &quot;Q1 97 results, apart from not being audited, have not been adjusted for alignment of accounting practices of erstwhile SCICI Ltd, with those of ICICI.&quot;</p>
<p>The profit in first quarter 1997/98 includes net capital gains of 470 million rupees compared with 50 million rupees in the corresponding period a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Another key feature of operations in the first quarter 97/98 was the continued growth of non-fund-based income which registered a growth of 68 percent from 220 million rupees in Q1 97 to 370 million rupees in Q1 98,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
