<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760452" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar surges vs. German mark, Dow hits new record.</title>
<headline>Dollar surges vs. German mark, Dow hits new record.</headline>
<byline>Wendy Pollack</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar surged to its highest level against the German mark since the fall of the Berlin Wall, and blue-chip stocks edged to another record high Monday.</p>
<p>Bond prices rose in light volume ahead of the release of several key reports on the economy.</p>
<p>The dollar has risen almost 20 percent against the mark this year on concerns that the planned single European currency would be weaker than expected and due to persistent weakness in the German economy.</p>
<p>The dollar's rise against the German currency has accelerated recently as investors have gained confidence that the U.S. economy was growing steadily with little inflation.</p>
<p>Late Monday in New York, the dollar stood at 1.8440 marks after earlier hitting 1.8490, its highest level since November 1989. The dollar closed at 1.8378 marks Friday.</p>
<p>The dollar also gained against the British pound amid uncertainty over British interest rates and climbed to its highest level against the Japanese yen in 2-1/2 months.</p>
<p>The dollar broke through 117 Japanese yen and stood at 117.87 yen late in New York, its highest level in 2-1/2 months, and up from 116.95 late on Friday. The pound fell to $1.6327 from $1.6640.</p>
<p>Stocks turned in a mixed performance, with the Dow Jones industrial average eking out another record while high-technology stocks fell.</p>
<p>The 30-share Dow rose 7.67 points to 8,121.11, edging past the previous record of 8,116.93, set on Thursday. It was the Dow's fourth record in the past five sessions.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues beat decliners, 1,440 to 1,415, on moderate volume of 464 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite index, heavily weighted with technology stocks, fell 6.05 points to 1,563.53.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury rose 21/32, or $6.563 on a $1,000 bond, lowering its yield to 6.41 percent from 6.46 percent on Friday. Bond prices and yields move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>Trading in the bond market was fairly subdued ahead of the release of important economic data, beginning Tuesday with the release of the second-quarter index of employment costs, a key barometer of inflation.</p>
<p>That report will be followed by the first estimate of second-quarter gross domestic product on Thursday and July's employment data on Friday.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, coffee prices jumped to their highest level in six weeks amid renewed concerns about supply shortages. At New York's Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange, coffee for September delivery rose 12.05 cents a pound, or nearly 7 percent, to 188.35 cents, the highest closing price since June 17.</p>
<p>Overseas, Britain's FTSE 100 rose 11.1 points, or 0.23 percent, to 4,862.6, while Japan's 225-share Nikkei closed at 20,575.26, up 185.72 points, or 0.91 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
