<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760523" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cusiana loadings at 14-15 cargoes in Sept - trader.</title>
<headline>Cusiana loadings at 14-15 cargoes in Sept - trader.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of loadings of Colombian Cusiana crude oil planned for September is 14 to 15 cargoes, up four to five cargoes from the August schedule, a trader said on Monday.</p>
<p>The increase partly reflects higher-than-expected production of the gasoline-rich grade. Output is projected to average 340,000 barrels per day (bpd), up from earlier predictions of 280,000 to 330,000 bpd.  </p>
<p>At the same time, local demand for Cusiana is on the low side of previous projections. The Barrancabermeja refinery is expected to utilize about 40,000 bpd of Cusiana, out of a normal range of 40,000 t0 55,000 bpd, the trader said.</p>
<p>Out of the 14-15 planned cargoes, equity producers British Petroleum and Total of France have five and two cargoes, respectively.</p>
<p>Colombian state oil company Ecopetrol has the balance, including a cross-month cargo scheduled to load between September 29 and October 3.  </p>
<p>Each cargo normally holds 550,000 barrels.</p>
<p>The first loading, which belongs to BP, is scheduled for September 3-7.</p>
<p>Even before the schedule came out late Friday night, Ecopetrol last week sold a cargo loading in the first decade of September to a U.S. refiner at 65 cents a barrel under benchmark West Texas Intermediate/Cushing on an fob basis.</p>
<p>Sellers are now asking around 55 cents under the benchmark, the trader said.  </p>
<p>Cusiana liftings have been rising steadily in recent months in line with growing production. Loadings climbed from an average of around seven cargoes a month until August, when they rose to 10 cargoes, including a cross-month cargo belonging to Ecopetrol.</p>
<p>All of the August cargoes have been placed with U.S. refiners.</p>
<p>BP operates the Cusiana/Cupiagua oil field complex in the Andes foothills region of Colombia.</p>
<p>BP's partners are Ecopetrol, Total and U.S. independent Triton.</p>
<p>--Patricia Garip-Bertuol NY Energy Desk ((+1 212 859 1620))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
