<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760637" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IPO VIEW-Offerings inspire optimism, not awe.</title>
<headline>IPO VIEW-Offerings inspire optimism, not awe.</headline>
<byline>Ruth Morris</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A batch of smaller stock issues slated to go public this week may not provide high drama, but investors could still reap premiums in Wall Street's bull market.</p>
<p>At center stage last Friday was computer reservation company Galileo International Inc., which stole most of the thunder from the IPO market, closing the day at 26-1/8, up from its 24-1/2 pricing.</p>
<p>The $784-million initial public offering helped boost the amount of money raised by IPOs for the week to $1.63 billion, its highest level since June 21, and nearly double the previous week's $831 million figure, according to the Security Data service.</p>
<p>However, this week's less glamorous array of IPOs -- the largest offering involves 7.2 million shares -- does not lack value for money, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a higher percentage of good quality companies to choose from,&quot; said Jay Gottlieb, publisher of New Issues Outlook, as he described a trend that he said set the 1997 IPO market apart from previous years.</p>
<p>David Menlow, president of IPO Financial Network Corp. in Springfield, N.J., added that he saw no &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; among investors, making it tougher for small underwriters to whip up enthusiasm about their offers.</p>
<p>Heading Menlow's list of stocks to watch this week was Ocular Sciences, underwritten by Morgan Stanley. The company, which manufactures and markets soft contact lenses, saw its price range boosted to $15.00 to $17.00 after an initial filing estimated shares would come in at between $14.00 to $16.00. Menlow said he expected Ocular to price at $16.00 and could gain over 20 percent in opening trading.</p>
<p>The number of Ocular shares available was unchanged at 7.2 million, half of them offered by shareholders and half by the company.</p>
<p>Also near the top of Menlow's list was Net.B@nk, offering three million shares at $10.00 to $12.00, and Corsair Communications, offering 2.25 million shares at between $12.00 and $14.00. Menlow predicted a premium of two to three points on each company's stock.</p>
<p>Corsair is underwritten by Deutsche, Morgan Grenfell, while Net.B@nk is underwritten by Morgan Keegan.</p>
<p>Standard and Poor's, however, issued cautious comments on Corsair.</p>
<p>&quot;The growth potential there is very limited,&quot; Mark Basham, an investment officer for Standard and Poor's, said of the company, which provides hardware and software products for the wireless telecommunications industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Valuation has really come down to reasonable levels,&quot; Basham said of the IPO market as a whole, though he cautioned that the Dow Jones industrial average's recent record highs were leading IPO pricings &quot;to creep back up a little.&quot;</p>
<p>Basham voiced optimism for the near-term prospects of Internet service provider Concentric Network.</p>
<p>&quot;Concentric is a step above most of the Internet providers out there,&quot; he said, citing deals signed with prominent companies like Netscape Communications Corp. and Japanese telephone company NTT.</p>
<p>Concentric is offering three million shares at between $10.00 to $12.00, underwritten by UBS Securities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
