<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760678" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FINLAND STILL CONFIDENT ON '97 EMU DEFICIT.</title>
<headline>FINLAND STILL CONFIDENT ON '97 EMU DEFICIT.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Finnish finance ministry said on Monday the public sector deficit in relation to GDP would be inside the three percent limit for European economic and monetary union despite an overshoot to 3.1 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Even in a worst-case scenario, the 1997 deficit would be safely within the EMU limit, state secretary Raimo Sailas told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not changed our forecast for this year,&quot; Sailas said, referring to the ministry's EMU deficit forecast of 1.4 percent of GDP. Countries aiming to join the single currency will be judged by their performance in 1997.</p>
<p>Both Sailas and an official at Statistics Finland (SF) said a recent revision of the 1996 EMU deficit to 3.1 percent of GDP from 2.6 percent was due mainly to non-recurring factors.</p>
<p>He was responding to data discussed in Brussels earlier this month, showing a statistical revision which pushed Finland's 1996 deficit outside the limit for EMU.</p>
<p>The revised deficit was slightly over three billion markka larger, mainly because state expenditure late in 1996 had been underestimated in the preliminary figures released by SF on March 3, the SF official said.</p>
<p>Asked whether there was any reason to expect revisions next year of preliminary 1997 data would push the Finnish public sector deficit over the three percent EMU threshold, Sailas said: &quot;The answer is no.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have made test calculations and we will be safely below three percent even in a worst-case scenario,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Since public sector finance data for all European Union countries would still be very preliminary in spring 1998 and subject to many later revisions, heated debate in many EU countries on the EMU deficit criterion -- especially on minutiae like decimals -- was rather fruitless, Sailas said.</p>
<p>EU leaders are scheduled to decide in April-May next year which countries qualify for the planned third stage of the single currency due for start-up in 1999.</p>
<p>Finland has repeatedly said it will meet the entry criteria and intends to be part of the founding members of the new euro.</p>
<p>--Peter Starck, Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 245,</p>
<p>						  e-mail news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
