<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76063" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka forces step up strikes on Tamil rebels.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka forces step up strikes on Tamil rebels.</headline>
<byline>Rohan Gunasekera</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lankan forces renewed air and artillery strikes on the rebel Tamil Tigers' northern stronghold on Wednesday in a bid to break through guerrilla resistance, military officials said.</p>
<p>The rebel Voice of Tigers radio, mouthpiece of the Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE), reported heavy fighting in the guerrillas' Kilinochchi base and said many civilians had been killed.</p>
<p>But a military spokesman said the strikes were focused on identified enemy positions.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been pounding the enemy to wipe out their resistance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Defence analysts said the pre-dawn air and artillery attacks could mean the army was on the advance again after consolidating their positions in newly captured areas.</p>
<p>The military spokesman said troops had repulsed several rebel counter-attacks on army defences overnight.</p>
<p>&quot;Terrorists fired mortars at our forward defences last night. There were also several confrontations along our defences but we have no details of casualties yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thousands of troops, backed by tanks, artillery and air support, have been advancing on Kilinochchi, 285 km (180 miles) north of Colombo, in their first offensive in more than a month. The operation was launched on Sunday.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the army was consolidating at Morasamoddai, a road junction just northeast of Kilinochchi, the northern entry point to the Tigers' jungle territory of the Wanni.</p>
<p>Defence analysts said government troops were trying to outflank the rebels, who were well dug in at Kilinochchi.</p>
<p>At least 37 soldiers were killed and 79 wounded in the first two days of the offensive, the defence ministry said.</p>
<p>On Monday, 35 guerrillas were killed and 100 wounded after some 200 rebels were killed or wounded on Sunday, the ministry said.</p>
<p>No casualty update was given on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Diplomats said heavy army casualties indicated the LTTE were putting up strong resistance. The rebels are fighting for an independent homeland for minority Tamils in the Indian Ocean island's north and east.</p>
<p>Military officials said they had stepped up surveillance in the Jaffna lagoon between the army-held Jaffna peninsula and the mainland, just north of Kilinochchi, to deter rebel attempts to land reinforcements by boat.</p>
<p>&quot;Ground troops have seen LTTE boats hugging the coast,&quot; said a military officer. &quot;They may be trying to bring up reinforcements as Kilinochchi is important for them. It is the last major town in their hands with a hospital and other infrastructure.&quot;</p>
<p>The army has said it wants to reopen the highway connecting Jaffna and Colombo, which passes through a large swathe of rebel-held territory separating Jaffna and the mainland.</p>
<p>The military has been targeting Kilinochchi since the LTTE overran the northeastern Mullaitivu camp in July, killing or capturing almost its entire garrison of 1,400 men.</p>
<p>It was the military's worst setback in the 13-year war in which the government says more than 50,000 people have died.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
