<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760829" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel economic activity rises in May, June.</title>
<headline>Israel economic activity rises in May, June.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economic activity in Israel rose in the months of May and June, the Central Bureau of Statistics said in a summary of recently published economic indicators issued on Monday.</p>
<p>The main economic indicators for these months show that industrial production and imports of production inputs rose along with a more moderate rise in private consumption.</p>
<p>The indicators show a continued slowdown in the growth of industrial exports and a slight increase in the trade deficit.</p>
<p>Unemployment was also higher in the two months, the bureau said.</p>
<p>Industrial production in April-May rose by an annualised five to six percent, compared with a rise of two to three percent in February-March having been unchanged in the September 1996-January 1997 period.</p>
<p>Imports of production inputs rose in the March-June period by six to seven percent, after a three percent rise in February and continued falls in imports in the previous months since February 1996.</p>
<p>Retail sales rose in June by an annualised 10 percent, after rises of 13 percent in the previous three months.</p>
<p>In January-June the number of tourist arrivals by air was only slightly higher than arrivals in the second half of 1996.</p>
<p>Exports of goods, excluding diamonds and exports from the West Bank and Gaza Strip, rose in June by an annualised three to four percent, after a rise of five percent in May.</p>
<p>The trade deficit, excluding diamonds, ships and aircraft, rose in June to $518 million after having fallen continuously since February last year. In January-February 1996 the deficit was close to $780 million a month.</p>
<p>Data on the consumer price indices shows that in the months of April-June prices rose by an annualised eight to nine percent, against rises of about 10 percent in the months of January-March.</p>
<p>Unemployment in May was 7.7 percent against 7.6 percent in April and 7.5 percent in March.</p>
<p>Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
