<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="760934" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hewlett-Packard to launch digital color copiers.</title>
<headline>Hewlett-Packard to launch digital color copiers.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hewlett-Packard Co. will launch a new line of InkJet-based digital colour copiers on Tuesday, and industry analysts believe the machines could help it win a sizable share of the U.S. personal copier market.</p>
<p>The copiers are especially suited for small offices and the home user, who currently might need to travel to a photocopying shop to make colour copies, often at a price of $1 to $2 a sheet.</p>
<p>The HP Colour Copier product line will be available immediately in the United States, where estimated street prices range from $699 for an HP Colour Copier Series 100 to $1,299 for an HP colour copier 210 LX.</p>
<p>The lower-priced model can produce up to seven copies a minute using black ink and up to three copies a minute in slightly lower resolution colour than the 210 LX. The more expensive machine can produce 10 black ink copies a minute and up to six in colour and also has an automatic document feeder.</p>
<p>A 210 model is also available without the document feeder for an estimated price of $999, the same price of the company's multipurpose OfficeJet Pro 1150c, introduced earlier this year. That machine can also scan documents into a computer and be used as a computer printer.</p>
<p>According to IDC Link, sales of personal copiers in the U.S. market slumped 3.6 percent to 440,000 in 1996 from 1995. But analysts at the research firm believe the new HP products will help boost the market by 11.4 percent in 1997 and that it will grow by 12.2 percent in 1998, to 550,000.</p>
<p>Richard Norton, president of DocuTrends, a market research firm in Saratoga, Calif., predicts HP could take 10 to 20 percent of the personal copier market in its first 12 months of sales.</p>
<p>Canon Inc. currently has about a 50 percent share of the market, with Xerox Corp. holding down more than a third of the market. Sharp Corp. has the remaining 15 percent or so, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this product is going to explode a segment or add a new segment just because it's there,&quot; he said. &quot;HP will do well just because they're HP and the word on the street is you can't go wrong if you buy HP.&quot;</p>
<p>To get best results, analysts noted, customers will need to use specially coated papers, which the company said will cost from around 10 cents a page to around $1 a page.</p>
<p>As with other HP InkJet products, sales of cartridges, which are estimated to cost up to around $35 each, and other supplies are expected to account for the most lucrative part of the business, analysts said.</p>
<p>Personal copiers are only a small portion of the $23 billion overall copy machine market, and analysts said they do not expect the new Hewlett-Packard machines to compete with $15,000 to $50,000 laser-based models.</p>
<p>&quot;They're inexpensive alternatives for colour copying,&quot; said Bob Leahy, an analyst at Peripheral Insights in Boston, Mass. &quot;They will be successful with it, but it will be a low-profile part of HP's product line.&quot;</p>
<p>HP said all of the machines use a flatbed copy surface and are equipped with zoom technology to reduce and enlarge documents from 50 percent to 400 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
