<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761027" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Argentaria H1 dips, sees full-yr turnaround.</title>
<headline>Argentaria H1 dips, sees full-yr turnaround.</headline>
<byline>Sharman Esarey</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's Argentaria posted on Monday a 10.7 percent earnings drop in the first half of 1997, but said staff cutbacks would help boost full-year profit growth by more than 10 percent.</p>
<p>The net attributable income of Spain's third-largest bank declined to 33.24 billion pesetas ($214 million) from 37.22 billion pesetas.</p>
<p>&quot;Net attributable profit is going to grow by more than two digits (for the full year),&quot; Chairman Francisco Gonzalez told a news conference.</p>
<p>Argentaria, which is still 29.2 percent state-owned, has aggressively restructured to cut costs, boost profitability and offset the drawbacks of having a relatively small domestic branch network.</p>
<p>Net interest income -- which reflects earnings on loans after costs from deposits -- rose to 108.51 billion pesetas from 97.37 billion.</p>
<p>Ordinary income, which also includes fees and commissions and trading income, climbed to 151.06 billion pesetas from 140.06 billion.</p>
<p>As a result and in the light of moderate growth in costs, operating revenue, a traditional yardstick of basic banking, rose a solid 12.6 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The results that we are presenting are very good. We have put tremendous importance on recurring income,&quot; Gonzalez said. &quot;This is an enormous qualitative change.&quot;</p>
<p>But perhaps even more important is the deal, announced on Friday, to slim down its Banco Exterior (BEX) unit, which has been hampered by above-average wage costs and has been considered the group's Achilles' Heel.</p>
<p>Argentaria, which was formed in 1991 through the merger of six state-owned banks and savings bank, agreed with unions to cut 2,100 jobs at BEX over the coming three years.</p>
<p>The entire Banco Exterior de Espana group, which includes national and foreign units, currently has 8,218 workers on its payroll.</p>
<p>&quot;This deal puts an end to the bank's two principal problems of the last two years -- too many people and an inapproprate union agreement,&quot; said BEX Managing Director Federico Outon.</p>
<p>Despite a sharp improvement at home, the bank is not yet ready to extend its reach abroad, although Gonzalez reiterated the group's interest in Latin America.</p>
<p>While Argentaria has been tidying up on the home front, Spain's top two banks, Santander and Banco Bilbao Vizcaya have sunk a combined $5.3 billion pesetas into the region this decade, spending $2.1 billion this year alone.</p>
<p>&quot;This group has more aspirations and we think Latin America is a good opportunity, but there are priorities,&quot; Gonzalez said.</p>
<p>Argentaria, which has said it has almost 300 billion pesetas available for purchases, is active in fund management in Bolivia, but has only minimal presence in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be (there) when an opportunity surfaces, not when the others do it,&quot; Gonzalez said.</p>
<p>--Madrid Newsroom +34  1585 2167</p>
<p>($ = 155.3 Spanish Pesetas)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
