<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761037" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: P&amp;U shares vulnerable to Q2 shocks - analysts.</title>
<headline>P&amp;U shares vulnerable to Q2 shocks - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Birgitta Forsberg</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in battered drugs group Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn could drop if the company's second quarter report, due Tuesday, unveils more restructuring costs or a lower than expected profit, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>P&amp;U, created by the merger of Pharmacia of Sweden and U.S. Upjohn in 1995, is at a crossroads and the market is looking to new chief executive and president Fred Hassan to prove he can sort the shaky group out.</p>
<p>P&amp;U is expected to post earnings per share (EPS) of US$0.36 for the second quarter of 1997, down from $0.51 before one-off costs in the corresponding quarter a year ago.</p>
<p>As P&amp;U's current share price of 294.5 crowns have benefited both from competitors strong earnings and expectations about a turnaround for the group in 1998, analysts say that bad news in the report could cause the shares to tumble.</p>
<p>The shares have climbed 37 percent from a year-low of 214.50 crowns at the end of April, aided by the company announcing a series of restructuring measures and appointing Hassan as the new chief in May.</p>
<p>&quot;The share is at a high level. A strong 1998 under the new management is on the cards,&quot; said analyst Goran Kallebo of Matteus who is neutral or slightly negative at this price.</p>
<p>&quot;If the report hinted at even greater difficulties in the second half of the year, the share will dive.&quot;</p>
<p>Others do not expect a plunge as many have cut forecasts after a string of profit warnings in the past 10 months.</p>
<p>&quot;It's now unlikely that the share price will collapse. People have cut their expectations to more realistic levels and the room for disappointment is much more limited,&quot; said analyst Franc Gregori at BZW.</p>
<p>Hassan issued one of the latest profit warnings on July 3, saying second quarter earnings could be lower than $0.37 EPS posted for the first quarter.</p>
<p>Many analysts regard 1997 as a lost year and focus on 1998 instead.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe this has been a clean-up quarter. We think that the clean-up and the realigning of management will lead to an acceleration in product roll-out and make 1998 a turnaround year,&quot; said Prem Lachman at Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>Although many analysts see a lower than expected profit pulling the share price down, costs are their greatest worry as confidence in P&amp;U has been shaken by repeated restructuring.</p>
<p>&quot;There can be a large negative effect on the share if the profit lands below the expected $0.36 (EPS),&quot; said one analyst who did not want to be named, adding that it would make it very difficult for the company to meet full-year earnings per share expectations of $1.66.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the cost side which is interesting. If the company announces further measures, costs will rise.&quot;</p>
<p>But as Hassan desperately needs to bring down the cost base to match more realistic sales expectations some analysts would welcome more restructuring costs.</p>
<p>&quot;I would see more restructuring costs as good news. It would be a tough measure and show that the company really intends to do something,&quot; said Marie-Helene Leopold at Paribas.</p>
<p>Despite many analysts expecting a recovery next year when EPS are seen rising to $1.93 from $1.66 this year, according to a Reuters survey, several are negative.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if new products pop up all the time this is counterbalanced by many of the company's patents expiring. It's cost cuts which will make earnings rise in 1998,&quot; Kallebo said.</p>
<p>Some analysts do not think the turnaround will come until 1999. They say P&amp;U needs new products, which have higher margins than old products, but notes that it keeps launching small products on competitive markets.</p>
<p>Others say the group is too unfocused with products sprawled across 10 therapeutic areas.</p>
<p>Analysts saw the company as a takeover target, but not until it has its house in order.</p>
<p>&quot;P&amp;U could be a takeover target but a company considering a takeover will probably wait for the restructuring to take effect instead of buying now and adding another mess into the company,&quot; Leopold says.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
