<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761184" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK gilts seen pausing for breath, seek U.S. lead.</title>
<headline>UK gilts seen pausing for breath, seek U.S. lead.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gilts shrugged off strong GDP data to end with modest gains on Friday, cutting the spread over Bunds to a three-week low in the process.</p>
<p>The September gilt future settled 8/32 higher at 115-19 to cap a positive week in which it posted a new contract high of 115-25. The contract ended last week at 114-24.</p>
<p>&quot;Gilts should maintain their positive feel for a while,&quot; said Mark Henry, analyst at futures brokerage GNI.</p>
<p>The gilt/Bund spread, at 149 basis points late on Friday, broke below 150 for the first time in more than three weeks. It has been tethered tightly to 160 basis points recently.</p>
<p>&quot;Speculation that the Bundesbank might be prepared to raise rates soon, has helped gilts relatively,&quot; Henry said.</p>
<p>The German central bank's decision not to detail its open market operations for the whole of its four-week summer break sparked a frenzy of speculation that it might push its repo rate higher. The September Bund future dropped 13 basis points to 102.92 on Friday.</p>
<p>Figures out early in the session showed the British economy grew by a sturdy 3.4 percent year-on-year in the second quarter with the service sector still rocketing along, up 4.5 percent from a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The key point from the figures is that the economy is growing at an unsustainable rate,&quot; said Adam Cole, UK economist at HSBC James Capel. &quot;I think the Bank of England will push up interest rates by another quarter-point at the August meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bank's monetary policy committee meets next on August 6 and 7.</p>
<p>Reflecting the odds of a fourth rate rise in as many months, the September short sterling future closed two basis points higher at 92.82, pricing in base rates a quarter-point above their current 6.75 percent within two months.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally think they will tighten in August,&quot; Henry said. &quot;But there is a growing belief that rates might peak only 50 basis points above here,&quot; much less extreme than many had thought.</p>
<p>Next week boasts little economic data apart from consumer credit figures on Tuesday. They are unlikely to do anything but confirm that consumer spending is powering along.</p>
<p>A rise in consumer credit of up to one billion pounds in June is forecast.</p>
<p>&quot;Some households may be using windfall gains to pay off outstanding debt, although there also seem to be many who are using them to finance current consumption,&quot; said David Philpotts, UK economist at Schroders.</p>
<p>-- Mike Peacock, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7708</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
