<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761253" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: INTERVIEW-Jackson's Austrim another BTR?.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Jackson's Austrim another BTR?.</headline>
<byline>Ian Pemberton</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Perhaps unintentionally, Alan Jackson appears to be building another industrial conglomerate much like the global BTR operation he led until the end of 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;I suppose it could be said, but I am not trying to follow them,&quot; Jackson said when asked if the comparison between his bite-size Austrim Ltd and BTR Plc was valid.</p>
<p>Austrim said earlier on Monday that its 1996/97 (July/June) net profit jumped to A$21.91 million and that it plans a rights issue that will raise A$208 million and wipe out all debt.  </p>
<p>The year-ago profit of A$4.41 million was achieved when Austrim was still a minor finance company and only six months after Jackson ended a five-year stint as chief executive of BTR Plc and chairman of its local offshoot BTR Nylex Ltd.</p>
<p>His period in the London head office has been viewed with some equivocation by analysts who regarded him as one of the City's derring-do Aussies in the early days.</p>
<p>Later on, however, Jackson's expensive and expansive strategies faced criticism for building an unwieldy company which had no definite focus.  </p>
<p>As the largest shareholder and executive chairman, Jackson has approved about A$250 million of acquisitions by Austrim in the last 12 months.</p>
<p>Some of the money has been spent on an agreed A$68 million bid for auto parts group Hawker Richardson Ltd, which is still underway, and the A$53 million purchase of the privately-held local textile firm Calum which has given the company a tentative footing in the Indian auto market.</p>
<p>Austrim also spent A$46.1 million in one day last August buying two plant hire firms.  </p>
<p>Jackson said his focus with Austrim is to invest only in the industrial manufacturing sector and achieve growth by building what the company already has and dipping into the coffers when an attractive business comes up for grabs.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very happy with industrial things. And I am very happy with industrial services like plant hire but I am not interested in the manufacturing of food products or those sorts of things.</p>
<p>&quot;I understand industrial and I am probably too old to change,&quot; said the 61-year old businessman whose experience is sought each month as a member of the Reserve Bank board of directors.  </p>
<p>Jackson is coy about the future, ruling out any temptation to predict future earnings but admitting that the company could raise plenty of cash if the right opportunity came along, as it has at least six times in the last 12 months.</p>
<p>&quot;By the time the rights issue is finished we won't have any debt at all. We would have a capacity for A$300 million to A$400 million of borrowings, I think.&quot;</p>
<p>Local and European fund managers are becoming interested in the company, although Jackson remains the largest shareholder with more than 11 percent and Kerry Stokes, the chairman of local television operator Seven Network Ltd, has about  </p>
<p>10 percent.</p>
<p>Both are showing handsome profits on their original investment, with the shares worth just 65 cents when Jackson first emerged on the share register.</p>
<p>Austrim shares soared 8.4 percent to close at A$4.15 on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
