<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761477" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Zhejiang Expressway mulls road investment.</title>
<headline>Zhejiang Expressway mulls road investment.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese toll road operator Zhejiang Expressway Co Ltd said it was in talks to invest in road construction and toll collection projects.</p>
<p>&quot;Following a successful listing, the main task is to ensure an appropriate application of the raised funds which involves the construction of Jiaxing Section of the Shanghai-Hangzhou Expressway and finacing the investment of new projects,&quot; Zhejiang Expressway said in an earnings statement on Monday.</p>
<p>The company said it was in discussion to invest in the construction of the 35-kilometre Huzhou section of the Hangzhou-Nanjing Expresswway and to purchase toll collection rights of the Huzhou section of National Road 104.</p>
<p>&quot;The discussion is expected to be concluded soon and construction is expected to commence by September,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The company also said it was considering an investment in the Shangyu-Sanmen Road if a feasibility study of the investment showed a rate of return of more than 20 percent.</p>
<p>Zhejiang Expressway, listed in May 1997, posted profit of 99.85 million yuan for the year ended in December 1996.</p>
<p>Zhejiang Expressway, representing the Zhejiang provincial government's main vehicle for expressway development, operates the Zhejiang section of the Shanghai-Hangzhou-Ningbo Expressway. Its shares eased HK$0.075 to HK$2.225 at midday on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020041">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
