<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761449" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Crude Outlook - Heavy grades see thin demand.</title>
<headline>Asia Crude Outlook - Heavy grades see thin demand.</headline>
<byline>Azlin Ahmad</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asia's heavy sweet crudes are expected to be under pressure this week with cool weather in Japan limiting summer demand there, traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>Prices of the heavy sweet burning grades such as Widuri and Cinta were artificially supported last week due to stagnant trading.</p>
<p>Sellers of Cinta and Widuri kept their offers around ICP +50 cents per barrel, in line with the last trades done.</p>
<p>But buying interest was very thin and traders expect prices to weaken unless the Japan summer becomes much hotter.  </p>
<p>Only Minas prices remained firm on tighter spot supplies following the smaller Indonesian August allocations, with August barrels traded at ICP +75 cents last week.</p>
<p>Japanese buyers are also starting to cover their September requirements, looking for lighter crudes to meet their heating oil demand as winter draws near.</p>
<p>This should provide some support the market for light Middle East crudes from Abu Dhabi and Qatar in September, which has just started trading.  </p>
<p>But although traders expect the September prices of Abu Dhabi Murban and Lower Zakum crudes to firm in comparison to August, it might still be difficult to achieve premiums over the monthly official selling prices (OSP) unless the OSPs are reduced.</p>
<p>Since July, Murban and Lower Zakum have been trading at discounts of 30/40 cents to their respective OSPs, due to limited buying interest and competition from West African crudes.</p>
<p>India awarded seven cargoes of Dubai crude in the September buy tender that closed on Thursday.  </p>
<p>This is higher than market expectations of four cargoes, and is expected to prop up Dubai prices over the next week.</p>
<p>Dubai intermonth spreads have already firmed, and the Brent/Dubai spreads have narrowed by 15 cents to 80/90 cents per barrel from Friday.</p>
<p>August supplies of Australian light crudes are committed, with trading for September likely to start this week.</p>
<p>Sellers of Australian crudes are offering higher prices compared to August, banking on increased buying from North Asia to stockpile for winter.  </p>
<p>But Malaysian crudes remain oversupplied, keeping their prices under pressure.</p>
<p>Last week a U.S. major bought a total of 900,000 barrels of August Tapis and Miri from another major, for the U.S. Gulf Coast.</p>
<p>The Tapis was traded at WTI +10, with Miri at WTI +23, on a cost and freight basis.</p>
<p>With freight estimated around $2.00 per barrel, traders equated the levels on a free on board basis to a discount of more than $1.00 to Tapis APPI -- the pricing benchmark.</p>
<p>The last Tapis trade done for August was at Tapis APPI -35.  </p>
<p>Traders said depressed gasoil prices were limiting the demand for Tapis crude from Asian refiners.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65 870 3082)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
