<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761405" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan retail buying of foreign bonds falls in June.</title>
<headline>Japan retail buying of foreign bonds falls in June.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign bond purchases by individual Japanese investors and corporations slumped in June, dropping more than one trillion yen from the peak in February, the Japan Securities Dealers' Association (JSDA) said on Monday.</p>
<p>Foreign bond buying by individual Japanese investors and corporations totalled 803.420 billion yen in June, compared with 969.732 billion yen in the same month a year earlier and February's peak of 1,885.152 billion yen, according to figures compiled by JSDA.</p>
<p>&quot;Figures in June were the lowest since we started compiling data under our current method in January 1996,&quot; a JSDA official said.</p>
<p>Japanese brokerage houses had hoped that yield-hungry individual investors would be keen to invest their summer bonuses, usually received in June, in foreign bonds.</p>
<p>But the dollar's nosedive of more than 15 yen in May was blamed for cooling individual investors' interest in foreign bonds, industry sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;As we had wild swings in foreign exchange rates, many people cautiously monitored currencies...and I think forex moves had the largest impact (on foreign bond purchases),&quot; a source at a major Japanese brokerage house said.</p>
<p>He added, however, that demand for foreign bonds will persist, given the current interest rate gap between Japan and other foreign countries due to Japan's policy of maintaining ultra-low interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar rose to 117 yen today, and if the trend toward a weaker yen reappears, then demand for foreign bonds will increase.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted around 117.10 yen in late afternoon Tokyo trade on Monday.</p>
<p>--- Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-8584</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
