<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761450" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs end Tokyo down after briefly touching 126.02.</title>
<headline>JGBs end Tokyo down after briefly touching 126.02.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key September 10-year Japanese government bond (JGB) futures contract ended thin Tokyo trade down on Monday after briefly touching 126.02 and then running into profit-taking sales prompted in part by firm stocks, traders said.</p>
<p>But operator wariness ahead of key Japanese data due out Wednesday and a lack of other factors kept the topside heavy.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though sentiment for JGBs is fundamentally firm and another test of the highs likely soon, some fresh factors are needed at this point,&quot; one trust bank trader said. Key September ended the day at 125.88, down 0.04 from Friday.  </p>
<p>Volume picked up during afternoon trade but still remained on the thin side at 30,123, and this was exaggerating moves a bit, traders added.</p>
<p>Key September had also risen to 126.02 on Friday, its highest level since April 25, prompting traders to say that the start of an uptrend that could lead to a challenge of 126.50 and then the record high of 127.34 soon was in the offing.</p>
<p>Others said the benchmark 182nd futures contract could test its record low yield of 2.075 percent within the month. But while traders agreed that sentiment is still firm, they said moves seemed stalled for now, with directionless trade likely.  </p>
<p>Morning stock gains and the yen's slide to 117.41 per dollar put JGBs under pressure in early trade, but short-covering and bargain-hunting erased this until just before the close, when further sales emerged.</p>
<p>Some traders said today's bond dip was a natural response to last week's quick rise, with 125.70 support likely to hold.</p>
<p>&quot;After reconfirming the downside during the early part of the week, key September could take a shot at breaking above 126.00 again, depending on factors,&quot; one trust bank trader said, adding that the market is closely watching Japan industrial production figures for June due out Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Japan's industrial output is expected to have fallen 2.8 percent in June from the previous month after a large increase in May, an average of economists' forecasts showed on Monday.</p>
<p>Economists' predictions for industrial output ranged from a fall of 1.2 percent to a fall of 4.0 percent, compared with the Ministry of International Trade and Industry (MITI)'s forecast of a 2.6 percent drop in manufacturers' output.</p>
<p>Although no substantial buying was detected in cash bonds, they remained well-bid, particularly in the longer end, and gave futures some support. The key 182nd bond yield was at 2.180 percent at 0635 GMT against 2.175 percent on Friday.  </p>
<p>Earlier, the yield ranged from 2.160 to 2.190 percent.</p>
<p>Persistent demand from institutional investors is expected to keep the downside well-supported, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Major investors, such as life and non-life insurers, have been slow to invest money earmarked for JGB investment for the April-June quarter,&quot; said Takayuki Tanaka, strategist at LTCB Securities.</p>
<p>The JGBs have been and will be supported by buying from investors who have not yet satisfied their portfolio demand, he added.</p>
<p>--Elaine Lies +81-3-3432-8806</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
