<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761634" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: FEATURE - Saudis battle to save water after subsidy.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Saudis battle to save water after subsidy.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The advertisement shows a veiled woman bathing her baby while water gushes out of taps into an overflowing basin. Suddenly the water flow stops and the child is left with soap all over its face.</p>
<p>&quot;We made from water every living thing,&quot; an old man in a flowing white robe says, reciting Islam's holy book, the Koran.</p>
<p>His message is clear: &quot;Please don't waste water.&quot;</p>
<p>The advertisement being screened on Saudi television is part of a campaign launched in July to get the 18 million people living in the desert state to cut profligate water use.</p>
<p>King Fahd is behind the drive. In late July he urged citizens to save water and said his government was revising laws regulating consumption. &quot;It is a religious as well as a national and development duty,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But economists and water experts say the authorities have a tough task ahead. For years there has been no incentive to save water, which is cheap at around 0.3 riyals ($0.08) per cubic metre (35 cubic feet), thanks to generous state subsidies.</p>
<p>Water use per person in the kingdom is said to be higher than in other countries at the same stage along the development road. Some officials have put per capita daily consumption at 400 litres (88 gallons), versus an international average of about 200 litres.</p>
<p>Residents say most house and apartment rents are inclusive of water charges, or a fixed fee is levied by the building owner once a year. Others say they never receive water bills.</p>
<p>&quot;The water charge is included in my rent, so I don't even have to think about how much I use,&quot; said a Western businessman.</p>
<p>A Saudi academic said he had not received a bill at home for 18 months. &quot;I want to pay because water should not be free.&quot;</p>
<p>FARMERS ARE THE MAIN CULPRITS</p>
<p>But domestic users alone are not to blame for excess water use, as they consume only 10 percent of total annual demand of around 18 billion cubic metres (635 billion cubic feet). The main culprits are farmers.</p>
<p>&quot;Agriculture continues to consume almost 90 percent of water from all sources, and the expansion in grain production has been heavily dependent on non-renewable ground water in most areas,&quot; says the kingdom's five-year development plan to the year 2000.</p>
<p>The plan targets a cut in water use to 17.5 billion cubic metres (618 billion cubic feet) by the end of the century from 1994's 18.2 billion (643 billion cubic feet).</p>
<p>It also calls for a decline in the use of non-renewable ground water to 13 billion cubic metres (459 billion cubic feet) from about 14.8 billion (523 billion cubic feet).</p>
<p>&quot;These targets are to be achieved by reducing the rate of water consumption in agriculture at an average annual rate of 2.2 percent and achieving balanced consumption rates for other purposes,&quot; the plan says.</p>
<p>More than 80 percent of the kingdom's water is non-renewable ground water. Around 14 percent is surface and shallow ground water and four percent is desalinated in the 24 plants which Saudi Arabia says are the world's biggest. Less than one percent is reclaimed or treated water.</p>
<p>Since the 1980s, Saudi Arabia has been growing many crops not suitable to its arid conditions, economists in Riyadh say.</p>
<p>Government help in drilling wells and cheap rates until 1995 for diesel used to drive water pumps were an incentive to grow crops that otherwise would probably have been imported.</p>
<p>In the early 1990s, Saudi Arabia was growing four million tonnes of wheat a year. This has fallen to about 1.3 million now, because of cuts in state grain prices. But this has led, ironically, to higher output of some even more water-intensive crops.</p>
<p>&quot;Production of alfalfa, which consumes more water than wheat and barley, has increased,&quot; Hussein Mousa of the U.S. Agricultural Trade Office in Riyadh told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is planning to reduce forage production because Saudi Arabia is exporting a lot of alfalfa to neighbouring countries, which is like exporting water,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>PENALTIES MAY FORCE MORE EFFICIENT WATER USE</p>
<p>Economists and water specialists say the kingdom desperately needs to enforce demand management and some suggest penalties -- including fines and cutting off water supplies -- for abusers.</p>
<p>&quot;The government might restrict or ban altogether the export of alfalfa,&quot; Mousa said.</p>
<p>&quot;Penalties may be a good idea, but it is politically sensitive. Water is strategic,&quot; said an agricultural economist.</p>
<p>Others say recycling water for irrigation and industrial use in cooling factories, for example, also needs to be promoted.</p>
<p>But they say the best way to change wasteful habits is to raise prices and enforce strict revenue collection.</p>
<p>&quot;Many people who never receive water bills think that, because it is free, we have plenty of it. If they are forced to pay realistic prices they will quickly learn water's worth,&quot; said an economist. ($1=3.75 riyals)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
