<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76161" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton encryption export proposal not ready yet.</title>
<headline>Clinton encryption export proposal not ready yet.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration is not ready to release a widely anticipated proposal to relax export restrictions on computer encoding technology, a Commerce Department official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Undersecretary of Commerce William Reinsch, at a hearing of the House Judiciary Committee, said the proposal had not yet been formalized.</p>
<p>&quot;Our work is not yet done,&quot; Reinsch said in prepared testimony. &quot;We are continuing to consult with industry and international partners to refine our proposal.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Judiciary Committee was holding a hearing on Resolution 3011, a bill that would dramatically relax encryption export limits.</p>
<p>Vice President Al Gore outlined the administration's ideas for relaxing limits on encryption exports in July, saying export controls should be liberalized only if encryption programs include so-called key escrow components.</p>
<p>The computer industry and many members of Congress oppose the key escrow and argue that foreign competitors will sell encryption programs without escrow features.</p>
<p>Reinsch said the key escrow approach is needed to help law enforcement and intelligence agencies deal with encryption.</p>
<p>&quot;This approach balances economic needs with law enforcement concerns and is one that many of our major trading partners, most notably the United Kingdom, are also adopting,&quot; Reinsch said in his testimony.</p>
<p>He said the United States is working in the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development to craft a global policy for encryption.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
