<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761705" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FEATURE - Wired? Maybe one day you won't need to be.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Wired? Maybe one day you won't need to be.</headline>
<byline>Sara Henley</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>There was a time when it was trendy to be wired -- forget it. Now you get &quot;unwired&quot;.</p>
<p>You do not need telephone wires or cables to surf the Internet. Getting &quot;unwired&quot; just requires another technology purchase.</p>
<p>Picture this recent scene: a sunny Sunday at the waterfront in the Finnish capital, brightly dressed day-trippers mill about, waiting for a ferry to one of the many islands popular with locals for picnics and bathing.</p>
<p>Your correspondent is among them in body, but not in mind. As we climb aboard the ferry, a small black box in my hand takes me to www.ramdomhouse.com/davebarry/emoticon.html.</p>
<p>A frivolous World Wide Web site, it contains a joke gallery of the signs Web-surfers dream up using punctuation marks to form graphics, building from the basic :) for a happy person, :-(sad person with a nose, :---(person who is sad because he or she has a very long nose.</p>
<p>It may well seem that only a very sad individual could need such entertainment when the sun is shining, the weather is warm, and everyone is on the way to a pleasant Sunday picnic.</p>
<p>But the point of this electronic excursion was to test that it was possible, and it was.</p>
<p>A PERSONAL ORGANISER YOU CAN TALK THROUGH</p>
<p>At the moment you can spend about $1,300 on a box slightly larger than a mobile telephone, rather like an electronic personal organiser. It opens out to form a palm-sized keyboard and it also works as a normal mobile phone.</p>
<p>The first machine of its kind, it has come from the country with the highest global penetration both of mobile phone use and Internet connections -- one in three Finns has a mobile phone and six out of every 100 have an Internet connection.</p>
<p>Manufacturer Nokia launched the Communicator 9000 in mass-market volumes in more than 30 European and Asian markets in the spring, and plans to sell it in the United States soon.</p>
<p>The actual price varies widely across markets, and Nokia will not comment directly on how the machine is selling.</p>
<p>But the company confidently loaned a Communicator on trial to this Reuters correspondent, a novice holding a device said to be be used for voice, data, fax, Internet and e-mail communication.</p>
<p>The conclusion: it can, usually with relatively few hitches.</p>
<p>People who are already comfortable with palmtop personal organisers would probably get the most out of the Communicator -- its calendar and contacts software make it like a personal organiser you can also talk to, as well as being able to fax and surf the Net.</p>
<p>Those with paper-and-pen habits would have to make a lot of lifestyle changes to incorporate it into the working routine, but could use the Communicator to write and send shorter items from distant places.</p>
<p>HIT THE SEND BUTTON</p>
<p>Strictly speaking, to get &quot;unwired&quot; you also need a cellular tele operator offering data as well as voice mobile services: most do in Europe but a businessman with a Communicator in Albania recently was not able to use it for much.</p>
<p>Sometimes the total cost includes an extra subscription to wireless data and fax services, although these come as standard in Finland. And expect a charge for a remote e-mail address.</p>
<p>For Nokia, the world-leader in digital mobile phones, the point of the Communicator is that it is data rather than chat which is driving growth in wireless communication.</p>
<p>Many parents have been happy to invest in mobile phones so they can check on the whereabouts of their teenagers, but this piece of equipment is in a different league.</p>
<p>For some its capacity may already outpace mainstream demand. In countries like Finland it is already possible, using an ordinary mobile phone, to learn top news and latest securities prices through smart messaging.</p>
<p>But important executives making promises to meet people as they travel around can book dates in their Communicator and hit the Send button to their secretaries.</p>
<p>CHALLENGE OF IMPROVED CONNECTIVITY</p>
<p>Back at ground level, rule number one in my experience was: read the manual. The Communicator is quite complicated.</p>
<p>Embarrassingly, talking was my first hitch. A mobile-phone user gets used to speaking into the same side of the handset as the keypad, but you have to flip the Communicator over. This fact dawned only after several bafflingly muffled conversations.</p>
<p>After reading the manual it also emerged that the hands-free option was probably easier.</p>
<p>The flip-open keyboard is dainty, and clumsy fingers can easily bash out mistakes, but for a short spell it is not too frustrating and the keys make a satisfying click.</p>
<p>Web-surfing was quite fast. In general in Finland it is speedy, also with fixed line connections. The Communicator took about 40 seconds to link up to one home page chosen at random.</p>
<p>The tiny Liquid Crystal Display screen and basic browsing software impose clear limitations on the kind of Internet pages it is possible to view: you can get to many, but trying to call up complex sites jams the machine. It can handle images, slowly.</p>
<p>Nokia has put together links for pages which are &quot;optimised&quot; for Communicator use, but so far there is not a very wide range. Finnish-language sites dominate, including news services, a Finnish-English dictionary and a road weather report.</p>
<p>An attempt to use a London road guide was pretty cumbersome, but tourist pointers for Paris were generally easy to find and use. On several occasions the Internet connection failed with the message &quot;Transfer was interrupted!&quot;.</p>
<p>But the speed and ease of sending e-mail messages and faxes -- once everything is set up -- was hard to believe. Fax displays were very clear and the machine can receive handwritten scribbles and drawings.</p>
<p>A highpoint was in solving problems a colleague was having getting through on fixed-line e-mail to an address to a large company. By copying it to the Communicator remote mailbox, it could easily be redirected as a fax, without any printing.</p>
<p>While in the Nordic area people are very keen on e-mail, Nokia spokeswoman Liisa Nyyssonen said faxes remain dominant elsewhere in Europe. (Once you have a fax in the Communicator, it is not possible to edit it or turn it into an e-mail.)</p>
<p>An e-mail sent to another Internet address took just two minutes to arrive, although it took a full night to get one to a company intranet e-mail address.</p>
<p>&quot;I think most of the challenges are related to improved connectivity (to company intranets),&quot; said Nyyssonen.</p>
<p>COMPOSE YOUR OWN TUNE</p>
<p>There are very sophisticated features on offer: you can connect the Communicator through an infra-red or cable link to a personal computer, making for a much smaller, handier version of &quot;briefcase&quot; software on portable computers to transfer files.</p>
<p>The Communicator highlights the realistic potential of one little black box that could do everything.</p>
<p>Nyyssonen said there were no plans yet to include an audio recording chip; but that and video cannot be far away considering miniature televisions on sale from Japan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
