<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="761709" id="root" date="1997-07-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest -July 28.</title>
<headline>Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest -July 28.</headline>
<text>
<p>-------------- GAM --------------------</p>
<p>REUTERS GERMAN ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST</p>
<p>----------- July 28, 1997 -----------------</p>
<p>News from Reuters and the German press on Advertising,</p>
<p>Marketing, Media, the Internet, Brand-name Products and</p>
<p>Consumer Trends</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Mid-size companies are discovering the increasing</p>
<p>importance of corporate communication and advertising, according</p>
<p>to a study by the RTS Rieger Team advertising agency.</p>
<p>(Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>HOCKENHEIM, Germany - Four years after its return to Formula One motor racing, Mercedes-Benz is still trying to recapture its former glory as a leader in one of the world's most glamourous sports. Mercedes, which left the sport in 1955 when one of its cars was involved in a horrifying crash at Le Mans, has notched only one Formula One victory since returning in 1994 with the Sauber team and then jumping in 1995 as engine supplier to McLaren. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Consumer and Media Analysis (VuMA) group in Germany reacts to recent criticism of its TV ratings system from television stations and ad agencies by integrating its VuMA TV ratings data into the model Plan-TV (AGF). The stations and agencies had questioned the validity of VuMA's practice of measuring ratings per ad block. Now Plan-TV offers data based on an average of &quot;a half hour in an half year&quot; which it provides more representative data. (Horizont)</p>
<p>**********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>MUNICH - ProSieben Media AG, which was floated recently on the stock market, says chief editor Gerd Berger is leaving the company, and that it will reduce the amount of in-house productions aired on its channels. ProSieben, which runs the ProSieben and Kabel 1 cable TV channels, says Jan Koerbelin would take responsibility for all output. Berger will not be replaced, a spokesman says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MADRID - A spokesman for Leo Kirch says the Germany media tycoon is checking a Spanish newspaper report that Kirch has become embroiled in allegations of tax and investment violations. The daily newspaper El Mundo reported that Spain's High Court charged Kirch for violations related to the purchase of a 25-percent stake in Spanish television channel Telecinco.</p>
<p>(Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>STUTTGART - German state representatives will meet on August 5 to discuss the expansion of the current radio and television user fees to Internet users. Among topics to be debated are group rates for companies and schools with multiple user sites, says the fee expert of the Sueddeutsche Rundfunk (SDR) station, Armin Herb. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>BONN - Wine-drinkers in Britain, the Netherlands and Denmark help boost German wine exports, which rose nearly five percent last year, the ZMP farm price and marketing office says. Despite tough competition, particularly on European markets, German wine exports increase by 4.7 percent to about 2.3 million hectolitres from the previous year. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Deutsche Bank AG denies a report it had planned to buy Bayerische Vereinsbank, prompting the Munich-based bank to merge with its fiercest rival to avoid being swallowed by Germany's market leader. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MOSCOW - A consortium of Russian and German banks won a quarter of Russia's telecoms holding company Svyazinvest in Moscow's biggest privatisation to date. The consortium is built around Uneximbank, Russia's third biggest bank headed by youthful ex-cabinet minister Vladimir Potanin, and Deutsche Morgan Grenfell (DMG), the London-based investment banking arm of Germany's Deutsche Bank AG. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MUNICH - The non-life German unit of insurance group Allianz AG says it expects competition in the sector to intensify, but believes it has taken measures to equip itself for the fight. &quot;Even better customer service and new sales strategies are among the measures with which we intend to strengthen our market position,&quot; the unit says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>PEOPLE NEWS:</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Ilona Klueck, the creative director of the Frankfurt-based agency Ogilvy &amp; Mather (O&amp;M), will take charge of the agency's giant Dresdner Bank account. She joined O&amp;M in July after leaving Scholz &amp; Friends in Hamburg, where she had been responsbile for the international West cigarettes account. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>Deborah Cole, Berlin Newsroom, 49-30-203-98114</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>For further information and news, see Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. And visit us on the Internet: http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com ***********************************************</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
