<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76205" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ted Turner owns 1.5 percent of New Mexico - paper.</title>
<headline>Ted Turner owns 1.5 percent of New Mexico - paper.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ted Turner, founder of the Cable News Network, has bought a 578,004-acre (233,918 hectare) New Mexico ranch in a deal which makes him owner of about 1.5 percent of the state, a newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Turner, married to Hollywood actress Jane Fonda, owns two other ranches in New Mexico, plus five in Montana and Nebraska, according to the Atlanta Journal-Constitution.</p>
<p>His latest purchase was the Vermejo Park Ranch, which lies in the shadows of the Sangre de Cristo Mountains of northeastern New Mexico. The newspaper said he bought the property for an undisclosed sum from the Pennzoil Corp. of Houston.</p>
<p>Turner officials were not immediately available to comment on the report.</p>
<p>With its addition to his existing stable of New Mexico properties, Turner owns 1,796 square miles (4,651 square km) of land in the state. The state encompasses 121,336 square miles (314,236 square km) of mostly semi-arid and mountainous land, with Turner owning 1.48 percent.</p>
<p>The Vermejo ranch was expected to become home to 4,000 bison, Turner's livestock of choice.</p>
<p>But the Journal-Constitution said there also will be elk hunting for $8,500 a week when the season opens on October 4. Miles of streams will be open to fishing, for a price.</p>
<p>And the ranch's 86-year-old rustic stone buildings are capable of accommodating up to 75 guests.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
