<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762087" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FDA panel backs Spectranetics laser sheath.</title>
<headline>FDA panel backs Spectranetics laser sheath.</headline>
<dateline>GAITHERSBURG, Md. 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. Food and Drug Administration advisory committee on Tuesday voted unanimously to recommend approval of Spectranetics Corp.'s laser sheath to be used to remove pacemaker and implantable defibrillator leads.</p>
<p>About 300,000 such leads are implanted worldwide each year, and Spectranetics estimates that 10 percent of leads may require removal for reasons such as infection or incompatibility.  </p>
<p>The FDA is not bound by its panels' advice, but usually follows it.</p>
<p>The committee suggested that the laser sheath be used only with conventional tools and not be used in heavily calcified arteries. The panel also said that trained surgeons should attend at least the first two procedures done by untrained physicians.</p>
<p>Surgeons should also be warned about the potential for short-term irregular heartbeats when the laser gets too close to the myocardial junction, the committee said.  </p>
<p>Lead removal with conventional surgical tools alone can be difficult because the lead is often surrounded by scar tissue. The surgeon may have to apply counterpressure to work the lead free from the heart wall, which can have a shearing effect. Spectranetics said that when its device is used with conventional tools, there is little counterpressure needed as the laser ablates tissue, freeing the lead, as it moves through the vein.  </p>
<p>In a pivotal 301-patient trial, surgeons successfully removed 94.3 percent of leads in 244 patients randomized to the laser procedure.  Some 2.4 percent were partial removals, and 3.3 percent failures.</p>
<p>Using conventional tools, surgeons successfully removed only 64 percent of leads, partially removed 1.9 percent, and could not remove 33.9 percent.  Failures with conventional tools were &quot;crossed over&quot; into the laser group.</p>
<p>Spectranetics found that success varied greatly among study sites, with failures more likely with certain types of leads.  </p>
<p>Physicians' standard tool preferences also influenced failure rates.  Seventy-two patients were switched to laser. Surgeons successfully removed 88 percent of those leads, but could not extract 8.3 percent.</p>
<p>FDA medical reviewer Christopher Sloan said that despite the company's efforts, the study design had not completely minimized the potential for bias.</p>
<p>Spectranetics said that there was a low complication rate -- only about 2 percent compared to 2.5 percent with conventional methods -- and low mortality, about 0.8 percent.  </p>
<p>The procedure is relatively easy for surgeons to learn, the company said, adding that success rates were high from the start.  But the trials were conducted by experienced surgeons. FDA's Sloan said that Spectranetics' results may not be &quot;generalizable to physicians with less experience.&quot;  Panelists also said that there may need to be more training to ensure proper use.</p>
<p>Ronald Weintraub of Harvard University asked the firm for guidance on when to use the laser, noting that it was likely to be expensive.  Bruce Wilkoff, a Spectranetics investigator from the Cleveland Clinic Foundation, said that use will probably depend on physician preference and experience and whether hospitals will allow it.  He said he probably wouldn't expect to use it for leads less than two years old.  But he noted that the laser sheath gives predictable results, cutting down on the &quot;sweat factor&quot; in the operating room.</p>
<p>The FDA and panelists said that the Laser Sheath's small size might limit the kinds of leads that could be removed. But Spectranetics has two larger sizes in development. Spectranetics also said that the device had been used to extract some smaller defibrillator leads.</p>
<p>Spectranetics applied for FDA approval in September 1996. The device has received approvel for full distribution in European Union member countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAITHERSBURG, Md."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
