<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762194" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH CABINET MAPS OUT REPAIR PLAN AFTER FLOODS.</title>
<headline>POLISH CABINET MAPS OUT REPAIR PLAN AFTER FLOODS.</headline>
<byline>Marcin Grajewski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish government, unveiling more details on Tuesday of its plan to reconstruct areas hit by July's floods, said it wanted to repair a large part of damaged buildings and infrastructure within the next six months.</p>
<p>The government spokewoman Aleksandra Jakubowska said priority would be given to rebuilding and repairing such public buildings as schools, courts, hospitals, local government headquarters, libraries and some sport facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;About 150 schools should urgently be repaired before the school year begins (on September 1),&quot; Jakubowska told a news conference.</p>
<p>The government will also seek to repair bridges, roads and railways, destroyed by the floods which hit southwestern Poland more than three weeks ago, but in many cases damages are so severe that full reconstruction would last much longer than six months, she said.</p>
<p>She said the government did not yet have estimates of the costs of removing the damages. Some independent analysts have put them at up to 7.5 billion zlotys.</p>
<p>German reinsurer Munich Re has estimated flood damages in the Czech Republic, Poland and Germany at 10 billion marks.</p>
<p>Jakubowska said the government planned to mend all protection dikes by the end of October, clear passages in all rivers beds by November 30 and repair rentention reservoirs by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Sewage plans and water intakes would also be quickly repaired and the government services will closely monitor the state of drinking water and inspect food warehouses to avoid erruption of epidemics, she said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz earlier said that under the government scheme, electricity should be restored in two weeks, natural gas supply in three months, all roads should be usable by August 15, basic sewage systems fixed by the end of September and telephone links repaired in several weeks.</p>
<p>The government programme will offer cheap credits for housing and investment, tax breaks, food and medicine supplies in the affected ares.</p>
<p>The government now has 650 million zlotys ($187 million) reallocated from the current budget to spend on flood relief and plans to borrow $600 million from the World Bank and the European Investment Bank (EIB) to help finance the programme.</p>
<p>Parliament has also let the government borrow 2.5 billion zlotys from the central bank this year, of which one billion have already been drawn.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz also said the government might consider issuing special bonds to help finance the reconstruction.</p>
<p>Some government members have proposed increasing excise tax on tobacco and alcohol to generate more funds for the flood relief, Jakubowska said, but played down chances of introducing the measure. &quot;These have been only token proposals.&quot;</p>
<p>Jakubowska said that in the long term the government programme will seek to fully regulate the country's biggest rivers, Wisla and Odra, moving some houses from low-laying area near rivers. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
