<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762253" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Atlantic Container Line may quit Sweden.</title>
<headline>Atlantic Container Line may quit Sweden.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Container shipping group Atlantic Container Line AB said Tuesday it was exploring options for quitting Sweden.</p>
<p>&quot;The board of directors has initiated a study to explore various potential future tax and cost efficient domiciles for the company,&quot; ACL said.</p>
<p>The company is currently domiciled in Sweden after being spun off by Swedish transport group Bilspedition in 1994 and listed on the Oslo Stock Exchange. Its operating base is in New Jersey in the U.S.</p>
<p>ACL information officer Nils Erikson said the company was looking at several options. The move was triggered by recent changes to tax laws for shipping companies in Europe, he said.</p>
<p>The Netherlands and Norway have implemented new tax rules for shipping companies to reduce their tax burden.</p>
<p>Several Swedish shipping companies have suggested they may move from Stockholm this year due to high costs. Frontline has moved its domicile to Bermuda and switched its listing to Oslo at the beginning of this month.</p>
<p>Erikson said other offshore options, such as Bermuda, were also being considered.</p>
<p>He could give no date for a final decision.</p>
<p>ACL today reported a Swedish crowns 36 million improvement in operating results for the first half of 1997 to crowns 208 million.</p>
<p>Net profits fell to crowns 131 million, from 141 million, including a non-monetary loss on exchange differences of 34 million crowns.</p>
<p>The company added that the second half was not traditionally as strong as the first, but it expected results for the whole of 1997 to exceed that for last year with the help of a strong U.S. economy.</p>
<p>ACL added that it switched to the U.S. Port of Baltimore from Halifax in Canada to improve its terminal operations.</p>
<p>ACL earlier said it has been unable to find a merger partner and will continue as an independent niche carrier.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Shipping News + 44 171 542 4087. Fax 5017.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
