<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762427" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AZERBAIJAN: Azeris in talks with US firms on $500m gold deal.</title>
<headline>Azeris in talks with US firms on $500m gold deal.</headline>
<dateline>BAKU 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Baku will present proposals to a consortium of U.S. companies on a possible $500 million joint deal to mine gold in Azerbaijan during President Haydar Aliyev's visit to the United States, a top official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>First Deputy Prime Minister Abbas Abbasov said the draft of the proposed deal envisaged joint exploration and exploitation of nine gold mines with estimated reserves of 270 tonnes of gold, 250 tonnes of silver and 1.5 million tonnes of ore.</p>
<p>&quot;If negotiations are successful, the American side may have a 49 percent stake in the contract,&quot; Abbasov told Reuters</p>
<p>He said the consortium was called RV Investment Group Services LLS but added he did not know which companies were members.</p>
<p>Aliyev began a ten-day official state visit to the United States on Monday.</p>
<p>Abbasov said the gold sites were located in Azerbaijan's Nakhichevan autonomous republic, and the Zangelan, Kelbadjar, Tauz and Kedabek regions of the country.</p>
<p>Kelbadjar and Zangelan have been occupied by forces from neighbouring Armenia since 1993. The two countries are involved in a protracted territorial dispute which has cost 35,000 lives.</p>
<p>It was not clear how the mines could be utilised while they were under Armenian occupation.</p>
<p>One of the mines, Zod, is situated along the border between Armenia and Azerbaijan is the subject of a dispute.</p>
<p>Armenia signed the contract with Global Gold Corporation of the United States on joint exploration of Zod mine recently this year.</p>
<p>Azerbaijan has protested the deal as illegal and Aliyev has said he will lobby for it to be annulled, but Armenian officials have dismissed this.</p>
<p>--Tbilisi Newsroom +995 32 983 961</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AZERB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAKU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AZERBAIJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
