<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762592" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil coffee council to hold extra meeting Thurs.</title>
<headline>Brazil coffee council to hold extra meeting Thurs.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of Brazil's coffee council, known as the CDPC, will hold another preliminary meeting in Brasilia Thursday ahead of its next formal session, a spokeswoman for the Industry and Commerce Ministry (MICT) said.</p>
<p>Mauricio Assis, head of the primary commodities department at the MICT, declined to discuss any specific issues following a meeting of council members earlier Tuesday.</p>
<p>He declined to comment on whether a government plan to lend stocks to the soluble industry, which has been complaining about difficulty in obtaining raw material, would go ahead amid market rumors that the project had been scrapped.</p>
<p>Soluble industry officials were not immediately available to comment on talk that they plan to import robusta coffee from India under a drawback regime instead to alleviate the supply problems.</p>
<p>Soluble coffee producers earlier this year threatened to import the coffee but held off after the government pledged to find a solution within the framework of the CDPC, which unites representatives of the public and private sectors.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said the MICT planned to discuss with the Finance Ministry next week a series of financing measures aimed at the whole of the coffee sector.</p>
<p>A date for the next formal CDPC metting, due to be held in Santos, has not yet been set.</p>
<p>((--Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom +55 61 314 1193))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
