<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762576" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Banco de Mexico net reserves rise, assets fall.</title>
<headline>Banco de Mexico net reserves rise, assets fall.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banco de Mexico said on Tuesday its international reserves as of July 25 were $22.512 billion, compared to $22.474 billion on July 18.</p>
<p>The central bank said that its net international assets as of the same date were $15.184 billion compared to $15.196 billion the week before.  </p>
<p>The central bank said the decrease of $13 million in net international assets during the period was due to:</p>
<p>--Net outflows from operations with state oil company Pemex worth $56 million.</p>
<p>--Net outflows of foreign currency from operations with the federal government worth $31 million.</p>
<p>--A net gain of $74 million for a combination of factors including changes in the dollar value of non-dollar assets and liabilities held by the bank; net returns on interest rates and from trading of metals and securities; and net deposits in dollar accounts from commercial banks at the central bank.</p>
<p>It said that as of July 25, the foreign currency fund aimed at a prepayment of bank notes on August 6 was $5.982 billion.</p>
<p>Banco de Mexico said that between April 18 and April 25 the monetary base fell 2.439 billion pesos due to a fall in the seasonal demand of bills and coins.</p>
<p>In the same period, the government's balance at the central bank rose 14.848 billion pesos, due mainly to tax collection.</p>
<p>The bank said it undertook monetary regulation operations for a total of 10.846 billion pesos in the same time frame in order to meet a greater demand for bills and coins as well as to offset the increase in federal government deposits in the account it holds with the central bank.</p>
<p>The following tables detail Banco de Mexico's reserves and net domestic credit. All figures are in billions of pesos, unless otherwise indicated.</p>
<p>			     July 18	 July 25</p>
<p>International Reserves</p>
<p>   Pesos		   177.765	174.958</p>
<p>   U.S. Dollars	  $22.474 bln  $22.512 bln</p>
<p>Monetary Base	     83.348	80.909</p>
<p>Net International Assets*</p>
<p>    Pesos		  120.202	118.008</p>
<p>    U.S. Dollars	 $15.196 bln  $15.184 bln</p>
<p>Net Domestic Credit    -36.854	-37.099</p>
<p>*Net International Assets are defined as gross international assets minus central bank liabilities with the IMF and assets of less than a six-month duration from other central banks.</p>
<p>((-- Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7902))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
