<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762597" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Soft-drinks add pop to Femsa Q2 results.</title>
<headline>Soft-drinks add pop to Femsa Q2 results.</headline>
<byline>Tomas de la Rosa</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Beverage analysts gave Mexican beer and bottling company Fomento Economico Mexicano SA a passing grade for its key beer division in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>But it was the soft drinks subsidiary that really added some pop to second-quarter results, analysts said.</p>
<p>Overall, results from the second quarter were better than predictions from a Reuters survey of three beverage analysts.</p>
<p>As with the past two quarters, the subsidiary Coca-Cola Femsa, also known as KOF, provided the best news for the Monterrey-based company, which is also Mexico's second-largest brewer to Grupo Modelo SA de CV.</p>
<p>KOF bottles and distributes Coke in Mexico and Argentina.</p>
<p>Beverage analyst Scott Kolb of the Banorte brokerage summed up the results as &quot;Very good for KOF and not very good for the beer part.&quot;</p>
<p>Income from beer rose only 0.7 percent in real pesos in the second quarter this year over Q2 of 1996. But other analysts were impressed with the sales volumes, which were up 4.8 percent overall, 3.3 percent domestically and 34.6 percent from exports.</p>
<p>Femsa posted earnings per share of 0.62 pesos in the second quarter with revenues of 5.757 billion pesos and operating income of 917 million pesos.</p>
<p>That compared with an EPS estimate of 0.48 pesos, sales of 5.914 billion pesos and operating income of 667 million pesos predicted in the Reuters survey.</p>
<p>&quot;In the end we saw the results as positive, especially on the operating level where the margins are rising well,&quot; Kolb said.</p>
<p>Femsa's operating margin in the second quarter was 15.9 percent, 4.9 percentage points higher than in Q2 1996.</p>
<p>Greg Rianhard, an analyst with the Interacciones brokerage, noted that Femsa's beer margins &quot;are approximating those of Modelo and that has not been the case in the past three years.&quot;</p>
<p>Rianhard predicted better results next quarter as the company continues to improve operations in all of its divisions. Apart from beer and soft drinks, Femsa has a packing division and the Oxxo chain of convenience stores.</p>
<p>Ixe analyst Roberto Solanco said he was impressed with the soft drinks division, which posted an increase of seven percent in sales and 60 percent in the operating margin.</p>
<p>On the whole, he said, &quot;Prospects for growth in the next few quarters look very promising.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom, +525 728-7912))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
