<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762643" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Paranapanema unveils finance restructuring.</title>
<headline>Paranapanema unveils finance restructuring.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian mining group Paranapanema said it will issue $200 million in non-convertible debentures as a first step of a financial restructuring plan aimed at returning the company to profitability.</p>
<p>About half of the debentures are expected to be acquired by local pension funds which control Paranapanema, said the group's Market Relations director Helio Blak.  </p>
<p>In February last year, a group of pension funds acquired Paranapanema, now formally known as Mamore, and three mining firms -- semi-finished copper goods producer Eluma, copper maker Caraiba Metais and zinc producer Companhia Paraibuna de Metais -- to form a mining conglomerate.</p>
<p>Blak said the debenture issue, which was approved by the company's shareholders Monday, would also facilitate eventual talks with strategic partners.  &quot;We are also issuing the debentures to restructure the company's debts and create conditions for talks with strategic partners,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>During negotiations for the takeover deal last year, mining giant Companhia Vale do Rio Doce (CVRD), private steelmaker CSN and South Africa's Anglo American Corp of South Africa Ltd were interested in joining the pension funds in the project.  But the group ended up being acquired only by the funds.</p>
<p>Paranapanema group showed a 27 million real loss in the first quarter of the year.  In 1996, the company reported a net loss of 79.5 million reais, mostly due to a broad restructuring program that followed the company's takeover by the funds and last year's plunge in world copper prices.</p>
<p>Blak said he expects the debenture deal to be completed in the first half of August.</p>
<p>((--Fatima Cristina, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 2485412))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
