<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762665" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: A year after Cavallo, Argentine economy shines.</title>
<headline>A year after Cavallo, Argentine economy shines.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Adam</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>One year after Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo was sacked, sparking fears of an economic debacle, Argentine indicators are shining brightly.</p>
<p>Cavallo is running for Congress on a center-right slate and is waging war on alleged government corruption, while his replacement, Roque Fernandez, has benefitted from robust international economic and financial conditions.  </p>
<p>&quot;Beyond a certain lack of action on the part of the Economy Ministry, the situation today is much better than we thought it would be when Cavallo left,&quot; economist Jose Rutman of the private Broda group said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cavallo's departure was a test for the Argentine economy as big as the (1994) Mexican devaluation: today the plan is stronger because it proved able to withstand outside shocks and because it does not depend on a single person.&quot;</p>
<p>Menem asked Cavallo for his resignation in July 1996 after fierce cabinet infighting sparked by the minister's charges of alleged crime rings in government.  </p>
<p>Although the economy has remained sound, Fernandez, who takes a lower profile than his predecessor, is described by analysts as a mere administrator, without Cavallo's authority, initiative and stamina to carry through reforms.</p>
<p>Cavallo not only launched the convertibility system, which pegged the peso to the dollar at par and tamed hyperinflation, but also privatized most state-run companies, deregulated the markets, and achieved high economic growth.  </p>
<p>Analysts and even former aides of Fernandez, like economist Guillermo Calvo, say the Argentine economy is running on &quot;automatic pilot&quot; because the minister makes no major economic decisions.</p>
<p>&quot;With Roque, it's more of the same; there is a very favorable international environment which has got us out of recession and back to economic growth,&quot; said Mercedes Marco del Pont, director of consultants FIDE.  </p>
<p>Cavallo was less positive: &quot;Fernandez is maintaining the same line, but is making no progress on reforms.&quot; His remarks echo analysts who complain the minister is stalling on efforts to push through deep labor reforms, changes in the tax structure, a more streamlined state, and more privatizations.</p>
<p>But Fernandez, who boasts he is restricting spending even in an election year, points to results: first-half growth of eight percent, zero inflation, and strong trade growth.  </p>
<p>The scenario is even healthier than between 1991 and mid-1996, when Cavallo ran the economy, because consumption is no longer the motor of growth, but rather investment and exports.</p>
<p>&quot;Do you think you achieve those results on automatic pilot?&quot; asked Carlos Rodriguez, the Economy Minister's chief advisor.</p>
<p>However, Miguel Angel Broda, one of Buenos Aires' most influential  economists, warns that if Fernandez fails to deepen reforms, &quot;People may say: 'the growth rate is very nice, but I'm getting nothing'.&quot;  </p>
<p>Broda touched on one of the thorniest issues Menem faces despite the good economic numbers: social unrest, as reflected in demonstrations and road blockades, tied to high unemployment and the unequal distribution of wealth.</p>
<p>But Fernandez's team proudly points to the drop in joblessness of more than one percentage point from the 17.3 percent rate inherited from Cavallo -- a drop which will favor the ruling Peronist party in October midterm elections.</p>
<p>Analysts agree that one of the minister's most successful roles has been the handling of bond placements to meet the country's mounting debt payment deadlines.  </p>
<p>&quot;They extended payment deadlines and brought forward issues, which will prevent having to go to the markets in volatile times, and they got good prices. The debt placement scheme is excellent,&quot; said Aldo Abram of the Proeco think-tank.</p>
<p>However, while analysts are optimistic on the state of the economy, they say Fernandez should not be satisfied with just implementing his predecessor's plan, but should deepen it to guarantee sustained growth.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clear that without new reforms there will be less growth and less well-being,&quot; Abram said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
