<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762600" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian stocks end lower, led by banks, cement.</title>
<headline>Colombian stocks end lower, led by banks, cement.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian stocks, led by bank and cement issues, closed slightly lower on Tuesday as investors adjusted their positions before the end of the month, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets always dip at the end of the month as investors take profits in order to square their financial obligations,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Bogota's IBB price index fell 0.26 percent to 1,190.72 on turnover of 4.3 billion pesos. Medellin's IBOMED general price index dipped 0.12 percent to 18,142.69 on turnover of 4.7 billion pesos.  </p>
<p>Banco de Bogota SA finished down 2.1 percent at 6,750 in Bogota and 3.5 percent lower at 6,750 in Medellin.</p>
<p>Compania de Cemento Argos SA closed down 0.37 percent at 8,420 in Medellin on a 1.9 billion pesos pocket-to-pocket cross deal, and down a wafer-thin 0.01 percent to 8,400 in Bogota.</p>
<p>Brewer Bavaria SA was the most active Bogota stock, closing up a slim 0.12 percent to 8,215, but holding steady at 8,200 in Medellin.</p>
<p>Banco Industrial Colombiano SA held steady at 3,900 in Bogota.</p>
<p>((--Juan Guillermo Londono, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
