<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762685" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Bufete says negotiating overdue payments.</title>
<headline>Bufete says negotiating overdue payments.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican builder Bufete Industrial said on Tuesday it is negotiating with the Federal Electricity Commission (CFE) for payment on two completed projects.</p>
<p>&quot;In regards to the CFE pending account receivables, related to Carbon II and Topolobampo projects, which were successfully completed in 1995 and 1996, negotiations have continued longer than originally anticipated,&quot; Business Development Vice President Luis Felipe Mendoza said in a statement.</p>
<p>The statement said Mendoza was responding to analyst comments to Reuters that the stock was down on Monday on &quot;a rumor in Europe the CFE will not pay Bufete out of political motives.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are very confident that a final agreement with CFE on satisfactory terms for the company will be forthcoming,&quot; Mendoza added.</p>
<p>Bufete's second quarter earnings report on Friday listed accounts receivable for work completed more than two years ago on the Carbon II and Topolobampo power projects. The CFE is Mexico's electricity monopoly.</p>
<p>Bufete's shares in Mexico closed at 52 pesos on Monday, down from more than 55 pesos in Friday's close.</p>
<p>((--Timna Tanners, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7903))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
