<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762621" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia state oil company seen in financial mess.</title>
<headline>Colombia state oil company seen in financial mess.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>State-run oil company Ecopetrol is facing financial crisis in the medium-term because of spiraling operating costs, poor accounting and unauthorized expenditures, Colombia's comptroller general said Tuesday.</p>
<p>In a highly critical report, David Turbay said Ecopetrol made a 30.5 billion peso (about $30.5 million) operating loss in 1996 against the backdrop of a 36 percent rise in operating costs.</p>
<p>The state enterprise's net profit rose to 299.9 billion pesos last year -- a 90 percent gain compared to the previous year, according to the Turbay's calculations.  </p>
<p>But he said most of the rise was due to adjustments made for inflation, or monetary correction, rather than the production and sales of crude and other hydrocarbons.</p>
<p>&quot;Ecopetrol faces a difficult financial situation in the medium-term if it continues posting operational losses and net profits based on monetary corrections,&quot; Turbay said in a press statement.</p>
<p>In 1996, Ecopetrol's bill for wage and pension payments was equivalent to 62 percent of its total revenue or about 2.5 trillion pesos.  </p>
<p>&quot;This fact could lead to shortfalls in liquidity in the medium-term as Ecopetrol strives to meet these commitments,&quot; Turbay said.</p>
<p>The comptroller general, whose role it is to monitor public sector performance, was highly critical of Ecopetrol's accounting techniques and said the head of the company's accounting department was not even a qualified public accountant.  </p>
<p>&quot;Ecopetrol has carried out no technical assessment of its plant, property and equipment...some fixed assets could not be assessed because they were not assigned a cost or were lost or were not registered in inventories,&quot; Turbay said in his press statement.</p>
<p>In addition, Turbay said the company paid out more than 210 billion pesos (about $210 million) in 1996 that was not covered in any valid contract.</p>
<p>&quot;Such a lack of planning and control of company activities could generate multi-million dollar losses and a serious problem for the company,&quot; the public official said.</p>
<p>Sources within Colombia's private sector oil industry have long criticized Ecopetrol for being an unwieldy bureaucracy unable to effectively keep track of its financial operations because of corruption and waste.</p>
<p>Some critics have accused the powerful oil workers' union USO of blocking moves toward more efficient working practices within Ecopetrol.</p>
<p>Ecopetrol officials were not immediately available for comment on the comptroller general's report.</p>
<p>((-- Karl Penhaul, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
