<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762898" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Easy passage seen for bipartisan budget, tax cuts.</title>
<headline>Easy passage seen for bipartisan budget, tax cuts.</headline>
<byline>Jackie Frank</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton and Republican leaders on Tuesday hailed their bipartisan accord to cut taxes and balance the budget with all signs pointing to quick passage this week.</p>
<p>Congressional leaders of both parties said there was little doubt the spending reductions and tax cuts would pass later this week by strong majorities. Lawmakers of both parties said they saw provisions they could claim as political victories.</p>
<p>Clinton, flanked by many Democrats, lauded the accord at a ceremony on the White House lawn. Republicans held their own celebration on the steps of the Capitol.</p>
<p>&quot;This budget reforms and cuts yesterday's government so that we can help provide our people the means to meet the challenges of tomorrow,&quot; the president said. He noted that when he took office in 1993 the deficit was $290 billion.</p>
<p>The plan seeks to balance the budget by 2002 by reducing federal spending $270 billion over the next five years and nearly $1 trillion over 10 years.</p>
<p>It gives a tax cut worth about $94 billion over five years, the bulk of which comes in a $500 per child tax credit. Investors also will see their tax rate on capital gains fall to 20 percent from 28 percent.</p>
<p>The good budget news may get better. A Senate Republican aide said current economic forecasts may result in a budget surplus in 1998, the first surplus in over a generation.</p>
<p>He emphasised that the budget deal included strict provisions to keep spending from ratcheting upward, including a 0.5 percent annual limit on spending increases.</p>
<p>Senate Budget Committee Chairman Pete Domenici, Republican of New Mexico, stressed that the budget estimates were very conservative. The legislation was based on the budget blueprint all sides agreed to in May.</p>
<p>State governors attending their annual in Las Vegas meeting also applauded the budget agreement, especially provisions to provide $24 billion in health insurance for children.</p>
<p>White House Chief of Staff Erskine Bowles said the package he and other top Clinton aides negotiated behind closed doors with opposition Republicans received a warm welcome from Democrats and he expected most would vote for it.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an overwhelming sentiment in our group of a major success for the president and our party,&quot; House Democratic Conference Chairman Representative Vic Fazio of California told reporters after the meeting with White House officials.</p>
<p>&quot;The president got basically everything he wanted out of this deal,&quot; New York Democrat Representative Gary Ackerman said.</p>
<p>The sentiment was largely the same in the Senate where Minority Leader Tom Daschle of South Dakota told reporters: &quot;An overwhelming majority of Democrats will support this agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>Democrats were largely left out of the negotiations between the White House and Republicans who control Congress.</p>
<p>House Minority Leader Dick Gephardt of Missouri, often mentioned as a rival for the presidency against Vice President Al Gore, did not attend the White House ceremony and did not publicly discuss whether he would support the accord.</p>
<p>Several Democrats said they feared the plan would squeeze domestic spending with its limits on annual growth.</p>
<p>Massachusetts Democrat Representative Barney Frank warned that it would make the federal tax system less fair and would crimp education, environmental and transportion budgets. &quot;For housing, it's an eviction budget,&quot; he said, adding it would result in fewer federally subsidised houses and apartments.</p>
<p>But these reservations were not widely shared. Ackerman said many lawmakers from his state welcomed the cut in the capital gains tax rate.</p>
<p>To bring the budget into balance, the plan slows the rate of growth in many federal social programmes and reduces Medicare costs by $115 billion over five years. At the last minute, lawmakers and the White House backed off a plan to require wealthier senior citizens to pay higher Medicare premiums.</p>
<p>The plan will raise the 24 cent-per-pack cigarette tax to 39 cents per pack by 2002. It extends the airline ticket tax to raise about $33 billion through 2002.</p>
<p>Clinton won a new $24 billion programme to provide health insurance to cover up to 2.2 million uninsured children. They also accepted his education proposals including $31 billion in Hope scholarships for post-secondary studies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
