<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762877" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinian report urges Arafat to sack ministers.</title>
<headline>Palestinian report urges Arafat to sack ministers.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>RAMALLAH, West Bank 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A panel of Palestinian lawmakers investigating corruption urged President Yasser Arafat on Tuesday to sack his entire cabinet and put at least two ministers suspected of wrongdoing on trial.</p>
<p>&quot;The committee recommends to the President of the Palestinian Authority to dissolve the cabinet and form a new cabinet made up of technocrats and qualified people,&quot; a report to Palestinian Legislative Council said.</p>
<p>It specifically recommended trial for Civilian Affairs Minister Jamil al-Tarifi and Planning Minister Nabil Shaath on suspicion of corruption and misuse of power.</p>
<p>The report also called for investigations against Transportations Minister Ali Qawasmeh and other senior Palestinian officials for alleged mismanagement and squandering of public funds.</p>
<p>Tarifi rejected the report, saying he would submit documents in his defense to the council on Wednesday and Shaath described the allegations as &quot;lies&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I categorically deny all the accusations and I will prove it with documents. I have nothing to hide,&quot; Tarifi told Reuters after the council session.</p>
<p>None of the ministers implicated in the report attended the session.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, it is all lies and nothing mentioned in the report is true. It is a political demonstration from those who have ambitions to become ministers or want to harm the Palestinian Authority's image internationally,&quot; Shaath said.</p>
<p>The recommendations, made in a report to the assembly by a panel of nine lawmakers, follow increasing complaints by Palestinians and legislators of alleged corruption and mismanagement in Arafat's Palestinian Authority.</p>
<p>&quot;The President of the Authority should issue his instructions to immediately punish violators against whom there have been proof of guilt and to take them to court in order to restore confidence between the Palestinian leadreship and the people,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Ministers found to be corrupt or incompetent should not be reappointed to the cabinet, it added. The report also called for action against security forces which interfered in the collection of taxes and fees.</p>
<p>An official auditor's report earlier this year found that members of the Palestinian Authority had squandered $326 million in public funds last year.</p>
<p>The council panel found that the auditor's report had only covered a fraction of the government offices and failed to investigate security and military branches as well as Arafat's office.</p>
<p>The audit report's findings were the subject of an investigation by a committee appointed by Arafat which reported last week that while money had not been squandered, serious financial, legal and administrative violations had taken place.</p>
<p>It recommended putting some senior officials on trial, changing the cabinet and proposed stringent reforms.</p>
<p>Higher Education Minister Hanan Ashrawi called the council's report a serious effort to secure public accountability and said its recommenations should be studied carefully.</p>
<p>PLO officials close to Arafat said they doubted he would take immediate action since he was reluctant to make changes under pressure.</p>
<p>Palestinian analyst Mahdi Abdel-Hadi said he thought Arafat allowed the findings of the audit report to be published in order to gain popular support for upcoming reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;The leak was intended to support Arafat's position and his coming decision to make major changes, hopefully very soon,&quot; Abdel-Hadi told Reuters. &quot;Palestinians need the changes to move from revolution to statehood.&quot;</p>
<p>The stench of corruption in Palestinian self-rule areas has increasd pressure on Arafat from international donors to ensure aid to the ailing Palestinian economy is properly spent.</p>
<p>Tuesday's report recommended that Tarifi be indicted in connection with the illegal waiving of fees of medicine imported from Egypt to Gaza that had passed their expiry date and violations of vehicle import regulations.</p>
<p>It also urged the Authority to indict Shaath for misusing international donors' funds and for financial, legal and administrative violations.</p>
<p>Several other recommendations were made to indict and investigate senior and junior officials suspected of misusing authority and of financial corruption.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAMALLAH, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
