<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="762929" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rosa Parks' adopted grandson dies in U.S. bus crash.</title>
<headline>Rosa Parks' adopted grandson dies in U.S. bus crash.</headline>
<dateline>STONY CREEK, Virginia 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The adopted grandson of U.S. civil rights pioneer Rosa Parks was killed and several people were injured when a bus loaded with children on a tour of the slavery-era &quot;underground railroad&quot; crashed into a Virginia river on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The bus, carrying six chaperones and 29 students aged 12 to 17 on the charter tour sponsored by the Detroit-based Rosa and Raymond Parks Institute, veered off Interstate 95 into the Nottoway River near Stony Creek, Virginia, police said.</p>
<p>The bus, which was heading north, ended up half-submerged in the five-foot (1.6 metre)-deep river, State Police spokeswoman Tammy VanDame said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have one confirmed fatality in this accident and I'm not releasing any names. We don't know how many people were injured yet, she said. &quot;The majority of the injuries were minor although we do have some life-threatening injuries.&quot;</p>
<p>The Rosa and Raymond Parks Institute said the person killed was 25-year-old Adissa Foulke, Parks' adopted grandson and one of the chaperones on the trip. Parks, along with Foulke's mother, Anita Peek, and Elaine Steele, co-founder of the Parks institute, travelled to Virginia on a charter flight to comfort those injured in the crash.</p>
<p>Parks told reporters before boarding the plane in Detroit that she was &quot;very sad&quot; about the loss.</p>
<p>Foulke &quot;was just as close to me as if he was my own grandson,&quot; Parks said. &quot;I felt that way about him and that's the way he felt that way about me.&quot;</p>
<p>She said she hoped the tour could continue.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that they can continue because he cares so much about them,&quot; she said of Foulke.</p>
<p>The bus, chartered in Detroit, was carrying students from all across the United States and the Bahamas on a tour called &quot;Pathways to Freedom,&quot; sponsored by the Parks institute, the U.S. Department of Transportation, Shoney's Restaurants.</p>
<p>It retraces the underground railroad route taken by black slaves escaping the southern states for freedom in the north.</p>
<p>This leg of the tour was from Charleston, South Carolina, to Washington.</p>
<p>Parks, 84, helped launch the U.S. civil rights movement in 1955 when she refused to give up her seat on a Montgomery, Ala., transit bus to a white passenger, as required by segregation laws at the time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STONY CREEK, Virginia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
