<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763007" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Silgan Holdings replaces bank facility.</title>
<headline>Silgan Holdings replaces bank facility.</headline>
<dateline>STAMFORD, Conn. 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Silgan Holdings Inc said on Tuesday it has completed the refinancing of $600.0 million of existing bank debt with a new $1.0 billion senior secured credit facility led by Bankers Trust Co.</p>
<p>As a result of this refinancing, Silgan said it will record an extraordinary non-cash pre-tax charge of $11.9 million in the third quarter for the write-off of unamortized debt financing costs related to the previous bank facility.</p>
<p>The refinancing is part of a plan to refinance higher cost indebtedness to improve cash flow and increase its operating and financial flexibility, Silgan said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The new facility lowers interest rates, increases the amount of borrowings available to the company, extends maturities and provides more flexibility to make acquisitions, pay dividends, repurchase stock, and refinance existing indebtedness, Silgan said.</p>
<p>The new bank agreement provides the company with $250.0 million of A term loans, $200.0 million of B term loans and a revolving loan facility of up to $550.0 million, Silgan said.</p>
<p>The A term loans and revolving loan facility mature on December 31, 2003 and the B term loans mature on June 30, 2005, Silgan said.</p>
<p>Based upon current borrowing amounts, the company expects an annual reduction in interest expense of approximately $8.0 million, Silgan said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STAMFORD, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
