<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763022" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UPS lays off workers as strike deadline nears.</title>
<headline>UPS lays off workers as strike deadline nears.</headline>
<byline>Mike Cooper</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Parcel Service of America Inc.  said Tuesday it was laying off employees nationwide and losing package orders as a Thursday strike deadline loomed.</p>
<p>A spokesman for America's leading package distribution company confirmed that employees were being laid off because of a drop in package volume, but he could not say how many workers were affected.</p>
<p>&quot;It's nothing of a large-scale nature, by any means. It's nothing that we are tracking specifically,&quot; company spokesman Mark Dickens said. &quot;It is likely to increase if volume continues to be diverted to other carriers.&quot;</p>
<p>The company said it intends to reach an accord with the Teamsters union with no disruptions in service but it cannot promise that it will be able to continue to complete deliveries after Thursday.</p>
<p>Dickens said companywide package deliveries were off by about 2 percent during June, or almost 250,000 packages a day out of a normal daily volume of almost 12 million. There has been further decline during July, he said.</p>
<p>Thursday is the final day of the current four-year contract. UPS said union negotiators have rejected a request for a contract extension as well as a request for five days prior notification of any work stoppage to notify customers.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still hopeful we're going to reach an agreement, or at least that we'll have an extension to the existing contract by midnight Thursday,&quot; Dickens said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Teamsters have not given us any indication that they intend to take a job action by Thursday midnight,&quot; he said. &quot;We're not as far along in the negotiations as we had hoped to be at this point. That doesn't mean that we can't reach an agreement, and we're still acting towards that.&quot;</p>
<p>UPS said it intended to maintain full service until a new contract is reached. The Teamsters represent about two-thirds of the company's domestic payroll, including delivery truck drivers, tractor-trailer drivers and package facility workers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
