<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763045" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMF praises Bulgarian policy, sees risks ahead.</title>
<headline>IMF praises Bulgarian policy, sees risks ahead.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund on Tuesday praised Sofia's efforts to stabilise the economy but said there was no room for complacency.</p>
<p>A statement issued after a July 23 IMF review of the Bulgarian economy said financial markets had responded favourably to the introduction of a currency board.</p>
<p>&quot;After very costly delays in its transition process, Bulgaria now had an excellent opportunity to reinvigorate and complete the reforms needed to provide the basis for sustained growth and improved living standards,&quot; the IMF said.</p>
<p>&quot;Directors commended the authorities' commitment to reform and were encouraged by their efforts to stabilise the economy, including the implementation of the currency board arrangement... They underscored that there was no room for slippage or complacency as significant risks remained.&quot;</p>
<p>Bulgaria introduced a restrictive currency board on July 1, fixing the lev at 1,000 per mark and limiting lev emissions to the amount of central bank mark reserves.</p>
<p>The IMF forecast a 7.4 percent fall in Bulgarian gross domestic product this year, after a slide of 10.9 percent in 1996. Consumer price inflation would be 566 percent after 311 percent last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Directors urged the steadfast implementation of the authorities' policy programme in order to unlock the economic potential of Bulgaria and to continue to establish a strong track record,&quot; the IMF said.</p>
<p>It said discipline was needed on budget and economic policy and governance in the banking sector needed to be strengthened. The government should improve tax administration and strengthen the tax system by broadening the tax base and making the system more efficient.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
