<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763000" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ohio Senate approves school funding reform plan.</title>
<headline>Ohio Senate approves school funding reform plan.</headline>
<dateline>COLUMBUS, Ohio 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Ohio Senate on Tuesday approved a $1.1 billion sales tax increase as part of a package of bills authorizing an overhaul of the system for funding the state's public schools, a Senate aide said.</p>
<p>The proposed changes, which require the voter approval, also require school districts to create &quot;rainy day&quot; funds, forecast future spending needs and meet academic standards, John Rabenold, an aide to Senate President Richard Finan, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Does this solve all the problems? No, but it is a good start,&quot; said Sen. Merle Kearns, Republican of Springfield. Kearns is chairwoman of the Senate Education Committee, which reviewed the academic and fiscal accountability issues.</p>
<p>The majority Republican Senate voted 21-11 along party lines to approve the financing plan, which includes a 20 percent rollback on property taxes. The package excludes an increase in the cigarette tax recommended by Gov. George Voinovich's school funding taskforce.</p>
<p>The Ohio Supreme Court in March overturned the state's school funding formula and gave lawmakers one year to create a system less dependant on local property taxes.</p>
<p>The Voinovich taskforce recommended increasing state aid by $1.1 billion in the current biennium and providing $5.8 billion for capital improvements over the next 10 years.</p>
<p>Brian Rothenberg, a spokesman for Ohio Senate Democrats, said the plan would not raise enough money to satisfy the state Supreme Court or meet the taskforce's recommendations.</p>
<p>The Senate plan would raise the state sales tax from 5 percent to 6 percent to generate about $1.1 billion annually and increase taxes on businesses and commercial properties.</p>
<p>The legislation now goes to the Ohio House. Republicans hold a 60-to-39 majority in the House, but are expected to need some assistance from Democrats to reach the 60 percent margin necessary to pass the bill, Rothenberg said.</p>
<p>Lawmakers must approve constitutional amendments by August 6 if the referendum questions are to be placed on the November ballot.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, Chicago Newsroom, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBUS, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
