<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763276" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Spot Prods - Lightning charges up Gulf gasoline.</title>
<headline>US Spot Prods - Lightning charges up Gulf gasoline.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Gulf Coast spot gasoline differentials, apparently picking up unfinished upside business from Monday afternoon, were again spiking upward Tuesday amid news of an Exxon refinery problem in the region.</p>
<p>In New York Harbor, MTBE still appeared to be the top story as reformulated or high octane grades blended with the additive added to or retained their recent price strength.</p>
<p>Underlying NYMEX gasoline futures, displaying the textbook &quot;buy the rumour, sell the fact&quot; trading philosophy, came off early highs as the Exxon news was percolating through the market.</p>
<p>But in Midcontinent markets, the word was that supplies were a lot more plentiful than in Houston or New York, particularly in the Group Three market.</p>
<p>At 1130 EDT/1530 GMT, August unleaded was up by 0.96 cent to 65.80 cents a gallon, while August heating oil was up 0.16 cent to 54.30 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>U.S. GULF</p>
<p>Exxon Corp said Tuesday its large fluid catalytic cracking unit unit in the Houston area at Baytown was out of service after it was struck by lightning Monday evening, but that it would &quot;soon&quot; restore it since it was not damaged.</p>
<p>Differentials on the bellwether &quot;M1&quot; regular conventional southern grade unleaded shot up by over a cent Tuesday, with prompt (front 22nd cycle) barrels heard getting done at 1.75, 1.50 cents over September NYMEX after getting done in the early going at 1.00 cent over.</p>
<p>Offers were even heard as high as 2.00 cents over.</p>
<p>It was not however immediately clear that Exxon's problems were behind the move, since M1 for delivery on Colonial Pipeline's front 22nd cycle must be scheduled by the end of today, and M1 typically becomes volatile ahead of such deadlines.</p>
<p>Also, Exxon did not appear so far to be among the various refiners eagerly scooping up barrels.</p>
<p>Differentials on the &quot;A1&quot; regular reformulated southern grade was also heard a cent firmer at levels as high as 3.50 cents over September NYMEX, but that could not be immediately confirmed since deals did not appear to be getting done.</p>
<p>In other Gulf Coast action, prompt front 22nd cycle barrels of 74-grade low sulphur diesel changed hands at 1.30 cents under September futures.</p>
<p>NEW YORK HARBOR</p>
<p>Gasoline differentials were powered higher on Tuesday by talk Tosco will shut its giant fluid cat cracker on Wednesday and by the continuing strength in MTBE.</p>
<p>MTBE was heard holding at the high 102 cents a gallon level in the Harbor, where it has been since last Thursday amid tight supply.</p>
<p>&quot;A2&quot; regular northern-grade reformulated firmed a half cent to offers at 2.75 cents and bids at 2.25 cents over the screen. Any months were pegged 2.25/2.50 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the reasons A-grade is up is because of MTBE. And the A-grade is pushing up the M2,&quot; said a products trader.</p>
<p>M2 regular conventional northern-grade strengthened more than a penny to 2.25/2.00 cents below the screen for prompt barrels. Much of the strength drew from market talk -- which began late on Monday -- that Tosco will shut its 140,000 bpd cat cracker for a 10-day maintenance starting on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Tosco news has already been priced into the market,&quot; said a Harbor trader.</p>
<p>The &quot;V2&quot; and &quot;D2&quot; 93-octane conventional and reformulated northern blends also held their strength, with prompt barrels of both grades offered as high as 7.25 and 12.00 cents over August NYMEX unleaded.</p>
<p>MIDCO</p>
<p>Prompt unleaded gasoline differentials in Group Three collapsed on Tuesday, weighed down by ample supply in the hub and sharp backwardation on the Merc.</p>
<p>In light Tuesday activity, July prompt unleaded tumbled 1.50 cent to 1.75/2.00 cents below the screen. A deal was done at 1.75 cent. Any August barrels were pegged 1.25/1.50 over September NYMEX.</p>
<p>Players pointed to the nearly five cent spread between August and September NYMEX futures as a culprit in Tuesday's sharp price drop.</p>
<p>&quot;Given how late it is in the month that spread is not going to hold,&quot; said a Group Three broker.</p>
<p>First cycle August barrels in Chicago markets, meanwhile, stayed steady at 3.00/3.25 over September futures. Any August was pegged 1.50/2.00 cents. July has been completed.</p>
<p>-- New York Oil Desk 1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
