<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763262" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT wheat sags quietly on technicals, hedges.</title>
<headline>CBOT wheat sags quietly on technicals, hedges.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soft red winter wheat futures were lower at midsession on technical signals and on hedge selling, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It looked like a little hedging came in on the open, not a lot but enough to take it down a little,&quot; a cash-connected trader said.</p>
<p>Technicians continued to point to the overbought signals as rationale for the wheat market's struggle to rally. The nine day relative strength index (RSI) for the September stood at just over 68 percent at 1050 CDT. An RSI of 70 or more is considered near overbought status for short-term traders.</p>
<p>Support came from the rally in corn and soybeans with a sale of U.S. wheat to Pakistan taken in stride by the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The Pakistan wheat sale isn't necessarily supportive. But if it hadn't happened it would have been negative, it removes another unknown from the market,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter.</p>
<p>Pakistan bought 500,000 tonnes of white wheat with 200,000 from the U.S., 250,000 from Australia and 50,000 from Canada, according to the Washington D.C.-based Pakistani Embassy.</p>
<p>At 1100 CDT, SRW wheat was unchanged to one cent lower, with September down one at $3.56-1/2.</p>
<p>Mild underpinning may have come from a slight decline in the condition rating for the U.S. spring wheat crop. USDA Monday said the spring wheat crop as of Sunday was 50 percent good to excellent, below the 52 percent in that category the previous week.</p>
<p>Also USDA Monday said the U.S. winter wheat harvest was 79 percent complete as of Sunday, above the 78 percent a year ago and above the 77 percent average pace.</p>
<p>Persistent drier-than-desired weather in portions of Australia's wheat growing region and mounting concern about dry weather in China's grain/soy belt also helped underpin wheat futures, traders said.</p>
<p>In early dealings, Prudential Securities bought one half million bushels of December, Paine Webber bought 300,000 bushels of December and there was a substantial amount of small lot commission house buying on the open, traders said. LIT America and Rand Financial sold one half million bushels of December, traders said. Merrill Lynch Futures sold 300,000 bushels of September, Cargill Investor Services bought 200,000 bushels of September and sold 300,000 bushels of September, traders said.</p>
<p>((Sam Nelson 312-408-8721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
