<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763324" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Rains close roads, wreck bridge in northern Sweden.</title>
<headline>Rains close roads, wreck bridge in northern Sweden.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Floods damaged roads and washed away two small bridges in northern Sweden, but heavy rains in the area were subsiding, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Rescue workers evacuated around 20 people, most of them elderly, from their homes by helicopter after the flooding outside the northern Swedish city of Pitea, about 900 km (550 miles) north of Stockholm, left them isolated, Swedish television reported.</p>
<p>The flooding destroyed one two-lane bridge and another smaller one, said Anneli Markstrom, a spokeswoman for Sweden's National Road Administration. A 25-km (16-mile) stretch of Swedish highway 373 was closed and would probably remain so for a few days.</p>
<p>Other roads closed by the flooding in this sparsely-populated area of Sweden had already been reopened.</p>
<p>No deaths or injuries because of the floods had been reported and estimates of the damages were not known at the time.</p>
<p>Esbjorn Olsson, a meteorologist for the Swedish national weather service, said rainfall in the affected region began on Sunday evening and totalled as much as 256 mm in two days.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not raining right now. There's still a risk for showers...but we don't think it will rain as much as it has already,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Flooding in central Sweden also closed some minor roads near the town of Flen, about 220 km (140 miles) west of Stockholm. Waters, which had in some places been over one metre (three feet) deep, were receding, police said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
