<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763384" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany launches offensive on child sex crimes.</title>
<headline>Germany launches offensive on child sex crimes.</headline>
<byline>Emma Thomasson</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany launched a new drive against child abuse, child pornography and sex tourism on Tuesday, combining tougher sentencing plans with preventive educational schemes.</p>
<p>&quot;We know children are abused daily in Germany and worldwide,&quot; Youth Minister Claudia Nolte told a news conference to launch the measures.</p>
<p>&quot;The German government has set itself the challenge to fight this with every means possible.&quot;</p>
<p>Nolte urged parliament to pass a draft law approved by the cabinet in March which would make punishment for sex crimes harsher in a bid to protect children from sexual abuse.</p>
<p>She also called for more cooperation between state governments, law enforcement agencies and authorities in other countries to tackle child pornography and sex tourists.</p>
<p>&quot;We will only win the fight through unified action by those responsible for protecting children,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;That means all of us.&quot;</p>
<p>Nolte said one million marks ($540,000) would go towards setting up a nationwide data bank to gather information about child abuse.</p>
<p>Her ministry has launched educational films, comics and pamphlets for children and parents and wants to increase the number of crisis telephone hotlines, she said.</p>
<p>Nolte also said funds would go towards training teachers, police officers, lawyers, medical personnel and tour guides to make them more aware of the problems of child sex abuse.</p>
<p>Ulla Schmidt, opposition Social Democrat (SPD) equality expert, said the SPD favoured even wider measures, including nationwide school programmes and more therapy for both the victims and perpetrators of abuse.</p>
<p>Schmidt said although some of the ruling coalition supported longer sentences for sex crimes, the Justice Ministry would not approve the plans.</p>
<p>&quot;The government coalition is once again blocking itself and hasn't got the strength for political action,&quot; she said in a statement.</p>
<p>Nolte said it was difficult to catch Germans who commit sex offences against children abroad, but said aid money was being directed at supporting training for children in countries like Thailand to prevent them resorting to prostitution.</p>
<p>Child welfare experts estimate 200,000 German men travel abroad each year in search of sex, many seeking girls under 14.</p>
<p>Bonn passed a law in 1993 allowing Germany to convict its citizens for having sex with minors abroad, but prosecutions have been rare since evidence is hard to gather and foreign officials often turn a blind eye to the problem.</p>
<p>($ = 1.836 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
