<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763351" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures ended little changed for the second day in succession and traders said they expected the contract to remain in a similar range on Wednesday ahead of key U.S. data due on Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>The September bond future was marked higher at the open but pressure to close a gap left on charts in the Bund pits weighed on the contract from the start and it soon slipped back.</p>
<p>Hopes a U.S. second quarter Employment Cost Index (ECI) would be lower-than-expected gave bonds a lift early in the afternoon but the rise in the ECI eventually came in at 0.8 percent, bang in line with the consensus.</p>
<p>The French bond future followed U.S. bonds and Bunds to the session lows after the ECI release and remained little changed until the close, getting some support from a lower-than-expected rise in U.S. July consumer confidence.</p>
<p>Traders said the range for the contract looked set to remain bounded by 130.34-40 at the bottom and 130.84-90 at the top, unless pushed one way or the other by the U.S. or German bond markets.</p>
<p>However, traders said activity was being adversely affected by the French holiday season and although volume picked up to 111,111 lots from a paltry 44,000 on Monday few expected major market moves with such limited interest.</p>
<p>&quot;The trend seems to me to be bullish but the market is going to breathe a bit,&quot; one head trader in Paris said. He said the contract could lose another 30 centimes and head to the bottom of the current range before climbing sustainable.</p>
<p>The retreat of the dollar against the mark and the franc on Tuesday calmed some nerves in the interest rate futures pits. September and June PIBOR both managed to make some gains after a series of losses on concern the German Bundesbank could tighten monetary policy to help the mark.</p>
<p>One options trader said he expected volatility to climb in the run up to the next Bundesbank council meeting but that he was also fairly bullish on the basis that fundamentally there was no need for interest rate rises.</p>
<p>The franc climbed as high as 6.1602 against the dollar from a low of 6.2066. It hit its lowest level since July 1991 on Monday. Against the mark, the franc was relatively stable at 3.3713 compared with 3.3704 late on Monday.</p>
<p>-- David Clarke, Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
