<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763426" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistani private power shares good buy - report.</title>
<headline>Pakistani private power shares good buy - report.</headline>
<byline>Tahir Ikram</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's four private power producing companies listed at the country's main Karachi Stock Exchange have been recommended as a &quot;good buy&quot; in a joint research report by a local and a foreign brokerage house.</p>
<p>&quot;We initiate coverage on the sector with an overall buy recommendation,&quot; said the report on private power companies by Merrill Lynch and Pakistan's brokerage house Khadim Ali Shah Bukhari and Co Ltd (KASB).</p>
<p>&quot;An insulating regulatory environment protects the IPPs (independant power producers) from most business risks,&quot; it said about Hub Power Company Ltd, Southern Electric Power Co Ltd (SEPCOL), Japan Power Generation Ltd (JPGL) and Kohinoor Energy Ltd (KEL).</p>
<p>These are the only four companies in the sector listed in Pakistan.</p>
<p>The 1,292-megawatts $1.571 billion Hub Power has started commercial production and 117-mw SEPCOL, at a cost of $119.49 million is expected to start production in December.</p>
<p>The 135-mw JPGL plant, at a cost of $116 million, is expected to produce commercial electricity in October and the 120-mw KEL project, at a cost of $138.2 million, has already completed construction and will produce power by December.</p>
<p>A total of 12 projects with a combined dependable capacity of 2,134 MW and costing $2.4 billion have achieved financial close (secured finances) and are expected to commence commercial production by December 1998, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;Including Hubco, the total additional capacity from the IPPs should be 3,334 MW,&quot; it said. &quot;This implies a 26 percent increase in total industry capacity by 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>Pakistan, facing a 2,000-mw shortfall of power in 1994, had opened its gates to private producers and gave them sovereign guarantees for fuel supply, power purchase, and a fixed, index-linked tariff of $0.065 (6.5 cents) per kilowatt hour.</p>
<p>&quot;Since tariffs are fixed in USD (U.S. dollar) terms, the earnings of all IPPs are senstive to exchange rate movements,&quot; the report said. &quot;Thus, a devaluation of the local currency, the Pakistani rupee, should increase earnings in rupee terms.&quot;</p>
<p>The report said the rupee had devalued by 8.6 percent against the dollar annually in the last 10 years and by 9.5 percent in the previous five years.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that IPPs are the only stocks in Pakistan which can provide an effective quasi-hedge to currency risk for foreign investors.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;With the Pakistani rupee expected to devalue by 7.5 percent in fiscal 1998 (July-June) and fiscal 1999, we would expect the shares to attract strong support from local investors,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The Pakistani government had recently hinted it would try to renegotiate power purchase agreements but Finance Minister Sartaj Aziz later said the IPPs with whom purchase agreements had already been signed were not in danger of tariff revision.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
