<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763461" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Bangladesh, UNHCR seek end to Burma refugee crisis.</title>
<headline>Bangladesh, UNHCR seek end to Burma refugee crisis.</headline>
<byline>Nizam Ahmed</byline>
<dateline>CHITTAGONG, Bangladesh 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangladesh and the U.N. relief agency UNHCR on Tuesday began efforts to persuade thousands of Burmese Moslem refugees to end a hunger strike.</p>
<p>Relief and Repatriation Commissioner Qamrul Huda and UNHCR representative Van To Nguyen, based in the southeastern district of Cox's Bazar, left for the camps early on Tuesday, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;They will talk to the militant refugee leaders who had enforced the food strike,&quot; one government official told Reuters. &quot;We are expecting the ice to start melting soon,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Scores of Bangladesh's 21,000 Burmese refugees, known as Rohingyas, have fallen ill after activists enforced a mass hunger strike July 21 and refused rations to protest alleged government attempts to send them home by force.</p>
<p>Clashes between police and Rohingyas resisting repatriation on July 20 left nearly 20 people injured, forcing authorities to postpone the repatriation from the two camps.</p>
<p>&quot;Forget the repatriation, we are now much more eager to persuade them to take food because any death out of starvation would trigger a far worse situation,&quot; one government official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The message by relief and government officials is that Dhaka would not send anyone home against their will.</p>
<p>&quot;This assurance has already been communicated to the refugees when Huda visited the camps Monday evening. We are going to say it again today,&quot; one official in Cox's Bazar said by telephone.</p>
<p>The UNHCR had lodged a strong protest with the Bangladesh government over the alleged forcible deportation of the refugees from camps lining the highway from Cox's Bazar to Teknaf In Bangladesh's southernmost tip.</p>
<p>The refugees were also preventing mothers from taking children to medical centres in an effort to intensify their campaign to stay in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Poverty-ridden Bangladesh sheltered some 250,000 Rohingyas who fled from west Burma's Moslem-majority Arakan province in early 1992 to escape alleged military persecution and forced labour.</p>
<p>Their lingering presence has angered local residents.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the Rohingyas crossed into Bangladesh to live an easy life and avoid hard physical work. Now their friends in Geneva and elsewhere are shedding tears over their so-called plight,&quot; said Mohammad Shahjahan, 37, a school teacher in Cox's Bazar.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHITTAGONG, Bangladesh"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
