<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763784" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Market eyes Dutch rate policy as guilder falls.</title>
<headline>Market eyes Dutch rate policy as guilder falls.</headline>
<byline>Chizu Nomiyama</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dutch guilder, renowned for its stability, fell to its weakest point in nearly four years against the mark on Tuesday, sparking speculation that the central bank will have to raise its key money market rate to stem the currency's slide.</p>
<p>Traders said expectations of an interest rate hike were triggered when the guilder passed a significant milestone on Tuesday, falling below its central parity rate against the mark in the European exchange rate mechanism.</p>
<p>The guilder fell to 1.126925 per mark in European morning trade, its lowest since August 1993, compared with its late Monday level of 1.126675/6750.</p>
<p>The size of the move would have been dismissed as minuscule in nearly any other European currency, but traders said this was an unusually big move for a currency that was virtually static.</p>
<p>&quot;We thought originally that (the ERM central rate of) 1.12673 would hold, but now that it's gone through that, people will be looking at the Dutch central bank to see if they raise the special advances rate on Thursday,&quot; said one trader at a Dutch bank in London.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking at a situation in which people prefer to hold marks rather than guilders, with the mark worth more at the longer end of the curve,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While the Dutch special advances rate currently equals the German repo rate at 3.00 percent, 10-year Dutch government bond yields are seven basis points below those of comparable German bonds.</p>
<p>Expectations of a Dutch rate hike were heightened by memories of the most recent rise in the special advances rate -- by 10 basis points to 3.00 percent on July 10 -- which the central bank said had been prompted by the guilder's weakness against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;The gap in the nominal German and Dutch interest rates has been reduced to zero, but because of higher Dutch inflation, this isn't favourable for the Dutch guilder,&quot; said Hans-Guenter Redeker, senior economist at Chase Investment Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;This has to be adjusted, otherwise you would be unable to stabilise the guilder against the mark. So a rate hike by the central bank is very likely,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some analysts were sceptical about whether the central bank had enough grounds to raise rates.</p>
<p>Considering that the guilder had slipped to just 0.2 percent below its ERM central rate and that it was fluctuating only very slightly, the authorities might judge it was not worth tightening rates, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dutch have tried to keep the guilder in a very tight band against the mark. Having said that, the amount of deviation we're talking about is very minimal,&quot; said David Brickman, European economist at Yamaichi International here.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless there were to be a significant weakening of the guilder or the economy were to show signs of overheating and inflationary pressure, our view is the Dutch would not raise rates,&quot; Brickman said.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the Netherlands would also be loath to move its interest rates before it was clearer where German rates were headed.</p>
<p>&quot;There's some doubt as to whether the Dutch will raise rates unilaterally...It's quite likely they'll wait and see what the Bundesbank does about the repo rate,&quot; the Dutch bank trader said.</p>
<p>Uncertainty about the outlook for German rates surfaced late last week when the Bundesbank council, before heading into a four-week summer break, set its repo rate for the first two weeks but not the latter two.</p>
<p>The market interpreted the move as a signal that the central bank was keeping its interest rate options open in case of market turbulence.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 6721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
