<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763832" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK gas watchdog's watchdog spreads the word.</title>
<headline>UK gas watchdog's watchdog spreads the word.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's gas industry watchdog Ofgas on Tuesday unleashed its latest weapon in its campaign to preach the gospel of gas competition - a dog of its own.</p>
<p>The watchdog's watchdog will appear in Ofgas advertisements and in all published material to do with competition.</p>
<p>&quot;Our cartoon watchdog will draw attention to the fact that Ofgas is here to make sure competition works for everybody's benefit, and that we have unbiased information available to anyone who wants it,&quot; said Clare Spottiswoode, Ofgas Director General.</p>
<p>Spottiswoode was speaking at the launch of a publicity campaign ahead of the introduction of domestic gas competition in Scotland and north east England on November 1.</p>
<p>&quot;What competition means most of all is cheaper bills,&quot; she said. &quot;But people need to be reassured that the same gas will travel down the same pipes and through the same gas meter as now. If you switch supplier, the difference will be who sends you the bill - and the fact that the bill will be a little lighter.&quot;</p>
<p>Competitive suppliers are expected to reduce average winter gas bills in Scotland and north east England by 10 stg a month, Spottiswoode added.</p>
<p>The UK is being opened to competition in stages from November 1, with the last area around London opening on June 19 next year.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom, +44 171 542 6412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
