<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="763923" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Cypriot fisherman found guilty in AIDS case.</title>
<headline>Cypriot fisherman found guilty in AIDS case.</headline>
<byline>Michele Kambas</byline>
<dateline>LARNACA, Cyprus 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Cyprus court on Tuesday found a Greek Cypriot fisherman guilty of recklessly transmitting the deadly virus that causes AIDS to his English lover, Janette Pink.</p>
<p>&quot;From January 1994 and for a period of two years, the accused repeatedly came in sexual contact with Janette Pink without the use of a condom. In no case did he tell her he was a carrier of the disease,&quot; District Court Judge Antonis Liatsos told the accused, Pavlos Georgiou, aged 40.</p>
<p>Georgiou, who is HIV positive, slouched over the dock as the judge read the verdict, which lasted 50 minutes.</p>
<p>Charged under a decades old law enacted to curb the spread of cholera on the island, Georgiou faces a sentence of up to two years in jail, a 1,500 Cyprus pound ($2,770) fine, or both. He is to be sentenced on Thursday.</p>
<p>Georgiou, dressed casually in jeans and a T-shirt, showed no sign of emotion as the verdict was being read out but said later: &quot;I know I am going to die soon. What could scare me any &quot;To be honest, the verdict really knocked me,&quot; the stocky bearded fisherman told Reuters outside the court.</p>
<p>Pink, 45, from Basildon, England, did not come to Cyprus for the verdict at the end of a three-month trial but issued a statement in London approving of the verdict.</p>
<p>&quot;I am relieved and pleased with the verdict. I am glad that at long last this is all over.</p>
<p>&quot;I now want to get as well as possible, enjoy my family and get on with my life,&quot; said Pink.</p>
<p>Georgiou, a father of four, was tested HIV positive in 1992 but shows no visible signs of illness. He had denied Pink's accusation that he lied to her about having the disease.</p>
<p>Throughout the three month hearing Georgiou had maintained Pink was well aware of his condition during their affair.</p>
<p>He admitted that on one occasion, when they were both drunk, they had unprotected sex. This, he claimed, took place after Pink, whom he described as having a &quot;weakness&quot; for unprotected intercourse, took the condom off him.</p>
<p>Shortly before the alleged incident, in April 1994, Pink had taken her first AIDS test which appeared negative.</p>
<p>&quot;It is inconceivable that a woman who has just found out she is healthy would have unprotected sex....it is illogical,&quot; Liatsos said, ruling Georgiou's testimony &quot;utterly unreliable&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The version of the circumstances by the accused is so unnatural it cannot be accepted,&quot; the judge said.</p>
<p>Pink took a second test in October 1994, which was positive. She had been sleeping with Georgiou for nine months by that time.</p>
<p>Liatsos said that Pink, who underwent gruelling examination and cross-examination at the start of the trial, had made an excellent impression on him.</p>
<p>Georgiou's youngest son is HIV positive and his wife died of an AIDS-related illness in 1994.</p>
<p>Pink said Georgiou lied to her about his wife's condition as well, claiming she suffered from leukaemia.</p>
<p>She stayed with him until July 1996, when, after developing full blown Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome, she returned to England for medical treatment.</p>
<p>It was there that she took the decision to report Georgiou to the Cypriot authorities.</p>
<p>The Terence Higgins trust, one of Britain's main aids charities, said in a statement that it sympathised with Pink but warned against criminalising HIV transmission.</p>
<p>&quot;This type of legislation will not encourage people to practise safer sex, it is more likely to discourage people from testing and from disclosing their HIV status. Driving HIV and AIDS underground will only increase the rate of transmission.&quot;</p>
<p>It is the first time the authorities have prosecuted an HIV carrier in Cyprus, which has a relatively low number of HIV infection in a population of some 800,000.</p>
<p>Since 1986, when records were first kept, 268 people have tested HIV positive, according to official statistics. Roughly half of them were foreigners who have since left the island.</p>
<p>($1 = 0.540 Cyprus Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LARNACA, Cyprus"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
