<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764139" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kohl defends double dike ploy in flood-hit Germany.</title>
<headline>Kohl defends double dike ploy in flood-hit Germany.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>ALTREETZ, Germany 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl on Tuesday defended efforts to build up a second line of dikes on the Oder river as angry villagers accused authorities of being ready to let their homes flood to save larger towns.</p>
<p>Around 9,000 soldiers have been working day and night for the past week in a two-tier plan to reinforce a main dike while building a secondary line of defence that would protect the towns of Bad Freienwalde and Wriezen.</p>
<p>&quot;There are so many soldiers working on the secondary dike. We believe there is not enough being done to save the main dike,&quot; Helga Scholz, mayor of the village of Alt Maedewitz, told Kohl as angry local residents looked on.</p>
<p>But the chancellor inisisted the villagers' homes were not being abandoned.</p>
<p>&quot;I have come here to tell you that the army has orders to hold the main line of dikes,&quot; Kohl told Scholz on a visit to the village of Altreetz, where sandbags littered the main square.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't come here for nothing,&quot; Kohl said emphatically, his hand on the mayor's shoulder.</p>
<p>Around 190 of the village's 300 inhabitants refused to be evacuated last Friday, and mothers, children and grandparents have been working tirelessly to carry sandbags to army trucks.</p>
<p>&quot;They've built the secondary dike so high we're now afraid that they will just let us be submerged,&quot; said local farmer Bodow Schroeder, leaning on a shovel as he took a break.</p>
<p>Schroeder recalled how his father and grandfather lost their farms 50 years ago the last time the low-lying Oderbruch area was flooded by a break in the dam near Reitwein.</p>
<p>&quot;We are really afraid that this will happen again. The Oder is more dangerous than I've ever seen it before.&quot;</p>
<p>Altreetz is one of a group of villages in the northern part of the Oderbruch area, where evacuations were ordered last week when officials feared a possible break in the dike.</p>
<p>Kohl stopped off in Altreetz after visiting soldiers at the Neu-Hardenberg military base, the largest army base in the region and an East German air station during the Cold War.</p>
<p>He was due to go on to Hohenwutzen, where 700 soldiers were toiling to stop the dike there from breaking.</p>
<p>Earlier, Kohl told residents in the town of Bad Freienwalde that defending the area was a task for the whole nation and demonstrated the solidarity between west and east Germans, seven years after the unification of the country.</p>
<p>&quot;The main thing I want to say, in this first natural disaster seven years after unification, is that we not only express ourselves in words but also in deeds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to ensure that people here feel our compassion in a special way. This is a national task.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl, who flew in from his Austrian vacation resort dressed in a casual suede jacket, said the federal and state governments were already thinking about how best to repair the dikes on the Oder river before the annual high water arrived in autumn.</p>
<p>Kohl, paying his second visit to the region, said the government planned to let the army stay throughout the summer to ensure repairs were completed by the autumn. He said it might be time to erect more modern flood protection along the river.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to think about whether these dams, which are 250 years old, should be kept in this form,&quot; the chancellor said.</p>
<p>&quot;No one should fear we will give up any of these areas,&quot; he said. &quot;The army plans to stay to defend the dikes.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl said people whose property had been damaged by flood waters needed quick and high-quality help. &quot;I will personally ensure that the large insurance companies quickly determine the extent of damage,&quot; he pledged.</p>
<p>At Ratzdorf, where the Oder and Neisse rivers meet, relief workers were building up an 800-metre (-yard) secondary dike, anticipating a possible break in the main dam near the town.</p>
<p>Brandenburg officials said a new surge of high water was approaching Ratzdorf and would reach the most critical areas of the east German stretch of the Oder later in the day.</p>
<p>The floods have claimed more than 100 lives in neighbouring Poland and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>Germany has so far escaped the worst of the damage. But thousands of people have already been evacuated from their homes and thousands more are on standby to leave at a moment's notice.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALTREETZ, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
