<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764193" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain says domestic demand growth continued in Q2.</title>
<headline>Spain says domestic demand growth continued in Q2.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's domestic demand continued to grow during the second quarter, the Economy Ministry's monthly report on Economic Indicators said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Recent indicators show a continuation of the expanding economic trend seen in the National Quarterly Accounting Report in the opening quarter&quot;, the report said.</p>
<p>Exports were also performing positively, &quot;allowing net external demand to provide a sustained positive contribution despite a growth in imports&quot;, it added.</p>
<p>Personal spending is being aided by the &quot;favourable development of real income&quot; as a result of the increase in employment, a fall in inflation and improved family sentiment.</p>
<p>Real wage indicators for the private sector, calculated on the basis of agreed salaries and Social Security affiliations, grew 5.6 pct year-on-year in the second quarter, nearly two percentage points higher than in the opening quarter.</p>
<p>The Ministry also said the average price differential with the three best placed EU countries was 1.1 percentage point.</p>
<p>&quot;One can foresee a reduction when figures for the next few months are added, guaranteeing the fulfilment of the Maastricht criterion based on annual figures&quot;, the report said.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
