<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764283" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares firmer in early bourse dealings.</title>
<headline>German shares firmer in early bourse dealings.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were slightly firmer in early bourse dealings on Tuesday as traders said the market was searching for direction after the recent advance to new all-time record levels.</p>
<p>At 0900 GMT, the 30-share DAX index was up 16.12 points at 4,387.28 points but off the session high so far at 4,398.67 points.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX, which reflects all-day computer dealings, was down 13.55 points at 4,386.75 points.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to predict where the market will trade,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;Dealings are very thin and it appears we cannot keep up the advance we have been seeking.&quot;</p>
<p>A flood of corporate earnings results gave the market fresh fundamentals to digest.</p>
<p>Dresdner Bank AG was up 75 pfennigs at 83.60 marks after saying it planned to raise its base capital by 120 million marks by issuing new shares. The bank, the second-largest in Germany, also said earnings were up 23 percent in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>Dresdner said the raise was for &quot;strategic moves&quot; -- adding fuel to speculation about banking mergers.</p>
<p>Commerzbank AG, considered the next target after regional banks Vereinsbank and Hypo-Bank announced plans last week to merge, was up 10 pfennigs at 61.80 marks.</p>
<p>Carmaker BMW AG slumped 15 marks to 1,460 marks after trading as high as 1,482.50 marks in IBIS trade after reporting a first-half group net profit of 435 million marks, which was slightly above market expectations for 400 million.</p>
<p>Dealers said other carmakers were benefiting from the positive outlook for the sector, which has been bolstered by the weak mark making exports more competitve.</p>
<p>Daimler-Benz AG, maker of Mercedes vehicles, was up 4.40 marks at 157.30 marks as traders set a near-term target of 160 marks, while Volkswagen AG was up 15 marks at 1,374 marks.</p>
<p>Degussa AG, the metal and chemicals group, was up 3.90 marks at 105 marks after reporting a 10 percent rise in nine-month group sales to 11.2 billion marks. Degussa also said it expected a higher profit for the 1996/97 year.</p>
<p>Other chemical sector shares were mixed, with Hoechst AG down 20 pfennigs at 86.30 marks and BASF AG up 1.25 marks at 71.90 marks.</p>
<p>Among other shares posting notable losses in early dealings were sportswear group Puma AG, which was down one mark at 53.90 marks on more volatile dealings amid fresh takeover talk for the Herzogenaurach-based group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
