<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764279" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algeria to privatise more than 200 firms.</title>
<headline>Algeria to privatise more than 200 firms.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algeria is planning to sell of between 200 and 230 state-owned companies either totally or in part, according to a senior Algerian official.</p>
<p>Algerian newspapers on Tuesday quoted Ahmed Tibaoui as telling a meeting of Algerian and German businessmen on Monday: &quot;The sectors of construction, major public works and building materials will be totally privatised.&quot;</p>
<p>The only exception would be the cement industry where the state would keep a stake but would open it to private capital.</p>
<p>Other areas where companies would be sold off included tourism, distribution networks and the chemical and pharmaceutical industry, Liberte newspaper quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>The newspaper said on the list were 18 chemical-pharmaceutical factories slated for total sale and four for partial privatisation. A tractor plant and railway wagon manufacturing unit would be opened up to private capital.</p>
<p>Tibaoui, the senior official responsible for overseeing state holdings, was quoted as telling the business forum: &quot;We are adapting each time to the demand from the non-resident market (Algerian expatriates and international firms)&quot;.</p>
<p>He said there were also plans for a second privatisation programme affecting local authority enterprises in which shares would be issued only to the company workers.</p>
<p>Liberte quoted Abderhmane Mebtoul, Algeria's privatisation council president, as saying that privatisation would speed up from next January.</p>
<p>The sale of state assets has made little progress since the policy was introduced four years ago after three decades of centralised state control.</p>
<p>Many companies have for years been heavily overmanned and Western diplomats have said that Algerian officials were wary of the inevitable increase in unemployment that would follow massive privatisation.</p>
<p>The officials have blamed unemployment, poverty and lack of hope for sending many young people into the ranks of Moslem fundamentalists who have been fighting for nearly six years to topple the authorities.</p>
<p>President Liamine Zeroual has criticised the pace of privatisation and earlier this month set up a privatisation control commission to oversee the programme.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
