<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76421" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>OMAN: Oman's private Manah power network completed.</title>
<headline>Oman's private Manah power network completed.</headline>
<dateline>MUSCAT 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first power network built and owned by the private sector in Oman has been completed, a director for United Power Co said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have now successfully completed construction including the interconnection of 186 km of transmission lines. The full network is in operation,&quot; Tony Georgiou said, adding that the work, completed last week, had cost $215 million.</p>
<p>The United Power Co was set up to build, own, operate and after 20 years transfer to the state the Manah power station near Nizwa in the interior of the sultanate.</p>
<p>It is the first infrastructure project in the oil-rich Gulf -- which is trying to give the private sector a bigger role in its state-dominated economy -- using the BOOT formula.</p>
<p>Georgiou said the 90 megawatt (MW) plant supplies Bahla, Nizwa and Izki towns in one of the most populous areas of Oman.</p>
<p>The first of three 30 MW turbines was switched on in April. The second and third turbines came on stream in June and July.</p>
<p>Companies belonging to Belgium's Tractebel group are the biggest shareholders in UPC, with about 35 percent. A number of Omani companies also own UPC equity.</p>
<p>The rest is publicly held.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUSCAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="OMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
