<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764334" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GrandMet's Burger King pulls out of France.</title>
<headline>GrandMet's Burger King pulls out of France.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hamburger chain Burger King, owned by Britain's Grand Metropolitan Plc, said on Tuesday it planned to withdraw from France after a review of its operations in Europe.</p>
<p>Burger King has a total 39 restaurants in France, mainly in and around Paris, 16 of these are company owned with the remainder owned by franchisees. Most of the franchised outlets will cease trading as Burger King by December 31, the company said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Burger King plans to grow the business in Europe with the focus of its effort on Britain, Germany and Spain, said David William's managing director Burger King Europe Middle East and Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result we have taken the difficult decision that due to our size, relative market position and sustained low level of profitability, we can no longer compete effectively in the French market and it does not make commercial sense to continue operating these restaurants,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Burger King has 973 outlets in Europe and the Middle East and is growing rapidly, opening some 300 restaurants in the region over the last two years.</p>
<p>The group aims to open a further 167 outlets in the current financial year and another 184 restaurants in the next fiscal year.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
