<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764445" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Latest record rally in NZ shares puzzles analysts.</title>
<headline>Latest record rally in NZ shares puzzles analysts.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Brockett</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand share market's surge to record post-crash highs on Tuesday has left analysts and brokers somewhat puzzled.</p>
<p>The broad-based equities rally flies in the face of a plunging kiwi dollar and rising short-term interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very difficult rally to explain, especially today where we saw the currency come off against the U.S. dollar by about 50 points,&quot; said Don Turkington, managing director at Cavill White Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;It came right out of the blue.&quot;</p>
<p>The NZSE-40 Capital Index closed at a record high on Monday and continued to boom on Tuesday morning, leaping a further 28.82 points to 2,570.92 -- its highest level since before the 1987 global share market crash.</p>
<p>But the kiwi dollar shed about one U.S. cent overnight, and in the process shoved up the benchmark wholesale market interest rate, on 90-day bank bills, by about 40 points to 8.6 percent.</p>
<p>As a general rule of thumb, investors sell shares when rates are high in favour of higher returns in the debt markets, and buy shares when rates fall.</p>
<p>Brokers said selected stocks were benefiting from the lower New Zealand currency, which fell to a low of US$0.6405 overnight and is now five U.S. cents weaker than it was six weeks ago.</p>
<p>Fletcher Energy, whose oil assests are denominated in U.S. dollars, is one example -- it has gained 75 cents this month to an all-time high of $5.25.</p>
<p>But stocks such as market leader Telecom, which hit an all-time high of $8.01 on Tuesday morning, are rising in spite of an economic environment that ought to see prices fall.</p>
<p>&quot;A lower kiwi and higher rates, you might argue, is slightly negative for Telecom,&quot; said John Rattray, director of equities at Ord Minnett.</p>
<p>&quot;But they seem to have this 'bellwether' status which seems to keep them in the fore even when you get factors like that that might work against them.&quot;</p>
<p>Rattray said there was a perception that interest rates would trend downwards as the Reserve Bank looked to ease monetary conditions further towards the end of the year.</p>
<p>But Telecom's strength took brokers by surprise, particularly in light of the sluggish New Zealand economy, which has yet to show signs of recovering from its current trough and has abeen putting corporate earnings under pressure.</p>
<p>&quot;All that doesn't seem to have been worrying people,&quot; Turkington said.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe they're picking a sharp upturn, but I don't think any of the economic forecasters have suddenly come to that view. I think if anything there's concern that this downturn will be He suggested the fall in the kiwi dollar may have been attracting offshore investors into New Zealand equities as better purchasing power gave them more shares for their money.</p>
<p>&quot;All I can think is that the lower kiwi, after initially depressing the market, might have led to some money coming in taking advantage of the lower rate,&quot; said Turkington.</p>
<p>Another possible factor behind the rally was a lack of liquidity, with very few sellers in major stocks, although the sudden reluctance of investors to part with New Zealand shares was somewhat perplexing, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pretty hard to pin it down to any rational argument,&quot; said Turkington, who also noted that the rally came at a time when Wall Street was subdued.</p>
<p>Despite the baffling nature of the rally, few in the market were complaining, and the consensus view was that the uptrend showed every sign of remaining intact. (US$=1.55NZ$)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
