<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764401" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian scientists see healing power of milk.</title>
<headline>Australian scientists see healing power of milk.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian researchers said on Tuesday a special powder they had extracted from cows' milk could heal wounds and smooth wrinkles, a discovery they say is potentially worth up to A$20 billion (US$15 billion) worldwide.</p>
<p>Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation (CSIRO) project leader David Belford said laboratory testing of the extract of whey, a waste product in cheese making, had almost doubled the healing rate of wounds in rats.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can reproduce even a fraction of (that) kind of activity...in the human population, we would be very pleased,&quot; Belford told Reuters.</p>
<p>Positive clinical tests on humans could result in the unique extract's use as a healing agent in dressings for minor wounds and as an application for leg and diabetic ulcers, pressure sores and even as a wrinkle remover in cosmetics, he said.</p>
<p>There was also veterinary potential in healing wounds in race horses and domestic pets, he said.</p>
<p>Belford, from the government-backed CSIRO human nutrition division, said the extract was unlikely to be available commercially before the turn of the century.</p>
<p>&quot;All the dressings at the moment really just provide an environment which facilitates optimal wound repair,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you can actually produce a product that stimulates wound repair, that would attract a fair percentage of market share.&quot;</p>
<p>Belford said the extract was a mixture of different &quot;growth factors&quot;, proteins that promote cell growth and division as well as the production of supporting structures like collagen.</p>
<p>The extraction process has already been patented and manufacturing rights has been awarded, while marketing negotiations were underway with a number of major international cosmetics and wound care companies, he said.</p>
<p>Belford said the first clinical trials, expected to be held next year, would be conducted on people with chronic peripheral ulcers caused by circulatory problems.</p>
<p>A pilot plant capable of processing 2,000 litres (440 gallons) of whey a day -- which would yield about 60 grams (two ounces) of the powder -- had been commissioned, Belford said.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.74)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
