<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764650" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Australia, Philippines set formal security talks.</title>
<headline>Australia, Philippines set formal security talks.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia and the Philippines on Tuesday announced closer cooperation in three areas, including the establishment of formal bilateral security talks, foreign ministers from the two countries said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're upgrading our security (ties) by establishing bilateral regional security talks (with the Philippines),&quot; Australian Foreign Minister Alexander Downer, said at a joint news briefing with Philippine Foreign Secretary Domingo Siazon.</p>
<p>The talks would &quot;allow discussion of regional security issues&quot;, with the first meetings to be held later this year, Downer said.</p>
<p>Australia already holds formal bilateral security talks with the United States, China, Japan and South Korea.</p>
<p>Asked if disputes by several Asian countries over territories in the South China Sea would be part of the bilateral talks, Siazon said &quot;...the South China Sea issue is one of the more, I would say, prominent subjects dealt with every year ...&quot;</p>
<p>But he added that all areas of potential conflict in the region would be discussed.</p>
<p>Another area of closer cooperation will be through the start of a Philippines-Australia dialogue that will bring together &quot;business people, academics and politicians to flesh out new ideas for the future&quot;, Downer said. Both foreign ministers will also participate in the dialogue.</p>
<p>In addition, Australia will conduct a survey of Australian investments in the Philippines and use the findings to &quot;highlight new areas of opportunity for Australian business, as well as identify problems and obstacles to our investment relationships&quot;, Downer said.</p>
<p>He said trade between the countries had grown 130 percent since 1991.</p>
<p>As part of the Philippine-Australia dialogue, Siazon will make his first visit to Australia in his role as foreign secretary in August. Downer will go to Manila in October, the ministers said.</p>
<p>Both ministers have been in Malaysia's capital city for the week-long Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) 30th anniversary meetings, which wrap up on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The regional grouping consists of Brunei, Burma, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam. Australia is one of 10 ASEAN dialogue partners of key Western and Asian powers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
