<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764786" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: FEATURE - Used car frenzy hits Cyprus.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Used car frenzy hits Cyprus.</headline>
<byline>Michele Kambas</byline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>It looks the same from the outside, a bit tatty inside but it does not really matter because you are only paying a fraction for a car which appears to be in mint condition.</p>
<p>That tear on the seat, marks of a cigarette stubbed out on the plastic interior or an air conditioning unit which in time starts letting off a distinctly fish-like smell isn't important.</p>
<p>It is the outside packaging that really sells, and after years in decline, the used car market in Cyprus is booming.</p>
<p>No more old bangers. An old car that looks brand new is vogue.</p>
<p>&quot;I have sold over 100 of these in the past six months. They are going like hot cakes,&quot; preened Christakis, a car dealer in a suburb of Cyprus's capital Nicosia as he notched up another sale, watching the young couple drive off in their new -- well almost new -- gleaming white Toyota Corolla.</p>
<p>In three years, the industry has turned into a goldmine for dealers importing second hand vehicles from Japan.</p>
<p>The local market was flooded with cheap imports when parliament amended a law allowing imports of cars up to five years old, from two years which existed previously.</p>
<p>USED &quot;CYPRIOT&quot; CAR SALES FALL</p>
<p>Two evidently unwanted cars covered in dust and bird droppings stand out at the end of the long line of Mazdas and Toyota Starlets in Christakis's yard.</p>
<p>&quot;They are Cypriot,&quot; he says dismissively. &quot;Nobody is interested in them. Cypriots don't know how to treat cars, they never take them for a service.</p>
<p>&quot;Besides, the ones from Japan not only look better, they are cheaper,&quot; he said before heading off to another prospective client eyeing a red sports car.</p>
<p>But before being carried away by air conditioning, central locking, car stereos and many more extras consumers should think twice.</p>
<p>At least, that is what importers of brand new cars say.</p>
<p>CAR IMPORTERS LAUNCH OFFENSIVE</p>
<p>Importers of new cars have declared war on cheap imports with an advertising blitz highlighting the murky past of second hand imports and slashing their prices.</p>
<p>The issue has become a hot topic on this Eastern Mediterranean island where a car is seen by many more as a status symbol than a means of transport.</p>
<p>According to official statistics, of 8,544 saloon cars registered between January and the end of May, more than half -- 5,135 -- were used vehicles.</p>
<p>With it has come a drop in prices of new cars, though importers say the two issues are not related.</p>
<p>&quot;Our members managed to get some very good deals from the manufacturers when they placed their orders,&quot; says Andy Apostolou, secretary of the Cyprus car importers association.</p>
<p>&quot;These cars may look exactly the same as the new ones, but the fact of the matter is they are made according to Japanese specifications only...We have these assurances from manufacturers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>That does not mean the vehicle will literally fall apart in the scorching Cypriot sun, but importers say it could mean a shorter road life, while finding spare parts and good backup service can be something of a pain.</p>
<p>Second hand importers put it down to sour grapes, and respond to the stated intentions of their rivals with open disbelief.</p>
<p>&quot;It all boils down to their own interests,&quot; scoffed Marios Frangou, a member of PASYMA, the Cyprus second hand car dealers association affiliated to the Cyprus chamber of commerce and industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Import duties have been continuously falling for the past few years and we didn't see them reduce their prices. Now a car that might have cost 12,000 pounds ($22,100) 18 months ago costs 9,000 or 8,500. That is because now they have got the competition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One of the main attractions of a second hand car is the small downpayment, and a repayment period which can reach up to five years.</p>
<p>The dribble in imports has now turned into a steady flow of sports cars, family saloons and four-wheel drives, that appears to show no signs of abating as more and more second hand dealers jump on the bandwagon of the lucrative car market.</p>
<p>Of PASYMA'S estimated 200 member companies, most import second hand cars from Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;Sure, there may be some cowboys, but most of the people who sell second hand cars are reputable businessmen who have a solid background in the trade,&quot; said one car dealer, who requested anonymity.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically the used second hand car dealers offered consumers the chance to buy a car -- without spending the next 40 years of their life paying for it.&quot; ($ = 0.542 Cyprus Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
