<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="764714" id="root" date="1997-07-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Jinro vows to keep managerial rights.</title>
<headline>Jinro vows to keep managerial rights.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-07-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jinro Ltd, South Korea's largest distiller, said on Tuesday it would not hand over managerial rights to creditors in exchange for emergency loans.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no plan to give up managerial rights. We will try to extend repayments of the promissory notes,&quot; said Kim Young-jin, director of Jinro's planning division.  </p>
<p>Jinro Ltd failed to honour repayments of promissory notes worth about eight billion won on Monday, Jinro's main creditor Commercial Bank of Korea said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>An official at the bank said final default, which would trigger formal court-receivership proceedings, would be avoided if Jinro met a final deadline on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The bank urged Jinro to give up managerial rights in order to receive 36.9 billion won of emergency loans.</p>
<p>&quot;We just informed our creditor banks of our intention to extend repayments of the loans by 4:00 p.m. (0800 GMT)&quot; said Kim.  </p>
<p>Unlisted Donghwa Leasing Co Ltd holds Jinro's promissory notes and Jinro said it had asked the leasing firm to extend its payments. A Donghwa official later said Donghwa had its own financial problems and that a final decision on Jinro's request had not been made.</p>
<p>In April, Jinro Group became the first conglomerate to benefit from a bank committee programme to keep troubled corporations afloat.</p>
<p>The committee protected Jinro for two months, and on July 25 agreed to extend 36.9 billion won to Jinro on the condition that the company turn over its managerial rights to creditors.  </p>
<p>But Jinro has not complied with that condition and the new loans have not been provided.</p>
<p>--Seoul Newsroom (822) 727 5645</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
