<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76491" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Simpson civil jury pool splits along racial lines.</title>
<headline>Simpson civil jury pool splits along racial lines.</headline>
<byline>Matt Spetalnick</byline>
<dateline>SANTA MONICA, Calif 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of the jury pool for the O.J. Simpson civil trial split mostly along racial lines Tuesday, with whites saying he was probably guilty of murder and blacks convinced of his innocence.</p>
<p>Reflecting America's racial divide over Simpson's acquittal last October on criminal charges, prospective jurors expressed strong opinions about whether the former football star was responsible for the 1994 killings of his former wife and a friend of hers.</p>
<p>A white man who described all paid expert witnesses in the first trial as &quot;whores&quot; and a white woman who insisted she would have a hard time setting aside her belief in Simpson's guilt were among those accepted as potential jurors in the case.</p>
<p>But the one panellist who received an unqualified stamp of approval from both sides was a black woman who professed near-total ignorance of the most highly publicised murder case in U.S. history.</p>
<p>As jury selection became increasingly bogged down in lengthy questioning, Judge Hiroshi Fujisaki pressed attorneys to keep the process moving.</p>
<p>Twelve regular jurors and eight alternates are needed to sit in judgment in the wrongful-death civil case brought against Simpson by the families of Nicole Brown Simpson and Ronald Goldman. Jury selection entered its fourth day Tuesday and was expected to last at least two to three weeks more.</p>
<p>Simpson looked on attentively, scribbling notes and occasionally whispering to his attorneys. During breaks, he wandered into the spectators' gallery and bantered with reporters about football and golf, but steered clear of discussing the case.</p>
<p>&quot;You got 12 lawyers working for a defendant who is flat broke. That's a phenomenal thing,&quot; he said jokingly in an aside to his bodyguard.</p>
<p>Simpson, whose personal fortune was once estimated at $10 million, spent millions on his criminal defence, and the legal fees are now mounting for his civil trial. He could be forced to pay heavy damages if he loses the case.</p>
<p>When the questioning got under way Tuesday, the racial divide between white and black jurors soon became clear.</p>
<p>A black man in his 30s said he believed police had tampered with blood evidence in the case -- a major thrust of Simpson's defence in his criminal trial.</p>
<p>A white man in his 40s and a white woman in her 50s both said they thought Simpson was &quot;definitely guilty&quot; of the murders. They were removed from the panel.</p>
<p>A white man in his 60s said &quot;professional witnesses&quot; like forensics expert Henry Lee, who testified for the the defence in Simpson's criminal trial, were &quot;whores&quot; who will &quot;say what they've been paid to say.&quot; He was allowed to stay on the panel over the defence team's strong objections.</p>
<p>But it was Juror 39 who had courtroom observers scratching their heads when she said she knew almost nothing about Simpson's criminal trial, which was broadcast live on national television. &quot;I'm not really sure of what went on,&quot; she said. &quot;I didn't have time. I work and I have two kids.&quot;</p>
<p>Stan Goldman, a Loyola University law professor, said attorneys in the case should be wary of such statements. &quot;You never know when someone wants to get on the trial because they have a hidden agenda,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Out of the 15 people questioned Tuesday, seven -- three whites, two blacks and two Asian-Americans -- were allowed to remain in the jury pool. Those who survive the latest phase, designed to weed out panelsts prejudiced by publicity, will move on to the the next, in which they will be questioned about race, domestic violence and other issues.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA MONICA, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
