<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="765633" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA TO OPEN SECRET POLICE FILES.</title>
<headline>BULGARIA TO OPEN SECRET POLICE FILES.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's parliament voted on Wednesday to open communist-era secret police files of public figures, despite Socialist opposition and warnings that the measure came too late.</p>
<p>The main opposition Socialists walked out of the session saying the move harmed national security and contravened the constitution. They plan an appeal to the Constitutional Court.</p>
<p>The National Salvation Union, the third force in parliament, abstained.</p>
<p>&quot;History should be read so that it is not repeated,&quot; said Ekaterina Mihailova, leader of the parliamentary group of the ruling Union of Democratic Forces (UDF).</p>
<p>The UDF says the law would prevent attempts to blackmail public figures, and opening the files was a major plank of its manifesto for April elections, but opponents of the measure warn too much time has passed and the files could be a Pandora's Box for the new government.</p>
<p>Files of top officials including the president, parliamentary deputies, ministers, government and court officials and state media directors will be made public.</p>
<p>A commission headed by Interior Minister Bogomil Bonev will be set up to check whether they worked for the State Security Service.</p>
<p>To protect national security, the names of agents still working for the security service will be kept secret. Reformist President Petar Stoyanov has said he will insist on having his file opened.</p>
<p>The State Security Service was dissolved in 1989 and its files are kept by the interior and defence ministries, the National Intelligence Service and the National Protection Service, which assures security for public figures.</p>
<p>The agencies will be required to submit the relevant files to the prime minister within a month.</p>
<p>Bonev said in April he felt it was now too late to open the files. More than seven years since the end of one-party rule have given ample opportunity for records to be forged, substituted or destroyed.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's communist secret service, closely allied to the Soviet KGB, had a network of 100,000 agents and informers.</p>
<p>Several prominent UDF figures, including former leaders Filip Dimitrov and Petar Beron, have been accused of having cooperated with the security services.</p>
<p>A former intelligence officer said recently that Ahmed Dogan, leader of the ethnic Turks' Movement for Rights and Freedoms, the main party in the Union for National Salvation, had been recruited while he was a student.</p>
<p>Opening secret police files has been a controversial step even in former East Germany, although made easier by the clean break the former communist state made with the past by unifying with West Germany and disbanding its own intelligence service.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
