<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76569" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. state budgets in healthy condition.</title>
<headline>U.S. state budgets in healthy condition.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>No U.S. state registered a budget deficit at the end of fiscal 1996, making their finances the healthiest since 1980, the magazine State Legislatures said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But the publication of the Denver-based National Conference of State Legislatures said the outlook for 1997 is not so rosy.</p>
<p>&quot;The aggregate year-end balance for fiscal year 1997 is projected to fall to 4.7 percent (as a percentage of general fund expenditures),&quot; the article said. &quot;Furthermore fewer states expect to end the fiscal year with balances exceeding five percent,&quot; the magazine said based.</p>
<p>The aggregate balance for FY 1996 stood at 5.8 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;On the bright side, no state expects FY 1997 with a deficit,&quot; the magazine said in an article based on the organization's annual survey of state budget and tax actions.</p>
<p>A handful of states expect revenues to drop below last year's collections, either because of sluggish economies or previously enacted tax cuts.</p>
<p>States expect to spend less on Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC) and to keep Medicaid spending in check, due in part to good economic conditions.</p>
<p>But spending on corrections has been one of the fastest growing areas of state budgets in recent years and are expected to grow 6.8 percent over fiscal 1996 levels.</p>
<p>Because of favorable economic conditions spending on higher education is projected to grow 5.1 percent in FY 1997, its largest percentage increase since the last 1980s, the magazine said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
