<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="765663" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY'S CEN.BANK EXCLUDES C/A, CURRENCY PROBLEMS.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY'S CEN.BANK EXCLUDES C/A, CURRENCY PROBLEMS.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary will avoid currency and current account problems faced by other countries in the region, despite increasing economic growth, a senior National Bank of Hungary (NBH) official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not seen any speculation against the forint and also I do not see a chance for that in the future,&quot; NBH Vice President Gyorgy Szapary told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamentals of the economy are so favourable that these will not create a speculation wave similar to what happened in the Czech Republic and Poland.&quot;</p>
<p>Hungary targets a gross domestic product (GDP) growth of three percent this year and four to five percent in the subsequent years, compared with a preliminary one percent in 1996.</p>
<p>A surge in imports in the Czech Republic and Poland, triggered by quick economic growth, have recently sparked fears of trade and current account difficulties, weakening the crown and the zloty.</p>
<p>Szapary said Hungary's quick export growth and maintained international competitiveness safeguarded the country against similar problems.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that Hungary will face current account problems because of a pick-up in growth if exports continue to grow so quickly and I don't see a reason why they should not,&quot; he said. &quot;There is no sign of a recession in Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>Hungary's main export market is the European Union.</p>
<p>&quot;The current account is going very well and its deficit could be lower this year than we expected,&quot; Szapary added.</p>
<p>Hungary's current account deficit target for this year is $2 billion, slightly up from a $1.7 billion gap in 1996.</p>
<p>Szapary said a further reduction in Hungary's monthly crawling peg devaluation rate would depend on how inflation developed.</p>
<p>As announced earlier, the monthly devaluation rate will be cut to one percent in August from the current 1.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The forint's depreciation must be in line with inflation and the increase in productivity in the economy,&quot; Szapary said, adding that Hungary's productivity growth has been the quickest in the region in the past few years. &quot;It is very important to maintain external competititiveness.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Currently the devaluation rate is lower than inflation but taking into account unit labour cost developments, the real exchange rate maintained international competitiveness,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Szapary said that Hungary's forint traded pinned to the resistance level of the 4.5 percent wide floating intervention range in the past two years, drifting away from the NBH bid only occasionally.</p>
<p>&quot;When the forint moved away (from the National Bank of Hungary's resistance level), this only lasted for a few days and to only a small extent,&quot; Szapary said. &quot;This shows clearly that the markets believe the forint will remain strong.&quot;</p>
<p>He said a widening of the 4.5 percent wide intervention band could give monetary policies a larger manoeuvering field.</p>
<p>&quot;But there is no pressure for a widening,&quot; Szapary said.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
