<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="765773" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: FORECAST-Canada housing market seen staying strong.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Canada housing market seen staying strong.</headline>
<byline>Greg MacDonald</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Low interest rates and increased demand for affordable housing will keep Canada's housing industry buoyant during the next two years, said economists in a Reuters poll released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The quarterly Reuters survey, which polled 26 economists in Canada and the United States, expected housing starts on average to remain consistently high for the rest of 1997 and increase slightly in 1998.</p>
<p>Economists predicted that housing starts would climb to just more than 153,000 by the end of 1997 and nudge upward to almost 158,000 by the end of 1998.</p>
<p>Canada Mortgage and Housing Corp recently reported that housing starts grew by 145,500 in the second quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Analysts said that historically low interest rates -- the Bank of Canada cut its key bank rate 11 times last year -- had drawn more Canadians into the housing market.</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamental reason underlying the forecast is that housing is now more affordable than it has been in the last 10 years,&quot; said John Anania, economist with Royal Bank of Canada.</p>
<p>&quot;Demographic requirements in Canada on average point to 160,000 starts a year. What we have now is a gradual rebuilding of housing starts to a more appropriate level,&quot; Anania said.</p>
<p>Canada's booming economy would help soften the effect of rises in short-term lending rates expected next year, Anania said.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though we are going to have rising interest and mortgage rates in 1998, it's going to be minimal. And it's going to be more than offset by the income gains that we are going to have,&quot; Anania said.</p>
<p>But some survey respondents predicted that Canada's housing industry would take a downturn later this year.</p>
<p>Jayson Myers, chief economist with the Alliance of Manufacturers and Exporters Canada, suggested weaker consumer confidence would counter the stimulus of low interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;When you look at consumer income overall, there isn't a lot to draw on.  Savings rates are at all-time lows.  Only 1.6 percent of disposable income is being saved right now,&quot; Myers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is a lot of wishful thinking going on here. I don't know where the income is going to come from to keep the rate of housing starts going,&quot; Myers added.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500011">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E61">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
