<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76579" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Northeast spot power steady amid cool weather - SEP 24.</title>
<headline>U.S. Northeast spot power steady amid cool weather - SEP 24.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot electricity prices in the northeastern U.S. ended Tuesday steady against Monday's quotes amid cool weather settling into the region, market sources said.</p>
<p>Along Northeast's U.S./Canadian border, temperatures were forecast to peak in the 50's Fahrenheit Wednesday. The rest of the region were predicted to experience weather in the 60 to 70 degree range.</p>
<p>Lack of weather-related demand for cooling and heating was offset by tight generation capacity in the Northeast linked to the outages of a couple of nuclear power plants in the region.</p>
<p>New York Power Authority's 800 Fitzpatrick station in Scriba, N.Y., began producing power today, and would not resume full output at least until Wednesday.</p>
<p>Boston Edison Co pushed back the restart of its 670 MW Pilgrim plant in Plymouth, Mass., to Saturday from Wednesday because additional inspection time was needed.</p>
<p>In the New York Power Pool (NYPP), non-firm electricity for peak load hours on Wednesday was assessed near $19.00 a megawatt hour (MWh) in the western part of the state, down from Monday's quote of $20.00.</p>
<p>Next-day power prices in eastern NYPP, was valued at $22.00, flat from Monday.</p>
<p>In the New England Power Pool (NEPOOL), peak, non-firm electricity prices for Wednesday was pegged at $28.00-$30.00 at the Northeast Utilities' territory border, a wider range than Monday's $29.25-$29.75.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
