<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="765762" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Arakis Energy management gets easy ride.</title>
<headline>Arakis Energy management gets easy ride.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Jones</byline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arakis Energy Corp's management got an easy ride from shareholders at the company's annual meeting on Wednesday as resolutions to adopt a poison pill and install new directors passed easily.</p>
<p>Arakis, which is developing a major oil concession in southern Sudan with an international consortium, has been under fire for operational control held by Chairman Lutfur Khan and his allies. Observers have said the control issue was one reason for Arakis's lackluster stock market performance.</p>
<p>But the company's board was expanded to nine members from five, with three independent directors and one nominated by major shareholder Sands Petroleum  being added.</p>
<p>Swedish-based Sands, which owns 8.2 percent of Arakis's stock and has had an often-rocky relationship with its management, had pushed for two nominees, but the request was rejected by Khan earlier this year.</p>
<p>Sands, represented at the meeting by director Ian Lundin, who is also president of Lundin family-controlled International Petroleum Corp, had planned to vote against Arakis's shareholder rights plan.</p>
<p>But the group was shut out of voting because documentation was not filed in enough time. Arakis lawyer Charles Selby said the resolution would have passed even if Sands was successful in voting against it.</p>
<p>Khan said the outcome represented a vote of confidence for Arakis's management and its plans to develop the 12.2 million acre southern Sudan oil concession.</p>
<p>The partners plan to drill 20 wells this year and 46 in 1998 in the civil-strife-torn African nation and are also developing a 900-mile, 250,000 barrel a day pipeline to the Red Sea. Total costs for the project, slated to be on stream in 1999, are pegged at $1 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very pleased they have a lot of confidence in the existing board and the management and the way the company is conducting its business,&quot; Khan told reporters during a break.</p>
<p>Khan acknowledged continuing market skepticism because of past misadventures was contributing to Arakis's chronic low stock price, which has mostly stayed below $4 for a year and a half. Arakis shares on Nasdaq closed on Wednesday at $3.375.</p>
<p>He also said the market was waiting for construction to begin on the pipeline before the project was deemed a reality.</p>
<p>Tenders for its construction are to be submitted by August 23 and winning bids will be announced on December 2.</p>
<p>Despite not being able to vote on the poison pill -- which gives the company's management more time to scout alternative deals should a hostile takeover attempt be made -- Sands' Lundin said the new board was a positive step for Arakis.</p>
<p>&quot;There are independent directors on there that will have a say and be able to monitor the activities, so the board will provide some checks and balances that weren't there before.&quot;</p>
<p>However, Sands submitted a letter to Khan outlining a number of concerns, including the need for a president with credibility in the international oil arena and on Wall St., outstanding loans provided to directors and former CEO John McLeod and rising general and administrative costs.</p>
<p>The project's operations are now conducted by a joint operating company that also includes its partners China National Petroleum Corp, Malaysia state oil company Petronas and the Sudan government.</p>
<p>Also on Wednesday, Arakis chief financial officer Ken Rutherford said the company was attempting to raise financing for the company's share of operating costs in 1998 and 1999.</p>
<p>Total requirements are $220 million, and Rutherford said the firm preferred to raise debt financing, as shareholders had over the past two years experienced major dilution.</p>
<p>A deal was target before the end of this year. ((Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
