<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="765793" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: IMF seen giving Kenya breathing space on aid.</title>
<headline>IMF seen giving Kenya breathing space on aid.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya is likely to win more time from the International Montery Fund (IMF) to prove it is committed to ending corruption in government and deserves IMF aid, senior financial and economic experts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The implications of a suspension or cancellation are well understood by the government. The government will be doing all it can to ensure aid flows continue,&quot; said John Munge, managing director at leading brokerage house Shah, Munge &amp; Partners.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of foreign investors making inquiries on what a cancellation means. The issue is clear,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>A government economist, who declined to be identified, said the IMF and Kenyan government were likely to reach an agreement on an extension of the deadline, which expires on Thursday.</p>
<p>Treasury economists said there were positive signs from bilateral donors and some had signed packages for Kenya in recent weeks but had asked that media should not be invited.</p>
<p>The IMF extended a three-year Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility (ESAF) loan worth $205 million in April last year but payments were conditional on Kenya meeting promises on reform.</p>
<p>The last scheduled ESAF payment, a $36 million tranche, was delayed by the IMF for a month from June 30, mainly because of concern at how Kenyan authorities had handled the multi-million dollar Goldenberg International financial scandal.</p>
<p>The IMF hit out at the government failure to &quot;take decisive steps to ensure transparency and accountability in the use of public funds and resolve outstanding energy sector reform&quot;.</p>
<p>Unless the government shows measures to prove its commitment to addressing those issues, the aid package lapses on Thursday.</p>
<p>Business leaders said the government was on course on all major economic points, giving the central bank more autonomy and planning to privatise utilities Kenya Posts &amp; Telecommunications Corporation and Kenya Power &amp; Lighting Company.</p>
<p>They added there remained plenty of donor goodwill for Finance Minister Musalia Mudavadi and Central Bank of Kenya Governor Micah Cheserem and it was well known they were working in a difficult environment ahead of a general election.</p>
<p>They said that a decision by the IMF to let the $36 million trance to lapse would send wrong signals on economic reform.</p>
<p>The IMF has quoted Goldenberg International to illustrate just how Kenyan authorities are reluctant to punish corruption.</p>
<p>In 1991 and 1992 the government paid a company called Goldenberg International about $100 million under an export compensation scheme for gold and diamond exports. Kenya however produces little gold and has no diamond deposits.</p>
<p>The men involved in the scandal were charged with defrauding the government in 1993 but the high court stopped the trial earlier this year, with a judge saying it clearly lacked focus.</p>
<p>Attorney-General Amos Wako has since charged the men again, but senior IMF officials contend that if Wako failed to convict them in five years, it is unlikely he will a second time round.</p>
<p>&quot;That is why the focus has to change to steps the government will take to ensure such fraud will not exist in the future. That theft was colossal and yet the government appears totally unable to get a conviction,&quot; the government economist said.</p>
<p>Mudavadi said on Tuesday that the government was drafting a bill to set up an anti-graft authority but he would not give any details on when it will be ready.</p>
<p>Crispus Mutitu, the permanent secretary in the Energy Ministry, said on Monday a bill was being drafted to set up an independent energy regulatory board. Mudavadi said that bill was one of the items on the IMF agenda.</p>
<p>The opposition cited Goldenberg's alleged links to powerful politicians as the main reason the prosecution was dropped.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
