<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="765860" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GEORGIA: Russia threatens peacekeeper pullout from Georgia.</title>
<headline>Russia threatens peacekeeper pullout from Georgia.</headline>
<byline>Lawrence Sheets</byline>
<dateline>TBILISI 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia on Wednesday warned Georgia that it would call home the troops who police a fragile ceasefire with the former Soviet republic's Abkhaz rebels unless the Georgian government made a formal request for them to stay.</p>
<p>But, on the eve of the expiry of the Russians' current mandate, Georgian leaders said they could not satisfy Moscow's demand, raising fears of renewed war around the breakaway region of Abkhazia, where thousands died in fighting four years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;If by July 31 we do not get confirmation from Georgia that it agrees to prolong the mandate we will withdraw the peacekeepers,&quot; Gennady Ilychev, a senior Russian foreign ministry official, told Reuters in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the official position of the foreign ministry.&quot;</p>
<p>Final diplomatic decisions lie with President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>Georgian President Eduard Shevardnadze has said that while he does not want the force to be withdrawn immediately, his government could not approve an extension of its mandate.</p>
<p>Observers fear a renewal of conflict if the 1,500-strong force is withdrawn. At least 150,000 ethnic Georgian refugees have not yet been able to return to the lush Black Sea province.</p>
<p>Georgia wants the force to take up an expanded remit -- policing more of Abkhazia and resettling refugees -- in return for renewing the mandate. The increased powers were approved in March by the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS), which groups 12 of the 15 ex-Soviet republics.</p>
<p>But Russia has rejected this, saying the Abkhaz must agree as well. The separatists are bitterly opposed, calling it an attempt to encroach on their territory. Abkhazia's de facto sovereignty has never been recognised abroad.</p>
<p>Georgian Foreign Minister Irakly Menagarishvili said his government had no intention of asking the Russians to stay but said that did not mean the force would have to leave right away.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our opinion that we should not extend the mandate of the Russian peacekeeping force,&quot; he told national radio. &quot;At the same time, that does not mean we are raising the question of the withdrawal of the peacekeepers.&quot;</p>
<p>Ilychev, who is the Russian foreign ministry's special envoy to the Georgian-Abkhaz talks, said Moscow needed both Abkhazia and Georgia to agree to keep the troops in the buffer zone.</p>
<p>Shevardnadze, the former Soviet foreign minister, told reporters on Tuesday that the risk of renewed war in Abkhazia was &quot;too high&quot; if the peacekeepers were pulled out abruptly.</p>
<p>But he stressed that the mandate could not be extended because of a resolution passed by parliament earlier this year.</p>
<p>The seemingly ambiguous Georgian position reflects opposition in Tbilisi to be seen &quot;giving in&quot; to Moscow and at the same time fear that the country, with its fragile stability and weak economy, can ill afford new chaos and bloodshed.</p>
<p>Russian-Georgian relations have never fully recovered from Tbilisi's charges that Moscow gave the separatists much-needed military hardware and logistical support during the war.</p>
<p>Shevardnadze wants to put off deciding the fate of the force until a meeting of the CIS security council in September.</p>
<p>He travelled abroad this month lobbying for an international force to replace or complement the Russians. But categorical Abkhas opposition to the idea has left it a dead letter.</p>
<p>The Russian peacekeeping force commander told Reuters last week new fighting was probable if he and his men left the buffer zone, which they have patrolled since 1994.</p>
<p>That is the opinion shared by most observers in Georgia and Abkhazia, who say a Russian withdrawal would leave a dangerous vacuum. A Russian peacekeeper was killed overnight in the so-called &quot;security zone&quot;, Itar-Tass news agency reported.</p>
<p>Peace talks between the sides are deadlocked, with the separatists wanting more sovereignty than Tbilisi will tolerate.</p>
<p>Abkhazia was once the holiday haunt of the Soviet Union's communist elite but the war left much of it in ruins. A subsequent CIS-led partial blockade has devastated the economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GRGIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TBILISI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GEORGIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
