<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="765884" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia privatisation row first test for reformers.</title>
<headline>Russia privatisation row first test for reformers.</headline>
<byline>Anatoly Verbin</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The public scandal that has erupted in Russia over the privatisation of the Svyazinvest telecommunications giant is the first serious test for top reformers in the government. Its political fallout is still unclear.</p>
<p>In simple terms, the liberals have to prove who is the master in the house and defend their motto that cool economic reason comes ahead of backroom politicking.</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin has offered them only limited backing.</p>
<p>He had a choice on Wednesday when he met reformer-in-chief Anatoly Chubais at the Volzhsky Utyos residence where the 66-year-old Kremlin leader is spending his holiday.</p>
<p>He could have come out openly in support of Chubais and his fellow first deputy prime minister Boris Nemtsov in their defence of the sale in the face of a violent smear campaign in influential media controlled by the losing bidders.</p>
<p>Or Yeltsin, who looking for a successor in the year 2000, could have left them to fight their own battles against the losers, who until recently were the reformers' allies.</p>
<p>That would let Yeltsin judge their ability to cope with a crisis -- especially Nemtsov, the 37-year-old golden boy of Russian politics and clearly the president's latest favourite.</p>
<p>Typically, though, Yeltsin left his options open.</p>
<p>He made no public comment but allowed Chubais, 42, to tell reporters the president had approved of the way the cabinet had handled the sale. Chubais also made a peace offering to the Svyazinvest losers, saying other assets could come their way.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear if they would accept peace.</p>
<p>The row, especially the blistering condemnations of the sale and of Nemtsov on television and on the front pages, made clear that an alliance of rival magnates who united their money and media muscle to secure Yeltsin's re-election was at an end.</p>
<p>Insiders say the bankers' reward was privatised state assets at knock-down prices. But relations among them have worsened in several disputes over previous murky state auctions.</p>
<p>The government, desperate for cash to pay debts to workers and pensioners, changed tack and opted for auctions that brought in more money. The Svyazinvest auction was the first to produce a winning bid that market analysts said was reasonably fair.</p>
<p>The winner was a consortium built around Uneximbank. Russia's third biggest, it is headed by Vladimir Potanin, 36, a first deputy prime minister until March.</p>
<p>It was backed by several foreign entities, including Deutsche Morgan Grenfell (DMG), the London investment banking arm of Germany's Deutsche Bank, U.S. financier George Soros, and U.S. asset management group Morgan Stanley Asset Management.</p>
<p>They offered $1.875 billion against $1.71 billion offered by the other bidder. Participants in the losing consortium have not been officially named.</p>
<p>But Potanin and the Russian media have said they were Vladimir Gusinsky, founder of the Most financial and industrial group, and tycoon Boris Berezovsky, who has formally dropped his business roles to take up a Kremlin post.</p>
<p>Powerful media organisations controlled by the two men's business groups have launched a bitter attack on the Svyazinvest deal, saying it was a shadowy affair between state officials and financial magnates. Nemtsov came in for particular criticism.</p>
<p>A reliable source in Moscow's political elite said late on Tuesday that the government and some of the top bankers have started &quot;a big-scale fight with unpredictable consequences&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The fight will go on. If it grows into open confrontation, it may result in the destruction of one of the sides,&quot; said the source, who spoke on condition of anonymity.</p>
<p>The government was preparing counter-measures, he added.</p>
<p>Potanin told Interfax news agency he, Gusinsky and Berezovsky had flown last week to meet Chubais, who was on holiday abroad, to present their bids.</p>
<p>The source said Gusinsky and Berezovsky had tried to pressure Potanin to drop his bid. Chubais was saying the government needed as much money as it could get and the only criterion for the Svyazinvest tender would be the highest bid.</p>
<p>Chubais and Nemtsov appear to have defended their ground but the political fallout is far from clear.</p>
<p>If their peace offer on future sales is rejected, they can expect a new wave of attacks in which their rivals could reveal their inside knowledge of the murky world of Kremlin politics.</p>
<p>This is sure to delight the Communist opposition, which is still reeling from last year's presidential election defeat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
