<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="766094" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Cifra results suggest consumer returning.</title>
<headline>Cifra results suggest consumer returning.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Second quarter results from Mexican retail giant Cifra, if not spectacular, highlight the trend towards a rebound in domestic consumption, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The consumer recovery has been slow and that has been seen even more so in Cifra due to the geographical zone in which it operates,&quot; said Inverlat analyst Deyanira Becerril.</p>
<p>Cifra has a concentration of stores in the Mexican capital, which has been slower to recuperate from the 1994 peso devaluation and subsequent recession than the country's north.</p>
<p>But analysts were encouraged by the one percent growth Cifra registered in same store sales.</p>
<p>&quot;The one percent increase in same store sales is the first postive number reported since the devaluation and I expect positive numbers for the rest of the year,&quot; said ING Barings analyst Barry Taylor.</p>
<p>Cifra reported net sales in the second quarter of 6.19 million pesos, above the 5.97 million pesos in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Real growth in sales was 4.0 percent. Taking the inflation differential for the period into account, the increase was one percent.</p>
<p>However analysts say that between April and June the firm's operating margin was 3.8 percent -- slightly below average expectations of 4.5 percent recorded in a Reuter survey of three analysts.</p>
<p>But they said the results were mainly in line with expectations.</p>
<p>Although operating results were weaker than expected, Cifra's financial results were above expectations once interest from extraordinary gains was taken into account.</p>
<p>&quot;The only surprise was that they realised an extraordinary gain, which I was not expecting until the fourth quarter,&quot; said Merrill Lynch analyst Robert Ford.</p>
<p>Cifra said that in the second quarter it had liquidated part of its pension plan under plans to merge its subsidiaries with Wal Mart's Mexico stores, giving it a extraordinary gain of 887 million pesos.</p>
<p>Analysts say that its expansion plans should enable it to increase is sales by four or five percent over the next one to two years.</p>
<p>((--Karina Balderas, Mexico City newsroom +525 728 7905))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
