<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="766274" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: North Korea says &quot;unprecedented&quot; drought continues.</title>
<headline>North Korea says &quot;unprecedented&quot; drought continues.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Famine-hit North Korea said on Wednesday it was still suffering &quot;unprecedentedly high&quot; temperatures and no early relief was in sight from its devastating drought.</p>
<p>&quot;The drought from the high temperature is inflicting a serious damage on agriculture and other domains of the national economy,&quot; said the Stalinist nation's official Korean Central News Agency (KCNA).</p>
<p>&quot;Rain is not expected to come in some days so much as to ease the influence of the drought in the whole areas of (North) Korea,&quot; it said in an English-language report monitored in Tokyo.</p>
<p>It said that according to Ri Jong U, director of the Central Forecast Institute of the hydro-meteorological service, the maximum temperature at noon in July was over 35 degrees Celsius (95 Fahrenheit) in Pyongyang and some other areas, three to five degrees higher than usual. In some other areas, temperatures were more than 10 degrees above average.</p>
<p>The high temperatures, which have lasted for tens of days, have no precedent in 61 years of weather observation, KCNA said.</p>
<p>Hundreds of reservoirs had dried up as well as thousands of rivers and streams, it said, seriously affecting the growth of crops and supply of industrial water through irrigation networks.</p>
<p>North Korea, which has long proclaimed a policy of self-reliance, has been forced to plead for foreign aid to keep alive its 22 million population.</p>
<p>International aid agencies are also stepping up food appeals for Pyongyang, warning of imminent starvation, particularly among young children who are most at risk.</p>
<p>The Rome-based United Nations World Food Programme (WFP) launched a fresh appeal earlier this month for $46 million in food aid for the North on top of an earlier request for $95.5 million.</p>
<p>Washington responded quickly, agreeing to increase its 1997 WFP contribution to $52 million from $25 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
