<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="766309" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan money rates end sharply up on T$ slide.</title>
<headline>Taiwan money rates end sharply up on T$ slide.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's money rates closed sharply higher on Wednesday on widespread worries that the central bank may enter the market to support the depreciating Taiwan dollar, dealers said.</p>
<p>The overnight interbank rate finished at 7.236 percent against Tuesday's 6.859 percent close -- outside the central bank's 5.0-5.5 percent target zone but far below the record double-digit closes of late June.</p>
<p>The 30-day commercial paper rose to 7.35-7.50 percent against 7.25 percent.  </p>
<p>Despite the central bank's repeated vows to keep its hands off of Taiwan dollar trading, dealers in the money market remained concerned that the bank may buy the local currency to prevent the Taiwan dollar from sliding further.</p>
<p>The Taiwan dollar plunged further against the U.S. dollar on Wednesday, ending at its lowest level since 1988 on the greenback's persistent strength overseas and the central bank's lifting of a key defence on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The local unit, facing intense selling pressure all session long, closed at T$28.480 against Tuesday's already sharply depreciated T$28.170 finish.  </p>
<p>Recent big turnover in the red-hot bourse also intensified a flow of liquidity from the banking system, dealers said.</p>
<p>Taiwan's central bank on Wednesday issued T$3 billion in seven-day negotiable certificates of deposit at a single yield of 7.248 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers expected the money rates to remain at the current high levels on Thursday.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 10-year 86/4 bond yield was traded at 6.0975 percent, off its intraday high of 6.1400, against Tuesday's 6.0725.</p>
<p>-- James Lin, Taipei newsroom (8862-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
