<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76659" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Renault shares rally in late trade.</title>
<headline>Renault shares rally in late trade.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in carmaker Renault SA rallied in late trading on Wednesday after the company announced it would cut prices in France by up to five percent on some models to recapture lost market share.</p>
<p>&quot;The announcement of a more aggressive commercial policy may have triggered the rebound in the shares,&quot; which have been hammered recently, a trader said.</p>
<p>But some analysts said the marketing policy had been previewed at an analysts' meeting earlier this month. They said they suspected the rebound in the stock was technical as the share had been drifting near all-time lows.</p>
<p>&quot;Every dog has its day,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Renault shares were up 4.28 percent at 124.20 francs at 1400 GMT, while the market's CAC-40 index was 1.2 percent higher.</p>
<p>Renault said it would simplify its price range, lower prices for some cars and provide more equipment and options without charging extra on others.</p>
<p>&quot;The supplementary sales volumes generated by this ambitious new marketing policy will generate economies of scale to reinforce the cost-reduction programme announced in March,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Renault's stock had fallen recently on disappointing first-half results and a forecast for a full year loss.</p>
<p>Its share of the French car market has fallen to 26 percent in the first half of 1996 from 33 percent at the start of 1995.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
