<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="766544" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks hit new record, interest rates tumble.</title>
<headline>Stocks hit new record, interest rates tumble.</headline>
<byline>Wendy Pollack</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks surged to a new record Wednesday as optimism over the economy and the balanced budget pact drove bonds higher and pushed long-term interest rates to their lowest levels in nearly 18 months.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to a new 2-1/2-month high against the Japanese yen, and gasoline prices rallied to their highest level in six months.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average jumped 80.36 points to 8,254.89, the third consecutive record for the blue-chip average and its sixth new high in the last seven sessions.</p>
<p>Other major averages also set records, and rising issues swamped decliners on the New York Stock Exchange as the relatively narrow rally of recent sessions spread to the broader market.</p>
<p>The gains again came on the back of a strong advance in the bond market that pushed interest rates broadly lower.</p>
<p>&quot;What justifies this market is lower interest rates, and there's a real perception that we're looking at a long bond that could be headed to 6 percent,&quot; said Richard Cripps, chief market strategist at Legg Mason Wood Walker.</p>
<p>&quot;If you believe that, then its certainly possible to be bullish on stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>The long bond, the benchmark 30-year Treasury, rose 26/32, or $8.13 on a $1,000 bond, lowering its yield to 6.33 percent, the lowest since Feb. 16, 1996, from 6.39 percent Tuesday. Bond prices and yields move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>The euphoric atmosphere on Wall Street has come as investors have been treated to strong corporate earnings and falling interest rates, while inflation remains under control.</p>
<p>Americans continue to plough huge amounts of cash into mutual funds, most of them stock funds, creating demand for stocks and helping to fuel the rally.</p>
<p>According to the Investment Company Institute, which monitors fund activity, $19.91 billion flowed into mutual funds in June, and while that was down from $33.52 billion in May, it put total combined assets of the nation's mutual funds above $4 trillion for the first time.</p>
<p>The dollar edged higher vs. the yen Wednesday, aided by concern about a weak Japanese economy and fears of renewed tension in U.S.-Japan trade relations. The dollar settled at 118.41 yen, up from 118.35 yen late Tuesday.</p>
<p>At the New York Mercantile Exchange, worries over tightening inventories boosted gasoline for August delivery to 69.90 cents a gallon, up 3.43 cents a gallon and its highest settlement since January 10.</p>
<p>Overseas, Britain's FTSE 100 closed at 4,927.3, up 50.7 points, or 1.04 percent. Tokyo's 225-stock Nikkei average closed at 20,212.82, down 189.92 points, or 0.93 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
