<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="767012" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: INTERVIEW-S.Lanka mulls new oil refining capacity.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-S.Lanka mulls new oil refining capacity.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka is considering building another oil refinery or expanding its existing capacity to meet growing demand for oil products, the head of state oil firm Ceylon Petroleum Corp (CPC) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Anil Obeyesekere told Reuters a number of options were open to the Indian Ocean island, including importing more oil products, enlarging the country's existing 50,000-60,000 barrels per day refinery at Sapugaskanda near the capital Colombo, or building an entirely new plant.  </p>
<p>Funding for any new refinery or additional capacity might have to come from a joint venture or an overseas loan but stressed that all options were being considered and no decision had yet been made, he said.</p>
<p>He said Sri Lankan demand for some oil products, such as gas oil (diesel) and kerosene were outstripping current supply.</p>
<p>National gas oil demand was rising at about 10-15 percent a year and at current growth rates would be around 50 percent above 1996 levels by 2000, he said.</p>
<p>CPC figures show Sri Lanka imported just over 592,000 tonnes of gas oil last year in a series of spot tenders.  </p>
<p>Obeyesekere said gas oil imports were set to rise to around 691,000 tonnes this year and 720,000 in 1998.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka used to rely on hydro-electricity for most of its power needs but a series of droughts in recent years has made this an unreliable source of energy at times.</p>
<p>The droughts failed last year and led to lengthy power cuts of up to eight hours at a time, which hit industry and caused a sharp fall in agricultural production and economic growth.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have therefore to look at (the) options. One would be to enhance the refining capacity -- in other words upgrade the refinery -- and increase the production of diesel and kerosene or the other alternative will be to import these total quantities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeking the services of a consultant who will recommend what the best policy would be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Obeyesekere said an entirely new refinery would be likely to create an exportable surplus of some products such as gasoline and this might tip the scales against a new unit and towards upgrading CPC's existing refinery.  </p>
<p>&quot;So that is why we are thinking in terms of upgrading the existing refinery to produce more diesel and kerosene,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked how big a second refinery might be if it were built, Obeyesekere replied:</p>
<p>&quot;We have a present a 50,000 barrels per day refinery. Maybe about the same capacity. But that has to be thought out by some experts in the field.  </p>
<p>&quot;The problem of finance is very important to us. We can't afford the huge investment that would be required...Certainly I don't think we can generate so much funds. It is a very expensive item and so we would have to look at some sort of funding,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;As to whether it is in the form of a joint venture, or bank funding or ADB (Asian Development Bank) funding, or World Bank funding that has to be determined,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He declined to discuss the details of the potential cost of a new refinery or of extra refining capacity.  </p>
<p>Obeyesekere said CPC was considering expanding its oil refining capacity to cope with the higher demand for products, possibly by building an entirely new plant, and would soon rebuild oil storage tanks blown up by separatist guerrillas two years ago.</p>
<p>The Sri Lankan government is fighting a 14-year-old war with guerrillas of the Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE) who demand a homeland for the minority Tamil population in the island's north and east.  </p>
<p>An attack by LTTE rebels in October 1995 destroyed or badly damaged more than a dozen tanks at CPC's main oil storage complex just north of the capital Colombo, removing some 225,000 tonnes of storage capacity.</p>
<p>CPC's flexibility over oil imports has been badly eroded by the destruction of the tanks, leaving it reliant on a constant stream of buying tenders from the spot market.</p>
<p>But Obeyesekere said rebuilding the tanks would start in January 1998 and should be completed by November 1999.  </p>
<p>A total of 11 companies had been short-listed for the tender to rebuild the tanks, which is expected to be worth more than $50 million. Tenders would close on August 26, he said.</p>
<p>He declined to identify the short-listed companies but industry sources said they included firms from Japan, China, South Korea, Singapore and Italy.</p>
<p>He said Sri Lanka would employ a consultant to advise on the expansion of refining facilities which are currently limited to just one unit at Sapugaskanda, north of Colombo.</p>
<p>&quot;We have therefore to look at the options,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked how big a second refinery might be, Obeyesekere said:  </p>
<p>&quot;We have at present a 50,000 barrels-per-day refinery. Maybe about the same capacity. But that has to be thought out by some experts in the field.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Sri Lanka was leaving all its options open and had to adapt its oil industry to changes in the market.</p>
<p>CPC also had to consider pressure to use cleaner fuels containing less pollutants.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an environmental lobby here to get low sulphur content diesel into our country,&quot; he said. &quot;In the years to come maybe we will have to comply with this requirement...maybe in about a year or so.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
