<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="767186" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK mulls power liberalisation carrot, stick regime.</title>
<headline>UK mulls power liberalisation carrot, stick regime.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK electricity companies which fail to make adequate preparations in time for the planned liberalisation of the under 100 kilowatt market may be subjected to penalties, the UK government said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be...helpful to set incentives for those who have worked hard to deliver their systems on time and penalties for those who are late,&quot; it said in its response to a report on the industry from parliament's Trade and Industry Committee.  </p>
<p>The committee, in a report issued before the May 1 election, had suggested that industry regulator Stephen Littlechild should not hesitate to announce a short postponement of liberalisation if he judged it was needed.</p>
<p>In its response, the government said: &quot;Whether that proves necessary nearer the time will depend on the extent to which the parties are able to deliver robust systems on schedule.&quot;</p>
<p>But it added: &quot;The Department (of Trade and Industry) believes that the introduction of competition should not be determined by the speed of the slowest player.&quot;</p>
<p>Energy Minister John Battle has already met chief executives of the public electricity suppliers and the Electricity Pool to discuss issues surrounding the liberalisation such as the design, development and integration of systems.</p>
<p>The government said a further meeting would be held after the summer break.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 5427767</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
