<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="767348" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Newcrest Q4 gold production up 5.9 pct.</title>
<headline>Newcrest Q4 gold production up 5.9 pct.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold miner Newcrest Mining Ltd said on Wednesday group equity gold production for the three months ended June had increased 5.9 percent to 108,142 ounces from the previous quarter.</p>
<p>However, compared to the previous corresponding period production was 13.6 percent lower, the company said.  </p>
<p>Cost of production in the quarter fell 8.1 percent to A$475 an ounce.</p>
<p>Newcrest equity production for the year totalled 473,642 ounces, the vast bulk of it from its 100 percent owned Telfer operation in Western Australia which contributed 337,297 ounces for the year.</p>
<p>In May, Newcrest announced a restructuring of the Telfer operation after losses in production due to inclement weather, low grades and higher costs.</p>
<p>Total cost of production for the year was A$542 an ounce with sales for the year of 486,096 ounces.  </p>
<p>Hedging protection was increased to 5.2 million ounces from 3.2 milion ounces since the close of the quarter, Newcrest said, with the current year's production fully hedged at A$580 per ounce.</p>
<p>Newcrest said engineering at its Cadia project near Parkes in New South Wales was 80 percent complete, while construction was 14 percent complete. The project remained on budget and on track for commissioning in September 1998, it said.</p>
<p>By 3.25 p.m. (0525 GMT), Newcrest shares were a cent lower at A$2.79 on turnover of 266,823 shares.</p>
<p>--Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
