<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="767331" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: FOCUS-RBA says expect the unexpected from now on.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-RBA says expect the unexpected from now on.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Hickey</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>As if it wasn't hard enough already, the business of predicting what the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) will do to official interest rates became just that little bit tougher on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Until now, most economists and central bank-watchers believed the RBA would move interest rates either immediately after a key piece of data or immediately after the bank's monthly board meeting on the first Tuesday of the month.  </p>
<p>But the RBA's 0.5 percentage point cut in official cash interest rates on Wednesday has shattered that mould and the bank's own comments have ensured that from now on economists will nervously wonder if every day could be the day.</p>
<p>&quot;For many in the financial markets, most attention seems to be devoted to picking the exact day when a change in monetary policy will occur, something which would be made easier if the bank were to follow a rule such as changing monetary policy on the day following the board meeting,&quot; RBA Governor Ian Macfarlane said in statement announcing the rate cut.  </p>
<p>&quot;Despite its simplicity, this has never become standard practice because of its lack of flexibility; only eight of the 22 changes made since 1990 have occurred on the day following the board meeting,&quot; Macfarlane said.</p>
<p>Macfarlane is of course right about there being no set timing policy, but the impression created by the four previous rate cuts in this current economic cycle and under Macfarlane's leadership was that rate cuts and key data would be the triggers.</p>
<p>The first two rate cuts in this cycle were on the day after board meetings.  </p>
<p>The bank itself said in its February bulletin the third cut was delayed for a week after the meeting by exchange rate volatility, leaving the implication that the meeting was the basic trigger.</p>
<p>The fourth cut on May 23 this year came the day after wages data soothed concerns about increasing wages growth.</p>
<p>This mini-history ensured that last Friday the whole market was glued to its screens at 9.30 a.m. (2330 GMT) after wages data on the Thursday appeared to give the green light.</p>
<p>When nothing happened, most reset their rate-cut diaries for August 6, the day after the next board meeting.  </p>
<p>So the cut on Wednesday surprised many, despite the fact most expected a rate cut within weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing was certainly a surprise and is a clear signal that if the market tries to pick a day the bank will frustrate it,&quot; said Deutsche Morgan Grenfell ecnonomist Tony Meer.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a well warranted rate cut, but they still managed to pick a day that's confused everybody,&quot; said UBS Australia chief economist Stephen Roberts.</p>
<p>&quot;Forget about Reserve Bank board meetings from now on, it seems to be on significant pieces of data,&quot; Roberts said.  </p>
<p>But even that does not explain the timing of Wednesday's cut. The only variable some have picked out is the performance of the Australian dollar, which spiked higher late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very curious decision to say the least,&quot; said Bankers Trust senior economist David Bassanese.</p>
<p>&quot;There maybe be something in the Australia dollar story. The fact that it was strong overnight gave them the window of opportunity to move,&quot; Bassanese said.</p>
<p>It now appears the timing triggers are board meetings and key data combined with favourable exchange rate movements.  </p>
<p>Whatever the case, RBA-watchers cannot now stray too comfortably from their RBA announcement screens at 9.30 a.m. (2330 GMT) if there is even the remotest chance of a rate change.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
