<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="767362" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Macraes half yr net profit NZ$3.9 mln.</title>
<headline>Macraes half yr net profit NZ$3.9 mln.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Macraes Mining Co Ltd said on Wednesday that its half year result, due in a few days, would show a net profit of NZ$3.9 million and cash on hand of $25.7 million.</p>
<p>The gold miner confirmed deferral of a major expansion which would result in annual savings of $19 million because of reduced outlays on exploration, administration, operations and capital expenditure.</p>
<p>Some 66 jobs would be cut at the mine site near Dunedin, the project office at Reefton and at the company's headquarters in Perth.  </p>
<p>Macraes said the fall in the price of gold and delays in gaining all necessary local government approvals were blamed for the postponed expansion.</p>
<p>Projected expansion to 300,000 ounces a year &quot;remains an objective of the company&quot; despite the decision, managing director Patrick O'Connor said, together with investment in a recovery enhancement project to boost long-term gold recovery.</p>
<p>Exploration outlays would be reduced by $12 million, administration costs by $3 million and operations and capital expenditure by $4 million, Macraes said.  </p>
<p>A review of the carrying value of capitalised expenditure would be conducted in the current six months.</p>
<p>The company also issued a revised forecast for its full-year gold production, which it said would total 120,000 ounces at a cash cost of NZ$490 an ounce.</p>
<p>In the June quarter its gold production totalled 32,130 ounces at a cash cost of $487, and a gross operating margin of $238 an ounce.</p>
<p>Macraes said it had hedging available for 773,302 ounces of gold which had a net surplus value compared to market value of $66.87 million.  </p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
