<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="767553" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks decline slightly by lunch break.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks decline slightly by lunch break.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks fell slightly by the lunch break on Wednesday as investors sold and took profits while they waited for the country's key economic indicators to be released by the central bank on Thursday, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said turnover was thin as most investors also awaited the implementation of a new rule which would increase upper and lower trading limits to 30 percent from 10 percent starting from Friday.</p>
<p>The composite SET index slipped 1.93 points to 680.23 on 2.2 billion baht turnover by the lunch break.  </p>
<p>&quot;Foreigners were also not active this morning as they also waited to see if the new trading limits rule would have any impact on the market when it comes into force,&quot; said Padermpob Songkroh of Nava Finance.</p>
<p>Foreigners had been actively buying in the past few days. On Tuesday, their total net buying amounted to 2.5 billion baht.</p>
<p>Finance sector was the most active counter in terms of value, rising 1.05 percent.</p>
<p>Thai Farmers Bank topped the list, losing one baht to 119. -- Suthep Chawla (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
