<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="767665" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Yamaichi shares slide on news of raid.</title>
<headline>Yamaichi shares slide on news of raid.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Yamaichi Securities Co Ltd dropped in heavy trade on Wednesday morning, depressed by news that Tokyo prosecutors were raiding its headquarters over suspicions of its involvement in a &quot;sokaiya&quot; racketeer payoff scandal, traders said.</p>
<p>As of 0118 GMT, Yamaichi shares were down 23 yen, or 7.64 percent, at 278 yen, making it the second-sharpest percentage loser on the first section of the Tokyo bourse. The shares were ask-only in the early morning.</p>
<p>It was most heavily traded issue with a volume of 2.791 million shares.  </p>
<p>Tokyo prosecutors said on Wednesday they suspected Yamaichi paid 79 million yen to a &quot;sokaiya&quot; corporate racketeer.</p>
<p>They told a news conference that 200 investigators, including 50 from the securities watchdog, were raiding 10 offices of Yamaichi on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A Yamaichi spokesman said about 100 investigators went into its headquarters around 9 a.m. (0000 GMT).  </p>
<p>Other &quot;Big Four&quot; brokerages and the securities sector as a whole were also depressed by the news.</p>
<p>Nomura Securities Co Ltd  was down 10 yen at 1,570. Daiwa Securities Co Ltd had shed 33 yen to reach 832 yen and Nikko Securities Co Ltd had slipped 17 yen to stand at 674.</p>
<p>Brokerages were the top retreating sector, down 2.63 percent or 81.95 points at 3,034.33.</p>
<p>&quot;The planned announcement of punitive measures against Nomura and also the Yamaichi raid is dampening market mood, sending investors to the sidelines,&quot; a trader at a second-tier brokerage said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, as far as the market is concerned, blue chips are fairly firm and there is little fear of a plunge,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
