<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768087" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Kredietbank up on renewed merger talk.</title>
<headline>Kredietbank up on renewed merger talk.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Belgian Kredietbank NV rose more than two percent on the Brussels bourse Wednesday on renewed talk of merger plans with another Belgian bank, Cera, as a precursor to cooperation with Dutch Rabobank.</p>
<p>At 0830 GMT KB was up 300 francs, or 1.9 percent, at 16,100 francs after earlier touching 16,175.</p>
<p>&quot;(KB and Cera) are no longer denying the reports,&quot; one trader said. He said the market was expecting a full merger or close cooperation between the two Belgian banks.</p>
<p>There were doubts however about a partnership with Rabobank, he added.</p>
<p>One trader said the rumours of a deal with Cera, which erupted early June, had been virtually discounted in KB's share price and that upward potential was limited.</p>
<p>&quot;On the contrary, (KB) will slide if it would be called off,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>KB was at 14,850 francs when first reports of talks with Cera and Rabobank emerged. The Dutch co-operative bank has since said it could undertake a joint venture with KB and Cera but ruled out a merger with them.</p>
<p>Belgian financial daily L'Echo quoted the chairman of Belgian holding company Almanij, Jan Huyghebaert, as saying there was a certain logic to an alliance with Cera.</p>
<p>L'Echo quoted him as saying there would be no important announcements before September-October.</p>
<p>A Cera Bank spokesman had no comment on the reports.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear that we have thought of Cera, but there is no news to report, or no news that is ripe enough to be news,&quot; a KB spokesman was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>-- Bert Lauwers, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6815, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
