<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768114" id="root" date="1997-07-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Bunds seen keeping close in step with U.S..</title>
<headline>German Bunds seen keeping close in step with U.S..</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-07-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>German debt prices started Wedmesday's session in a lively mood, helped by a buoyant U.S. Treasury market and a continued pause in the recent sharp decline of the mark.</p>
<p>Analysts said the German market would remain heavily under the influence of the U.S. with a fresh bout of hard-hitting economic releases due from there at the end of the week.</p>
<p>At home, comments late on Tuesday from Bundesbank council member Hans-Juergen Koebnick did not ruffle too many feathers, but would ensure that investors kept a close eye on the mark if it were to resume its downward push, analysts said.  </p>
<p>Koebnick said the central bank must and would &quot;act very cautiously&quot; in the cae of a weak mark and a weak economy.</p>
<p>Some analysts said this was one of the clearest signs yet that the Bundesbank would consider interest rate action if the mark were to resume is rapid downward path.</p>
<p>&quot;Koebnick gave a clear signal that the central bank is considering a rate hike in case of further mark weakness,&quot; said Armin Kayser, economist at SBC Warburg in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>But he said that Koebnick had also made clear that the Budnesbank would not want a strong hike, but favour a measured move that would not harm the struggling economy.  </p>
<p>Analysts said Koebnick's remarks also suggested that the Bundesbank might decide to use a system of &quot;parallel tenders&quot;, with one fixed two-week repo running alongside a four-week variable rate.</p>
<p>This, they said, would ensure the Bundesbank could keep control of money market rates while at the same time banks were likely to push rates up slightly, potentially supporting the mark withough damaging the overall recovery.</p>
<p>For the moment, however, U.S. events were of more immediate concern on the trading floor, with the market looking ahead to second quarter GDP numbers on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters expect the U.S. economy to have slowed dramtically in the second three months of this year, growoing just 1.9 percent versus a rocking 5,9 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will be pretty sensitve to the GDP numbers, but overall I think we'll probably get confirmation that the U.S. economy has calmed down,&quot; said ane trader.</p>
<p>By 0849 GMT, the September DTB Bund future was trading 21 basis points higher at 103.35, while the 10-year benchmark Bund was at 103.17 for a bid yield of 5.496 percent.</p>
<p>--Kate Kelland, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
