<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76834" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sales of existing homes fell in August.</title>
<headline>Sales of existing homes fell in August.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sales of existing homes fell modestly in August, the National Association of Realtors said Wednesday, a third straight monthly decline as the housing market showed signs of leveling off.</p>
<p>The real estate lobby group said sales of existing, or used, homes fell 0.5 percent in August to a seasonally adjusted annual rate of 4.13 million. That followed a revised decline of 0.2 percent to 4.15 million in July and a sharper 2.8 percent drop in June sales.  </p>
<p>The falloff in August existing-home sales was not quite as sharp as forecast by Wall Street economists, who had forecast a drop in the sales rate to 4.09 million a year.</p>
<p>The real estate group revised up its estimate of July sales to an annual rate of 4.15 million instead of the 4.14 million it reported a month ago.</p>
<p>Despite three months of weakening business, sales of existing homes in August still were 2 percent higher than a year earlier in August 1995, when they were selling at a rate of 4.05 million a year.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, the falloff in sales last month occurred despite cheaper long-term mortgage rates that seemed to indicate some steam was going out of a robust housing market.</p>
<p>The Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corp., or Freddie Mac, said the average rate for a 30-year mortgage loan in August was 8 percent, down from July's 8.25 percent average and June's 8.32 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The nation's housing market is easing in for a soft landing,&quot; said John Tuccillo, chief economist for the National Association of Realtors. He added that after surging earlier this year, &quot;it's only natural that the market will correct itself.&quot;</p>
<p>Sales of existing homes peaked in May at a record annual rate of 4.28 million.</p>
<p>A waning housing market would fit with Federal Reserve policy-makers' evident belief that the overall economy os slowing. On Tuesday, the Fed decided against raising interest rates in the apparent hope that the economy was likely to cool off on its own and so keep inflation in check.</p>
<p>During August, sales of existing homes fell 9.5 percent in the Northeast to 570,000 a year while in the South, the nation's biggest regional housing market, they were down 1.9 percent to a rate of 1.53 million.</p>
<p>But in the Midwest, August sales edged up 0.9 percent to a rate of 1.07 million a year and in the West they increased strongly by 5.6 percent to 950,000 a year.</p>
<p>The average price for an existing home resold in August was $149,900, up slightly from $149,600 in July.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
