<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768368" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Index put buyers out in force.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Index put buyers out in force.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors were buying major U.S. stock index puts Thursday but some analysts said put buyers would not likely be rewarded by a falling market.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got some put buyers in our pit,&quot; said an S&amp;P 500 index .SPX options trader. &quot;They've been doing a three-way. Selling some out-of-the-money September calls and buying out-of-the-money put spreads.&quot;</p>
<p>In late trading, the SPX was up 3.88 at 956.27 and September S&amp;P 500 futures were up 3.85 at 961.  </p>
<p>The heaviest index option activity was in the SPX September 880 and 940 puts, which traded 11,285 and 11,520 contracts, respectively.</p>
<p>The SPX September 935 puts traded 5,650 and the September 995 calls traded 3,750 contracts.</p>
<p>In the August series, the 920 puts traded more than 7,900 contracts, the 940 puts traded about 6,165 and the 950 puts traded 2,625.  The August 980 calls traded nearly 9,600 contracs and the August 990 calls traded 5,920.</p>
<p>Overall SPX put volume beat call volume by 69,668 to 26,386 at 1400 CDT/1900 GMT.  </p>
<p>In the OEX, put volume also outpaced call volume, but at a slower pace.  Total OEX put volume was 32,537 compared with call volume of 29,162.</p>
<p>&quot;The naysayers, the doubters, they're all lined up,&quot; said Jerry Hegarty, an options analyst at Thomson Financial Services.  &quot;It's there in the put/call (ratios).  Everybody is in a state of disbelief.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he expected the market to rally sharply beginning Friday.  </p>
<p>Despite the gains in the S&amp;P 500 futures and broad market indexes, the bellwether Dow industrial average .DJI was lagging.  It was off 18 points at 8,236.</p>
<p>One S&amp;P 500 futures-options trader said the market appeared to be setting up for a decline and investors were wary of the market as it traded up against all-time highs.</p>
<p>He said the key for Friday, which is expected to be volatile in reaction to the July U.S. employment report that is scheduled for release before the market opens, will be bonds.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the employment report comes out worse than expected, you should see bonds tanking and that should open up the floodgates&quot; for stocks, the trader said.</p>
<p>Economists on average expect payroll employment to be up 193,000 compared with a rise of 217,000 in June.  Average hourly earnings are forecast to be up 0.2 percent after a 0.3 percent rise in June.</p>
<p>Traders said volatilities in index options held firm going into the jobs report.</p>
<p>The volatility index .VIX, a measure of front-month volatility in the OEX, was up 0.57, or 2.45 percent, at 23.97.</p>
<p>((Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
