<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76848" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French insurer Axa first-half profit leaps.</title>
<headline>French insurer Axa first-half profit leaps.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>French insurer Axa revealed a big surge in first-half profits on Wednesday, on the back of strong performance from non-life insurance.</p>
<p>It also said it was aiming for average annaul growth of more than 15 percent in earnings per share between 1995 and the year 2000 and that its medium-term target for return on equity was 15 percent.</p>
<p>Axa reported a net attributable profit of 1.98 billion francs ($388.7 million) for the first six months of 1996 compared to 1.30 billion francs in the first half of last year.</p>
<p>Chairman Claude Bebear told an analysts meeting where he presented the results that he expected a good second half but that it would &quot;be a bit optimistic&quot; to expect it to match the first half.</p>
<p>&quot;Grosso modo, the second half will be good,&quot; he said. But as far as matching the first-half performance, he said, &quot;we would like it to be so but I can't promise it, it would be even a little optimistic.&quot;</p>
<p>Axa said in a results statement non-life insurance profits nearly doubled to 610 million francs from 320 million and that another strong point was financial services, where the result leapt to 618 million francs from 397 million francs.</p>
<p>Group turnover, at 87.5 billion francs, rose 21.2 percent.</p>
<p>Life insurance, however, turned in a profit contribution of 504 million francs versus 555 million francs last time.</p>
<p>&quot;This evolution reflects the lower contribution of U.S. life insurance activities, the negative contribution of German activities and start-up costs related to the group's newly created Japanese life insurance company,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the U.S., life insurance activities contributed 197 million francs, down from 293 million francs in the first half of 1995,&quot; the group said.</p>
<p>&quot;This decline reflects a 72 million franc exceptional charge related to changes in accounting principles and an increase in valuation allowances on mortgage loans and real estate assets.&quot; ($ = 5.094 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
