<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76851" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Subic port winner's announcement angers Ramos.</title>
<headline>Subic port winner's announcement angers Ramos.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Fidel Ramos said on Wednesday that the Subic Bay board's selection of a Hong Kong company to develop the freeport was only a recommendation and angrily denounced people who announced it without his knowledge.</p>
<p>Ramos said he was informed of the decision by the Subic Bay Metropolitan (SBMA) picking Hong Kong's Hutchison Whampoa HK as the winning bidder on Wednesday, a day after it was released to the press.</p>
<p>&quot;A point I would like to make clear is that whoever are involved in this so called leak ... should really give some courtesy to the president of the Philippines,&quot; Ramos told his weekly news conference when asked about the SBMA announcement.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, an SBMA official said the board had upheld approval for Hutchison to develop and operate a container port in Subic following a re-evaluation of the bidding.</p>
<p>The SBMA, which runs the port at the former U.S. naval base north of Manila, said in a statement on Wednesday that the decision was subject to review by Ramos.</p>
<p>Ramos said the SBMA ruling was &quot;recommendatory.&quot;</p>
<p>Obviously miffed, Ramos said what he got on Wednesday morning was a copy of the Subic board's announcement.</p>
<p>&quot;Such a matter of such sensitivity and importance should have been hand carried by a responsible official, properly clasified as confidential and not just dispatched by hacks,&quot; the president said.</p>
<p>Ramos said he had called a meeting for Friday to discuss the SBMA decision and find out if there was a leak.</p>
<p>News offices first learned of the results of the SBMA re-evaluation on Tuesday evening in a faxed note. The release did not carry the usual Subic Bay news letterhead.</p>
<p>SBMA had initially awarded the contract to Hutchison, but it was challenged by losing bidder, Philippine port operator International Container Terminal Services (ICTSI).</p>
<p>SBMA rejected ICTSI's original bid on grounds that it would violate a law forbidding monopolies in the port industry. ICTSI operates the Manila International Container Terminal, which handles 70 percent of container traffic in the country.</p>
<p>Analysts are concerned that the row over the bidding coudl taint the country's privatisation process in the eyes of foreign investors, whoch have complained in the past that requirements were often changed after bids were opened.</p>
<p>Other government biddings which have become controversial are the privatisation of Camp John Hay, a former U.S. military recreation camp, and the sale of the historic Manila Bay Hotel to a Malaysian group, which was stopped by a rival bidder's complaint that a heritage building could not be sold to a foreigner.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
