<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768560" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Q DATA RISES ON THREE MLN RAND DOCTOR DEAL.</title>
<headline>Q DATA RISES ON THREE MLN RAND DOCTOR DEAL.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African information technology firm Q Data Ltd surged nearly eight percent in fairly active trade on Thursday after news the company had signed a deal with Interdoc worth at least three million rand, dealers said.</p>
<p>The share touched a day's high of 11 rand from a close of 990 cents but by 0940 GMT had retreated to 10.80 rand. It was the eighth highest percentage gainer on the Johannebsurg Stock Exchange and 209,300 shares had so far changed hands.</p>
<p>&quot;Q Data secured a deal to supply hardware and software to this company called Interdoc, which is basically links medical aids and doctors directly,&quot; one dealer told Reuters.</p>
<p>Q Data said the deal could be worth more than three million rand over time.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made that deal. It involves hardware and software equipment to Interdoc. On the basis that they have about 1,300 doctors on their books we've calculated the three million rand. Three million rand is definite but there could be more,&quot; said Q Data services director Tony Gill.</p>
<p>Dealers said the share was fuelled by growth opportunites in the healthcare and information technology sector.</p>
<p>&quot;It's running on the obvious growth opportunities in that sector. If successful this (deal) could lead to international opportunities. The euphoria about the information technology sector just keeps on going,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>But dealers said the share would probably not rise much further during the day.</p>
<p>Q Data is part of the Grinaker group and shares in associated electronic company Siltek Ltd also enjoyed buying on Thursday.</p>
<p>Dealers said Siltek was also rising on news of the Interdoc deal. Siltek touched a day's high of 22 rand from a close of 20.55 rand. By 0940 GMT it was trading at 21.30 rand.</p>
<p>-- Melanie Cheary, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
