<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768698" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW-Amvescap on acquisition lookout.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Amvescap on acquisition lookout.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gill</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fund management group Amvescap Plc said on Thursday it was on the lookout for acquisitions in a variety of regions, including Britain, although high valuations were a hindrance.</p>
<p>&quot;In the UK marketplace, we believe there is a real opportunity to have another critical player and we would like to be that, but unfortunately the price on the acquisitions has become pretty steep,&quot; Robert McCullough, Amvescap chief financial officer, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the group would be happy to add to its U.S. product portfolio with growth style, products to complement its traditional value style base, and would also look particularly at the Pacific region.</p>
<p>Growth style investing emphasises capital appreciation over dividend income, while value investment tends towards recovery stocks with a higher than average dividend yield.</p>
<p>But he said the group was not in negotiations at the moment.</p>
<p>McCullough was speaking after the release of the first interim results to report for the merged operations of Invesco Plc and the U.S. based AIM Management Group.</p>
<p>The group reported pre-tax profit of 73.5 million stg, well up on the 32 million from Invesco at the same time last year. Funds under management came in at $177.5 billion and the dividend was raised 25 percent to 2.5 pence.</p>
<p>He said earnings were well ahead even if AIM figures are excluded, reflected in a 20 percent rise in earnings per share.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets have been quite kind to us,&quot; he said, but added that a large portion of the improvement was due to improved operating profits and income from all business groups.</p>
<p>He said Amvescap was on target to reach a 35 percent operating margin in 1997, coming in at 34.8 percent at the half year stage.</p>
<p>Amvescap brought in net new business of $5 billion in the six month period, and gained another $15.6 billion through market gains.</p>
<p>McCullough said net new business gains were reported in all but the U.S. institutional business, where clients were moving out of its core value equity products into passively managed or speciality products.</p>
<p>The U.S. institutional group saw net redemptions of some $2.9 billion in the first half, almost all of it coming from large state retirement plans moving to index investing.</p>
<p>&quot;No-one likes to lose the assets and we would like to see that changing as well, but the important point is the fees are very low by comparison with the new business fees.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the fee range for first half new business was 45-50 basis points and the average for the lost business was less than 20bp.</p>
<p>He said the group was not planning to move to passive investing.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel that our business is as active managers and the fees on passive are really so low that it is hard to make a go of it.&quot;</p>
<p>McCullough said the stronger sterling exchange rate had a negative 5.8 million stg effect on operating profit.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +171 542 5887</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
