<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768741" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya says tackling graft, IMF demands political move.</title>
<headline>Kenya says tackling graft, IMF demands political move.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya sought on Thursday more time to meet International Monetary Fund demands to combat corruption or lose a key aid package but said much of what the IMF wanted was political.</p>
<p>The IMF demanded last month Kenya take action by Thursday to show its commitment to fight corruption and reform the energy sector or it would let a three-year aid package worth $205 million lapse.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Musalia Mudavadi said Kenya had asked the IMF to extend the deadline and was waiting for an answer. &quot;I am crossing my fingers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in the middle of consultations. We are still talking with (IMF headquarters in) Washington,&quot; said the minister, adding that negotiations on the aid package had not collapsed.</p>
<p>In Washington, an IMF spokesman said the Fund was considering the Kenyan request.</p>
<p>Fares Kuindwa, head of the civil service and secretary to the cabinet, later told a news conference that 90 percent of what was demanded by the IMF to continue with the aid package was political and its language could &quot;be a lot more diplomatic&quot;.</p>
<p>Kenya's opposition says corruption extends to the highest levels of government and this is why President Daniel arap Moi's government has failed to fulfill promises to combat all sleaze.</p>
<p>Kuindwa said Moi received a letter from the IMF on Tuesday with a reply expected on Wednesday and the president replied on Thursday. &quot;For a sovereign nation, the timing is rather intriguing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He criticised the letter to the president, saying it would have better been addressed to the finance minister. &quot;The issues raised (by the IMF) are 90 percent political,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said Kenya was committed to cutting corruption and wanted to resolve in court the Goldenberg scandal in which about $100 million was paid to a company in compensation for gold and diamond exports. Kenya produces little gold and has no diamonds.</p>
<p>Kuindwa listed other corruption-related cases and said they were being tackled and the government did not condone graft.</p>
<p>The shilling fell against the dollar and pound on Thursday because of market uncertainty ahead of the IMF decision. It weakened to 58.92 to the dollar from Wednesday's 58.06.</p>
<p>The IMF extended a three-year Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility (ESAF) loan worth $205 million in April last year but payments were conditional on Kenya meeting promises on reform.</p>
<p>The last scheduled ESAF payment, $36 million, was delayed by the IMF for a month from June 30, mainly because of its concern at the way Kenyan authorities had handled the Goldenberg scandal.</p>
<p>The IMF had demanded the government &quot;take decisive steps to ensure transparency and accountability in the use of public funds and to resolve outstanding energy sector reform&quot;.</p>
<p>Mudavadi said losing the ESAF would be a big blow to Kenya, where Moi, 73, the country's ruler for 19 years, seeks re-election this year in the face of opposition demands for political reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;This could have serious repercussions. It could dent investor confidence, affect the shilling, affect inflation and it is something that could shake confidence in the economy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added the government was drafting a bill to combat corruption but this was not enough to meet the IMF demands.</p>
<p>The IMF has quoted Goldenberg International to illustrate how Kenyan authorities were reluctant to punish corruption.</p>
<p>The IMF delayed releasing the $36 million ESAF tranche after the high court decided on June 20 to end the prosecution of a businessman and former officials implicated in the scandal.</p>
<p>The businessman and former officials have been charged again. ($1=58.9 Kenyan Shillings)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
