<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768739" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC: France to shut key military base in Central Africa.</title>
<headline>France to shut key military base in Central Africa.</headline>
<byline>Gaby Mepoka</byline>
<dateline>BANGUI 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>France is to close down a key military base in the north of the Central African Republic and to wind down a second in the capital, Central African television reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>The state television said the closure of the Bouar base was announced by French Defence Minister Alain Richard during a meeting with President Ange-Felix Patasse in Bangui.</p>
<p>&quot;For budgetary and professional reasons, the French government has decided to reduce its garrisons in Africa and notably to close the Bouar military base,&quot; Richard said.</p>
<p>&quot;As for the base situated in Bangui, a progressive withdrawal of personnel is planned,&quot; Richard said without giving a timeframe for either move. The two bases have a total of about 1,200 troops backed by warplanes.</p>
<p>The televison said Richard gave an assurance that France would &quot;listen attentively&quot; to any pleas for help from Patasse, who was protected by French troops during a series of revolts by his army in the past year.</p>
<p>France would also maintain material and logistical support for an African force that has taken over policing of the capital from French troops following accords last February ending the latest army mutiny.</p>
<p>Richard was wrapping up visits to Gabon, Chad and the Central African Republic, where France has troops under accords with its former African colonies dating back to the 1960s.</p>
<p>The new Socialist government in Paris has announced its intention to reduce France's military presence in Africa, which</p>
<p>Richard embarked on the tour to explain the new French policy, which has provoked fears in conservative French circles of opening the door to wider U.S. influence in Africa.</p>
<p>Apart from other considerations, the cuts underline a belief that Africa needs less policing after the end of the Cold War.</p>
<p>New Socialist Prime Minister Lionel Jospin's government plans to cut the number of French troops in Africa by about 40 percent to 5,000 from 8,350, French government sources said.</p>
<p>But Richard said at his earlier stops that France would leave its 800-strong garrison in the Chad capital N'Djamena untouched and would upgrade facilities at its base in Gabon.</p>
<p>The N'Djamena base was bolstered when French troops backed Chad during its conflict with Libya in the 1980s. Bases in Central African Republic have played a frontline role in France's numerous interventions in its former African colonies.</p>
<p>France also has much larger bases, including naval units, in Djibouti at the mouth of the Red Sea and in the Indian Ocean.</p>
<p>The cutbacks come at a time Paris has suffered a string of setbacks in Africa, culminating in the overthrow of long-term ally president Mobutu Sese Seko this year in what was Zaire by Laurent Kabila's forces.</p>
<p>Before a left-wing victory in France's June 1 election, Jospin said the former government's support for Mobutu sealed &quot;the bankruptcy of France's Africa policy&quot; under conservative President Jacques Chirac.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGUI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
