<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768863" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania central bank says lek reccvery unwarranted.</title>
<headline>Albania central bank says lek reccvery unwarranted.</headline>
<byline>Llazar Semini</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's central bank governor Qamil Tusha said on Thursday psychological rather than economic factors were behind an abrupt strengthening of the national currency, the lek.</p>
<p>The lek firmed to 139 to the dollar in Tirana's informal open-air street market on Thursday, considerably stronger than the 170 level traded at the end of last week. It was at 100 to the dollar at the start of the year before the collapse of pyramid investment schemes triggered steep falls.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say this lek evaluation is a psychological factor... an exagerated movement which has no economic basis,&quot; Tusha told a news conference.</p>
<p>Tusha said the central bank would intervene to keep the currency at an acceptable level, which he said was at around 150 leks to the dollar at the moment.</p>
<p>&quot;In such instances, when the figures do not justify the lek's strengthening, the central bank intervenes to stabilise it at acceptable levels so that we do not have frequent or strong oscillation within a day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sentiment for the currency has improved since the new socialist government won a general election last month. Prime Minister Fatos Nano said on Monday his leftist coalition government would move quickly to restore order, and pledged to compensate Albanians who lost their savings in pyramid investment schemes.</p>
<p>But Tusha said the lek's rise was in no way warranted by Albania's economic fundamentals.</p>
<p>Inflation was forecast to hit 50 percent by year-end compared with 17.4 percent last year, while money supply had increased by around 60 percent so far this year, he said.</p>
<p>At the same time, Albania's budget and trade deficits were gaping, with the budget shortfall at 25.6 billion leks and the trade deficit at 149 million for the first seven months of 1997, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This pressure on the current accounts influences the lek,&quot; Tusha said.</p>
<p>Albania's Savings Bank was quoting 150 leks to the dollar early in the day, but said it planned to adjust the level.</p>
<p>&quot;This (currency rise) is mainly a psychological effect,&quot; a bank dealer said. &quot;There are no economic factors to justify it.&quot;</p>
<p>Tusha said the central bank had tried to keep the lek under control this year by limiting bank cash transfers. It had also raised interest rates and shortened the borrowing time for credits.</p>
<p>Albania would compile programmes to stabilise its economy with help from international institutions, mainly the International Monetary Fund, he said.</p>
<p>The IMF said on Wednesday it would help the new government restore its shattered economy and deal with the pyramid savings scandal which toppled its predecessor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
