<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768850" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatia's Privredna Banka signs for DM150 mln loan.</title>
<headline>Croatia's Privredna Banka signs for DM150 mln loan.</headline>
<byline>Kolumbina Bencevic</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatia's Privredna Banka Zagreb signed up on Thursday for a 150 million German mark ($81.7 million) syndicated loan, arranged by Deutsche Bank AG and underwritten by 15 other leading international banks.</p>
<p>The loan marks renewed trust of foreign creditors in the country's once leading commercial bank, which almost sank under the weight of its borrowers' unpaid debts, representative of the lead manager told a celebratory gathering.</p>
<p>However, they remained elusive about the price Privredna will pay on its first large borrowing since the government launched a massive operation to salvage it late in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very good rate,&quot; said Peter Mils of Deutsche Bank.</p>
<p>Privredna's chief executive Ivan Tesija told Reuters the margin over Libor was &quot;lower than that paid by the government&quot;.</p>
<p>Tesija referred to a debut two-year sovereign credit of 300 million marks, raised at 1.75 percentage points over Libor in October last year. Privredna's loan is for a total of eight years, including a three-year grace period.</p>
<p>He also compared the price to that charged by foreign banks to Zagrebacka Banka for its three-year loan in marks with a benchmark 50 basis point margin.</p>
<p>&quot;Terms are not exactly the same but are not far off,&quot; Tesija added.</p>
<p>The funds will be channelled into financing of profitable projects of Privredna's clients, including the Adriatic pipeline operator Janaf, oil company INA and other utilities.</p>
<p>Among its clients are also the troubled state railways, ironworks and a large portion of the wood-processing industry.</p>
<p>The bank used to service some 70 percent of the public sector, but has greatly reduced its lending to the ailing firms as part of the rehabilitation process.</p>
<p>The government wrote off its uncollected debts, most of which dated back to the former Yugoslav era when the country borrowed heavily abroad. It also partly recapitalised the bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Privredna Banka will now press on with further personnel and technological restructuring and will also adjust its business strategy,&quot; Tesija said.</p>
<p>He mentioned plans to establish new products and improve the quality of banking services in a bid to revert to profit.</p>
<p>The bank ended last year with a 1.1 billion kuna ($168.4 million) net loss, reflecting writeoffs and increased risk provisions. Its balance sheet was reduced by 20.2 percent to 14.875 billion kuna. ($ = 1.835 German Marks) ($ = 6.533 Croatian Kuna)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
