<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768908" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish lower house adopts controversial tax bill.</title>
<headline>Polish lower house adopts controversial tax bill.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish legislators on Thursday adopted a bill standardising all taxes to eliminate legal loopholes and curb tax evasion, which includes a controversial clause obliging the better-off to declare their wealth.</p>
<p>The bill, known as the tax ordination, does not determine tax levels, but provides a unifying legal basis for all taxes, which the government says should bring Poland's law to European Union standards. </p>
<p>Under the bill, passed by the lower house of parliament, an adult who has more than 500,000 zlotys in assets, securities or cash will have to declare them each year to enable the tax office to determine whether taxes have been paid properly.</p>
<p>The bill's critics, mainly business groups and some opposition parties, say it would give the state too much power over citizens and did not include enough measures preventing officials from abusing it. </p>
<p>The bill, which still has to clear the senate and be signed by President Aleksander Kwasniewski, would in some cases give tax inspectors powers to examine people's accounts at banks, brokerages and investment funds.</p>
<p>The bill, which will take effect next year unless the Senate fails to pass it before parliamentary polls on September 21, would allow the Finance Ministry to speed up tax deductions or reimbursements. -- Marcin Grajewski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
