<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="768933" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian parliament approves post-communist crest.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian parliament approves post-communist crest.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's parliament on Thursday approved a new national crest after seven years of political wrangling, substituting a crown for the communist red star which previously sat above a lion.</p>
<p>Immediately after the vote, President Petar Stoyanov went from parliament to hang the coat of arms over the main entrance to the presidency. A military band played the national anthem and passers-by applauded.</p>
<p>The design has a lion on a red shield, flanked by two more lions, with a crown above it and a motto underneath reading &quot;unity is strength&quot;. Parliament approved the crest with 177 votes in favour, 16 against and 29 abstentions.</p>
<p>Stoyanov praised parliament for &quot;fulfilling the expectations of a large part of Bulgarian society -- the expectation to crystallise Bulgarian national dignity and Bulgarian tradition in a Bulgarian coat of arms&quot;.</p>
<p>The president, who took office in January, negotiated a consensus between the political parties on the design.</p>
<p>It includes the crown of 14th century monarch Ivan Shishman of the Second Bulgarian Kingdom, rather than the Saxe-Coburg crown of exiled king Simeon's dynasty, which formed part of the pre-communist coat of arms.</p>
<p>The Union of National Salvation, formed by ethnic Turks and monarchists, insists on restoration of the pre-communist coat of arms of the Third Kingdom which lasted until 1947.</p>
<p>Last July, the former Socialist-dominated parliament approved an uncrowned lion as the country's official post-communist emblem.</p>
<p>Opposition parties boycotted that vote because they wanted the lion to have a crown, and former president Zhelyu Zhelev vetoed the design, saying it was divisive and lacked broad national support.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has been without an official coat of arms since it began removing the communist era hammer and sickle and red star from public buildings after the collapse of Todor Zhivkov's regime in 1989.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
