<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76908" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NatWest Bank securitises loans, frees capital.</title>
<headline>NatWest Bank securitises loans, frees capital.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's National Westminster Bank Plc on Wednesday announced it would securitise $5.0 billion of its corporate loans, boosting its capital base by around 200 million pounds ($312 million).</p>
<p>NatWest said it would package the loans and issue asset-backed floating rate notes and commercial paper in the Eurobond market.</p>
<p>&quot;This transaction is a significant step in removing low-margin assets from the balance sheet,&quot; said NatWest chief executive Derek Wanless.</p>
<p>The move immediately raised the question of what NatWest was planning to do with the extra capital since it already has more than adequate capital ratios and these would be further raised.</p>
<p>The bank is known to want to boost its capacity to sell retail financial products in the UK, possibly through the purchase of a building society but has said in the past that it has not found any acquisitions which meet its criteria. In the absence of acquisitions, NatWest in July announced a 450 million pounds share repurchase programme which, it said, was in line with its policy of returning value to shareholders.</p>
<p>Corporate loans have carried notoriously low margings in recent years with some banks withdrawing to a large extent from this type of business. ($1=.6420 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
