<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769163" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: S&amp;P sees better Australasian dairy credit quality.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P sees better Australasian dairy credit quality.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australasian diary companies have posted improved credit quality due to mergers and acquisitions, regulatory changes and export growth, ratings agency Standard and Poor's said on Friday.</p>
<p>S&amp;P associate director Brenda Wardlaw said recent mergers and acquisitions in particular had led to efficiency gains through rationalisation of processing plants.</p>
<p>&quot;Rationalisation has also increased as a result of changes in the share structure of the New Zealand Dairy Board, progressive deregulation of the liquid milk market in Australia, and increased milk supply in both countries,&quot; Wardlaw said.  </p>
<p>Export growth opportunities from increased access to key markets and subsidy cuts in the European Union and other producers countries were also positive.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said total world consumption of dairy products was forecast to rise at one-to-two percent a year for the next five years, but growth rates in the Asian region were expected to be much higher.</p>
<p>The traditionally sound credit quality of Australasian dairy companies reflected the global cost competitiveness of the Australian and New Zealand dairy industries, and the system of paying creditors in supplier-owned companies.  </p>
<p>Australia's two listed dairy companies are National Foods Ltd and QUF Industries Ltd.</p>
<p>Supplier owned companies are Bonlac Foods Ltd, Murray Goulburn Co-operative Ltd and Australian Co-Operative Foods Ltd (ACF),</p>
<p>In New Zealandm recent mergers have led to two companies accounting for more than 74 percent of the processed milk market -- New Zealand Co-Operative Dairy Co Ltd and Kiwi Co-operative Dairies Ltd.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
