<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769218" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: FOCUS - Big Thai June reserves figures a surprise.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Big Thai June reserves figures a surprise.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand on Thursday surprised financial markets with higher-than-expected foreign reserves and improved balance of payments data but analysts were disappointed over sustained weak exports and private investment.</p>
<p>A central bank chief economist tipped more gloom in the months ahead for the frail economy.</p>
<p>Analysts said Bank of Thailand figures showing end-June foreign reserves of $32.4 billion, a 25-month low, were more than market projections of $24-31 billion and against $33.3 billion in May.</p>
<p>&quot;The reserves figure defied our bearish forecast. It showed that although the economy is going through a rough time, the situation was not as bad as we had feared,&quot; said Kulthida Malakul of Chao Phaya Finance and Securities Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected the reserves to fall sharply on capital outflows and central bank intervention in defence of the shaky baht in May when the reserves fell by $4 billion.</p>
<p>Central bank chief economist Kleo-thong Hetrakul said the June balance of payments deficit narrowed to a moderate 22.8 billion baht from an exceptionally high 112.3 billion in May when foreign currency reserves were used to defend the baht.</p>
<p>Most analysts had predicted a June deficit of about 60 billion baht, partly due to a decline in non-resident bank deposits.</p>
<p>But the central bank economist also said uncertainties over the baht's value, the outlook for the troubled financial sector and high interest rates could dampen the economy.</p>
<p>The baht has lost 20 percent of its value since its de facto devaluation on July 2.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in the transition period and going through uncertainties, including adjustment in the financial sector, the new foreign exchange system, and tight liquidity which has pushed up interest rates. The downturn is expected to continue into the second half of 1997,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Kanchit Assavasamrarn of Vickers Ballas Co Pte Ltd said the market was disappointed by sluggish 0.8 percent year-on-year export growth in May, the latest figure available, against a 2.5-3.3 percent rise expected by the market and a 5.3 percent increase a month earlier.</p>
<p>The central bank said exports increased only two percent year-on-year during the first five months against 7.2 percent growth it projected for the whole of 1997.</p>
<p>Thai stocks did not react to the better than expected foreign reserves data. The composite SET Index closed down 13.91 points or 2.05 percent to 665.62 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Irene Cheung, economist at Merrill Lynch in Singapore, said she expected exports to post a modest recovery in the third quarter helped by a weaker baht.</p>
<p>Kleo-thong said the May trade deficit narrowed to 16.8 billion baht from 41.0 billion the previous month, largely because of a 10.2 percent year-on-year decline in imports.</p>
<p>Vuth Puthamon of Multi-Credit Corp of Thailand Plc said he detected signs that the central bank may have injected baht funds into the economy for the second consecutive month in June when the Thai money base surged 29.9 percent year-on-year despite smaller foreign reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;The reserve and money base figures contradicted each other, prompting some people to assume that the central bank may have printed more new bank notes than it should have. The market believed the authorities must have injected a lot of money into ailing finance companies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts partly attributed a 14.2 percent year-on-year rise in the June M-2 money supply to a heavy shift of public deposits from shaky finance firms to commercial banks.</p>
<p>Outstanding bank deposits rose 15.5 percent year-on-year in June against 11.8 percent a month earlier but against 18.1 percent growth a year ago.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) is this week holding talks with Thai officials on an austerity package to help the country overcome its worst economic crisis in over a decade.</p>
<p>Analysts said the IMF, as a condition for providing aid to Thailand, would likely ask the government to stop using tax payers' money to bail out troubled financial institutions.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Thanong Bidaya is set to announce an economic rehabilitation package by August 5. Analysts said the biggest question mark in the package was whether it would include details of IMF assistance and loans.</p>
<p>($1 = 31 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
