<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769221" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China B shares end easier in shadow of Hong Kong.</title>
<headline>China B shares end easier in shadow of Hong Kong.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's B shares for foreigners closed easier on Thursday as investors kept to the sidelines or switched funds to the red-hot Hong Kong market, brokers said.</p>
<p>B shares lost ground on both the big bourse in Shanghai and the southern exchange in Shenzhen while A stocks for domestic investors were mixed.</p>
<p>The Shanghai B index edged down a negligible 0.028 point to 72.903 as turnover shrank to $3.931 million from $4.330 million on Wednesday. In Shenzhen, the B share index slipped 0.44 point to 129.60.</p>
<p>&quot;As major investors were sidelined, trading was very sluggish despite some bargain-hunting,&quot; said a broker.</p>
<p>The listless trade failed to gain a lift from news that economic tsar Zhu Rongji had urged lumbering state firms to look to the share market as a means to raise capital rather than relying on bank credits.</p>
<p>&quot;The positive news failed to activate the B share market, as major investors are trading in Hong Kong,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index powered 2.39 percent higher to another record close, reaching 16,365.71 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Shanghai Huili Building Materials was the biggest loser on expectations it will report disappointing interim profits. It shed $0.020 or 9.52 percent to $0.190 on volume of 332,000 shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai Refrigerator Compressor was the most active issue, rebounding from recent losses. It gained $0.010 or 2.57 percent to $0.398 on volume of 921,300 shares.</p>
<p>In Shenzhen, Jiangling Motors absorbed the biggest loss as it slid HK$0.19 or 6.88 percent to HK$2.57 in thin trade.</p>
<p>Shanghai's A share index extended its recent upward climb on active buying of a handful of companies. It gained 11.122 points or 0.90 percent to 1,245.578.</p>
<p>Yizheng Chemical Fibre surged 0.28 yuan or 5.97 percent to 4.97 yuan. Brokers linked the rise to rumours the company would merge with another manufacturer or announce a restructuring but an Yizheng spokesman said there was no such plan.</p>
<p>Yizheng also has shares listed in Hong Kong and those shares were suspended from trading pending an announcement.</p>
<p>In Shenzhen, the A share index lost 0.23 point to 407.49, pressured by light profit-taking.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
<p>($1 = HK$7.8)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
