<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769230" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan money rates end up on stock rise, T$ slide.</title>
<headline>Taiwan money rates end up on stock rise, T$ slide.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's money rates closed higher on Thursday amid tightening liquidity due to a sizzling stock market and sliding Taiwan dollar, dealers said.</p>
<p>The overnight interbank rate closed at 7.455 percent against Wednesday's 7.236 finish -- outside the central bank's 5.0-5.5 percent target zone but far below the record double-digit closes of late June.</p>
<p>The 30-day commercial paper was stable at 7.50 against 7.35-7.50.  </p>
<p>Despite the central bank's vows to keep its hands off Taiwan dollar trading, dealers in the money market remained concerned that the bank may buy the local currency to prevent it from falling further, thus tightening banking system's liquidity.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Sheu Yuan-dong said after a board meeting on Thursday that the bank would let market forces dictate the exchange rate unless there were &quot;abnormal, speculative&quot; factors.</p>
<p>The Taiwan dollar on Thursday plunged for the third straight session, closing at T$28.70 to set its lowest level since 1988.  </p>
<p>Recently red-hot stock market also has intensified a flow of liquidity from the banking system, dealers said.</p>
<p>The index, boosted by rallies on Wall Street and in Hong Kong, finished with a gain of 123.56 points or 1.24 percent to 10,066.35, its highest level since it registered 10,907.09 close on April 4, 1990.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rates would continue to face appreciation pressure on Friday following the central bank's decision to raise two key interest rates and slightly tighten its monetary policy.  </p>
<p>In the bond market, the 86/4 bond yield fell to 6.0725 against 6.0975.</p>
<p>-- James Lin, Taipei newsroom (8862-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
