<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769266" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan files for oil spill clean-up compensation.</title>
<headline>Japan files for oil spill clean-up compensation.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan has filed claims totalling 840 million yen ($7.11 million) to cover the cost of a clean-up operation after a Russian tanker sank causing a massive oil spill in northwestern Japan, officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The 13,157-tonne Russian tanker Nakhodka, which was carrying about 19,000 tonnes of heavy fuel oil, broke in half in the Sea of Japan in January. About 5,200 tonnes of fuel oil washed up on beaches and threatened prized fishing grounds.</p>
<p>Officials said the claims were filed by Japan's Maritime Safety Agency and the Transport Ministry to cover the cost of fuel used by boats and planes in the clean-up operation, cleaning solution and other items.</p>
<p>They were filed with the International Oil Pollution Compensation Fund (IOPCF) and the UK P&amp;I Club, officials said.</p>
<p>IOPCF is funded by oil companies and tanker owners, while the UK P&amp;I Club is the insurer of Nakhodka.</p>
<p>A Maritime Safety Agency official said the claims were the first to be filed by the central government, but that other government agencies were likely to make additional claims.</p>
<p>The private sector has filed separate claims.</p>
<p>Japanese and Russian authorities have been unable to agree on the cause of the tanker accident.</p>
<p>Russian Transport Minister Nikolai Tsakh said in February that Moscow believes &quot;an external cause&quot; is to blame for the huge ship breaking in two, reiterating the conclusion of a Russian commission which determined that the tanker had been in good condition but split up and sank after hitting a half-submerged ship in heavy seas.</p>
<p>However, a Japanese Transport Ministry panel on Thursday blamed the accident on the age of the tanker.</p>
<p>The ship went into service more than 25 years ago.</p>
<p>($1=118 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
