<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769257" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China wool taste seen leaning to finer quality.</title>
<headline>China wool taste seen leaning to finer quality.</headline>
<byline>Mishi Saran</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's demand for imported wool had dropped in the first half of this year and consumer tastes were increasingly leaning towards the finer quality wool used for apparel, traders and analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>China's total wool imports in the first half of 1997 had dropped to 85,585 tonnes, down 20 percent from its imports in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>It imported 46,609 tonnes of Australian wool in January to June this year, down 18 percent from the 57,155 tonnes imported in the same period last year.</p>
<p>The figures have been converted to clean weight by IWS International Pty Ltd from data supplied by Chinese customs.</p>
<p>In comparison, China imported about 13,840 tonnes of wool from New Zealand in the first half of 1997, down 52 percent from the 28,960 tonnes imported in the first half of last year.</p>
<p>Reasons for the drop in Chinese wool imports in the first half were complex, but the imports had felt the impact of rising world prices, said Martin Szeto, manager of planning at IWS International Pty Ltd.</p>
<p>The eastern market indicator had moved up to 722 cents, about 100 cents higher than its level of three months ago, making up ground lost when the overheated market plunged 47 cents in the last week of June.</p>
<p>Chinese consumers tastes have also been changing, turning toward finer quality wools.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the past three years, Chinese consumers, particularly in Shanghai, are increasingly demanding quality knitwear that's made of finer and lighter wool they can wear next to the skin,&quot; said Szeto.</p>
<p>Although fine wool was available in China, there was no replacement for the quality wool produced in Australia, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The proportion of fine wool imported by China over the years has definitely increased,&quot; a Chinese trader said. Australian Marino wool, with fibres of between 18.5 and 21 microns in diametre, was very popular, Szeto said.</p>
<p>In comparison, New Zealand wool supplied slightly coarser products for a different market sector, he said. Despite somewhat bearish import figures, wool traders in Hong Kong agreed that China would continue to be an important wool consumer, but they stopped short of offering total import figures for the year.</p>
<p>According to Tony Wilson, director of Australia's biggest exporter Itochu Australia, China was expected to be in the market for 1.2 million bales, up around 100,000 bales on the last season. -- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100124">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
