<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769278" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Currency impact on Indonesian economy seen muted.</title>
<headline>Currency impact on Indonesian economy seen muted.</headline>
<byline>Mantik Kusjanto</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The impact of the recent sharp depreciation of the rupiah against the dollar on Indonesia's economy is likely to be muted, although the trade surplus could narrow in the interim, strategists said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The rupiah, which started the year at 2,363 to the dollar, had fallen some 10 percent by Thursday to about 2,600.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the impact for the overall 1997 growth rate should be more or less muted,&quot; Vincent Low, fixed-income strategist at Merrill Lynch in Singapore, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Indonesia has forecast GDP growth of 7.1 percent for 1997/98.</p>
<p>But Low said Indonesia might have to deal with a smaller trade surplus because of inelasticity of capital good imports.</p>
<p>&quot;In the interim it will narrow because the downward sloping portion of the J-curve is going to be prolonged, unless you believe that demand is really very elastic,&quot; Low said.</p>
<p>The J-curve, so called because of its shape, charts the reaction of the trade balance following a currency depreciation.</p>
<p>The trade balance deteriorates as import costs rise, then recovers as exports expand in volume due to cheaper exchange costs.</p>
<p>&quot;The upward portion of the J-curve will sort of kick in very fast. I would say for 1997, in the next six months, the dollar denominated trade balance would actually sort of decline in dollar terms,&quot; the strategist said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's part of the process the government has to undergo.&quot;</p>
<p>But economists believed inflation was likely to remain under control as major parts of the Indonesian consumer price basket were of indigenous origin unlike other neighbouring nations.</p>
<p>Chan Kok Peng of Credit Suisse First Boston said the government's inflation target of six percent for this year was on track because the imported components of the inflation basket were minor.</p>
<p>Chan said overall impact on the economy should also be limited because the country's imports as a percentage of GDP were much lower than its neighbours.</p>
<p>Chan said Indonesian imports as a percentage of GDP were only about 25 percent last year, compared with 95 percent in Malaysia and 48 percent in Thailand.</p>
<p>The central bank said on Tuesday the rupiah had returned to a normal trading range in recent days after reaching a record low last week in the wake of an attack by speculators.</p>
<p>The assault on the rupiah followed speculative attacks on other regional currencies, with market-forced devaluations in the Thai baht and the Philippine peso.</p>
<p>Paul Soetopo, a director of Bank Indonesia, said after reaching a low of 2,663 rupiah against the dollar on July 21, the currency had in recent days reached a normal level of between 2,555 and 2,610 rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;Under current conditions, the range is considered normal,&quot; Soetopo said.</p>
<p>Economists said the range mentioned by the central bank suggested a level the bank was comfortable with. It would also help Indonesia remain competitive with its neighbours after factoring in a plunge of 25 percent in Thailand's baht and some 10 percent in the Philippine peso.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is still a need (to depreciate) because Indonesian exports by large still remain price-sensitive to exchange rates, especially commodity products,&quot; Low said.</p>
<p>&quot;For Indonesia (the impact) would be less muted than in a more open economy. But it has to deal with a wider trade balance. It's just the mechanics of the J-curve at work,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
