<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769241" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Fuel Oil - Firm in line with crude gains.</title>
<headline>Asia Fuel Oil - Firm in line with crude gains.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore high sulphur fuel oil market maintaind its firm tone on Thursday, tracking gains in the crude market for the second day, traders said.</p>
<p>September Brent crude closed up 38 cents per barrel to $18.97 on the International Petroleum Exchange on Wednesday and gained another three cents on SIMEX.</p>
<p>Singapore's declining fuel oil stocks also slightly boosted prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Singapore's weekly fuel oil residues fell by 219,000 barrels to 10.855 million in the week ending July 30, Singapore's Trade Development Board (TDB) data showed on Thursday.  </p>
<p>The weekly stocks have been falling in the past three weeks.</p>
<p>The 180-cst grade was offered at $102.25 per tonne, compared with the $101.75 traded level on Wednesday, for late August lifting but no deals were heard on late Thursday.</p>
<p>Fuel oil swaps also firmed, with both August and September quoted at $101.25/$102.00, up from Wednesday's $100.75/$101.75.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems the market will continue to follow the strong crude market for a while,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>However, the trader noted a lack of fresh buying demand and saw limited gains.  </p>
<p>Other traders also noted the low American Pertroleum Institute stocks data.</p>
<p>Taiwan's state-owned Chinese Petroleum Corp (CPC) issued a tender on Thursday to buy two low-sulphur fuel oil cargoes for delivery in September.</p>
<p>The tender seeks to buy one 0.5-percent and one 1.0 percent low-pour cargoes for delivery in the second half of September, a company source said.</p>
<p>The tender closes on August 6 and is valid for two days.  </p>
<p>The low sulphur waxy residue (LSWR) market was under pressure amid higher supplies from Indonesia in August than in July, traders said.</p>
<p>Indonesia's state oil company Pertamina allocated a total of 2.7 million barrels of LSWR for August lifting and traders expected further allocation in late August.</p>
<p>(Prices in dollars per tonne, unless stated)</p>
<p> MTH  FOB SIN		   BUY/SELL	     PREV BUY/SELL</p>
<p> AUG  LSWR *		    15.50/16.00	  15.80/16.30</p>
<p> AUG  FUEL OIL (180 CST)   100.00/102.00	100.00/102.00</p>
<p> AUG  FUEL OIL (380 CST)    98.00/100.00	 98.00/100.00</p>
<p> AUG  FUEL OIL SWAPS	 101.25/102.00	100.75/101.75</p>
<p> SEP  FUEL OIL SWAPS	 101.25/102.00	100.75/101.75</p>
<p>*Dollars per barrel</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (+65-870 3571)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
