<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76926" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Debt, purchasing power blocks FDI to Africa - UNCTAD.</title>
<headline>Debt, purchasing power blocks FDI to Africa - UNCTAD.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign direct investment (FDI) to Africa was a &quot;modest&quot; $5.0 billion in 1995, concentrated in just a few countries and held back because of low purchasing power and enduring debt burden, a United Nations report said.</p>
<p>The annual World Investment report from the Geneva-based United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) said FDI inflows to Africa doubled from 1985 to 1995 but with no increase last year, Africa's share actually fell to 4.7 percent from 5.8 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>Efforts were being made to encourage FDI, UNCTAD said. By June 1996, African countries had signed 258 bilateral investment treaties to promote and protect FDI and 155 treaties to avoid double taxation. But the continent still risks being marginalised, the report said.</p>
<p>UNCTAD officials said at a briefing on the report in London that Africa's low purchasing power, its overhanging debt burden and a slow programme of privatisations were among the reasons why it languished at the bottom of the FDI league.</p>
<p>The report noted the geographic pattern of FDI in Africa has changed. In the 1980s, southern Africa accounted for 40 percent of Africa's FDI stock. By 1993 this was just 25 percent.</p>
<p>North Africa's share, which was a mere 12 percent in 1980, had risen to 30 percent by 1993, due mainly to rising levels of European investments.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors from the developed countries have displayed uneven interest in Africa,&quot; the UNCTAD report said. &quot;Due to geographical proximity and post-colonial ties, Western European investors have always been more active compared with both the United States and Japanese investors.&quot;</p>
<p>Belgium was an increasingly important FDI player, it added.</p>
<p>The importance of FDI also varies amongst African countries. &quot;For countries with large inflows, such as Nigeria, FDI is not as significant relative to the size of the domestic economy as it is for countries with small flows, such as Equatorial Guinea,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Nigeria accounted for around 48 percent of all 1993-1995 flows into sub-Saharan Africa, while Egypt accounted for around 48 percent of flows into North Africa over the same period.</p>
<p>UNCTAD noted Africa was growing some large transnational corporations but nine of the top 10, excluding finance and insurance firms and rated by sales value, were based in South Africa.</p>
<p>Among Africa's finance and insurance companies, rated by assets, the top five were Banque Algeriennne de Developpement ($15.3 billion), Nedcor Bank Ltd ($13.7 billion), Banque Misr ($11.8 billion), Banque du Caire (SAE) ($5.3 billion) and Commercial Bank of Ethiopia ($2.1 billion).</p>
<p>South Africa assumed the chair of UNCTAD for the next four years at its nineth conference meeting in Johannesburg in May this year.</p>
<p>-- Caroline Allen, London newsroom +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
