<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769265" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan market readies for legalised index futures.</title>
<headline>Taiwan market readies for legalised index futures.</headline>
<byline>George Hsu</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan brokerages were making final preparations on Thursday for a long-awaited financial liberalisation -- legal trading of offshore futures pegged to the island's own stock market performance.</p>
<p>The move, set for Friday, appears well timed, with Taiwan's cash market bounding higher by the day and many analysts saying the stock index's all-time high of 12,495 was in reach this quarter.</p>
<p>The Taiwan stock index closed at a seven-year high on Thursday, gaining 123.56 points or 1.24 percent to 10,066.35.</p>
<p>Daily turnover has been huge recently, often eclipsing T$200 billion (US$7 billion) and sometimes spiking toward T$300 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Futures volume could top T$50 billion a month if even one percent of the stock market's volume speculates or hedges in the futures market,&quot; one Taipei broker said.</p>
<p>On January 9, the Singapore International Monetary Exchange (SIMEX) and the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME) launched rival index futures pegged to proprietary Taiwan stock indexes compiled by Morgan Stanley and Dow Jones, respectively.</p>
<p>Taiwan regulators opposed the contracts, hoping that index futures could be pioneered by the island's own long-delayed futures exchange, now aiming to open in October.</p>
<p>Local investors have been banned from trading the contracts, but in the face of daunting pressure, regulators announced they would lift the ban from August 1.</p>
<p>To date, the SIMEX contract, based on the Morgan Stanley Capital International index, has fared better than the CME's Dow Jones Taiwan Stock Index futures, with daily volumes averaging 1,000-2,000 lots.</p>
<p>The CME futures have not been traded actively, with daily volume often less than 100 lots.</p>
<p>Brokers said they had not written the CME off completely, but that major effort was needed to revive that market.</p>
<p>&quot;I won't say the CME Taiwan index is dead, but they need to promote it harder to gain businesses,&quot; one Taipei broker said.</p>
<p>Futures houses have focused on the SIMEX contracts, taking index futures road shows to eager investors in almost every Taiwan town.</p>
<p>The CME index has not been promoted widely by local brokers, due chiefly to the sluggish volume, executives said.</p>
<p>One broker estimated that in July alone, over 3,000 Taiwan investors had opened futures trading accounts -- mainly in anticipation of trying their hand at Taiwan index futures.</p>
<p>The Securities and Futures Commission was expected to disclose numbers of futures trading accounts in late August.</p>
<p>Singapore futures traders were cautiously optimistic about the lifting of the ban, saying they expected Taiwan investors to boost SIMEX volumes.</p>
<p>But no immediate flood of new business was expected, they said. However, one upbeat projection put potential volume at 10,000-15,000 lots.</p>
<p>Dealers and analysts have said the SIMEX Taiwan contract would need to generate daily turnover in the region of 5,000 lots to attract and retain institutional interest.</p>
<p>There are 21 Taiwan brokerages qualified to take individual investors' SIMEX orders, which will be executed and cleared by one of two SIMEX clearing members in Taiwan -- UOB Bullion and Futures Ltd and Fimat Futures Taiwan Branch.</p>
<p>A key question, market players said, is whether the offshore contracts, which cannot use the Taiwan Stock Exchange's main Taiwan Weighted Index, can grab significant market share before October when Taiwan's new futures exchange will launch a futures contract based on the weighted index.</p>
<p>($1 = T$28.68)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
