<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769388" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cohen faults U.S. general for Saudi bombing lapses.</title>
<headline>Cohen faults U.S. general for Saudi bombing lapses.</headline>
<byline>Jim Wolf</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen said on Thursday he was blocking the promotion of the Air Force general in charge of a housing complex in Saudi Arabia where 19 U.S. airmen were killed in 1996 by a truck bomb.</p>
<p>Shortly after the announcement, the officer, Brig. Gen. Terryl Schwalier, resigned.</p>
<p>Speaking after meeting with President Bill Clinton on the matter, Cohen said he was holding Schwalier personally accountable for not doing enough to guard the barracks known as Khobar Towers from the June 25, 1996, blast in Dhahran.</p>
<p>&quot;The president accepted my recommendation that Brig. Gen. Schwalier's name be withdrawn from the promotion list,&quot; Cohen told a news briefing at the Pentagon.</p>
<p>With his once-bright career prospects dimmed, Schwalier said in a statement that he had submitted his request for retirement, adding that he was walking away with &quot;head high.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;My intense hope is that commanders in the field will not be unduly criticised every time something bad happens,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cohen faulted Schwalier for failing to adequately assess the threat to the barracks' perimeter and failing to prepare for possible attack. In so doing, he overrode two Air Force reports clearing Schwalier and other Air Force officers.</p>
<p>Cohen cited the lack of an effective alarm system to warn of an impending attack and inadequate evacuation plans. Hundreds of troops were wounded.</p>
<p>&quot;I know that perfection is impossible. And I also know that a zero-defect attitude can make commanders very cautious and timid, jeopardising success in battle,&quot; Cohen said.</p>
<p>&quot;But we do expect high standards of performance for the commanders in the field. General officers in particular must demonstrate awareness, resourcefulness and judgment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The issue of holding Schwalier accountable for Khobar security lapses has deeply troubled the armed forces. Anticipating Cohen's decision, Air Force Chief of Staff Gen. Ronald Fogleman resigned on Monday, saying he felt &quot;out of step&quot; with Pentagon leadership.</p>
<p>Though he praised Schwalier as a &quot;fine officer who has served his country well during a long career,&quot; Cohen said he fell down on the most important task, protecting his forces.</p>
<p>At the time of the bombing Schwalier was commander of the U.S. air wing in Dhahran.</p>
<p>Schwalier was approved by the Senate for promotion from brigadier general, a one-star rank, to major general, a two-star rank. The promotion was put on hold earlier this year, pending Cohen's decision, which was endorsed by the nation's top uniformed officer, Gen. John Shalikashvili, chairman of the joint chiefs of staff.</p>
<p>In what he called a message to young U.S. field commanders, Shalikashvili said the military must resist the temptation &quot;to circle the wagons&quot; for one of its own.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
