<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76934" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Profit-taking takes heat off Australian bonds.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Profit-taking takes heat off Australian bonds.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>--------------(Snapshot at 4.35 P.M./0635 GMT)------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES					  CASH YIELD</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS  (DEC) 93.33  (+ 0.04)    6.95    (UNCH)</p>
<p>3-YR T-BONDS  (DEC) 92.87  (+ 0.07)    6.99    (- 0.07)</p>
<p>10-YR T-BONDS (DEC) 92.140 (+0.070)    7.85    (- 0.07)</p>
<p>AUD/USD  0.7879 (PREV 0.7893) US 30-YR 7.01   (6.99 NY)</p>
<p>-------------------------(Sept 25)------------------------------</p>
<p>*Australia bond yields ended at the lowest level in a month, but were above the intra day lows amid some profit-taking after the 10-year bond futures failed to take out the August high.</p>
<p>*Volatile period seen ahead for U.S. Teasuries  </p>
<p>By Colin Brinsden</p>
<p>Australian bond yields closed at their lowest level in a month as the market rallied strongly initially in response to an unchanged policy stance by the U.S. Federal Reserve which fuelled hopes of another local easing.</p>
<p>However, the market ran into some profit-taking after the December 10-year bond futures contract just fell short of taking out August's 92.210 peak.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we got a little head of ourselves and I'm slightly negative short-term, but I expect to see lower yields by the end of the year,&quot; said one trader at a European-based bank.  </p>
<p>Many economists are predicting an Australian rate cut before the end of the year based on the country's low inflation outlook, a weak labour market and to compensate for the government's stiff fiscal stance.</p>
<p>Howeverm, those looking for new Reserve Bank governor Ian Macfarlane to shine some light on the current policy stance in a speech on Wednesday would have been disappointed.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no clues on monetary policy direction at all. But the fact that there are no clues, probably by default means that they haven't closed the window on an easing,&quot; said Stephen Roberts, chief economist at UBS Australia.  </p>
<p>The December bill futures contract touched a high of 93.40 in early trading, indicating a cash rate of 6.60 percent by maturity compared with official interest rates of 7.0 percent.</p>
<p>The relief factor from no U.S. rate hike proved short-lived for U.S. Treasuries, and saw the 30-year bond yield back over 7.0 percent in Tokyo trading.</p>
<p>Markets had been expecting a 25 basis point tightening.</p>
<p>&quot;We should be expecting more erratic leads from the U.S. Treasury market, which will be very much churning with the data. That would have been cured if the Fed had done something,&quot; UBS's Roberts added.  </p>
<p>-------------------------(SPREADS)------------------------------</p>
<p> AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	 67 (+ 02)   108 (- 02) * FUTURES   73   (+ 00.5)</p>
<p> CAD	146 (+ 12)    61 (+ 04) * CASH	87   (UNCH)</p>
<p> NZD     -109 (- 05)   -32 (- 04) *</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Local bonds gave up some ground against other dollar bloc bonds as they edged back from the highs and after scoring a 10-year spread low of 104 basis points against the U.S., its lowest for 2-1/2 years. Canadian bonds outperformed as stable U.S. policy raised hopes of an easing by the Bank of Canada.  </p>
<p>----------------------(TECHNICALS)---------------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES	*DAY'S HILO  *SUP/RES     *RSI    *MA-10 *MA-20</p>
<p>10-YEAR (DEC)*92.20-92.12 *92.11-92.21 *65 PCT *92.01 *91.91</p>
<p>3-YEAR  (DEC)*92.94-92.85 *92.86-92.95 *66 PCT *92.75 *92.63</p>
<p>90-DAY  (DEC)*93.40-93.31 *93.30-93.35 *59 PCT *93.29 *93.24</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Colin Brinsden 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
