<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769300" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish police fine Islamist drivers in protests.</title>
<headline>Turkish police fine Islamist drivers in protests.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish police have fined more than 500 drivers in a central town for blocking traffic and beeping their horns in Islamist protests against secularist education reforms, Anatolian news agency said on Thursday.</p>
<p>It said police had fined 556 car and truck drivers a total of 1.6 billion lira ($10,000) over the last three days in protests in the traditionalist town of Kayseri.</p>
<p>Islamists have been driving around the town in vehicle convoys to protest government plans to extend secularist schooling in a bill that would close religious high schools.</p>
<p>The plan has further set Islamists against Turkey's secularist government and military.</p>
<p>Dozens of people were arrested in Ankara on Tuesday in an Islamist march in protest at the reforms that turned ugly. Eleven people, mostly journalists, were injured when police baton-charged crowds outside the education ministry.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Mesut Yilmaz has vowed to push the education bill through parliament in the coming weeks despite the protests.</p>
<p>President Suleyman Demirel also backs the plan.</p>
<p>&quot;Schools in one place, mosques in another. There is no sense in confusing the two,&quot; Anatolian news agency quoted him as saying at the foundation-laying ceremony for an Istanbul primary school.</p>
<p>The liberal Yeni Yuzyil daily said that police had received information of Islamist plans to demonstrate at chosen mosques in different areas of the country every day in protest at the education reforms. There was no independent confirmation.</p>
<p>($1 = 159,390 Turkish Lira)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
