<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="76939" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Westpac Australia leading index jumps in July.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Westpac Australia leading index jumps in July.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Westpac-Melbourne Institute Leading Index of economic activity, which indicates where activity will be in six to nine months time, rose by 2.5 points or 1.7 percent in July.</p>
<p>The annual growth rate of the index was 3.4 percent, up from 0.1 percent in June. The coincident index, which provides a broad measure of the current state of economic activity, posted a rise of 1.1 points or 0.6 percent in July, lifting the annual growth rate to 5.2 percent from 3.9 percent in June.</p>
<p>The leading index of inflation fell again by 0.2 percentage points to 4.5 percent from 4.7 percent in June.  </p>
<p>&quot;The strong rise in the Leading Index in July supports Westpac's view there will be an upswing in economic activity underway from mid-1997, although we expect some slowing in the near term,&quot; Westpac general manager, economics, Bill Evans said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The clear trend of a slowing in the Leading Index of Inflation, which peaked at 7.2 percent a year ago, points to a continuing deceleration in inflation as the economy moves into 1997,&quot; said Evans.</p>
<p>Also encouraging for economic prospects was a sharp rise in leading indexes for East Asia, Australia's major export market.  </p>
<p>Commenting on the data, the Melbourne Institute said the June national accounts figures and improvements in building activity had resulted in the healthy leading index, which had now shown low but positive growth for the last seven months.</p>
<p>However, it was important to remember that the index had been below its long term average for 20 of the past 21 months suggesting the economy may still have some slowing to come, the Institute said.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain of the view that monetary policy is too tight in Australia,&quot; it said. &quot;However, continued improvement in the leading index would cause us to reassess that view.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Institute noted the 4.5 percent reading for the leading indicator of inflation in July was significantly below the annual consumer price average of 6.2 percent recorded between January 1951 and May 1995.</p>
<p>The lagging indicator of growth rose 3.9 points or 2.7 percent in July to be up 12.5 percent in annual terms.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
