<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769511" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US LPGs slow as sellers want yesterday's prices.</title>
<headline>US LPGs slow as sellers want yesterday's prices.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot liquefied petroleum gas prices were mostly unchanged in thin trading Thursday following Wednesday's gains.</p>
<p>Traders said the lack of LPG activity reflected Thursday's crude oil fall on the NYMEX.</p>
<p>Propane values in the Mont Belevieu, Texas, market were unchanged at 35.25 and 35.50 cents a gallon, but August propane deals were made at 35.63 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>Propane values in the Conway, Kansas, were a quarter cent firmer at 34.50/34.75 cents, but players said no deals had been heard done.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone seems to have taken care of what was on their books,&quot; said one trader, &quot;my phone isn't ringing.&quot;</p>
<p>In one of the few deals heard done at the Conway hub midday was natural gasoline at 45.00 cents. August material there was pegged at 44.75/45.00 cents.</p>
<p>Isobutane values moved the most in Conway. It was pegged 0.75 cent higher at 42.00/42.75 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;Sellers are trying to get yesterday's values,&quot; said one trader, &quot;but the buyers are basically hiding.&quot; --Tim Gardner, New York Oil Desk +1 212 859 1632 --</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
