<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769667" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Richard Jewell sues ABC radio station.</title>
<headline>Richard Jewell sues ABC radio station.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Richard Jewell, whose name was leaked by the FBI as a suspect in the 1996 Olympic Summer Games bombing but who was eventually cleared, on Thursday sued a New York radio station, charging that one of its talk show hosts libelled him.</p>
<p>The lawsuit, filed in U.S. District Court in the Southern District, was the second filed by Jewell against a media outlet in two weeks.</p>
<p>Jewell alleged that the host, who goes by the single name of Lionel, broadcast a series of false and defamatory statements in the days following the bombing on July 27, 1996, in Atlanta.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for ABC said the company had no comment.</p>
<p>Jewell, cleared of suspicion last October in the bombing, is seeking $2.5 million in compensatory damages, and $5 million in punitive damages.</p>
<p>Jewell's suit alleged that the broadcasts portrayed him &quot;as an individual who was guilty or likely guilty of criminal involvement&quot; in the bombing.</p>
<p>According to the lawsuit, Lionel said in a broadcast on July 31: &quot;He did it... He probably did it.&quot;</p>
<p>According to the lawsuit, the host also said, &quot;It's very sad that people lost lives and people were injured by (Mr. Jewell.)&quot;</p>
<p>Separately, in Washington on Thursday, U.S. Attorney General Janet Reno apologised to Jewell for news leaks that put him in the public spotlight.</p>
<p>At her weekly Justice Department news conference, Reno said, &quot;I think we owe him an apology.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We should insure that there be no leaks,&quot; she said. &quot;And I regret very much the leak that made him an object of so much public attention.&quot;</p>
<p>Jewell last week sued the New York Post, also alleging libel, and is seeking $5 million in compensatory damages, and $10 million in punitive damages.</p>
<p>Jewell reached legal settlements with CNN and NBC over their coverage. A lawsuit is pending against the Atlanta Journal-Constitution, owned by private Cox Enterprises.</p>
<p>Jewell first noticed an unattended package at Centennial Olympic Park, and helped evacuate people from the area. The bombing, which remains unsolved, left two people dead and more than 100 wounded.</p>
<p>After being hounded by the FBI and the news media for 88 days, Jewell finally was cleared by the Justice Department of any suspicion in the bombing.</p>
<p>WABC Radio is a unit of ABC Inc, a subsidiary of Walt Disney Co. The New York Post is owned by News Corp Ltd .</p>
<p>CNN is a part of Time Warner Inc, and NBC is a unit of General Electric Co.</p>
<p>((-- Jeff Benkoe, 212-859-1735.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
