<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769717" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sallie Mae holders vote for dissident plan.</title>
<headline>Sallie Mae holders vote for dissident plan.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Student Loan Marketing Association shareholders voted Thursday to privatise the government-sponsored enterprise through a plan put forward by a dissident group.</p>
<p>At a special meeting in Washingtin, shareholders also chose a 15-member board of directors nominated by the Committee to Restore Value (CRV), a group opposed to existing management.</p>
<p>William Arceneaux, outgoing chairman due to the vote, said shareholders had voted overwhelmingly to privatise the company and restructure it according to CRV's proposal.</p>
<p>&quot;Preliminary results indicate the shareholders owning 80 percent of the shares (voted to) recharter the company as a wholly private entity,&quot; Arceneaux said.</p>
<p>&quot;Preliminary results show a majority of the shares present in voting have selected the slate of nominees representing the CRV to be appointed as the initial board of directors,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The vote ended months of dueling between CRV and Sallie Mae and set into motion the privatisation ordered by Congress.</p>
<p>With newly elected Chief Executive Officer Albert Lord, CRV plans to expand the company's student loan operations by originating loans and competing directly with other lenders.</p>
<p>Edward Fox will become the new chairman.</p>
<p>Shareholders rejected a slate proposed by Sallie Mae management that would have included five CRV members on the 15-person board. The management proposal was designed to appeal to a wider range of shareholders while maintaining the current management direction.</p>
<p>Sallie Mae purchases student loans from banks, keeping some in its portfolio and securitizing others for sale to investors.</p>
<p>Lord and Fox plan to expand Sallie Mae's business to include the origination of student loans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
