<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769942" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Japan's Toyota set to seal India joint venture.</title>
<headline>Japan's Toyota set to seal India joint venture.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Kirloskar group is set to sign a joint-venture agreement with Japan's Toyota Motor Corp to manufacture sports utility vehicles, group executive Vikram Kirloskar told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>Kirloskar, who is managing director of Mysore Kirloskar Ltd , one of the group's leading companies, said total investment in the joint venture would be $170 million.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be signing the joint venture agreement with Toyota on Monday at Toyota's headquarters in Japan,&quot; Kirloskar said by telephone from the southern city of Bangalore.</p>
<p>Kirloskar said Toyota would hold 74 percent of the joint venture and the Kirloskar group the rest. The plant, to be built at Bidadi, near Bangalore, would produce 2000cc &quot;family recreational vehicles&quot;.</p>
<p>Start-up is scheduled for the second half of 1999 and the plant will initially product 50,000 units annually, he said.</p>
<p>Kirloskar told Reuters last month the sports utility vehicle would be a new variant of Toyota's popular Kijang model.</p>
<p>Analysts expect India's market for cars to grow to around one million units in 2000/2001 (April-March) from 345,355 in 1995/96.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
