<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="769903" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Relatives wail after 24 die in Bangladesh stampede.</title>
<headline>Relatives wail after 24 die in Bangladesh stampede.</headline>
<byline>Shakeel Anwar</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police on Thursday struggled to disperse hundreds of angry protesters trying to storm a locked up building in the Bangladesh capital where a fatal stampede killed at least 24 garment workers and injured over 100, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Outside the morgue at the Dhaka Medical College Hospital, grieving parents and relatives wailed inconsolably as they waited for the bodies of the victims.</p>
<p>&quot;Let me take my daughter home,&quot; said a 50-year-old man. His daughter Yasim (one name) was among the dead.</p>
<p>The stampede occurred on Wednesday evening after an electrical short circuit at Shanghai Apparels, one of four garment factories housed in the multi-storey building at Dhaka's Mirpur area.</p>
<p>&quot;Although there had not been any actual fire, it (the short circuit) caused a severe panic among workers of the Shanghai Apparels and in the three other factories,&quot; one police officer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some 1,000 workers at the factories started scrambling down narrow stairs causing severe suffocation and many also jumped from fourth floor windows,&quot; one fire brigade officer said.</p>
<p>Most of the victims were women, who constitute 90 percent of textile workers in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Police said the workers panicked because eight people had been killed in another garment factory fire in the capital on July 16.</p>
<p>Demonstrators at Mirpur shouted slogans against the factory owners, some accusing them of ignoring safety requirements.</p>
<p>Police and military officials at the scene said they were expecting President Shahabuddin Ahmed to visit the factories.</p>
<p>As survivors gave horrific accounts of the accident, the authorities on Thursday announced a decision to give compensation to families of the victims.</p>
<p>Each family will receive 100,000 taka ($2,272), half of it provided by the government and half by the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA).</p>
<p>&quot;I feel I escaped from hell. Hundreds were shouting fire, fire. I ran to the staircase on the fourth floor but couldn't get down as dozens of others were climbing up for safety,&quot; said Dolly Begum, 20, looking bewildered.</p>
<p>&quot;I then took off my saree, tied it to a window grille and managed to climb down to the street,&quot; she told reporters at Mirpur.</p>
<p>&quot;Many others did the same and scores jumped out of the windows. The air was heavy with people screaming, shouting and crying for help,&quot; Begum said.</p>
<p>Police said the factory's owners and managers stayed away in fear of attacks by outraged workers and relatives of the victims.</p>
<p>A senior fire brigade official said most of the garment factories in Dhaka lacked fire escapes and held no fire-fighting exercises.</p>
<p>Some 150 workers have been killed and at least 500 injured in a series of garment factory fires in recent years, he said without giving details.</p>
<p>BGMEA President Golam Quddus said the association had served notice last week on all garment factories to ensure the required fire-prevention measures were taken.</p>
<p>&quot;We have told them to immediately arrange a second staircase at every factory and mobilise adequate fire fighting materials,&quot; he told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I admit many factories have ignored the matter in the past. Now we have asked them to correct their mistakes or face cancellation of the association's membership.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
