<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770058" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Eurobourses boosted by Dow rally, dlr softer.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Eurobourses boosted by Dow rally, dlr softer.</headline>
<byline>Peter Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>European stock markets forged ahead in early trade on Thursday, boosted by another overnight rally on Wall Street, but activity was muted by a softer dollar and uncertainty about U.S. employment figures due on Friday.</p>
<p>London shares also suffered somewhat from a bounce in the already strong British pound, provoking further jitters among exporters.</p>
<p>On the foreign exchange front the dollar slipped briefly below 118 yen in early European business, partly in reaction to comments by a Japanese car industry official, which fanned concern that trade tension between the U.S. and Japan could resurface.</p>
<p>Takao Tominaga, vice chairman and executive managing director of the Japan Automobile Manufacturers' Association, said 110 to 120 yen was an appropriate range for the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade will always be a focus for the market as long as Japan is running a current account surplus with the U.S.,&quot; said Jesper Dannesboe, treasury economist at ABN Amro in London.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar looked toppy yesterday and did not have too much momentum so it is not surprising that it has come back a bit,&quot; said Paul Coughlin, chief trader at Amex Bank. &quot;But it should be fairly rangebound before the (jobs) data, with tomorrow's payrolls being the main focus.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists expect Friday's non-farm payrolls report to show 193,000 jobs were added to the U.S. economy in July.</p>
<p>The dollar has surged as much as 60 percent against the Japanese currency from a post-World War Two low in April 1995 but has fallen back nearly seven percent from the 57-month high of 127.46 yen it hit on May 1.</p>
<p>The dollar was at 118.25 yen at 1000 GMT from 118.40 late on Wednesday in Europe. It also slipped against the mark to around 1.8336 from 1.8383 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Meanwhile sterling was looking robust in Europe, having rebounded to above three marks, though it was off early morning peaks.</p>
<p>It turned positive after Chancellor of the Exchequer Gordon Brown said in a newspaper interview he had no plans for a special autumn budget to try to brake consumer spending, leaving the impression that inflation would be controlled by further interest rate rises.</p>
<p>Britain's leading FTSE 100 share index was in positive territory, but only just, in early trade at around 4,931, and was taking little comfort from a batch of earnings reports.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial response is for the market to open higher but after that it may prove that there is not much follow through and there may be suspicion of the uptrend at these levels,&quot; said Richard Jeffrey, chief economist at brokerage Charterhouse Tilney.</p>
<p>&quot;Approaching 5,000 points psychologically is always going to prove an important level and people will ask questions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>British Telecommunications, drug giant Glaxo Wellcome, engineers TI Group and energy company Lasmo all traded unchanged to lower after their earnings proved uninspiring.</p>
<p>Sterling's bounce back above 3.0 marks kept the spotlight on overseas earners ahead of the Bank of England's rate-setting Monetary Policy Committee meeting on August 6-7.</p>
<p>British Steel's chairman and chief executive, Sir Brian Moffat, warned that Britain could move &quot;rapidly from apparent boom to recession&quot; unless action was taken to reverse the rise in the value of the pound.</p>
<p>&quot;The government and the Bank of England should be encouraged to say they think the pound is ludicrously overvalued,&quot; he wrote in Thursday's Financial Times.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt the main DAX index hit a new record high in early trade at 4,452.28 points, and dealers said it might reach 4,500 later in the day, though volumes were lower than on previous days.</p>
<p>&quot;We were a bit shaky at the beginning. Volumes are a little lower than in recent days, but I'm confident that we can reach 4,500 points at some stage over the day,&quot; a Frankfurt broker said.</p>
<p>Underpinning early gains was the fresh Wall Street rally, which saw the Dow Jones Industrial Average closing around one percent higher at 8,254.89 points.</p>
<p>One focus was Daimler-Benz AG, whose shares fell about five percent from their session peak on profit-taking after the German industrial group reported half-year results generally in line with market expectations.</p>
<p>On the Paris bourse the CAC blue-chip index gave back some of its gains after opening up 0.66 percent. But traders said the market was well supported by the bull run on Wall Street and other centres.</p>
<p>One big mover was car maker PSA Peugeot Citroen, which roared ahead 4.51 percent to 719 francs as brokers upgraded the stock after a positive sales announcement on Wednesday.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1000 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.8336 marks and 118.25 yen compared with 1.8383 and 118.40 in late trading on Wednesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1000 GMT</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index was up 3.8 points at 4,931.1.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The DAX index was up 23.05 points in bourse trade at 4,444.77.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 was up 11.7 points at 3,081</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $326.00 compared with Wednesday's London close of 326.65. Silver was two cents firmer at $4.40.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
