<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770040" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Congress sends tax, budget measures to White House.</title>
<headline>Congress sends tax, budget measures to White House.</headline>
<byline>Sue Kirchhoff</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Congress on Thursday overwhelmingly approved legislation to balance the budget and cut taxes, sending the measures to President Bill Clinton for his signature.</p>
<p>By a bipartisan margin of 85-15, the Senate early Thursday gave final approval to legislation designed to erase the deficit by 2002 by cutting Medicare, Medicaid and other programmes while creating a new children's health initiative.</p>
<p>By even more lopsided margins, both chambers then passed a companion bill cutting taxes by a net $95 billion, including a $500-per-child credit, a major reduction in the capital gains rate and new incentives for higher education.</p>
<p>Lawmakers were bursting with bipartisan good cheer as they praised each other for coming together to finally break Washington's long habit of deficit spending.</p>
<p>&quot;On both sides of the aisle and both ends of Pennsylvania Avenue, Republicans and Democrats, House and Senate and, yes, the president are all saying, 'This is good for America,'&quot; said Senate Republican Leader Trent Lott of Mississippi.</p>
<p>Lott told senators he was humming &quot;Hail to the Chief&quot; in honour of the deal. Clinton and House Speaker Newt Gingrich held a breakfast chat on ways to sustain good relations.</p>
<p>At the White House, the president hailed approval as &quot;the achievement of a generation and a triumph for every American.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This budget marks an end to decades of deficits and just as important, it honours our values,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>Not everyone was happy. House Democratic Leader Dick Gephardt, a possible presidential contender, voted against the budget and tax bills.</p>
<p>&quot;This budget has a deficit of fairness, a deficit of investment and a deficit of dollars,&quot; Gephardt said. He complained important social programmes were being cut to finance tax cuts that would mainly benefit the well-off.</p>
<p>Some conservative Republicans, including Texas Sen. Phil Gramm, opposed the spending bill arguing it avoided needed long-term reforms of Medicare while creating a new $24 billion programme for children's health.</p>
<p>There was also a late flareup as Democrats complained Republicans had inserted a last-minute provision in the tax bill that would deduct revenues generated by a 15-cents-per-pack increase in the cigarette tax from industry payments under a proposed settlement of state lawsuits.</p>
<p>Republicans have long made balancing the budget and cutting taxes a top priority. That goal appeared out of reach in 1995 when party leaders forced an unpopular government shutdown in a failed effort to get a more radical budget plan.</p>
<p>Without a single Republican vote Clinton in 1993 pushed legislation through Congress raising taxes and cutting spending. Democrats believe the tough fight over that budget legislation was a major reason they lost control of Congress.</p>
<p>Helped along by a robust economy that sliced the deficit, and let them sidestep some tough decisions, the two sides finally came together on this year's budget deal.</p>
<p>The spending bill by itself would not bring the budget into balance. The measure reduces mandatory programmes such as Medicare and Medicaid by about $130 billion over five years.</p>
<p>It directs Congress to find another $140 billion in cuts over that same period as part of annual spending bills, but does not specify where they are to come from.</p>
<p>Critics charged future Congresses will never muster the political will to cut veterans, education, nutrition and other social programmes, making the bill an empty promise.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
