<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770568" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>TUNISIA: Tunis bourse lifted by over-the-counter trade.</title>
<headline>Tunis bourse lifted by over-the-counter trade.</headline>
<dateline>TUNIS 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Tunis Stock Exchange index on Thursday closed up by 0.36 percent in higher trade boosted by over-the-counter exchanges, bourse sources said.</p>
<p>The 31-share index closed at 447.81 points, up from 446.19 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Total volume was 3.73 million dinars against 1.01 million dinars over the previous session. Over-the-counter exchanges amounted to 3.16 million dinars.</p>
<p>Chemical firm Alkimia gained one dinar to 42 dinars. Airline Tunis Air gained 0.44 dinar to 23.44 dinars with the exchange of 8,662 shares. Investment fund Placement de Tunisie was up 0.34 dinar to 11.99.</p>
<p>Banque du Sud rose 0.31 dinar to 10.96 dinars. Banque de l'Habitat advanced 0.28 dinar to 15.78 dinars.</p>
<p>BTEI bank was up 0.2 dinar to 22.2 dinars. Banque Nationale Agricole rose 0.18 dinar to 18.8 dinars with 9,125 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>Household firm Ateliers Mecaniques du Sahel advanced 0.11 dinar to 8.3 dinars.</p>
<p>Insurance firm ASTREE fell 0.72 dinar to 23.66 dinars. Detergents firm SPCD was down 0.22 dinar to 29.04 dinars. Palm Beach Hotels eased 0.18 dinar to 9.2 dinars.</p>
<p>($1=1.1465 dinar)</p>
<p>- Tunis newsroom 2161-787538</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUNIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TUNISIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
