<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770567" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel bonds end higher after Wednesday's bombs.</title>
<headline>Israel bonds end higher after Wednesday's bombs.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli bonds closed higher on Thursday and traders said trading was unaffected by the bomb attack in Jerusalem on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Indices:</p>
<p>* Government bonds general: +0.1 pct to 110.56</p>
<p>* CPI-linked government bonds: +0.14 pct to 110.71</p>
<p>* Unlinked government bonds: -0.02 pct 109.97</p>
<p>* Dollar-linked government bonds: +0.2 pct to 110.81</p>
<p>* Bank of Israel short-term Makam bills: +0.05 pct to 108.28</p>
<p>Volume including Makams was an average 170 million shekels.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading was unaffected by the bombing in Jerusalem yesterday. Prices of CPI-linked bonds continued to rise while prices of unlinked bonds were stable,&quot; said an investment manager at United Mizrahi Bank.</p>
<p>Double suicide bombings by Moslem militants on Wednesday killed 13 people in an attack in an outdoor market in the heart of Jewish west Jerusalem.</p>
<p>&quot;Yields of the CPI-linked bonds are on their way down towards 3.8 percent for short and medium bonds and to 3.9 percent for long bonds,&quot; the Mizrahi investment manager said.</p>
<p>&quot;Yields of CPI-linked bonds are falling because of the scarcity effect. The government is issuing far less bonds than redemptions, which is drying up the market,&quot; said Adam Reuter of the Financial Immunities consulting firm.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders are also afraid of a rise in inflation and are covering themselves with CPI-linked bonds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fear of a higher inflation was the main reason unlinked bonds were unattractive to traders, Reuter said, along with the fact that at the end of the month money-funds generally sold unlinked bonds for tax reasons.</p>
<p>The rise of the dollar against the shekel in June, which caused June's CPI to rise a steep 1.1 percent, has triggered fears of a series of high indices in July and August. The shekel has recovered some of its losses against the dollar in the past two weeks.</p>
<p>July's CPI will be published on August 15.</p>
<p>Prices of dollar-linked bonds rose on Thursday on the strengthening of the dollar against the shekel on Wednesday, The shekel rose slightly against the dollar on Thursday. The representative rate for the dollar was fixed at 3.5400 shekels compared with 3.5460 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Note: Makams are zero-coupon unlinked certificates with durations of three months to one year. The Bank of Israel issues Makams to absorb liquidity.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.54 shekels)</p>
<p>- Shoshanna Solomon, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211 x233</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
