<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770555" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel cracks down on Palestinians over bombing.</title>
<headline>Israel cracks down on Palestinians over bombing.</headline>
<byline>Howard Goller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel suspended peace talks over a Jerusalem suicide attack, made arrests and threatened to re-enter Palestinian areas to seize &quot;terrorists&quot; on Thursday if President Yasser Arafat's forces failed to do the job.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's cabinet demanded Arafat clamp down on Moslem militants responsible for the double suicide bombings that killed 13 people and wounded 170 at a Jewish market on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In Jerusalem, mourners streamed to cemeteries for the funerals of victims of the deadliest attack on Israelis in over a year. Memorial candles flickered on a makeshift shrine at the spot where one of the bombs went off and walls were plastered with black-bordered funeral notices.</p>
<p>The front pages of Israeli newspapers reflected the depth of sorrow and fury over the suicide bombings, publishing huge photos of bloodied and blackened men, women and children wounded by the blasts.</p>
<p>&quot;The terrorism is back,&quot; read one headline.</p>
<p>In the West Bank town of Ramallah, Arafat faced another challenge. The 88-member Palestinian Legislative Council gave him one month to dissolve his cabinet and appoint a new one following a corruption probe.</p>
<p>Countries that have pledged millions of dollars in aid to Arafat's administration since it was established in 1994, including the United States, have set clean government as a condition for delivering the funds.</p>
<p>Taking swift action after the market bombings, Israeli security forces raided several West Bank villages under its own control and arrested activists of the militant Moslem group Hamas and their families.</p>
<p>A leaflet issued in Hamas's name claimed responsibility for Wednesday's attack. Israeli pathologists were trying to identify the bodies of the two bombers.</p>
<p>Late on Wednesday, Netanyahu's security cabinet ordered a halt to peace moves and vowed to act.</p>
<p>&quot;The cabinet decision is quite clear. If Israel has to, that is if the Palestinian Authority is not going to do what it is supposed to do against the terrorists, Israel will have to do it,&quot; Netanyahu's adviser David Bar-Illan told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Israel will have to go into the areas controlled by the Palestinian Authority if that is necessary and get the terrorists there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Palestinians said soldiers stormed Dahariyeh village near Hebron and arrested members of two families whose sons, both Islamic militants, have been missing for 15 months. It was not immediately clear if the missing pair were the bombers.</p>
<p>Relatives of the two were taken by Israeli police to the forensic institute near Tel Aviv for tests to determine the bombers' identities, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Israel sealed off the West Bank and Gaza Strip immediately after the Jerusalem attack. Military checkpoints blocked movements of residents and tourists alike. Israel prevented Palestinian newspapers from being delivered to self-ruled Gaza.</p>
<p>A Palestinian security official said Arafat, who condemned the bombing, had declared a state of emergency in Palestinian areas and ordered the arrest of activists of &quot;extremist groups&quot; including Hamas and Islamic Jihad.</p>
<p>Israel has only rarely re-entered the self-rule areas of Gaza and the West Bank to make arrests or battle Palestinians. It has handed the areas over to self-rule under peace deals signed since 1993.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials said Israel's confiscation of lands and expansion of Jewish settlements had driven Palestinians into a state of despair and frustration. Peace talks have been stuck since Netanyahu broke ground on a settler enclave in Arab East Jerusalem last March.</p>
<p>Arafat's adviser Nabil Abu Rdainah insisted the Palestinian Authority was preventing attacks from being launched from areas under its control and warned Israel it would be &quot;overstepping the red line&quot; by entering Palestinian-controlled territory.</p>
<p>Officials said Israeli-PLO security meetings took place late on Wednesday in the West Bank but they did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Nearly a full day after the mid-day blasts, police were still trying to identify some of the bodies blown apart by the two 10-kg (22 pound) bombs that the well-dressed attackers carried in briefcases.</p>
<p>Police urged the public to be on the alert for suspicious people and objects. Suicide bombers killed 57 people in a wave of attacks over eight days in February and March 1996.</p>
<p>World leaders urged Israel and the Palestinians to press on with negotiations but U.S. special Middle East envoy Dennis Ross postponed a planned mission to salvage peacemaking during a period of national mourning.</p>
<p>Among Jewish shoppers in the market, the mood was a mixture of resignation and defiance.</p>
<p>Miriam Goldberg said Arab bombs would not drive her away.</p>
<p>&quot;These barbarians, animals of prey, want to throw us out of the country. We won't go,&quot; she said as soldiers and police patrolled nearby.</p>
<p>But she lamented: &quot;How much longer? How much longer?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
