<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770566" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli shares rebound as attack effects recede.</title>
<headline>Israeli shares rebound as attack effects recede.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli shares closed higher on Thursday and traders said the market had fully recovered from the impact of a bomb attack that killed 13 people on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The benchmark Mishtanim index of the top 100 shares rose 1.26 percent, or 3.81 points, to 306.14 on a high all-share turnover of 232 million shekels against 240 million shekels on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Maof 25 blue chip index closed 1.45 percent higher at 314.37.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is used to tragic events and they  never affect it for more than a day or two. The strength of the market today was a little surprising but the direction will not change because of one event,&quot; said Zvi Hoffman at Meitav Investments and Securities.</p>
<p>Tel Aviv stocks closed lower on Wednesday, reversing morning gains after a double suicide bomb by Moslem militants killed 13 people in an attack in an outdoor market in the heart of Jewish west Jerusalem.</p>
<p>&quot;Israelis return fast to reality and the market was showing strength today. There are enough investors that are only waiting for an opportunity to get into the market and after such a day they think they can buy stocks at a cheaper price,&quot; said Eli Nahum head of trading at Zannex Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Wednesday's attack did not change the situation,&quot; Nahum said. &quot;The market is very bullish and it prefers to ignore bad news,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hoffman said that the market now awaits the release of the July consumer price index (CPI) on August 15.</p>
<p>&quot;A relatively high CPI might bring an end to the positive trend. If the CPI rises by one percent or more the central bank may decide to raise its key lending rate.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;A CPI figure of 0.8 percent or less would be seen as a positive sign and I find it hard to believe that interest rates would rise,&quot; Hoffman said.</p>
<p>He added that until the release of the CPI the market was likely to continue rising. &quot;The market continues to be very attractive,&quot; he said</p>
<p>Nahum said that technical analyses of the market also support the assumption that it will continue rising in the near term.</p>
<p>Solid Financial Markets on Thursday issued a strong buy recommendation for Nice Systems and set a 12-month price target of $48-$52 a share.</p>
<p>Nice rose 3.0 percent to 13,546 agorot.</p>
<p>The most active shares were Teva Pharmaceutical Industries, which lost 0.5 percent to 20,761 agorot (Israeli cents) on volume of 13.9 million shekels and Leumi Insurance, which surged 7.0 percent to 273 agorot on turnover of 12.6 million shekels.</p>
<p>Traders said that Leumi rose on rumours of a big off-the-floor deal made in the company's stocks.</p>
<p>Koor Industries, the third most active share, rose 1.0 percent to 40,130 agorot on volume of 11.9 million shekels.</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211 x233</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
