<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770680" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FedEx cargo plane crash-lands at Newark, N.J.</title>
<headline>FedEx cargo plane crash-lands at Newark, N.J.</headline>
<dateline>NEWARK, N.J. 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Five crew miraculously escaped unhurt when their Federal Express MD-11 cargo plane crash-landed early on Thursday at Newark International Airport, overturned and burst into flames, officials said.</p>
<p>The five flight crew crawled to safety through a cockpit window after the crash at 1:35 a.m. EDT (0535 GMT) about 200 yards (metres) from a terminal, a spokesman for the New York/New Jersey Port Authority said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very hard landing,&quot; Port Authority spokesman Allen Morrison said. &quot;The plane, on impact, flipped over and began to burn. All five crew members on board were able to crawl out the cockpit window.</p>
<p>&quot;They all walked away from it,&quot; Morrison said. They were treated for unspecified minor injuries at Elizabeth General Hospital in Elizabeth, New Jersey.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very pleased that no was injured seriously and we're looking forward to them returning to work,&quot; Fedex spokesman Chris Atkins said at Newark airport.</p>
<p>Hours after the crash, firefighters were still battling the burning, charred wreckage with foam.</p>
<p>The airport, one of the busiest in the United States, was closed for several hours before re-opening at 7.33 a.m. EDT (1133 GMT) for some departures, another Port Authority spokesman said.</p>
<p>Arriving aircraft were being diverted to John F. Kennedy International airport and La Guardia airport in New York, officials said.</p>
<p>The cause of the crash was not known. Officials said National Transportation Safety Board investigators would visit the site to begin their probe once the blaze was extinguished.</p>
<p>&quot;Pieces of the plane are scattered on the runway,&quot; Morrison added. The fuselage was missing both wings and the tail section, witnesses said.</p>
<p>CBS radio quoted a witness as saying he had seen flames coming from the plane before it crashed.</p>
<p>The wide-body aircraft was flying into Newark from Anchorage, Alaska, according to Warren Perkins, a Federal Express Hub Command Centre agent in Memphis.</p>
<p>&quot;It is one of the larger types of aircraft in our fleet,&quot; Perkins said.</p>
<p>Fedex is the world's biggest cargo airline, carrying 3.77 million scheduled freight tonnes in 1996, ahead of Lufthansa with 2.88 million tonnes, according to the International Air Transport Association (IATA).</p>
<p>Fedex, which has 23 MD-11s in its fleet, is also the biggest U.S. domestic cargo carrier, with 2.97 million tonnes last year, ahead of UPS with 2.60 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWARK, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
