<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770777" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: P&amp;U falls as EPS estimates cut 5-10 pct.</title>
<headline>P&amp;U falls as EPS estimates cut 5-10 pct.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Schmelz</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The continuing woes of Swedish-U.S. drug company Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn depressed its share price further on Thursday as analysts cut forecasts by up to 10 percent following a weaker-than-expected second quarter.</p>
<p>P&amp;U, formed through the 1995 merger of Pharmacia of Sweden and the U.S. Upjohn, posted earnings on Tuesday per share (EPS) of $0.34 for the second quarter, down from $0.51 a year before and below market expectations of $0.36.</p>
<p>After rebounding four crowns and 5.5 crowns respectively on the two days following the report, the share slipped back on Thursday, shedding seven crowns to 296.5 by 1400 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;The more people had a chance to look at it, the less they liked what they saw,&quot; said pharmaceuticals analyst Jeff Chaffkin at PaineWebber in New York.</p>
<p>PaineWebber has cut its EPS estimates to $1.50 from $1.60 for calendar 1997 and to $1.75 from $1.95 for 1998.</p>
<p>Chaffkin said portfolio managers used to regard the share as one of the cheaper drug stocks, lagging behind its rivals after a series of profit warnings over the past 10 months.</p>
<p>But closer inspection unveiled stubborn problems.</p>
<p>&quot;The major driver behind reduced earnings estimates is the much higher costs of goods sold,&quot; Chaffkin said. &quot;These problems are not easy fixes.&quot;</p>
<p>Several analysts said the share was in for a rough ride as generic products eroded product prices, especially in the U.S.</p>
<p>Janet Dyson, pharmaceuticals analysts at Merrill Lynch, said she had lowered her EPS estimates for the year to $1.45 from $1.60 before the report, and to $1.70 for 1998 from $1.85.</p>
<p>&quot;We still don't think the difficulties in the generic business have bottomed out. The amount coming in for new drugs is not substantial enough to offset generic pressure,&quot; Dyson told Reuters.</p>
<p>P&amp;U said in its half-year report that many of its products continued to face competition from generic brands.</p>
<p>&quot;This price erosion has balanced out all their cost savings,&quot; said Handelsbanken analyst Stefan Wikholm. &quot;The market thought price erosion may level out, but it's continued.&quot;</p>
<p>Wikholm has lowered his EPS estimates for 1997 to $1.64 from $1.78 and for 1998 to $2.10 from $2.31.</p>
<p>BNP Capital Markets analyst Ian Broadhurst told Reuters he had cut his EPS estimates for 1997 to $1.60 from $1.70 and to $1.80 from $2.10 for 1998.</p>
<p>Analysts said they would examine details of advertised cost cuts very closely.</p>
<p>P&amp;U said on Tuesday it would publish a progress report in the fourth quarter, and some further job losses to be expected.</p>
<p>The company said it would have to take some extraordinary restructuring charges in addition to a charge of 10-16 cents a share in the third quarter for merging P&amp;U's Pharmacia Biotech unit with a division of British Amersham International Plc . Some analysts saw this as another profit warning.</p>
<p>Newly appointed chief executive Fred Hassan has his work cut out to meet his expectations of a turnaround in 1998, Chaffkin said.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect not just (cuts) on the administration side but also in R&amp;D and acceleration of plant consolidation and of the plant closure schedule,&quot; Chaffkin said.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
