<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770918" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss credibility dipping amid Holocaust row - poll.</title>
<headline>Swiss credibility dipping amid Holocaust row - poll.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss image abroad continues to suffer from the crisis over the lost assets of Jews killed by Hitler despite the publication of nearly 2,000 names of foreign holders of dormant wartime accounts, a poll showed on Thursday.</p>
<p>French-language Swiss weekly L'Hebdo said nearly a third of the Americans and the French questioned for the poll said their opinion of Switzerland had deteriorated in recent months because of the simmering conflict with Jewish groups worldwide.</p>
<p>Among ordinary people, a third of the French and nearly 40 percent of Americans surveyed had not heard of the crisis.</p>
<p>But L'Hebdo said the Alpine nation's fall from grace was most notable among decision-makers, managers and high-level professionals in the U.S. and France, nearly half of whom surveyed said Swiss credibility was continuing to suffer.</p>
<p>L'Hebdo's opinion poll was conducted among more than 1,000 respondents in the United States by Gallup and nearly 500 in France by Ifop.</p>
<p>Nearly 70 percent of the U.S. respondents associated the Swiss with money, 30 percent with order and nearly one-fifth with egoism, L'Hebdo said.</p>
<p>Swiss neutrality amidst a warring Europe is under attack as little more than collaboration with Nazis under a different name amid Jewish charges that its banks hoarded the wealth of Holocaust victims and cleared looted Nazi gold.</p>
<p>Swiss banks took an unprecedented step to appease their main critics, the World Jewish Congress (WJC), by breaking secrecy last week to publish over 1,870 names of foreigners who opened Swiss accounts before the end of World War Two in 1945.</p>
<p>But observers say the publication of the list after 52 years of deliberate silence and only under mounting international pressure is not a way back to credibility.</p>
<p>The revelations are part of what has become a familiar pattern of Swiss management of the crisis -- first denial and later a steady drip of information to widespread disbelief.</p>
<p>Critics saw the presence of names similar to leading Nazis in the list as evidence that the notoriously secretive Swiss banks had ignored post-war pressure from the Allies to identify all German assets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
