<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="770989" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW-New Glaxo drugs eclipse Zantac.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-New Glaxo drugs eclipse Zantac.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Glaxo Wellcome Plc said on Thursday that its single biggest drug, anti-ulcer medication Zantac was &quot;disappearing from view&quot; as new products streamed onto the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The new products are powering ahead and driving the growth, and that is what we always said,&quot; chairman and chief executive sir Richard Sykes told Reuters in a telephone interview. &quot;Zantac is disappearing from view.&quot;</p>
<p>Sykes noted that sales of products launched since 1990 were up 50 percent to 1.3 billion stg in the first half of the year, making up one-third of total sales.</p>
<p>He singled out the imminent launches of diabetes drug Romozin and new antibiotic Raxar and newly-launched anti-smoking tablet Zyban as examples of the group's commitment to constant innovation.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the secret of this businesses, to increase new product innovation,&quot; he said. Other drugs with significant potential included migraine treatment Naramig, AIDS treatment 1592 and Lamivudine for hepatitis B as well as Romozin. The latter two products &quot;go into areas of unmet clinical need,&quot; Sykes said.</p>
<p>He repeated his prediction that Zantac sales could drop by 80 to 90 percent in the U.S, where sales of the drug totalled around 400 million stg in the first half of the year, when it eventually faced &quot;full-blooded competition&quot;.</p>
<p>However a squabble among generic manufacturers has delayed competition until the end of August at the earliest. &quot;Every day that we don't face competition benefits us,&quot; Sykes said.</p>
<p>The drug is also expected to continue to grow in Japan, now its second biggest market, where it still enjoys patent protection.  </p>
<p>Sykes said Glaxo would look at acquisitions of products and companies in emerging markets, notably Asia and South America.</p>
<p>He said acquisitions could help to take account of the disparity in treatments and approaches to medicines in different markets. &quot;Latin America is very different to Korea and Taiwan,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company would also continue to pursue its policy of pricing drugs differently in different markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Different pricing is not something we have a big problem with,&quot; said Sykes. &quot;We have to have pricing policies that reflect the different markets and licensing systems.&quot;</p>
<p>Sykes added that Glaxo Wellcome was now gaining support from the market for its strategy to cope with Zantac's decline. &quot;People can see very clearly where we are going.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think the big issue was the merger with Wellcome. That really broadened out the portfolio, with anti-virals now 18 percent of the business, and diluted Zantac out very significantly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Jonathan Birt London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
