<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771020" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - Gilts to pause before attack on 116-02.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Gilts to pause before attack on 116-02.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>September gilt futures may scale back at the open on Thursday, awaiting U.S. GDP data later to provide fuel for testing levels above 116-00, analysts said.</p>
<p>Philip Gardiner, analyst at Technical Data in London, said stochastics and the Relative Strength Index turned down on the hourly chart towards the close on Wednesday, suggesting a slide early in the session.</p>
<p>&quot;If we break below 115-23 there won't be anything to stop us until 115-15,&quot; said Gardiner. That level was Wednesday's low. The high at 116-02 was likely to be initial resistance.</p>
<p>At 0710 GMT, the September gilt was 6/32 down at 115-23.  </p>
<p>Gardiner said further support would come from 115-04, the bottom of a recent congestion area that topped at around 115-23.</p>
<p>Analysts at Chase in London said it was important to hold the trend and Elliott support intervening at 115-02, although a decline below there must be confirmed by a close below 114-30.</p>
<p>They said in a research note short-term support intervened at 115-23 and from there gilts should put trendline resistance at 116-06/09 on weekly and daily charts under pressure.</p>
<p>&quot;It might go above 116-02 but not very far,&quot; said Technical Data's Gardiner. He saw a Fibonacci projection level of 116-13, and above there 117-02 on the weekly chart as the next barriers.  </p>
<p>The U.S. GDP data for the second quarter is due at 1230 GMT, and analysts are looking for a 1.9 percent rise.</p>
<p>Chase analysts said given bullish momentum indicators a drift below 115-02 was unlikely, while the momentum would be further underlined on a break of 116-09, suggesting a move to 117-13 and then to 117-25.</p>
<p>At the short end of the curve, December short sterling futures stood 0.03 down on the day at 92.58.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
