<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771171" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine peso ends steady but still defensive.</title>
<headline>Philippine peso ends steady but still defensive.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippine peso ended steady on Thursday at 29 to the dollar with the central bank the only seller of dollars in the market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;No one else was willing to offer dollars at 29 pesos,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Commercial demand for dollars amid inadequate supply kept the peso defensive throughout the day, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There were not much inflows. Who will be attracted to this kind of market when a lot of restrictions are now in place,&quot; a foreign bank dealer said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't see the same offshore players coming back in the market,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Since the peso was effectively devalued over two weeks ago, the central bank stopped onshore banks from engaging in non-deliverable contracts to sell dollars.</p>
<p>It also cut banks' long dollar positions and reduced the over-the-counter sales limit of dollars per individual.</p>
<p>Traders said exporters are not yet convinced the peso is set to recover, resulting in very thin volumes at the Philippine Dealing System (PDS) as well as in the parallel market.  </p>
<p>Volume at the PDS, the computerised trading of Philippine peso/dollar among banks, had a lower volume of $65.9 million on Thursday versus the previous day's $73.10 million.</p>
<p>-- Lilian Karunungan (63 2) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
