<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771200" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei futures erase losses, seen supported.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei futures erase losses, seen supported.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Nikkei futures bounced back from their early losses to a firm finish on Thursday despite lingering concerns about a growing racketeer scandal surrounding some Japan brokerages.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market looked well-supported on the lower end and was likely to continue trading within its recent ranges because a recent spate of bad news had not pushed it below the psychological 20,000 level, as initially feared.</p>
<p>Nikkei cash and futures markets came under pressure on Wednesday on news of raids on Yamaichi Securities in search of suspected illegal links with racketeers.  </p>
<p>The Ministry of Finance's announcement of a raft of punitive measures against Nomura Securities and Dai-ichi Kangyo Bank for their involvement in a racketeer payoff scandal also contributed to the market's early declines.</p>
<p>The lead Nikkei 225 September contract added 125 points to end at 20,345 after falling as low as 20,040 in early trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a pretty supportive close. The market may go down when there is any bad news but it should otherwise trade between 20,300 and 20,600,&quot; a trader at a U.S. futures house said.</p>
<p>But dealers said the September Nikkei would continue to struggle with resistance above 20,600.  </p>
<p>Taiwan stock index futures ended sharply higher as Taipei share prices soared past the 10,000 threshold to close at a seven-year peak on strong buying of electronics and financial sector shares.</p>
<p>The August MSCI contract added 9.1 points to close at 436.4 on active volume of 2,621 lots.</p>
<p>Refco Singapore Pte Ltd said in a daily commentary sentiment on the SIMEX contract remained bullish, with the participation of Taiwanese investors from August 1 expected to boost volumes.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
