<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771319" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Khmer Rouge say support ousted Prince Ranariddh.</title>
<headline>Khmer Rouge say support ousted Prince Ranariddh.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The political leader of the Khmer Rouge said on Thursday he supported ousted Prince Norodom Ranariddh as Cambodia's first prime minister and he would help oppose the rule of strongman Hun Sen.</p>
<p>Khieu Samphan, one of the main leaders of a Khmer Rouge faction that broke with guerrilla chief Pol Pot, said his political party, the National Solidarity Party, would join all other groups in opposing Hun Sen.</p>
<p>&quot;We still recognise Prince Norodom Ranariddh as the legal first prime minister of the country,&quot; Khieu Samphan said in a guerrilla radio broadcast monitored in Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>&quot;We oppose any nomination to replace Prince Norodom Ranariddh,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Second Prime Minister Hun Sen ousted Ranariddh after two days of fighting in the capital on July 5-6.</p>
<p>Members of Ranariddh's royalist party who stayed in the country after the prince's ouster nominated Foreign Minister Ung Huot to replace Ranariddh as first prime minister.</p>
<p>Hun Sen backs Ung Huot's nomination, but Ranariddh expelled Ung Huot from the royalist FUNCINPEC party.</p>
<p>Before Hun Sen's bloody takeover, Ranariddh was negotiating with Khieu Samphan for peace, the handover of Pol Pot, and for a political alliance.</p>
<p>Khmer Rouge radio has launched regular attacks on Hun Sen since the prince's ouster, deriding him as a &quot;puppet&quot; of Vietnam and calling for opposition to his rule.</p>
<p>&quot;The National Solidarity Party joins and supports all national forces and all political parties who implement policies to oppose and destroy...the puppet Hun Sen,&quot; Khieu Samphan said on Thursday.</p>
<p>He also said Pol Pot was now completely finished and that the National Solidarity Party respected Cambodia's constitution and supported free and fair elections.</p>
<p>Pol Pot, under whose 1975-79 &quot;killing fields&quot; rule more than one million Cambodians died, was condemned by his former comrades and sentenced to life under house arrest at a show trial last Friday.</p>
<p>In a separate development, Hun Sen's forces took full control of the northwestern border town of Poipet after troops loyal to Ranariddh either defected to Hun Sen's side or withdrew to join their comrades in the forest, officials in the town said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The town, the main trading point on Cambodia's border with Thailand, has been tense since Ranariddh's ouster on July 6.</p>
<p>Poipet was controlled by the princes' forces at the time of his ouster, but Hun Sen's troops gradually moved in under local-level agreements. By late on Wednesday, Hun Sen's men were in command.</p>
<p>&quot;The officials of prime minister Hun Sen took full control of the town from late on Wednesday,&quot; police Colonel Haem Thieng told a Reuters reporter visiting the town.</p>
<p>A brief clash between the rival forces on Sunday left four soldiers dead and eight wounded.</p>
<p>A Thai army source on the border said royalist forces from Poipet were apparently heading north to link up with their comrades.</p>
<p>Royalist forces have been pushed back to a remote area in northern Cambodia in clashes with government troops under Hun Sen since the prince's ouster.</p>
<p>Ranariddh and Hun Sen shared power in an unwieldy coalition government formed after a 1993 election organised by the United Nations and narrowly won by Ranariddh.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
