<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771316" id="root" date="1997-07-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASIAN EXOTICS - Regionals succumb to dollar demand.</title>
<headline>ASIAN EXOTICS - Regionals succumb to dollar demand.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southeast Asian currencies came under renewed pressure on Thursday from month-end commercial demand for the dollar and continuing worries about Thailand's economic troubles, dealers said.</p>
<p>The market was awaiting the release later in the day of Thailand's monthly economic data with interest focused on the foreign reserves number.</p>
<p>That would give an indication of how much the central bank spent to defend the baht in June before it effectively devalued the currency on July 2. Since then it has dropped more than 20 percent against the dollar.</p>
<p>On Thursday morning, the baht slipped on dollar purchases by importers and companies while exporters held back from selling dollars ahead of the release of the economic data, due to be released at 0800 GMT.</p>
<p>The baht was quoted at 32.05/32.25 to the dollar at 0400 GMT onshore against 31.900/32.10 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said other currencies in the region were being driven by the fortunes of the baht and sentiment was likely to remain jumpy ahead of the Thai government's rescue package for the ailing economy, due by August 5.</p>
<p>It is  expected to include assistance from the International Monetary Fund (IMF). That has cheered the market, which expects IMF help to include tough measures to right the Thai economy.</p>
<p>The Malaysian ringgit lost its footing again as hedge funds, which were booking profits on the dollar on Wednesday, started dumping the ringgit again.</p>
<p>Dealers said importers and Kuala Lumpur companies were also buying up the dollar and strong bids were seen around the 2.6250 ringgit level. The ringgit was at 2.6350/70 to the dollar against 2.6260/90 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But buying of the ringgit/Singapore dollar cross would provide a temporary cap to dollar/ringgit, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I favour the ringgit/Sing going back to 0.5600 and higher so I would just buy dollar/Sing on any dip,&quot; a European bank dealer in Singapore said.</p>
<p>She said U.S. funds had bought the U.S. dollar against the Singapore unit at the open, pushing it all the way up to 1.4720 after some stop-loss buy orders were triggered at 1.4680.</p>
<p>&quot;I think 1.4720 looks a bit toppish but I would buy on any dips to 1.4690/1.4700. It's better to be long in dollar/Asia at the moment,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The Singapore dollar was at 1.4708/18 to the U.S. dollar against 1.4667/77 late on Wednesday. Ringgit/Sing was at 0.5578/86.</p>
<p>In Indonesia, the rupiah slithered back to the 2,600 level as weakness in the rest of the region and caution ahead of the Thai data prompted dollar buying.</p>
<p>&quot;It's regional rather than rupiah trading. You have to look to other currencies in the region before you can have a view on the local market,&quot; a local bank dealer in Jakarta said.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah was at 2,600 at 0400 GMT against a previous 2,582.00.</p>
<p>The Philippine central bank sold dollars at 29 pesos in early trade and Manila traders said the peso would remain on the defensive despite a new ruling cutting banks' long dollar positions to five percent of capital from 10 percent.</p>
<p>The Taiwan dollar was weak after opening sharply lower on the back of the U.S. dollar's strong tone against major currencies.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected some profit-taking later in the day as the U.S. dollar appeared to have hit a short-term peak after Taiwan's central bank abandoned its defence of the local currency on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Taiwan dollar was quoted at T$28.585/608 against Wednesday's late 28.480.</p>
<p>-- Madhav Reddy in Kuala Lumpur (603-206 2323), Mantik Kusjanto in Jakarta (6221 384-6364), Anchalee Koetsawang in Bangkok (662) 652-0642, Lilian Karunungan in Manila (632-841-8937), Kevin Chen in Taipei (8862-508-0815) and Sonali Desai in Singapore (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-07-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
