<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771596" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-CHELSEA FANS TRADE MEMORY LANE FOR KINGS ROAD.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CHELSEA FANS TRADE MEMORY LANE FOR KINGS ROAD.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sort of Chelsea fan who believes life  begins at 50 and mid-life crises are for youngsters may have a sense  of deja vu at the Charity Shield on Sunday.</p>
<p>The rest, including all the players and manager Ruud Gullit, could  be about to experience the totally unfamiliar in one of English soccer's  classic north-south battles.</p>
<p>Winning at Wembley will not be a novelty -- Chelsea did that in the  F.A. Cup final last season.</p>
<p>But capturing the traditional curtain-raiser to the league season  would be a first for a generation or two of fans.</p>
<p>Chelsea have done it only once before, 42 years ago, and few lovers  of &quot;the Blues&quot; can remember that.</p>
<p>Sunday will therefore be a trip down memory lane, rather than the  more familiar Kings Road, only for the older fan.</p>
<p>Chairman Ken Bates's schooldays were well behind him when Chelsea  beat Newcastle 3-0 at Stamford Bridge in 1955 for the Shield, the  year of the Londoners only league title to date. But other members  of the staff have a less distant recall.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been here the longest and it certainly rules me out,&quot; said one  female club official.</p>
<p>The only other occasion that Chelsea have qualified for the Shield  -- In 1970 when they lost 2-1 to league champions Everton -- also  seems lost in the thick mists of time.</p>
<p>It may be the start of August but the arrival of the Shield means  the summer and its focus on cricket is effectively over for the nation's  soccer lovers.</p>
<p>In one week the serious action starts with the premier league back  in full flow and both Chelsea and Manchester United high on the lists  of likely champions.</p>
<p>In some ways this year's Shield pits the traditional powers of the  game against the parvenus -- at least in money and merchandising terms  if not pure soccer ones.</p>
<p>Chelsea have opened a new megastore and have invested heavily on the  sort of foreign players who would never have graced the club of 10  years ago, let alone 40, in a genuine championship challenge to take  on the traditional big spenders.</p>
<p>United, the masters of marketing who long ago learned the importance  of merchandise sales and bourse listings in funding the club's development,  will be chasing their 14th Charity Shield triumph in 16 appearances  since 1908.</p>
<p>Such has been their recent dominance that last season they arrived  at Wembley as both league champions and cup winners and thrashed league  runners-up Newcastle 4-0.</p>
<p>United started the season as they finished it, as champions, but this  year they embark on the post-Cantona era after the retirement of French  striker Eric for a new career outside soccer.</p>
<p>England striker Teddy Sheringham, formerly of Chelsea's north London  rivals Tottenham, fills the gap left by Eric. Cries of &quot;Ooh, ah, Sheringham&quot;  are not to be expected.</p>
<p>United manager Alex Ferguson has selection worries, with last season's  leading scorer Ole-Gunnar Solskjaer definitely out of action because  of an injury that threatens to sideline him for the first month of  the new season.</p>
<p>Ferguson's hopes of signing Brazilian defender Celio Silva were also  dashed after he was refused a work permit.</p>
<p>Gary Pallister and Gary Neville are recovering from injuries but Jordi  Cruyff, son of Johan, has been in impressive form.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
