<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77159" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan August forex reserves rise to US$86.387 bln.</title>
<headline>Taiwan August forex reserves rise to US$86.387 bln.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's foreign exchange reserves rose to US$86.387 billion at the end of August from US$86.124 billion a month earlier, the central bank said in a statement on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>The bank gave no immediate interpretation of the rise.</p>
<p>Taiwan's foreign exchange reserves, the world's third largest after Japan and China, fell in late 1995 and early 1996 as political tensions with rival China intensified into a military crisis in March, triggering heavy capital outflows.</p>
<p>The trend reversed after Taiwan's March 23 presidential election and a clear easing of tensions with China. The reserves have risen slowly but steadily since April.</p>
<p>Beijing held war games and missile tests in the Taiwan strait in the run-up to the presidential poll, triggering waves of U.S. dollar buying and a run on gold.</p>
<p>The central bank intervened during the crisis to support the Taiwan dollar and the island's hyper-sensitive stock market.</p>
<p>Taiwan's foreign reserves peaked at $100.412 billion in June 1995.</p>
<p>    Period	 August 1996    July 1996    August 1995</p>
<p>    Reserves	  86.387	 86.124	 92.988</p>
<p>NOTE - Foreign currency reserves in billions of U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (2-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
