<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771601" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: ATHLETICS-KENYAN PREPARATIONS HAMPERED BY HAPHAZARD SELECTIONS.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-KENYAN PREPARATIONS HAMPERED BY HAPHAZARD SELECTIONS.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenyan preparations for the sixth world  championships starting on Saturday have been hampered by the most  haphazard selection and training policies for decades.</p>
<p>The Kenyan selectors said the first two finishers at the national  trials in June would automatically win a place on the team, with a  third slot based on Grand Prix circuit form.</p>
<p>But that policy was thrown out the window without any explanation  and as a result Kenya will not field a 4x400 metres relay team nor  will hurdler Erick Keter take part in Athens.</p>
<p>There is no place for a third 1,500 metres runner, no field athlete,  no sprinters and just three women in the Kenyan team.</p>
<p>In addition a number of elite runners have shunned high-altitude training  at the foot of Mount Kenya, the camp for all major championships since  1972, in favour of London. The Kenya Amateur Athletic Association  did not pay for the London camp and could not therefore exert any  control.</p>
<p>The association also allowed seven other athletes, including Commonwealth  800 metres champion, Patrick Konchellah, to train at home near Nairobi.</p>
<p>Despite the chaos, Kenyans remain optimistic about their prospects  following a disappointing Olympics in Atlanta last year.</p>
<p>&quot;I can assure everybody that we will give it our best performance,&quot;  said Kenyan delegation leader Patrick Kiambata. &quot;The team is in high  spirits and promises gold.&quot;</p>
<p>Kenya's major gold prospects lie in world steeplechase champion and  record holder Moses Kiptanui plus training partner and friend Daniel  Komen, who will compete in the 5,000 metres.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to win the steeplechase again. After that I will just hang  on and try to win an Olympic gold. That is my plan for the moment,&quot;  Kiptanui said.</p>
<p>&quot;All is well and we are both physically and psychologically prepared  for the championship. We are very sure we will have a similar success  as in the world cross country championships in Italy last March,&quot;  said women's 5,000 metres hopeful Lydia Cheromei.</p>
<p>Konchellah, younger brother of former world champion Billy Konchellah,  sees himself as the only man who could come between Kenyan-born Dane  Wilson Kipketer and another world championship gold.</p>
<p>&quot;Kip is very strong and we all admit the fact that he is one of the  best athletes of all time and also a major sensation at the games  but I can assure you that we are putting up a very spirited fight  for this gold,&quot; Konchellah said.</p>
<p>Konchellah has run the fourth fastest time of the year and last beat  Kipketer in a race in Belgium in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;I have planned well for the race and all I can say is that the altitude  training here has given me a great boost,&quot; said Konchellah, who returned  to Kenya after finishing second to Kipketer when he equalled the world  record in Stockholm this month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
