<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771881" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Tanzanian shilling boosted by Kenya inflows.</title>
<headline>Tanzanian shilling boosted by Kenya inflows.</headline>
<dateline>DAR ES SALAAM 1997-07-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Tanzanian shilling, boosted  by capital inflows from Kenya, has defied market expectations of a  post-budget slide, financial analysts and dealers said on Friday.</p>
<p>The shilling exchanged at a commercial mean rate of 624.7890 against  the dollar compared to 624.8088 on Thursday, the central bank said.  The shilling stood at 624.1059 against the dollar on July 19, the  date of Tanzania's budget.</p>
<p>Against the pound the shilling exchanged at a mean rate 1024.9695  from 1024.5646 on Thursday, the bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of money coming into the market from Kenya and that  is having the effect of keeping the T-shilling firm, much more firm  than would be expected in the post budget situation,&quot; a senior financial  analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;It (Kenyan capital) is having a mild destabilising effect on the  foreign exchange market in Tanzania, but in a positive way. Tanzania  is definitely a beneficiary of capital flight from Kenya -- it's hot  money,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Estimates of the amount of capital inflows to Tanzania from Kenya  ran to $12 million over the past month, the analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;For a small market like this that is not a little amount,&quot; he said,  adding Kenyan investors were attracted by Tanzania's political stability.</p>
<p>In July the interbank forex market traded $50-$60 million, $10-$12  million more than average.</p>
<p>&quot;Supply has definitely increased...We've suddenly seen more bullish  activity on the interbank market,&quot; said one trader employed by a prominent  foreign bank.</p>
<p>The Kenyan shilling weakened in Nairobi on Friday after the International  Monetary Fund halted a key aid package to Kenya because of corruption,  damaging its international credibility and scaring short-term foreign  investors in the country.</p>
<p>Financial analysts in Dar es Salaam said if Kenya's economic and political  problems were protracted then investors would keep their money in  Tanzania and its shilling might even strengthen.</p>
<p>Nine people died in Kenya on July 7 when police moved against political  rallies by constitutional reform campaigners. Kenya must hold elections  by the end of this year, though no date has been set.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAR ES SALAAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
