<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="771899" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: Ivorian land laws tighten title rules for farmers.</title>
<headline>Ivorian land laws tighten title rules for farmers.</headline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ivory Coast is to establish new land laws  aimed at clarifying title over property in an attempt to facilitate  farm credit decisions and property transactions.</p>
<p>&quot;The bill will remedy the lack of any real rural land ownership legislation  in a mainly agricultural country,&quot; the government said in a statement  after a cabinet meeting late on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The policy will be realistic in that it recognises common law rights...after  an investigation and evidence of peaceful occupation,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Under the new law, rural land would be considered separate from public,  urban and protected forest categories.</p>
<p>As a first step, land certificates for individual or collective holders  of recognised common law title would be issued before final registration  of ownership, the statement said.</p>
<p>Ivorian nationals' existing rights to land would be unaffected and  unattributed land would belong to the state. Applicants had three  years to conform with new laws.</p>
<p>The bill shows the government's intention to clarify rural landownership  and create a real market in property ownership with a mechanism for  sale and rent, the statement said, pointing to requests from young  farmers and financial organisations for such clarification.</p>
<p>Poorly defined land laws have been cited by local crop analysts as  one reason for indiscriminate slash-and-burn farming with little attempt  to achieve maximum crop yields from plots.</p>
<p>Ivory Coast's founding president Felix Houphouet-Boigny gave cocoa  planters a common law right to land they planted and encouraged a  wave of internal migration of aspiring cocoa farmers as well as newcomers  from countries such as Burkina Faso to the north.</p>
<p>Cocoa production rose to make Ivory Coast the world's largest producer  -- with about 40 percent of output. It notched up a record 1.2 million  tonnes in the 1995/96 season.</p>
<p>Ivory Coast recently embarked on a policy of evicting coffee and cocoa  farmers from dwindling protected forests, forcing foreign and non-local  farmers out of encampments onto adjacent non-protected land.</p>
<p>The policy is aimed at preventing further destruction of forest cover  essential for favourable climate for legal farms elsewhere, as well  as promoting sustainable forestry.</p>
<p>It was also aimed at cutting Ivorian cocoa production to less than  a million tonnes a year, to support world prices.</p>
<p>Ivory Coast classified certain forests as protected in 1973 but officials  say many farmers settled in them after that and therefore have no  common rights over land they have farmed. Many have been away from  their homes for long periods.</p>
<p>Property developers have complained of land shortages and rising prices  in growing urban areas such as the commercial capital, Abidjan. --Matthew  Bunce, Abidjan newsroom + 225 21 90 90</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
