<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772165" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - August 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - August 1.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights in the Bosnian  press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not  vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DNEVNI AVAZ</p>
<p>- High representative in Bosnia Carlos Westendorp urges the Bosnian  Council of Ministers to harmonise their positions after they failed  to adopt a law on citizenship and passports during Thursday's session.</p>
<p>- High Representative in Bosnia called the laws on citizenship, passports  and opening of the three Bosnian airports for civilian traffic the  gravest issues at the moment.</p>
<p>- The international community is getting very tired of the lack of  commitment to the peace process shown by those who claim to represent  the people of this country, says the spokesman of the office of High  Representative.</p>
<p>- The Moslem-Croat federation parliament's House of Representatives  decided to form a committee to investigate the validity of British  Foreign Secretary's accusations on alleged corruption of Bosnia's  administration.</p>
<p>- The Moslem leading Party of Democratic Action (SDA) says British  Foreign Secretary Robin Cook was a &quot;victim of misinformation&quot;.</p>
<p>- There has been no malversation or abuse of funds and equipment that  go through the World Bank says Saumya Mitra, deputy director to the  World Bank Mission in Sarajevo.</p>
<p>OSLOBODJENJE</p>
<p>- The president of the Bosnian Trade Union, Sulejman Hrle, at a meeting  with International Labour Organisation coordinator for Bosnia Herbert  Schmidt, said Moslem and Croat workers in Bosnia's Serb entity and  Moslems and Serbs in so-called Herzeg-Bosnia are being fired because  of their ethnic origin.</p>
<p>- The International Labour Organisation will insist on the application  of an ILO convention which prohibits the dismissal of workers on the  basis of their nationality.</p>
<p>--Sarajevo newsroom +387 71 663 864</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
