<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772182" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: FEATURE - Romania to resist upward pressure on leu.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Romania to resist upward pressure on leu.</headline>
<byline>Mirela Eremia</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania has achieved a measure of economic  stability but should carefully manage its currency policies to avoid  large exchange rate swings, analysts say.</p>
<p>Growing foreign inflows, boosted by market liberalisation and pledges  of reform eight months after the election of a centrist government,  brought the leu currency back to 7,100 to the dollar after slipping  to a record low of 9,000 in February.</p>
<p>Central bank and government officials insist they want to keep the  currency stable, countering the pressure for it to appreciate to keep  Romanian exporters competitive.</p>
<p>&quot;The key issue now is to avoid large (leu) fluctuations,&quot; said central  bank (BNR) chief economist Daniel Daianu in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We need an exchange rate policy that stimulates exports. This does  not necessarily imply depreciation but should avoid loss of competitive  edge from appreciation.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the foreign inflows that put the upward pressure on the leu  have been spurred by swiftly rising yields, growing liquidity in Romanian  equities and by fresh investor-friendly legislation. Strong gains  were posted on the bourse, in operation for 18 months, and on the  more recently opened over-the-counter market.</p>
<p>INVESTORS' MOTTO WAS &quot;BUY EVERYTHING YOU CAN STOMACH'</p>
<p>Officials say portfolio inflows in recent months have ranged between  $100 million to $200 million. Analysts said regional investment funds  had committed around $400 million this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people bought earlier on the market's potential rather than  fundamentals,&quot; said Marcel Cobuz, vice president of Creditanstalt  Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The motto originally was 'buy everything you can stomach'. It later  changed into 'buy everything worthwhile.'&quot;</p>
<p>Among the first to enter the market were hedge funds, who ventured  to take a bite even before some key legislation was put in place,  analysts said.</p>
<p>Current rules say repatriation of initial investment and capital gains  is free and set a tax of up to 1.5 percent on each portfolio deal.  But foreigners' access to government securities has yet to be clarified.</p>
<p>However, analysts said, inter-company loans or special deposits allowed  some foreign funds to invest in high-returning Romanian T-bills earlier  this year.</p>
<p>CAPITAL INFLOWS HELP LEU, BUILD RESERVES</p>
<p>As dollars flooded the market, the BNR tried to keep the leu from  rising by soaking up hard currency and building consistent foreign  reserves, now at $2 billion and seen rising to $3 billion or even  $4 billion by end of the year.</p>
<p>Reserves would allow the BNR to resist attacks on the currency if  portfolio investors withdraw, creating a devaluation pressure on the  foreign exchange market.</p>
<p>Last week, the market underwent a first test with dollar demand surging  on profit-taking in equities, depressing the leu more than 2.5 percent  in a day to 7,400/600 to the dollar.</p>
<p>The BNR intervened within 24 hours to stop a steeper fall, but some  analysts said it should have reacted much more quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;The BNR has reserves to resist outflows,&quot; said one analyst. &quot;But  it should prove its ability to prevent large capital outflows turning  into a trend of massive repatriation.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts said the portfolio regime might be too liberal. That  could make it difficult to introduce restrictions in case of a massive  capital outflow.</p>
<p>Yet the advantage of a liquid market is that it encourages investors  and makes central bank policies more flexible.</p>
<p>&quot;Any restrictions are perceived as a bad signal for investors even  though they are meant to protect economic stability,&quot; said a local  banker.</p>
<p>Daianu said Romania should rely on inflows from foreign direct investment  rather than more volatile portfolio capital to ensure sound funding  of trade deficits after economic growth resumes.</p>
<p>He said the BNR would closely monitor portfolio money flows: &quot;We will  not give up our goal to preserve stability and we will react accordingly.&quot;</p>
<p>Romania has limited convertibility, applicable to current account  operations. It allows companies to retain hard currency earnings and  the leu floats freely without corridors.</p>
<p>LEU'S RISE SHOULD BE AVOIDED</p>
<p>Analysts say foreign capital would continue to pour into Romania,  perceived as one of the region's hottest markets after Russia. This  trend, they said, would keep an upward pressure on the currency.</p>
<p>&quot;If investors' appetite stays high, the leu will no longer have problems  with the traditional pressure from winter fuel imports,&quot; said one  economist. &quot;But we will have to resist pressure to push up the currency.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said reining in upward movement of the leu, that could later  produce an equally strong trend downward, was a vital follow-up to  measures which have started to keep in check inflation and deficits.</p>
<p>Estimated monthly inflation in July has been put at less than two  percent, the lowest this year, after the freeing of prices pushed  the figure up to more than 30 percent in March.</p>
<p>The trade balance has also shown sharp improvement, with the deficit  shrinking to $339.9 million in the first five months of the year from  $783.1 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Economists say higher exports will underpin a sound recovery in view  of continued declines in output and consumption after the introduction  of tough monetary policies.</p>
<p>&quot;The exchange rate shouldn't suffocate exports,&quot; said one economist.  &quot;There is the danger of building larger current account deficits if  the exchange rate has an inappropriate level when the economy takes  off again.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
