<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772301" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican vigilantes nearly lynch 17 &quot;delinquents&quot;.</title>
<headline>Mexican vigilantes nearly lynch 17 &quot;delinquents&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>CARDENAS, Mexico 1997-07-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>An angry mob of about 700 villagers  in this town in southeastern Mexico rounded up 17 alleged delinquents  and burned their homes, local official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Police eventually rescued the 17 men from the mob on Thursday after  20 hours in captivity. They were turned them over to authorities with  the state of Tabasco, officials said.</p>
<p>The assault began on Wednesday when five homes belonging to the 17  men were set afire, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Angry villagers told Reuters they were willing to lynch the men, whom  they accused of a series of assaults, robberies, burglaries and the  stealing of crops.</p>
<p>&quot;We want justice. We don't want them here,&quot; Jose Garica Garcia, elected  leader of the community of Indepedencia, told Reuters. Garcia, however,  was not a member of the mob.</p>
<p>Independencia is a communal property, or edijo, in the state of Tabasco  about 30 miles (45 km) southeast of the state capital Villahermosa.  Tabasco is a tropical state near the Yucatan peninsula.</p>
<p>Earlier this year three alleged thieves were taken from their homes,  beaten, doused with gasoline and nearly lynched in this corn- and  sugar-cane-growing town.</p>
<p>Villagers on Thursday said the band's recent attack on a married couple  was the last straw in an alleged crime spree.</p>
<p>After rounding up the 17 men, the mob took them to the centre of town,  where a list of allegations was read publicly and the men declared  guilty. It was then that police intervened, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Independencia itself is home to about 300 families, but leaders of  the mob enlisted the help of angry residents from five nearby communities  for the vigilante rampage, Garcia said.</p>
<p>Police took no action against the mob.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-07-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARDENAS, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
