<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772371" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Hills falls into pothole on Were &quot;sell&quot;.</title>
<headline>Hills falls into pothole on Were &quot;sell&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Hills Motorway Ltd fell nine cents  or over four percent to A$1.96 in active trading on Friday after broker  J.B. Were posted a &quot;sell&quot; recommendation on the stock and estimated  a lower fair value range for the shares.</p>
<p>Market sources told Reuters earlier on Friday that Were had issued  a report late last month estimating a fair value range of A$1.35 to  A$1.66 a share.</p>
<p>The report estimated the M2 motorway operated by Hills would generate  long term average daily traffic volumes of about 49,800 vehicles,  well below Hills' prospectus forecasts of 72,000 by the end of 1998.   </p>
<p>The sources said Were's fair value range had increased by about 10  cents since the initial recommendation three weeks ago because of  falling bond yields, but it remained below Hills' closing price of  A$2.05 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Hills announced on July 15 that average daily traffic in June, the  motorway's first month of operation, was 39,801 vehicles. This prompted  a selloff in Hills' shares despite the company's comments that it  was too early to say what long term volumes would be and that volumes  usually rose in the first few months of operation as commuters learned  how to use the road.  </p>
<p>Hills' shares fell in early Friday trade to A$1.95, just above its  six-month intra-day low of A$1.90 reached on July 21.</p>
<p>They have now fallen 19 percent from the 1997 intra-day high of A$2.42  on June 4.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020041">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
