<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772472" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: TIFFE settles down after renewing contract high.</title>
<headline>TIFFE settles down after renewing contract high.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aug 1 settlement  prev settlement</p>
<p> TIFFE Euroyen 3M (H)     99.19		  99.20</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The key March three-month TIFFE euroyen futures  contract eased on Friday after renewing its contract high on weak  stocks and gains in Japanese government bonds (JGBs). But profit-taking  then emerged, taking it lower.</p>
<p>JGBs rose on talk that Japan's July domestic vehicle sales would drop  20 percent. But sales developed after the actual data showed a fall  of 10.1 percent. It was the fourth straight month in which domestic  sales had fallen year-on-year.  </p>
<p>Euroyen futures moved in tandem, rising to renew their contract high  of 99.22 on the rumours and then edging back down again after profit-taking  emerged at that level, traders said.</p>
<p>Key March settled at 99.19, down from 99.20 on Thursday. Volume was  40,620 contracts.</p>
<p>Although some traders have said a decisive break over 99.22 could  lead the March quickly to 99.25 and then 99.28, others said this is  unlikely at present, with 99.22 becoming a resistance amid worries  the contract may have been overbought. &quot;Given the current high levels,  we'd need very clear signs the economy's really bad to push March  much higher,&quot; one said.  </p>
<p>Others said the March is likely to consolidate at current levels,  but that continuing bullish sentiment will keep the downside solid  near 99.15.</p>
<p>&quot;There is good bargain-hunting interest, so the downside is likely  to remain well-supported,&quot; one trust bank trader said.</p>
<p>Weak Tokyo stocks also gave euroyen futures support. The Nikkei average  ended down by 527.05 at 19,804.38.</p>
<p>Overnight call money was trading at around 0.50 percent, and traders  said the weighted average was likely to be 0.50 percent as well, unchanged  from Thursday. Strong funds demand despite a generous Bank of Japan  (BOJ) operation kept it firm.  </p>
<p>The BOJ injected a net 400 billion yen into the money market in its  morning operation, keeping the market in surplus by about 300 billion  yen.</p>
<p>Short-term fund demand is quite strong as interest in certificates  of deposit (CDs) and other longer money market instruments wanes in  the face of increasing signs that there will be no changes in Japanese  interest rates for some time, and this is keeping the overnight rate  firm, traders said.</p>
<p>Overseas banks appeared to be remarkably active in raising funds through  the overnight call market on Friday, also helping maintain the firm  tone, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;There appear to be some foreign banks who are finding it difficult  to convert funds to yen due to current conditions in the foreign exchange  market, so they are choosing to raise funds in yen directly through  the overnight call market,&quot; one overseas bank trader said.</p>
<p>Around 10 billion yen worth of three-month CDs was issued at 0.63  percent, unchanged from Thursday. Around 30 billion yen of two-month  CDs were issued at 0.64 percent, down from 0.65 percent on Wednesday,  the last day they were issued.</p>
<p>--Elaine Lies, +81-3-3432-8806</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
