<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772464" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine peso ends barely changed.</title>
<headline>Philippine peso ends barely changed.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippine peso closed barely changed  on Friday as the central bank kept up its defence of the local currency  by selling dollars, traders said.</p>
<p>The peso settled at 28.99 to the dollar from the previous close of  29. Volume was at $59.3 million with the central bank accounting for  about 3/4 of the sales at the rates of 28.99/29, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders said banks have started selling their dollars in compliance  with the new ruling of the central bank cutting their long dollar  positions to five percent from 10 percent of capital.  </p>
<p>&quot;But they were unloading to meet the pent-up demand of commercial  clients,&quot; a trader said, forcing the central bank to also sell dollars  to banks.</p>
<p>However, banks have started to sell dollars to clients at lower rates,  encouraged by the fact the central bank was always in the market to  sell dollars, one trader said.</p>
<p>In the parallel market, the dollar was being exchanged for pesos at  a softer rate of 29.20/29.30 versus the previous day's 29.30/29.35.   </p>
<p>But other traders said the pressure on the peso may not ease yet because  of the import season which lasts up to October and the reluctance  of exporters to sell their dollars because of the currency volatility  persisting in the region.</p>
<p>-- Lilian Karunungan (63 2) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
