<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77257" id="root" date="1996-09-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: EU meets Iran, hopes for Rushdie progress.</title>
<headline>EU meets Iran, hopes for Rushdie progress.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Nicholas Doughty, Diplomatic Correspondent</p>
<p>The European Union held a top-level meeting with Iran on Tuesday and said it was determined to find a solution to the long-running crisis over British author Salman Rushdie.</p>
<p>Rushdie has been in hiding since Iran issued a &quot;fatwa&quot; or religious edict condemning him to death in 1989 for alleged blasphemy against Islam in his novel &quot;The Satanic Verses.&quot; The EU has been trying to get Tehran to drop the edict.</p>
<p>Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring, whose country currently holds the EU presidency, told reporters after meeting Iranian Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velyati in New York that they had not discussed the Rushdie affair.</p>
<p>&quot;It was obvious to both sides that discussions that have taken place haven't matured to a stage where you would actually be making decisions,&quot; Spring said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking for a solution, we are determined to find a solution.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign ministers from EU members the Netherlands and Italy were also present at the meeting, on the sidelines of the U.N. General Assembly.</p>
<p>Spring said they had discussed the Middle East peace process, the plight of the Kurds in northern Iraq, Bosnia and other issues.</p>
<p>Velayati declined comment on the Rushdie affair but said relations between Tehran and the EU had improved, although differences remained.</p>
<p>Dutch Foreign Minister Hans van Mierlo said EU foreign ministers would discuss the Rushdie question at a regular meeting in Brussels next week.</p>
<p>&quot;We thought it was better to postpone (the discussion) a bit...I'm not pessimistic,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Earlier, diplomats had said news reports of an imminent deal with Iran on Rushdie were exaggerated.</p>
<p>Some reports suggested Iran was prepared to give commitments that it would not send anyone to kill Rushdie or assist others in killing him, but Tehran says the fatwa, issued by Iran's late spiritual leader Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomein, cannot be revoked formally.</p>
<p>Iran's Foreign Ministry repeated that in a statement on Tuesday in Tehran, saying the death edict was irrevocable.</p>
<p>Although the statement also said the Iranian government would not send anyone to kill the author, European officials said this would probably be insufficient without a further commitment to prevent others from doing so.</p>
<p>Iran's government has already rejected an EU request for a written declaration that it would not carry out the fatwa and would seek to restrain Iranians from trying to do so.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the terms of any agreement would have to be acceptable to Rushdie, who has made more public appearances in the past year in an attempt to lead a more normal life.</p>
<p>The United States wants its European allies to cut off all links with Iran, which Washington regards as a sponsor of terrorism. Iran denies those charges.</p>
<p>Despite U.S. pressure, the European Union has refused to suspend what it says is a &quot;critical dialogue&quot; with Iran.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
