<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772556" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: HK govt sees no outright property speculation now.</title>
<headline>HK govt sees no outright property speculation now.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong Secretary for Housing Dominic  Wong said on Friday that the territory's real estate market was currently  dominated by end-users and he saw no current need to impose measures  against property speculators.</p>
<p>But he told Reuters that the government continued to monitor the property  market and did not rule out future action.</p>
<p>The government would make a &quot;conscious decision&quot; if speculation became  rife, Wong said.</p>
<p>&quot;A very, very high proportion of buyers are now end-users,&quot; he said  in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no outright speculative activities.&quot;  </p>
<p>Wong said the government's announcement last month that it would increase  housing and land supply had helped cool escalating property prices.  While the government was looking at possible measures to impose if  speculation became rife, he said so far &quot;the need is not indicated&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation has not got to a point that we will do it but it does  not mean that we will not do it,&quot; said Wong.</p>
<p>&quot;Here I am dispelling some of the wrong statements that some people  in the market seemed to have put out that the government are not doing  anything. That is wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>Wong said while the government did not want to impose measures on  speculators &quot;unless absolutely necessary&quot;, it wanted speculators to  stay out of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Although it has been our policy not to intervene in a free market,  we do believe that to some extent housing is a necessity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We would not like to see the property market shooting all the way  up so as to preclude people from purchasing their own properties,&quot;  said Wong.</p>
<p>-- Jennifer Genevieve (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
