<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772539" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shenzhen B shares end up on Bengang rally.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen B shares end up on Bengang rally.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's hard currency B share index  closed slightly up on Friday, fuelled mainly by gains in market newcomer  Bengang Steel Plates, analysts said.</p>
<p>The index edged up 1.25 points or 0.97 percent to 130.86 on turnover  of HK$63 million against Thursday's HK$43 million.</p>
<p>The domestic A share index gained 1.96 point or 0.48 percent to 409.46  points on turnover of 3.8 billion yuan against 4.4 billion yuan in  the previous session.</p>
<p>&quot;The rise in B shares was mainly triggered by a rebound in Bengang,&quot;  an analyst at China Guotai Securities said. &quot;And the rebound was because  the share has been oversold.&quot;  </p>
<p>Bengang closed up HK$0.06 or 2.99 percent at HK$2.07 on volume of  2.3 million shares, placing it at the top of the B share active list.</p>
<p>Bengang, listed in early July at HK$2.38 per share, is the first B  share listed in 1997 to remain below its offer price since its debut.  Bengang listed in early July.</p>
<p>Analysts said some institutions intended pushing up Bengang to pave  the way for upcoming new issues.</p>
<p>&quot;Some investors are waiting for the listing of Lutai,&quot; an analyst  at the Sun Hung Kai Investment Services Ltd said.  </p>
<p>Lutai Textile Joint Stock Co Ltd launched an initial public offering  of 80 million B shares from Thursday. The share issue, scheduled for  completion by August 5, was priced at HK$1.93 per share for listing  in Shenzhen.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Petrochemical was the best performer in the B share market,  gaining HK$0.18 or 8.33 percent to HK$2.34 on volume of 3,000 shares.</p>
<p>Building materials producer Shenzhen Fangda Industrial Co, was supported  by institutional demand on confidence in the company's 1997 interim  profits, brokers said.  </p>
<p>The issue advanced HK$0.73 or 6.47 percent to HK$12.01 on volume of  1.6 million shares, the day's third most actively traded counter.</p>
<p>Fangda contributed to the B share index rise, analysts said.</p>
<p>There were signs some foreinn investors were diverting their funds  into B shares from the Hong Kong stock market, where profit-taking  had emerged after recent strong rises, traders said.</p>
<p>Brokers said the A share market was still undergoing consolidation,  adding A share trading lacked clear direction.  </p>
<p>Yantian Harbour was the biggest A share gainer and the most actively  traded issue, firming 0.96 yuan or 8.37 percent to 12.43 yuan on volume  of 26.8 million shares.</p>
<p>Trading in Gintian Industry (Group) Co's A and B shares was suspended  on Friday morning, when the Shenzhen-based conglomerate announced  its 1997 interim results.</p>
<p>The company posted net profits 13.85 million yuan for the first half  of 1997, down 54 percent from 29.84 milion yuan in the year-ago period.   </p>
<p>Gintian, a conglomerate involved in real estate development, textile  and foreign trade, was the first of the 49 Shenzhen-listed B share  companies to release its 1997 interim earnings.</p>
<p>Trading in the company's shares resumed in the afternoon, with its  B shares closing down HK$0.06 at HK$2.35 and A shares off 0.28 yuan  at 7.77 yuan.</p>
<p>Domestic A share counter First Automobile Works Car Co Ltd reported  a 59 percent surge in first half 1997 profits to 219.64 million yuan,  from 138.37 million in the year-ago period.  </p>
<p>Its last share trade was at 11.43 yuan, up 0.49 yuan in afternoon  trading after a morning suspension for its results announcement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
