<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772733" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - August 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - August 1.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Manila newspapers  on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch  for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- Gasoline prices are going up by an average of 47 centavos per litre  effective today, the biggest increase since the government fully deregulated  the oil industry in February. Oil firms say they raised prices to  recover losses arising from the recent peso devaluation. (ALL NEWSPAPERS)</p>
<p>- Manila Mayor Alfredo Lim is stopped temporarily by the Pasig regional  trial court from continuing his spray-painting of suspected drug pushers'  houses to hound them out of the city. (STANDARD/CHRONICLE/INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- Drug lords are behind the smear campaign against politicians to  divert attention from the government's determined campaign against  illegal drugs, President Ramos says. (JOURNAL/BULLETIN)</p>
<p>				 +++++++++</p>
<p>BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>- Philippine Long Distance Telephone Co posts a net profit of 3.75  billion pesos for the first half of 1997, an increase of 28.6 percent  from the year-earlier 2.92 billion despite intensified competition  in the industry. (ALL NEWSPAPERS)</p>
<p>- The move of the central bank to lower the limit on long dollar positions  of banks to five percent from 10 percent of capital is expected to  release some $200 million into the system, central bank governor Gabriel  Singson says. (INQUIRER/BULLETIN)</p>
<p>- San Miguel Corp made a profit of 2.89 billion pesos during the first  six months of 1997, an increase of 20 percent from 2.41 billion pesos  in the same period last year. (ALL NEWSPAPERS)</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
