<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772768" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Car bomb blast in Turkish Islamist escape bid.</title>
<headline>Car bomb blast in Turkish Islamist escape bid.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A car bomb exploded in central Turkey on  Friday in an apparent attempt to free eight Islamist convicts being  carried to court in an armoured prison vehicle, Anatolian news agency  said.</p>
<p>It said three gendarmerie police and an inmate were wounded in the  attack in the arid province of Kirsehir. Other gendarmes sealed off  the area and prevented the suspects from escaping, the state-run agency  said.</p>
<p>&quot;A bomb loaded into a car at the side of the road was set off by remote  control...as the armoured prison vehicle was going past,&quot; Anatolian  quoted local official Osman Gurbuz as saying.</p>
<p>The prisoners face the death sentence on charges of forming an armed  group with the intention of changing Turkey's secularist constitution.</p>
<p>They were being taken to Ankara for a retrial in their case, related  to the killing of 37 people, most of them members of a liberal, heterodox  Moslem sect, in an Islamist arson attack in 1993.</p>
<p>Turkish courts sometimes issue death sentences although no one has  been executed in Turkey since the early 1980s.</p>
<p>The eight were among 41 people originally sentenced to 15 years each  for the arson attack, in the city of Sivas. The appeals court later  called for retrials and tougher sentences.</p>
<p>Police stepped up security measures near mosques throughout Turkey  to prevent expected Islamist protests after Friday noon prayers at  government plans to curb religious education.</p>
<p>Witnesses said police armoured cars took up position at key spots  in the centre of Ankara. Uniformed and plainclothes police milled  around outside the Grand Mosque in Diyarbakir, the main city in the  mainly Kurdish southeast.</p>
<p>Police on Tuesday detained more than 50 people at a large Islamist  rally in Ankara that turned violent.</p>
<p>Islamist anger at Turkey's secularist establishment has risen since  Islamist Pime Minister Necmettin Erbakan resigned under military pressure  in June.</p>
<p>He was replaced by secularist Mesut Yilmaz who has vowed to carry  out a key military demand to restrict the scope of Islamic schools.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
