<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772793" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares rise in mixed trade.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares rise in mixed trade.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish stocks saw moderate gains on  Friday morning with selective activity in a mixed trade, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB National-100 rose 1.08 percent or 21 points to 1,974. Morning  trade volume shrank to 11.582 trillion lira ($71.4 million) from Thursday's  17.31 trillion ($108.6 million).  </p>
<p>&quot;Brokers were cautious ahead of July's monthly inflation figure to  be announced on Monday,&quot; said Erden Gokay from Taksim Securities.</p>
<p>Turkish bankers and economists have predicted that the July inflation  figure will be higher than that for the same 1996 month due to mid-month  petroleum product price rises.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll showed that July consumer prices are expected to be  around 4.8-5.5 percent and wholesale prices 5.5-6.0 percent.</p>
<p>State-owned flat steel producer Eregli's shares, the leading share  in the past two days, were quiet, brokers said. The share ended the  morning session at 26,000 lira down from Thursday's 26,750.</p>
<p>Mine Mumcu from Eczacibasi Securities believes foreign investors buy  blue chips and Eregli shares.</p>
<p>&quot;However they are not very aggressive,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Mumcu said the market index broke its resistance at 1,950.</p>
<p>&quot;In the afternoon session, we may see some profit taking sales but  I do not expect much,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The index fluctuated in a band of 1,943-1,980 in the morning session.</p>
<p>* Of 248 shares traded, gainers outdid losers sharply by 135 to 39  and 74 were stable.</p>
<p>The IMKB Industrial inched up 0.47 percent to 1,912, the IMKB Services  eased 0.41 percent to 1,933 and the IMKB Financial gained 2.57 percent  to 2,118.</p>
<p>The highest gain was seen in the banking sector index which showed  a 3.18 percent rise.</p>
<p>The highest trade volume was seen in largely state owned flat steel  producer Eregli, down 750 lira to 26,000, followed by electronics  utility Vestel up 1,100 lira to 11,500 and media conglomerate Dogan  Holding up 200 to 4,350.</p>
<p>The three made up 20.4 percent of total volume.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-275 0875.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
