<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="772996" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UPS says package volume down.</title>
<headline>UPS says package volume down.</headline>
<byline>Mike Cooper</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Parcel Service of America Inc. said  Friday that it had lost substantial package delivery business to competitors  because of a threatened strike by the Teamsters union.</p>
<p>&quot;We have literally lost hundreds of thousands of packages in terms  of those being diverted to competitors, many of which are non-union  shops,&quot; spokeswoman Jennifer Jiles said.</p>
<p>She spoke during a break in last-ditch negotiations to avoid a strike  by about 185,000 members of the Teamsters union who work for UPS,  the nation's largest parcel carrier.</p>
<p>A four-year contract between UPS and the International Brotherhood  of Teamsters expired at midnight, but the two sides agreed to continue  bargaining and the workers stayed on the job.</p>
<p>UPS normally ships about 12 million packages a day. Jiles could not  give numbers for shipments on Thursday or Friday. &quot;I can't put a specific  figure on overall volume,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Jiles said that the company was operating normally, and money-back  guarantees still applied to time-sensitive deliveries such as next-day  and second-day air.</p>
<p>However, she said UPS could not guarantee totally uninterrupted services.  &quot;This is in effect because our Teamsters are working without a contract,  so there could be a work stoppage at any time,&quot; Jiles said.</p>
<p>&quot;If there were a work stoppage both international and domestic air  would be given priority, but we could not guarantee delivery at the  specified time,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Teamsters, which represent about two-thirds of the domestic payroll  of UPS, postponed strike action Thursday night as negotiations continued.</p>
<p>UPS said its impasse with the Teamsters would not impact packages  and documents traveling between countries outside the United States.  The company also said it expected the labor negotiations to have &quot;little  impact&quot; on packages bound for the United States.</p>
<p>The company said earlier this week that company-wide package deliveries  were off by about 2 percent, or almost 250,000 packages a day, during  June. It added that there were further declines in July.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
