<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="773258" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US blue chips end lower as interest rates spike up.</title>
<headline>US blue chips end lower as interest rates spike up.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street stocks finished mostly lower  on Friday, as investors were twice startled by sharp upturns in U.S.  payrolls and manufacturing activity.</p>
<p>While the economic news sparked a sharp sell-off in the bond market,  stocks again proved their resilience, shaking off most of an early  session decline to end with moderate losses.</p>
<p>By the end, the session appeared to represent little more than a breather  for the stock market, with the Dow industrials falling 29 points to  8194.  </p>
<p>The late recovery all but erased an early sell-off that dragged the  Dow down as many as 119 points, but even so, analysts pointed to the  heavy early losses as evidence the market is ill-prepared to withstand  any unpleasant surprises.</p>
<p>The surprises today came in the form of a free-fall in the bond market  after learning the U.S. economy added 316,000 new jobs in July, far  outpacing forecasts for roughly 200,000.</p>
<p>A second report showed U.S. manufacturing activity and prices paid  by manufacturers both registered unexpectedly sharp rises, reawakening  latent inflation concerns.  </p>
<p>Investors immediately engaged in a broad selling spree after the news,  intent on cashing in on some of the market's dizzying and relentless  gains.</p>
<p>&quot;The image I use is that of a forest that hasn't experienced a fire  in a very long time,&quot; said Charlie Crane, chief market strategist  at Key Asset Management. &quot;You get one spark and suddenly you have  a blaze on your hands.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts were reluctant to predict whether the market was destined  to duplicate last summer's performance, when stocks corrected steeply  after a similar employment report surprise.  </p>
<p>But several analysts said the market appeared to have little room  to maneuver higher, if only because investors have already built an  ideal outlook into pricing levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Both the bond and stock markets have come a very long way,&quot; said  Gail Dudack, chief investment strategist at UBS Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;What today says is that both markets are in the process of discounting  perfection and when you do get a blemish, the result is a sharp retracement,&quot;  she said.</p>
<p>The retracement hit interest rate sensitive shares particularly hard  and sent bank stocks tumbling.  </p>
<p>Bank of New York Co Inc fell 1-7/16 to 47-3/16 and BankAmerica Corp  shed 1-3/8 to 74-1/8. Dow component J.P. Morgan &amp; Co Inc fell 1-3/8  to 114-1/2.</p>
<p>Among individual issues, Kellogg Co jumped 5-9/16 to 97-7/16 after  the company's second quarter earnings more than doubled, coming in  well ahead of Wall Street estimates. The company also raised its dividend  and declared a stock split.</p>
<p>Kenneth Cole Productions Inc fell 2-3/4 to 12-1/2 after the fashion  shoe company reported second quarter net income fell 70 percent versus  a year ago and Morgan Stanley lowered its rating on the shares to  neutral.  </p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 index fell 7.15 points to 947.14.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite rose 0.52 to a record 1594.33.</p>
<p>((-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
