<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="773313" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Boeing adds four to board after McDonnell merger.</title>
<headline>Boeing adds four to board after McDonnell merger.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boeing Co. said it added four members to  its board of directors Friday after completing its $16.3 billion acquisition  of McDonnell Douglas Corp.</p>
<p>Former McDonnell Douglas board members John Biggs, Kenneth Duberstein,  John McDonnell and Harry Stonecipher were appointed to the Boeing  board, which now has 12 members.</p>
<p>Boeing also said its former chief executive, Frank Shrontz, who stepped  down as chairman in April, had retired from the board along with former  Chevron Corp. Chairman and Chief Executive Harold Haynes.</p>
<p>The changes meet a requirement of the merger agreement which called  for one-third of the Boeing board to be made up of former McDonnell  Douglas board members.</p>
<p>McDonnell had been chairman of McDonnell Douglas.</p>
<p>Biggs is chairman and chief executive of Teachers Insurance and Annuity  Association-College Retirement Equities Fund. Duberstein is chairman  and chief executive of The Duberstein Group.</p>
<p>Stonecipher, former president and chief executive of McDonnell Douglas,  has been elected president and chief operating officer of Boeing,  as anticipated.</p>
<p>Boeing also unveiled a new corporate logo incorporating a symbol inspired  by the McDonnell Douglas logo.</p>
<p>Boeing's stock lost 12.5 cents to $58.94 at mid-afternoon on the New  York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
