<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="773667" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans quietly lower on technical setback.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans quietly lower on technical setback.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soybean futures opened quietly lower  on Friday on a technical setback following the week's sharp gains,  pit sources said.</p>
<p>Trade was said to be thin ahead of the weekend as weather uncertainties  lingered. Forecasts generally called for dry weather to persist in  the central U.S. Midwest through early next week but there were some  outlooks for showers to push further south on Saturday.</p>
<p>Dry weather has been the catalyst for this week's 60-cent-per-bushel  climb in November soybeans but traders said any hint of moisture could  quickly wipe out that weather premium.</p>
<p>The National Oilseed Processors Association weekly crush report was  neutral, traders said. NOPA early Friday said the U.S. soy crush during  the week ended July 30 totalled 23.577 million bushels, within the  range of expectations for 22.7 million to 24.2 million bushels.</p>
<p>In opening trade, Cargill Investor Services bought one million bushels  November while Farmers Commodities Corp sold 0.5 million November,  pit sources said. Locals and commission houses wer also said to be  light sellers.</p>
<p>At 0959 CDT, soybeans were down five to 1/2 cent per bushel with August  down 1/2 at $7.67-1/2.</p>
<p>((Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
