<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="773645" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. jobless rate dips, jobs growth up sharply.</title>
<headline>U.S. jobless rate dips, jobs growth up sharply.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kelley</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The nation's jobless rate dropped to  a 24-year low of 4.8 percent last month as the economy produced new  jobs at an unexpectedly strong pace, the government said on Friday.</p>
<p>The Labour Department's monthly payroll survey showed that 316,000  new jobs were created outside the farm sector in July, compared with  a revised 228,000 in June. The new figures stand in contrast to the  June report, which had painted a picture of a slackening labour market.</p>
<p>The services sector added 113,000 new jobs in July, while retail trade  contributed 65,000 jobs. The key manufacturing sector lost 5,000 jobs  last month.</p>
<p>Wall Street forecasters surveyed by Reuters had expected the report  to reveal that 193,000 jobs were created outside the farm sector.  The economists had predicted the jobless rate would edge back down  to the 4.9 percent level it hit in April.</p>
<p>Marilyn Schaja, money market economist at Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette  Securities Corp., said the big gains in the service sector employment  were &quot;not an aberration.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing in the numbers indicates it is an aberration. Most of that  gain is real,&quot; she said. &quot;The labour market remains tight, but we  are not seeing that filter through to wages.&quot;</p>
<p>In June, the jobless rate stood at 5.0 percent after rising from May's  4.8 percent, its lowest level in nearly a quarter century.</p>
<p>The report showed workers spending less time on the job, with the  average work week dropping to 34.4 hours from 34.7 hours. The factory  work week dipped to 41.7 hours, while overtime fell to 4.6 hours,  the department said.</p>
<p>&quot;The labour market is tight, lots of jobs are being created and it  looks like the economy is picking up in July,&quot; Hugh Johnson, chief  investment officer at First Albany Corp., said.</p>
<p>&quot;But when you look more closely at manufacturing and construction  jobs, it seems to indicate that industrial production was not that  strong in July, housing was not that strong ... &quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Even though there's tightness in the labour market, we're not seeing  upward pressure on wages,&quot; Johnson added.</p>
<p>The employment report -- the government's first reading on the economy's  pace in July -- followed a report Thursday showing economic growth  slowed markedly in the second quarter.</p>
<p>The nation's gross domestic product, the government's broadest measure  of overall economic activity, showed a growth rate of 2.2 percent.  That was less than half of the revised 4.9 percent rate for the first  three months of the year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
