<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77377" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Shareholder sues Sumitomo over copper loss fund.</title>
<headline>Shareholder sues Sumitomo over copper loss fund.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO</dateline>
<text>
<p>A shareholder of Japan's Sumitomo Corp filed a lawsuit on Thursday seeking to repeal a decision taken at a shareholders' meeting approving a fund to pay for massive copper trading losses, a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>The shareholders' meeting was held on June 27, two weeks after Sumitomo announced it had amassed huge losses from unauthorised copper trades over a 10-year period.</p>
<p>Several of those attending the meeting complained they were shunted into side rooms to watch the proceedings on television monitors, with no chance to question executives, while the main room was filled with Sumitomo employees who had arrived early.</p>
<p>The meeting lasted less than 40 minutes and approved by voice vote, with no casting of ballots, plans to cover the massive copper losses by setting up a separate fund and by cancelling a share buy-back.</p>
<p>A Sumitomo spokesman said the suit filed on Thursday at a district court in Osaka sought to repeal approval of the separate fund and of retirement payments to five members of the board of directors.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought it was strange that the shareholders' meeting ended without any objections, despite the occurrence of such a major incident,&quot; Kazuyoshi Yuoka, who filed the suit, told Japanese public television station NHK.</p>
<p>Sumitomo said in a statement: &quot;If this case is requesting the repeal of resolutions at our general shareholders' meeting, it is our belief that the meeting was held for the shareholders themselves and that procedurally it was in accord with commercial law, and therefore there are no problems with it.&quot;</p>
<p>According to Japanese media reports, Yuoka, who holds 2,000 shares in Sumitomo, said he was denied an opportunity to ask questions of Sumitomo executives.</p>
<p>Yuoka could not immediately be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Sumitomo jumped back into the headlines last week when, after months of official silence on the copper scandal, it announced that it had raised its estimated copper trading losses to $2.6 billion from the $1.8 billion it announced in June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
