<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="773886" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Quiet Danish shares tread water, no joy seen ahead.</title>
<headline>Quiet Danish shares tread water, no joy seen ahead.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish share prices closed marginally  up on Friday in a standstill market lacking news or outside inspiration  with dealers seeing little action until the first-half 1997 corporate  result season gets under way in mid-August.</p>
<p>&quot;Next week is also going to be pretty desultory with little action  expected until the results season which starts in about 10 days time,&quot;  one dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index gained a meagre 0.10 point to close at 189.28,  while the KFX August future fell 0.50 point to 189.20 with 504 contracts  each worth 100,000 crowns traded.  </p>
<p>Tele Danmark started down and closed seven crowns lower at 390 on  fears of increasing competition from new rivals. East Asiatic had  a bad day too, shedding seven crowns or 4.43 percent to finish at  151.</p>
<p>Moeller's D/S Svendborg and D/S 1912 were among the few KFX papers  to hold their own, putting on 61.50 and 3,694 crowns respectively  to close at 440,000 and 305,694.</p>
<p>Overall turnover for the day was 1.186 billion crowns.</p>
<p>--Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom +45-33-969652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
