<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77382" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: ViewCall in deals to offer Internet via TV.</title>
<headline>ViewCall in deals to offer Internet via TV.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>London-based ViewCall Europe on Thursday said it signed deals with three separate companies to offer its OnTV television-based service to the Internet.</p>
<p>ViewCall said it signed agreements with Mitsubishi Electronics America, the world's largest television manufacturer, Yahoo!, designer of Internet browser software, and USA Today.</p>
<p>OnTV is a subscription-based service that provides a link to the Internet for televisions equipped with television browser hardware.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi plans to begin marketing its browser-equipped DiamondWeb televisions in the U.S. by the end of 1996 and expects to sell about one million DiamondWeb TVs by the end of 1997, John Bentley, chief executive of ViewCall, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi will also sell special set-top boxes equipped with the TV browsers that can be connected to existing televisions.</p>
<p>ViewCall, a 15 month-old company, is the second firm to offer a television-based Internet service. WebTV Networks, a start-up U.S. company, launched its service earlier this month when Philips Electronics, the Dutch electronics manufacturers, began shipping its Philips Magnanox Internet television terminal.</p>
<p>Bentley, however, said OnTV will allow connections to the Internet with any brand of television -- via purchase of a browser-equipped settop box.</p>
<p>ViewCall is currently negotiating with additional manufacturers in Europe, Asia and America to incorporate the browser hardware directly into televisions. &quot;We hope there will be a number of other announcements soon,&quot; Bentley said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
