<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="773996" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Europe's PC sales up in 1st half,seen accelerating.</title>
<headline>Europe's PC sales up in 1st half,seen accelerating.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>Sales of personal computers in western Europe  gathered pace in the first half of 1997, and are likely to accelerate  in the second half, a report published on Friday said.</p>
<p>Compaq Computer Corp of the U.S. improved its position as market leader  with 14.6 per cent of sales, market researcher CONTEXT said.</p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp retained its distant second place  with 9.3 percent, while Hewlett-Packard was third with 6.2 percent.</p>
<p>Siemens Nixdorf of Germany was the top European performer in fourth  place with 5.8 percent.</p>
<p>West European sales in the first half rose 10.5 per cent to 8,575,959  PCs compared with the same period last year. Growth spurted to 14.0  percent in the second quarter, substantialy better than the first  quarter's 7.5 percent, according to CONTEXT.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the result of the partial recovery of some of the biggest  European markets like France, Italy, Spain and Sweden,&quot; said Emmanuel  Lalloz, senior PC research analyst at CONTEXT.</p>
<p>&quot;If, as is likely, the consumer market grows stronger again in the  last quarter of this year, CONTEXT expects the second half of 1997  to be even better, with growth approaching 15 to 16 per cent,&quot; Lalloz  said.</p>
<p>This contrasts with market conditions at the end of the first quarter,  when CONTEXT said consumers were worried about their prospects. Sales  were also held back ahead of the introduction of Intel Corp's new  Pentium 2 chip which was launched early in May.</p>
<p>Germany, Europe's biggest market, experienced moderate growth with  sales hitting 965,100 in the second quarter, 7.8 percent over the  first three months. German sales are being hampered by the economic  recession, Lalloz said.</p>
<p>Britain, the second biggest market, grew by 12.1 percent in the first  half.</p>
<p>Lalloz said Compaq's powerful performance was due to its increasingly  aggressive pricing, and its improved distribution.</p>
<p>&quot;IBM had problems with managing its inventory in Europe, over-stocking  desktop computers while not being able to supply in the notebook market,&quot;  Lalloz said.</p>
<p>&quot;Siemens Nixdorf outperformed all its competitors in the second quarter  by achieving the highest year-on-year growth of 59.3 percent, with  248,324 PCs shipped.&quot;</p>
<p>Ailing Apple Computer of the U.S. held on to its ninth place or three  percent market share.</p>
<p>&quot;This is partly a result of high sales in the education sector, and  of the success of the company's refocus on the high-end market, and  partly a consequence of improved logistics, and stock control.&quot;</p>
<p>The rapid pace of change in personal computers has been a serious  constraint on sales, as individual consumers and small businesses  hold back to avoid being saddled with obsolete technology.</p>
<p>According to Lalloz, companies like Compaq and Hewlett-Packard, and  particularly IBM, are trying to woo new customers with leasing type  deals, which include service and also guarantee that computers will  be updated to incorporate the latest technology.</p>
<p>This would take some of the hesitancy from consumers, and also allow  suppliers to flatten out their volatile production runs and cash flows,  Lalloz said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
