<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774062" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - SGL Carbon upbeat for 97 as Q2 profit rises.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - SGL Carbon upbeat for 97 as Q2 profit rises.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's SGL Carbon AG on Friday forecast  improved results for the second half, saying there was no need to  set aside funds for an international price-fixing investigation.</p>
<p>&quot;We will enjoy a clearly better second half,&quot; SGL Carbon management  board chairman Robert Koehler told a news conference, after having  already affirmed the group's forecast for double-digit profit growth  for the full year.</p>
<p>A recovering economy, seen boosting volume sales, as well as room  to raise some prices and the fact SGL Carbon had digested 10 million  marks ($5.4 million) in one-off costs during the first half, should  help shore up second-half results, Koehler said.</p>
<p>SGL Carbon, a leading carbon and graphite maker producing a range  of products for the electrical, steel and semi-conductor industries,  said it had no plans to make provisions for any possible consequences  relating to a price-fixing enquiry.</p>
<p>&quot;We see no need to build provisions,&quot; Koehler said, stressing that  SGL Carbon had not been charged with any wrong-doing. But the group  has retained lawyers and some provisions might be made later to cover  their fees, Koehler said.</p>
<p>&quot;European Union and U.S. cartel office authorities have completed  a search, but gave no hints of what might follow,&quot; Koehler said. &quot;We  have no further information and cannot say how long this process might  take,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Buoyed by improved European steel industry conditions, first-half  sales climbed by 10 percent to 961 million marks as pre-tax profits  rose two percent to 159 million marks. Net profit however stagnated  at 97 million marks.</p>
<p>Koehler said the second quarter was the growth engine for the first  half, helping gloss over some of the group's disappointing first quarter  results.</p>
<p>Looking forward to filled order books, Koehler predicted much higher  volume sales in the second half, reversing a three percent drop during  the first half.</p>
<p>Similarly, anticipated cost reductions and the scope for price hikes  should help SGL Carbon meet targets, Koehler said.</p>
<p>He steered clear of detailing how shareholders might benefit from  the anticipated jump in results however, saying only that the group  would do its best to please shareholders.</p>
<p>At midday SGL shares had climbed 1.6 percent to 248.50 marks after  results were slightly above market expectations.</p>
<p>The shares, debuting at 55 marks in 1995, had risen five-fold in value,  Koehler said, explaining why SGL stock had not kept pace with Germany's  30 most industrialised companies' recent dizzying highs.</p>
<p>Among the three business units, carbon and graphite posted a nine  percent rise in sales to 607 million marks, trailing the 11 percent  jump in speciality graphite sales to 199 million marks and the 18  percent rise in technical products sales to 152 million marks.</p>
<p>Of the three, carbon and graphite was also the most profitable with  operating profit climbing 16 percent to 151 million marks. Profits  in speciality graphite climbed 10 percent to 25 million marks while  profits climbed nine percent to 12 million marks at the technical  products unit.</p>
<p>In the technical products area SGL Carbon expects to double annual  sales to around 500 million marks by the year 2000, driven in part  by takeovers like the recently completed purchase of U.S. group Hitco  Technologies Inc.</p>
<p>Hinting more acquisitions were on the way, especially in this area,  board member Klaus Warning said &quot;now things will really begin to pick  up.&quot;</p>
<p>($ = 1.846 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
