<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774111" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: President asks Swiss to unite to restore image.</title>
<headline>President asks Swiss to unite to restore image.</headline>
<byline>Alice Ratcliffe</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss President Arnold Koller on Friday urged  his citizens, torn by controversy over their country's role in World  War Two, to rally behind efforts to repair Switzerland's standing.</p>
<p>Koller's speech was one of an estimated 3,000 by politicians, dignitaries  and others on the Swiss national day, which commemorates the alliance  between the first three Swiss cantons in 1291.</p>
<p>&quot;Solidarity inside and outside the country is a duty which over time  has become part of the concept of the Swiss nation, as much as our  direct democracy, federalism or right to freedom,&quot; Koller said in  his speech, broadcast on radio and television.</p>
<p>&quot;We must also renew solidarity in order to once again secure Switzerland's  humanitarian tradition in the world, and give it a new shine. We are  especially in need of this, as a neutral small nation,&quot; Koller said.</p>
<p>The word &quot;solidarity&quot; carries extra resonance in Switzerland since  the cabinet called in February for a seven billion franc ($4.6 billion)  &quot;Solidarity Foundation&quot; to aid the needy at home and abroad.</p>
<p>The idea followed sharp foreign criticism of the country's World War  Two role.</p>
<p>Documents recently released from U.S. archives have shone the international  spotlight on Switzerland's wartime past.</p>
<p>Some Swiss industrialists aided the Nazis, while some banks kept accounts  for Nazis, or failed to find assets left for safe-keeping during World  War Two by Holocaust victims.</p>
<p>On Thursday, a U.S. court began hearings on whether Swiss banks could  be liable to face class-action suits from Holocaust victims who said  the banks stole their assets.</p>
<p>The latest criticism of Switzerland's wartime role has been led by  international Jewish organisations and U.S. Senator Alfonse D'Amato.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, D'Amato demanded that the country's biggest bank,  Union Bank of Switzerland (UBS), apologise to a former security guard  who fled the country fearing for his safety after saving Holocaust-era  documents from shredding at the bank.</p>
<p>Far-right politicians have used criticism of Switzerland to attract  votes. Mainstream politicians in turn fear this could block approval  of the Solidarity Foundation, to be funded from a revaluation of Swiss  gold reserves.</p>
<p>Right-wing leader Christoph Blocher, who says the Foundation is akin  to an admission of Swiss guilt, said in a speech on Thursday that  Switzerland could go its own way without needing to isolate itself.</p>
<p>Some Swiss on Friday staged an &quot;alternative&quot; national day celebration,  first begun by post-war Swiss authors Max Frisch, Friedrich Duerrenmatt  and others.</p>
<p>Catholic priest Cornelius Koch, who led the  celebration this year,  warned that the divisions in the country could foster racism and xenophobia.</p>
<p>&quot;The banks should stop using people and the government as hostages  and finally face up to their guilt,&quot; he said in a speech.</p>
<p>&quot;These public discussions about the past, which could be a thunderstorm  that clears the air, are now being used by the extreme right and populists,&quot;  he said. ($ = 1.516 Swiss Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
