<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774187" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares weaker in early bourse dealings.</title>
<headline>German shares weaker in early bourse dealings.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were generally lower in  early bourse dealings as Daimler-Benz AG took a beating after two  major investment banks lowered earnings estimates on the industrial  group.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index was down 28.72 points at 4,410.21 points, while  the IBIS DAX, which reflects all-day computer dealings, was up 5.06  points at 4,410.58 points.</p>
<p>Dealers expected the market to remain under pressure throughout the  session from profit-taking and ahead of the release at 1230 GMT of  U.S. July unemployment data.</p>
<p>Market attention focused on Merill Lynch and Morgan Stanley downgrading  1997 and 1998 earnings estimates for Daimler. Merrill also cut Daimler  to intermediate reduce from neutral but left the share as a long-term  hold.</p>
<p>The downgrades came after Daimler released six-month results that  showed group operating profit more than doubling to 1.849 billion  marks.</p>
<p>Daimler shares were down six marks at 148.80 marks and were among  the top percentage losers during the bourse session.</p>
<p>Daimler chief executive Juergen Schrempp said in a radio interview  on Friday that he did not understand the disappointment among analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a excellent performance when a company more than doubles its  operating profit,&quot; Schrempp told InfoRadio.</p>
<p>Some traders said the drop was an overreaction and ABN AMRO issued  a buy recommendation on Daimler.</p>
<p>Other major DAX index components were lower, including banking industry  shares such as Commerzbank AG and Deutsche Bank AG.</p>
<p>Commerzbank was down 45 pfennigs at 62.55 marks, while Deutsche was  down 2.50 marks at 122 marks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
