<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774258" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT -FTSE may sink to 4,890 then hold steady.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT -FTSE may sink to 4,890 then hold steady.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The FTSE 100 index may sink back to 4,890  on Friday and then try to hold steady for most of the session, technical  analysts said.</p>
<p>Confrontation to levels above 4,940 will have to wait awhile following  Thursday's aimless wandering and a late sell-off which will have unnerved  investors, they added.</p>
<p>By 0710 GMT, the FTSE was indicated up 1.2 to 4,908.7.</p>
<p>Technically, the market fell back yesterday before meeting the top  of an upward channel which consists of a pair of parallel trendlines  connecting the FTSE's intra-day highs and lows since July 28.  </p>
<p>Vertical distance between the parallel lines is about 60 points and  the lower end of the channel is now near 4,900. Although the FTSE  stayed within its channel boundaries on Thursday, analysts expressed  doubts that it could cling to that level -- at least for the first  half of today's session.</p>
<p>The FTSE closed at around its two-thirds retracement level following  the loss of 200 points on an intra-day basis between July 18-19 and  as a result it may now ease back.</p>
<p>Any ambitions to scale new heights will be thwarted if economic data  from the U.S. at 1230 GMT shows non-farm payrolls and wage inflation  are higher than expected.  </p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters forecast U.S. non-farm payrolls for July  to have increased by 193,000 taking the unemployment rate to 4.9 percent.</p>
<p>Average hourly earnings for July are expected to have risen by 0.2  percent.</p>
<p>The stock market should get a boost if the actual figures are at least  in-line with forecasts, but the FTSE may tumble if payroll numbers  are greater than expected and these are accompanied by a jump in hourly  earnings, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Pradip Mishra, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7954</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
