<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774293" id="root" date="1997-08-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Winded Irish pound pauses for breath.</title>
<headline>Winded Irish pound pauses for breath.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-08-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Irish pound opened quietly on Friday,  still licking its wounds after a sharp sell-off by offshore operators  on Thursday, dealers said.</p>
<p>By 0935 GMT, the Irish pound was unchanged on closing levels at 0.8860  stg but recouped some losses against the mark trading at 2.6805/45  marks, having lost a pfennig on Thursday to close at 2.6760 marks.</p>
<p>&quot;It has stabilised somewhat but there was sharp selling pressure from  offshore yesterday,&quot; one currency dealer said.</p>
<p>He said selling interest was partially triggered by stering's rally  and a belief that even if Ireland revalues the currency, it will still  need to drop from current levels versus the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;As sterling bounces back it produces levels in the mark/Irish, which  is the focus of a lot of institutional investors, who then find it  attractive to sell,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>He said there was also some speculative play in Thursday's sell-off.</p>
<p>&quot;There was speculative pressure as well from the offshore community  on the belief that a revaluation will only produce maybe five to 10  percent change, bringing the middle band to a level that is still  not as high as where we are in the mark/Irish at the moment,&quot; the  dealer said.</p>
<p>Dealers said while the main selling pressure was in the mark/Irish,  it was also impacting on sterling/Irish although the Irish unit was  still off the lows of last week where it bottomed out at 87.30 stg.</p>
<p>Sterling's bounce on Thursday was triggered by comments by Gordon  Brown who dispelled the theory that he was going to have an interim  budget in November, the dealer said.</p>
<p>Brown said in a Times interview that he had no plans for a special  autumn budget to attempt to brake consumer spending.</p>
<p>Dealers said local activity was likely to remain subdued ahead of  Ireland's long weekend but direction will be dictated by international  moves.</p>
<p>-- Carmel Linnane, Dublin newsroom + 353 1 676 9775</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
