<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774591" id="root" date="1997-08-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Role of ousted Ranariddh is key Cambodian issue.</title>
<headline>Role of ousted Ranariddh is key Cambodian issue.</headline>
<byline>Robert Birsel</byline>
<text>
<p>PHNOM PENH, Aug 3 (Refuter) - ASEAN envoys and Cambodian leader Hun Sen found some common ground in their talks on the weekend, but the key question of what future political role ousted Prince Norodom Ranariddh can, or should, play remained unresolved.</p>
<p>The Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) wants to see Cambodia stick to its own constitution and laws, and hold free and fair elections next year that are open to all participants.</p>
<p>But Hun Sen appears determined to see that the prince has no role in politics, analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;That's always been the sticking point and it hasn't been resolved,&quot; said one diplomat on Sunday of Prince Ranariddh's role.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the hard part, the fundamental question: what role can or should Ranariddh play?&quot; said a political analyst.</p>
<p>Second Prime Minister Hun Sen ousted his senior co-premier and coalition partner, Prince Norodom Ranariddh, on July 6 after two days of battles in Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>The coup by Hun Sen prompted ASEAN to postpone Cambodia's induction into the regional grouping along with Burma and Laos on July 23. ASEAN's other members are Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam.</p>
<p>Ranariddh left Cambodia shortly before the fighting and has since called from abroad for opposition to Hun Sen.</p>
<p>Hun Sen has said the prince was free to return home, but would have to face trial for his alleged illegal negotiations with the outlawed Khmer Rouge guerrilla group and for weapons smuggling.</p>
<p>But analysts said if Ranariddh is prevented from taking part in next year's election, Hun Sen will face problems in trying to convince the world the poll was free and fair.</p>
<p>&quot;If Hun Sen sticks with his insistence that Ranariddh answers charges, it's going to be very difficult for him to have any role,&quot; said another diplomat.</p>
<p>&quot;But, equally, if Ranariddh doesn't have a role in the election, it's going to be very difficult for Hun Sen to say the elections were free and fair.&quot;</p>
<p>Since taking sole power, Hun Sen has said he wants his coalition with Ranariddh's royalist FUNCINPEC party to remain in place, for FUNCINPEC to choose a successor for Ranariddh as first prime minister, and for elections to be held in May as scheduled.</p>
<p>Alatas said he and his two colleagues, foreign ministers Prachuab Chaiyasan of Thailand and Domingo Siazon of the Philippines, raised the issue of the prince's role in their Saturday talks with Hun Sen but had not received a clear response.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course we talked about Prince Ranariddh's role, both now and in the future elections,&quot; Alatas told a news conference after the talks.</p>
<p>Alatas declined to give details of his discussion with Hun Sen on the prince's future, but said: &quot;He (Hun Sen) agreed with us that the general elections in May would have no meaning unless participated in by all political forces, and all political parties, freely.&quot;</p>
<p>Hun Sen suggested on Saturday that Ranariddh should not come back to Cambodia because doing so could lead to further bloodshed.</p>
<p>Alatas said he had asked Hun Sen for clarification of the rules governing the National Assembly and the FUNCINPEC party in what analysts said was an attempt by ASEAN to determine the legal picture before deciding what course to follow on Cambodia.</p>
<p>&quot;ASEAN is very keen to see everything done by the rules,&quot; said the first diplomat.</p>
<p>&quot;ASEAN is trying to check which game they can play, which way they can go on,&quot; said the political analyst, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;They want to know what is the legal reality on the ground. Can Ranariddh be legally removed? If so, that solves the problem. But if not, then Hun Sen has to find a way to compromise,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
