<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774592" id="root" date="1997-08-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Hanoi sheds few tears for death of last emperor.</title>
<headline>Hanoi sheds few tears for death of last emperor.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-08-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam broke its silence on Sunday over the death of its last emperor, Bao Dai, and said the exiled monarch had failed history by refusing to take part in the building of its communist state.</p>
<p>A Foreign Ministry statement said Bao Dai, who died in a Paris military hospital on Thursday at the age of 83 after four decades in exile, had rejected an olive branch offered by the newly formed post-World War Two government of president Ho Chi Minh.</p>
<p>&quot;This is maybe the only such occasion in history where this (such leniency) has happened,&quot; the statement said. &quot;Unfortunately, not long after that he failed to live up to the good will.&quot;</p>
<p>Bao Dai, the last king in Vietnam's Nguyen Dynasty, earned a reputation as a playboy emperor through a hedonistic lifestyle spent mostly outside Vietnam. He abdicated in 1945.</p>
<p>Officially sanctioned accounts of his depict him as a puppet of French colonial rule in Indochina and as a collaborator with the wartime Japanese occupying forces.</p>
<p>Born Nguyen Vinh Thuy in 1913, he took the title Bao Dai (Keeper of Greatness) at the age of thirteen before assuming his royal duties at the imperial capital in Hue six years later.</p>
<p>His rule ended in 1945 when Ho Chi Minh's communist forces seized on the end of Japanese occupation in Vietnam to proclaim an independent republic in an attempt to forestall the return of French colonialism.</p>
<p>In front of thousands of people in Hue, he handed over his sword and royal seal to the new administration and was renamed Citizen Nguyen Vinh Thuy.</p>
<p>But he later rejected a role of adviser offered by Ho. He left for Hong Kong in 1946 to return briefly as interim premier, and was briefly reinstalled by the French as monarch.</p>
<p>Bao Dai left Vietnam permanently following the final defeat of France's colonial forces at the battle of Dien Bien Phu in 1954.</p>
<p>France paid tribute to him on Friday as &quot;a true friend of our country&quot;. Hanoi's statement said Vietnam had sent condolences to his family.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
