<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774531" id="root" date="1997-08-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Leading Argentine opposition parties form alliance.</title>
<headline>Leading Argentine opposition parties form alliance.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-08-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's two main opposition forces, centrist Radical Party and center-left FREPASO, forged Sunday an alliance to face Peronist Party in power in congressional polls in October and presidential polls in 1999.</p>
<p>Under the pact announced in the morning by both parties, FREPASO's senator Graciela Fernandez Meijide will head the list of candidates to the mational lower chamber for the key Buenos Airesa province followed by radical Federico Storani.</p>
<p>In the capital, the list for national deputies candidates will be headed by FREPASO's Carlos Alvarez followed by the President of Radical Party Rodolfo terragno.</p>
<p>The agreement was announced hours after former Argentine President Raul Alfonsin, a Radical, said he agreed to decline his candidacy to national deputy for Buenos Aires province. His decission was considered a crucial factor for the alliance to be formed.</p>
<p>Leaders from both parties said there could be still some changes in the lists for October 26 congressional polls.</p>
<p>The new partners committed themselves to face President Carlos Menem's Peronist Party in 1999 presidential polls, with a formula chosen in internal joint polls.</p>
<p>Menem ends in 1999 two succesive terms in power and under the Constitution he can not be re-elected for a third straight period.</p>
<p>The Radical Party and FREPASO have strongly chided his liberal economic program. Menem stabilized the currency and erradicated inflation but unemployment grew to 16.1 percent after skyrocketing to 17.3 percent in October 1996. They also criticize corrupction cases involving government officials.</p>
<p>Hours before the alliance was announced Menem said it reminded him of the &quot;sinister&quot; Democratic Union, a coalition of radical, conservatives and socialists defeated in 1946 polls by the founder of Peronism, the late Juan Peron.</p>
<p>Menem nevertheless clarified he did not mean the new coalition was also sinister.</p>
<p>Buenos Aires Peronist Governor Eduardo Duhalde was forced to launch in May the candidacy of his wife Hilda to the lower chamber for the province when FREPASO's Fernandez Meijide --a senator for the capital-- said she would run for deputy for the Buenos Aires province, Duhalde's stronghold.</p>
<p>According to private surveys, in Buenos Aires province Hilda Duhalde heads voting intentions with 30 percent against about 30 percent of Fernandez Meijide. Alfonsin was running third with less than 20 percent.</p>
<p>Those who head the lists are guarnteed to be elected for the lower chamber but what is really at stake is how many colleagues they can pull along to a congressional seat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
