<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774671" id="root" date="1997-08-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran's Rafsanjani urges nation to be vigilant.</title>
<headline>Iran's Rafsanjani urges nation to be vigilant.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-08-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's outgoing president Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani urged the nation to remain vigilant against its traditional enemies who he said sought to overthrow its Islamic system of government.</p>
<p>Iran &quot;continues to have her traditional enemies who...would not desist from plotting against the Islamic revolution and the Islamic government,&quot; Rafsanjani said in an interview on state radio and television on Saturday, reported on Sunday by the official news agency IRNA.</p>
<p>&quot;(Rafsanjani) reminded the nation of the need to be even more vigilant than before for safeguarding the system and the fruits of the Islamic revolution,&quot; IRNA said.</p>
<p>The United States and Israel are regularly denounced by Iran's leadership for aiming to overthrow the Tehran government.</p>
<p>Rafsanjani stands down on Monday when Mohammad Khatami, a 54-year-old moderate Shi'ite cleric and winner of a landslide election victory in May, is sworn in as the country's highest elected official.</p>
<p>Rafsanjani thanked the Iranian people and the country's arch-conservative supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei for their support during his eight years in office, the maximum allowed under Iran's constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;(Rafsanjani)...offered his personal appreciation to the nation and to the leader of the Islamic revolution, Ayatollah Seyed Ali Khamenei, for the support he received from them during his term in office,&quot; IRNA reported.</p>
<p>Rafsanjani is expected to maintain a major role in Iranian politics as the head of a powerful council which will draw up long-term policies and advises supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</p>
<p>The outgoing president also used the broadcast to summarise the achievements of his office, emphaising the reconstruction of the economy after Iran's devastating 1980-88 war with Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;President Rafsanjani admitted, however, that his administration could not possibly have satisfied the expectations of each and every citizen no matter how hard it had tried,&quot; IRNA reported.</p>
<p>&quot;But, he said, all in all the nation had done well in every sector and had made big progress. He said he felt personally assured about the future of the Islamic government.&quot;</p>
<p>Rafsanjani recalled his &quot;sweetest personal memory&quot; in office as the day Iranian prisoners of war returned home after a ceasefire in the war with Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
