<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774625" id="root" date="1997-08-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Efforts under way for return of EU envoys to Iran.</title>
<headline>Efforts under way for return of EU envoys to Iran.</headline>
<byline>Ashraf Fouad</byline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-08-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran and the European Union are engaged in last-minute efforts to try to get the EU's envoys back to Tehran in time for the new president's swearing-in ceremony on Monday, diplomats said on Sunday.</p>
<p>They said the efforts aimed at timing the return so that EU ambassadors could attend the oath-taking ceremony of President Mohammad Khatami in parliament.</p>
<p>Khatami was formally confirmed as president by supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on Sunday but efforts for the envoys to attend that ceremony failed.</p>
<p>EU states except for Greece recalled their ambassadors from Tehran after a German court concluded in April that Iran's top leaders had ordered the 1992 assassination of four Iranian Kurdish dissidents in a Berlin restaurant.</p>
<p>Iran is insisting that the German ambassador, Horst Beschmann, should be the last to arrive and has rejected a European offer that he be the last to step off a plane carrying all the envoys to Tehran, the diplomats said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Iranians are insisting that the German envoy be the last one to arrive. There are still some efforts for tomorrow Monday,&quot; an Arab ambassador told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still a chance...They could come,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>When the EU envoys left Tehran the 15-nation bloc also suspended all ministerial contacts with Tehran as well as its policy of &quot;critical dialogue&quot; with Iran.</p>
<p>Iran, which has repeatedly denied involvement in the Berlin killings, retaliated by withdrawing its ambassadors from EU capitals.</p>
<p>But when the EU countries later decided to send their ambassadors back to Tehran, Khamenei said the German ambassador was not welcome in Tehran.</p>
<p>The EU sent a delegation to Tehran in May for talks with officials on the strained relations.</p>
<p>Iran's outgoing President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani on Saturday indicated that the European ambassadors may return to Tehran but Bonn's envoy must be the last.</p>
<p>Asked to comment on indications by EU countries that they were ready to send their envoys back to Iran, Rafsanjani said: &quot;That is true. They are now ready to return since the leader of the revolution (Khamenei) said that they can do so. Germany must return after everyone else.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the European states wanted to return together but that Iran would deal with each country separately.</p>
<p>&quot;You must sort yourself out. If you wish to work with Iran, you should not resort to such ploys,&quot; Rafsanjani said. &quot;The (European countries) thought that we will retreat in the face of this pressure and make concessions, but they realised that Iran is far stronger than to be frightened by such ploys,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, this has not ended yet. The issue can go on, but eventually the Europeans must accept that they have made a mistake,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
