<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774768" id="root" date="1997-08-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai PM seeks to reassure foreign creditors.</title>
<headline>Thai PM seeks to reassure foreign creditors.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK, Thailand</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh assured anxious foreign creditors Sunday that they would be fairly treated if Thai private companies defaulted amid the country's economic turmoil.</p>
<p>After a meeting with bankers from 25 foreign financial institutions, Chavalit said foreign creditors had expressed deep concern over their exposure to the troubled Thai private sector.</p>
<p>The meeting was organised by the foreign banks' association, which sought assurances of fair and equitable treatment as economic problems intensified.</p>
<p>&quot;They are worried. So I assured them that they will be treated fairly. I also told them what the government plans to do to solve the problem,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>According to participants in the meeting, Chavalit told them of Thailand's plan to accept an International Monetary Fund (IMF) economic rescue package but gave no details.</p>
<p>He also asked them to cooperate by extending credit lines and rolling over loans to Thai companies, they said.</p>
<p>Thailand is facing a severe economic crisis after a decade of high growth.</p>
<p>The financial sector has been hard hit by a liquidity crunch and rising non-performing loans due to over-exposure to non-productive industry, especially the property sector.</p>
<p>The country is now seeking help from the IMF to put it back on track. Details of the rescue package are expected to be announced next week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK, Thailand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
