<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774745" id="root" date="1997-08-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Too few doctors to treat wounded Afghan warriors.</title>
<headline>Too few doctors to treat wounded Afghan warriors.</headline>
<byline>Brian Williams</byline>
<dateline>GULBAHAR, Afghanistan 1997-08-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) on Sunday evacuated about 25 Afghan rebels badly wounded in frontline fighting for control of the capital Kabul.</p>
<p>The evacuation was carried out as concern grew about a shortage of doctors to care for the wounded on both sides in the figtht.</p>
<p>An ICRC road convoy carrying the wounded took them to the strategic highway town of Pul-i-Khumri, a six-hour drive from where the so-called Northern Alliance are fighting some 20 km (12 miles) from Kabul against the nominal government of the Islamic fundamentalist Taleban movement.</p>
<p>Wounded who could not be treated even at Pul-i-Khumri would be taken further back to Mazar-i-Sharif, the rear headquarters of the alliance.</p>
<p>Several doctors from Pul-i-Khumri were sent to the front line to help care for the wounded and to prepare for more casualties in the days ahead, when fighting is expected to reach a new pitch.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a shortage of doctors on both sides, there is a lot of concern about,&quot; Baghlan province governor Syed Jafar told reporters.</p>
<p>Jafar said the fighting was cutting off routes for doctors to get to wounded both from troops of the alliance and the Taleban.</p>
<p>The Taleban in Kabul have banned women from doing some medical jobs, draining the pool of doctors and medical workers.</p>
<p>The alliance's chief military commander Ahmad Shah Masood on Sunday called a meeting in Gulbahar of frontline commanders for a pep talk and discussion of how to break the stalemate in fighting.</p>
<p>Masood launched a nationwide assault nearly two weeks ago to break the Taleban's grip on the capital they captured last September.</p>
<p>After swift advances, the drive appears to have stalled over the last few days in the face of strong Taleban counter-attacks, some of them mounted across minefields.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GULBAHAR, Afghanistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
