<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774800" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Bel-20 correction expected to lose steam soon.</title>
<headline>Bel-20 correction expected to lose steam soon.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bel-20 index of leading Belgian shares on Monday slid 2.59 percent on profit-taking in one of the biggest falls in its seven-year history but dealers and analysts expected the correction to be shortlived.</p>
<p>&quot;The correction is quite solid but there's quite a bit of profit that can be taken...it's a healthy correction,&quot; Stefan Casteleyn at Antwerp brokerage Corluy &amp; Co said.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 index, which was introduced in March 1990, was stripped of 65.70 points to end at 2,470.34, just off the session low of 2,469.49. The correction had started on Friday with a 1.68 percent drop following a raft of strong U.S. data.</p>
<p>Casteleyn said the Bel-20 was already approaching attractive levels. &quot;We don't have to go much lower to find buying opportunities again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added most fundamentals, led by the strong dollar, were still favourable and bound to shoulder the resumption of the upward trend.</p>
<p>He named electronics firm Barco, steel wire and cord maker Bekaert, shipper CMB and cement maker CBR among dollar-sensitive stocks to be first in line for renewed buying interest.</p>
<p>But dealers were unable to say whether the correction would already come to a standstill on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said the weakness had hit Belgian financials, dollar-sensitives and industrials alike.</p>
<p>&quot;Unlike the Netherlands where basically just financials are smarting,&quot; Casteleyn said.</p>
<p>One of the stocks that was expected to show the way to recovery in the near future was chemicals and drugs firm UCB, which was still quoted at 153,000 francs two weeks ago but lost nearly 12 percent last week and another 3.8 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>Holding firm GBL was the only Bel-20 stock to survive the onslaught and finished 0.2 percent firmer at 5,990 francs.</p>
<p>Holding firm Gevaert announced after the close of business that its consolidated net profit in the shortened financial year of six months had jumped 23.8 percent to 4.67 billion francs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
