<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="774831" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-GLAMORGAN GO TOP OF COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-GLAMORGAN GO TOP OF COUNTY CHAMPIONSHIP.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Glamorgan seized the lead in the race for the English county championship on Monday despite being frustrated by a rescue act from Nottinghamshire all-rounder Chris Tolley.</p>
<p>Tolley hit an unbeaten 73 off 162 deliveries, his highest score for Notts, to save his side from the prospect of an innings defeat on the fourth and last day at Colwyn Bay.</p>
<p>Notts, 151 behind on first innings, slumped to 32 for four in the morning and were later 159 for eight, but hung on to force a draw.</p>
<p>Tolley, who beat his previous best of 67, and James Hindson, with 42 not out, took Notts to safety with an unbroken ninth wicket stand of 80 as their side ended on 239 for eight.</p>
<p>However, the 11 points which Glamorgan took from the game lifted them to a total of 159 points -- 10 ahead of second-placed Gloucestershire, who were not involved in the current round of matches. Both teams have played 11 of their 17 fixtures.</p>
<p>Former England all-rounder Craig White produced championship-best bowling figures of five for 31 to earn Yorkshire a 36-run win over Northamptonshire at Headingley.</p>
<p>Northants, who started the final day promisingly placed at 78 for one in pursuit of a victory target of 213, were undone on an unreliable pitch.</p>
<p>Medium-pacer White had an opening spell of three for five in 17 deliveries, including potential match-winner Kevin Curran without scoring. He subsequently polished off the tail as Northants crumbled to 176 all out.</p>
<p>Third-placed Kent's attempt to close the gap on the leaders by beating Worcestershire at Worcester was dashed by rain.</p>
<p>Set a victory target of 321 in a minimum 80 overs, Kent were spurred to 158 for four by Trevor Ward's 52 in 77 balls before play was washed out for the rest of the final day.</p>
<p>Kent have 147 points, two ahead of fourth-placed Essex, who were held to a draw in a high-scoring affair at Colchester.</p>
<p>Replying to Essex's first innings of 533 for eight declared, Leicestershire made 515 for nine after a ninth wicket stand of 139 betewen Ben Smith and David Millns.</p>
<p>Smith batted through the day for an unbeaten 131, facing 313 balls and hitting 14 fours.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
