<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77482" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Political fears drag Bombay shares down at close.</title>
<headline>Political fears drag Bombay shares down at close.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices fell broadly on Thursday at the Bombay and National bourses in jittery trade caused by fresh worries of political uncertainty, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said sellers outnumbered buyers in sluggish trade after a court rejected an anticipatory bail request by former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao against possible arrest in a criminal conspiracy case.</p>
<p>&quot;There's extreme pessimism,&quot; said one trader. &quot;Collectively, bearish.&quot; The 30-share Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) index ended 38.42 points, or 1.15 percent, lower at a provisional 3,305.50 off the day's low of 3,293.71.</p>
<p>The 50-stock National Stock Exchange (NSE) index dropped 11.99 points, or 1.23 percent, to a provisional 959.01.</p>
<p>The 500-share CRISIL index shed 7.42 points to a provisional 642.22.</p>
<p>The minority coalition government of Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda depends on the support of Rao's Congress party.</p>
<p>On Saturday, Rao stepped down as the president of the Congress after a judge ordered him to personally appear in court as a co-accused in the case.</p>
<p>Two other people accused in the case are in jail pending trial.</p>
<p>Traders said most funds were net sellers during the day. Only the state-owned insurance firms were net buyers.</p>
<p>Bank share SBI fell 5.0 rupees to 259.25 on the BSE. It lost 4.95 to 259.85 at the NSE.</p>
<p>Analysts said a further fall in prices could mar SBI's $400 million global depositary receipt issue which was expected to be priced at a premium to the underlying stock.</p>
<p>IPCL fell 7.0 to 115 after its chief said he expects a net profit of 2.2 billion rupees in the first six months to September 30, against 3.05 billion in the year-ago period.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
