<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77499" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: AMR sees weaker second-half earnings.</title>
<headline>AMR sees weaker second-half earnings.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>AMR Corp chief executive Robert Crandall said Thursday that the airline company's earnings were expected to be weaker in the second half of the year than they were in the first half.</p>
<p>He said profits at AMR, parent of American Airlines, had improved strongly year over year in the first half. &quot;I expect that level of improvement to drop dramatically as the year goes on...Certainly earnings will not be as good in the rest of the year as they have been in the first part of the year,&quot; he said, referring to the third and fourth quarters. He spoke to reporters after a speech to a business group in Vancouver.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think earnings in the fourth quarter will be a good deal weaker than they have been year-over-year to date,&quot; Crandall said. He cited a sharp rise in fuel prices and the reimposition of a 10 percent U.S. federal excise tax.</p>
<p>Crandall said AMR expects to close the initial public offering on its SABRE Group Holdings Inc unit in mid-October. AMR announced plans to spin off about 16 percent of the reservation and information system earlier this month.</p>
<p>Crandall said AMR hopes the offering will be priced at the high end of its estimated range of $20 to $23 a share. The deal is valued at about $434 million.  </p>
<p>AMR has set no new target date for the finalization of its delayed alliance with British Airways Plc, Crandall said.</p>
<p>The two companies originally aimed to complete the link by next April, but the implementation has been delayed by slow progress in talks between the United States and the United Kingdom on liberalizing air travel.</p>
<p>Crandall said the two airlines would remain patient as long as that process still has &quot;positive momentum.&quot; If it received a &quot;negative signal&quot; from either government, then AMR would &quot;go off and do something else,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He did not elaborate on what those other options might be but said the alliance with British Airways was the most logical. In his talk to the Vancouver Board of Trade, Crandall said he thought the alliance would cause trans-Atlantic fares to decrease.</p>
<p>Crandall said he expects airline fares overall to decline in real terms by about one to two percent a year for the foreseeable future, a trend that he said has been in place for 20 years. Crandall said American hopes to strengthen its link with Canadian Airlines Corp and its Vancouver hub to boost its traffic, especially to Asia.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
