<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775008" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent ends firm on crude cuts, gasoline, Iraq.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent ends firm on crude cuts, gasoline, Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE September Brent crude oil ended Monday some 50 cents higher on a combination of bullish factors, brokers said.</p>
<p>The contract closed up a half a dollar at $19.45 a barrel, off the late intraday high of $19.64.</p>
<p>News that Occidental Petroleum had shut in production and declared force majeure in the Colombian Cano Limon crude field for the second time in three weeks saw prices soar. The field, which was averaging 175,000 barrels per day, was shut after rebel attacks and a landslide over the weekend partially destroyed the pipeline which pumps crude from the lifting terminal.</p>
<p>Approval of the Iraqi aid distribution plan by the U.N. on Monday saw traders needing to cover short positions finding only buyers on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone was short and thought they would buy back when the (Iraq/U.N.) news came out and prices went down. Prices didn't drop and they had to cover anyway,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>September Brent broke through resistance at $19.10 and triggered further buying. Next resistance was seen at $19.69 a barrel, brokers said.</p>
<p>Products on both side of the Atlantic were also independently firm following technical problems at three gasoline units in NW Europe and tight supplies of reformulated gasoline (RFG) in the U.S. on the back of strong demand.</p>
<p>RFG in the U.S. was strongly bid on talk that two major players were having difficulty coming up with barrels that they were obliged to deliver after holding short positions in the August gasoline contract.</p>
<p>August gas oil on the IPE ended the day earlier up 75 cents at $172.25 a tonne. The late rise on crude and U.S. heating oil should see the IPE prompt contract start Tuesday some $3.5-4.0 a tonne firmer, brokers said.</p>
<p>--Siobhan Hayden London Newsroom +44 171 542 8978</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
