<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775024" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Oil rises despite Iraqi export progress.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Oil rises despite Iraqi export progress.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices rose on Monday despite news that the United Nations had removed the last major obstacle to a resumption of Iraqi crude exports.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary General Kofi Annan formally approved a revised aid distribution plan submitted by Baghdad, clearing the way for the first Iraqi crude exports since late May.</p>
<p>Despite expectations that the news from the U.N. would bring prices crashing down London September futures for bellwether North Sea Brent blend edged higher, gaining 11 cents to $19.06 a barrel by 1730 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone knew the headline was going to come out and had shorted the market and came in to buy it,&quot; said one futures broker. &quot;We don't know anything we didn't know a month ago - we'll have Iraqi crude again by mid-August.&quot;</p>
<p>Prices have been helped by technical problems at three gasoline producing units in northwest Europe, which have fuelled fears of scarcer supplies just as holiday makers push demand to its seasonal peak.</p>
<p>Disruptions to Colombian crude supplies after the country's main pipeline was blown up twice and partially destroyed by a landslide at the weekend were also helping to balance the bearish impact of the Iraqi news.</p>
<p>But analysts said the prospect of Iraq's return was bound to work through to the market in the medium-term.</p>
<p>&quot;Once the August demand peak passes, rising supply will be the dominant force affecting price dynamics. Iraq will exacerbate an already oversupplied crude market,&quot; said Washington-based consultants Petroleum Finance Company in a report.</p>
<p>Traders said Iraqi crude could be flowing again from the Mina al Bakr terminal in the Gulf and the Turkish port of Ceyhan in a matter of days once pricing formulas and contracts have been agreed.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the U.N. deal implemented last December, Iraq is allowed to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months in two 90-day periods of $1 billion each to raise money for food and medicine.</p>
<p>The deal was renewed on June 8 but Iraq refused to export any more oil until the U.N. agreed to a streamlined aid distribution plan, depriving world markets of some 600,000 barrels per day of crude.</p>
<p>The fall in crude supply coincided with a surge in U.S. gasoline demand which inflated refinery operating rates.</p>
<p>Prices responded by touching a six-week high of $19.09 a barrel on July 31 but given Monday's news were headed in only one direction, analysts said.</p>
<p>Traders say Iraq looks set to push as much as 1.4 million bpd to buyers in a short burst in an effort to meet the billion-dollar target in the first tranche of the agreement, which expires in early September.</p>
<p>Even so, lean global stocks should prevent crude prices going into an immediate tailspin, they said.</p>
<p>Mehdi Varzi at research house Kleinwort Benson said he had reduced his estimate for the global build in oil stocks during the second quarter by 700,000 barrels a day (bpd) to 1.5 million.</p>
<p>His forecast for the third quarter had been cut by 200,000 bpd to 1.6 million</p>
<p>&quot;Inventories have grown at a much slower rate so far this year than originally feared,&quot; said Varzi.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the stockbuild during the period of Iraq's absence and compare it with what was expected you have a totally different fundamental picture,&quot; a European oil trader said.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>					Aug 04    Aug 01</p>
<p>				     (1730 GMT) (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent		   $19.46    $19.33</p>
<p>    IPE September Brent	 $19.06    $18.95</p>
<p>    NYMEX Sept light crude    $20.30    $20.28</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
