<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77526" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: G24 willing to support SDR allocation plan - draft.</title>
<headline>G24 willing to support SDR allocation plan - draft.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The G24 group of developing countries is willing to support a proposal that would break a two-year deadlock with industrialized nations over the issue of SDRs, the IMF's currency, according to a draft report.</p>
<p>The draft was prepared for delegates of the G24 countries from Africa, Asia, and Latin America, who will meet here Friday and Saturday, as part of the annual meetings of the International Monetary Fund and the World Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;In a spirit of solidarity, (delegates) were prepared to support a one-time move to equalize the ratio of cumulative allocations (of SDRs) to present quotas,&quot; said a copy of the draft obtained by Reuters.</p>
<p>The Special Drawing Rights, an artificial currency issued by the IMF, allows member countries to beef up their currency reserves and effectively boost their borrowing power.</p>
<p>The G24, which groups countries as diverse as India, Saudi Arabia and Brazil, had blocked since a meeting in Madrid two years ago a plan supported by the rich nations to allot about 16 billion SDRs (worth nearly $23 billion) to the IMF's newest members, so-called &quot;transition&quot; countries like Russia.  </p>
<p>Arguing that the IMF's articles only allowed for general allocations of SDRs, they supported an alternative proposal made by IMF managing director Michel Camdessus to issue 36 billion SDRs for a broad-based distribution.</p>
<p>Leading members of the Group of Seven industrialized countries, however, objected to such a large issue, charging that it could trigger inflation.</p>
<p>Camdessus told a news conference Thursday that a breakthrough had been achieved recently, as the IMF's executive board, where all members are represented, supported yet another plan drafted by his staff.</p>
<p>The new plan entails amending the IMF's articles to allow for a special &quot;equity&quot; allocation to bring all countries up to the same ratio of SDRs to their membership quotas.</p>
<p>Camdessus said members have not yet reached an agreement on the size of the issue but ventured that it could be around 26 billion SDRs.  </p>
<p>The G24 draft report said it supported the IMF chief's suggestion &quot;for a benchmark ratio of 33 percent of quotas as a minimum figure for providing a modest contribution to meeting world liquidity needs&quot;.</p>
<p>The amendment of the IMF articles would still have to be approved by member countries' governments.</p>
<p>-- Peter Bate, IMF Newsroom (202) 898-8325</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
