<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775293" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania's M2 money supply 5.56 pct up in June.</title>
<headline>Romania's M2 money supply 5.56 pct up in June.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's M2 money supply rose by 5.56 percent in June after a 4.8 percent increase the previous month, central bank data (BNR) showed on Monday.</p>
<p> ROMANIAN MONEY SUPPLY	 JUNE 97     MAY 97     JUNE 96</p>
<p> M2 money supply (bln ROL)  43,956.9   41,641.1    21,405.2</p>
<p> of which foreign currency  13,074.7   13,245.7     4,858.3</p>
<p>NOTE: M2 is Romania's measure of broad money. Inflation was 2.3 percent in June, down from 4.3 percent the previous month.</p>
<p>The money supply expanded by a year-on-year 105.4 percent in June, when cash in circulation soared by 17.4 percent to 6.36 trillion lei after staying unchanged in May.</p>
<p>Local bankers said the upswing of cash in circulation, which triggered a 12.4 percent rise of M1 narrow money, was a seasonal trend linked with the summer holiday period.</p>
<p>The M1 narrow money, which includes currency outside banks and demand deposits, stood at 11.85 trillion lei in June, when demand deposits grew by 7.1 percent to 5.49 trillion lei.</p>
<p>Household savings saw a 7.9 percent rise to 14.56 trillion lei in June, after an 11.6 percent increase in May. Banks' deposit rates fell to about an annual 70 percent from 87 percent the previous month following slower inflation.</p>
<p>Residents' hard currency deposits slipped, taking 29.7 percent of end-June broad money, down from 31.8 in May. ($=7,407 lei)</p>
<p>-- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
