<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775358" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria Issue Dept assets rise to 3.46 bln marks.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria Issue Dept assets rise to 3.46 bln marks.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) Issue Department assets, which make up BNB foreign exchange reserves, rose to 3.461 billion marks on July 31 from 3.117 billion marks on July 25, a BNB official said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The department's assets rose by 344 million marks to 3.461 billion marks due to net purchases and translation of part of dollar reserves into marks,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The official declined to specify the net amount of marks the central bank had bought from local banks and individuals last week.</p>
<p>Under an IMF-prescribed currency board system introduced on July 1 the lev was pegged at 1,000 to the mark as an anchor in the system and the BNB pledged to buy and sell unlimited volumes of marks at 995 and 1,000 levs, respectively.</p>
<p>The system bans the BNB from lending to the government and commercial banks and requires levs in circulation to be fully matched by BNB foreign exchange reserves.</p>
<p>The cash and nostro accounts in foreign currency of the assets rose to the mark equivalent of 1.745 trillion levs on July 31 from 1.432 trillion levs on July 25, figures showed.</p>
<p>The BNB holding in foreign securities rose to 1.067 trillion levs from 1.041 trillion levs.</p>
<p>Apart from the holding in foreign securities and cash and nostro accounts in foreign currency, the Issue Department assets included 640.727 billion levs in monetary gold and 8.217 billion levs in accrued interest receivable as of July 31.</p>
<p>Currency in circulation, a part of Issue Department liabilities, rose to 834.0 billion levs on July 31 from 806.4 billion levs on July 25 due to mark sales from the BNB to individuals last week.</p>
<p>The department liabilities also included 655.7 billion levs in bank deposits and current accounts on July 31, down from 727.7 billion levs on July 25.</p>
<p>The State Fund for Reconstruction and Development (SFRD) account, also a part of Issue Department liabilities rose to 609.9 billion levs on July 31 from 602.3 billion levs.</p>
<p>Part of the liabilities also were 12.7 billion levs in other deposits and accrued interest payable of 190 million levs.</p>
<p>The liabilities also included a 792.0 billion lev deposit of the BNB Banking Department, a rise by 253.3 billion levs from July 25 as Bulgaria received $137 million loan instalment under an IMF 14-month $510 standby on July 29.</p>
<p>The BNB Banking Department can lend to sound banks only in case of systemic risk for the banking and payment system and its primary objective is to ensure confidence in the liquidity of the banking system and more broadly, the efficiency of key financial markets. -- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 911 88</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
