<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775574" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia landslide leaves scars in mountain villa.</title>
<headline>Australia landslide leaves scars in mountain villa.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>THREDBO, Australia 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The emotional scars from Australia's ski lodge disaster will never disappear for the Snowy Mountain village of Thredbo, but like their tough forefathers whose exploits are seared into folklore, its residents will recover.</p>
<p>Inside a mountain chapel here on Monday, these words of comfort were issued by religious and political leaders to relatives and friends of nine people killed by a mountain landslide and 10 still missing.</p>
<p>&quot;We are sure that the Snowy and its people, who hold such a special place in our nation, in its achievements and in its folklore, will come through these tragic days with that legendary determination,&quot; said Governor-General Sir William Deane, who represents Australia's head of state, Britain's Queen Elizabeth.</p>
<p>The courage of settlers in the Snowy Mountains is immortalised in a late 19th century poem every school pupil knows, The Man From Snowy River, a tale of extraordinary horsemanship in this alpine wilderness.</p>
<p>But Snowy Mountains pastor Clare Singleton said the scars of last week's tragedy would never disappear.</p>
<p>&quot;In our days of deep grieving on the mountainside here, our village has drawn us together,&quot; Singleton said. &quot;In the days ahead we must reach an understanding because the scars of the mountain we will carry always.&quot;</p>
<p>At any other time, it would have been an odd gathering: skiiers kitted out for the snow, dark-suited politicians, white-robed priests and emergency workers wearing orange overalls and cradling hard hats.</p>
<p>In Thredbo on Monday, they hugged, held hands and wept for the dead and missing from the landslide on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>As rescuers looked for another survivor in the wreckage of two ski lodges engulfed in the landslide, over 500 people made the sad pilgrimage to Thredbo's year-old chapel.</p>
<p>Colleagues and friends of survivor Stuart Diver, a ski instructor who lived for 64 hours in a concrete tomb before he was pulled from the rubble on Saturday night, swept down from the snowfields to attend the church service.</p>
<p>Wearing the uniforms of ski instructors and alpine search-and-rescue teams, they leant their skis against the chapel's timber wall and, still wearing their ski boots, clomped inside to join in prayer.</p>
<p>&quot;The rest of Australia really stands in awe of you people in Thredbo and beyond Australia I know that your heroism has been recognised...,&quot; Catholic Bishop Patrick Power said.</p>
<p>&quot;When I saw those rescue workers trudging up the hill, finally carrying Stuart to safety, my mind went back to 1969 when man walked on the moon. When I saw Stuart talk to the world yesterday I felt I was witnessing a miracle.&quot;</p>
<p>The sunlit chapel, built in the lee of Australia's highest mountain, overflowed with mourners, including family of the landslide victims. About 400 people stood outside, many locked in tearful embraces.</p>
<p>Two people, including an elderly woman, fainted.</p>
<p>Inside, two sets of skis and stocks were carried down the central aisle of the chapel and placed before the altar. A bouquet of flowers was then placed between the skis.</p>
<p>&quot;It will take a long time in many ways, but the Snowy Mountains will bounce back and we'll be here to help,&quot; said acting prime minister Tim Fischer, who regularly hikes these mountains.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THREDBO, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
