<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77564" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. EPA approves California's clean air plans.</title>
<headline>U.S. EPA approves California's clean air plans.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) gave final approval on Thursday to a California plan to reduce ozone pollution in seven areas with unhealthy levels of the smog ingredient.</p>
<p>The California state implementation plan, or SIP, would help the state meet federal health standards in those areas, some of which suffer from the nation's highest ozone levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we are approving this plan, which sets out a blueprint for the state to bring healthy air to all Californians,&quot; Felicia Marcus, regional administrator for U.S. EPA's western region said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The plan, first submitted in 1994, received preliminary approval early this year pending public review and comment.</p>
<p>Under the U.S. Clean Air Act, states with unhealthful air are required to submit plans showing how health standards for smog will be met by the deadlines set forth in the law.</p>
<p>Ground-level ozone damages lung tissue and makes the lungs sensitive to other irritants.</p>
<p>&quot;EPA's goal has always been to work with the state to develop its own clean air plan that makes economic and environmental sense for the people of California,&quot; Marcus said.  </p>
<p>The plan sets deadlines for cleaner air based on each of the seven area's current levels of pollution.</p>
<p>The South Coast region, including Los Angeles, must attain the plans standards by 2010, the Southeast Desert by 2007, Ventura and Sacramento by 2005, San Joaquin and San Diego by 1999, and Santa Barbara by 1996.</p>
<p>The EPA recently proposed a tightening of national emission standards for heavy-duty trucks and buses, set new standards for lawn mowers and marine vessels and together with California, agreed with manufacturers to set standards for diesel engines in construction and farm equipment.  </p>
<p>The South Coast Air Quality Management District, an air regulator for greater Los Angeles, recently released a draft 1997 air quality plan, but it remains incomplete and has not been submitted to the EPA. It was not included in today's approved plans, the EPA said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
