<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775780" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks edge up, bond slip again on inflation fears.</title>
<headline>Stocks edge up, bond slip again on inflation fears.</headline>
<byline>Wendy Pollack</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks eked out small gains on Monday while bond prices fell for the second consecutive session as investors grappled with signs of renewed U.S. economic vigour.</p>
<p>The dollar ended mixed after setting new highs early in the day, while gasoline prices rose.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average rose 4.41 points to close at 8,198.45. Economically sensitive sectors such as retailing and technology led the advance, which snapped a brief, two-session losing streak for the blue-chip average.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues led decliners, 1,484 to 1,365, on moderate volume of 456 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index posted solid gains, rising 11.12 points to a record 1,605.45, helped by its weighting toward technology stocks.</p>
<p>Stocks rose despite weakness in the bond market, where interest rates continued to creep higher in the wake of strong manufacturing and employment figures released last Friday.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond fell 12/32, or $3.75 on a $1,000 bond, raising its yield to 6.48 percent from 6.45 percent at Friday's close.</p>
<p>While concern about the pace of growth has bond investors on edge, the stock market has largely held its ground.</p>
<p>&quot;For now, the strong economy is good news because it creates spending and that helps earnings,&quot; said Arnie Owen, managing director of capital markets at Cruttenden Roth. &quot;We certainly aren't seeing any sign it's driving up prices.&quot;</p>
<p>The higher close came a day ahead of a pair of weekly reports on the nation's retail sales activity. With Wall Street on alert for any sign of an overheating economy, the reports -- which often fluctuate erratically week to week -- will draw a high level of scrutiny.</p>
<p>&quot;With the new case of jitters in the bond market, it certainly appears the retail numbers will get some attention,&quot; said Greg Nie, technical analyst at EVEREN Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;I still have a feeling we're underestimating just how strong the economy is, but even so, that is more of a hurdle for bonds than stocks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The dollar rallied to its highest level against the German mark in nearly eight years early Monday, but it retreated to close at 1.8655 German marks, up from 1.8625 marks on Friday. The dollar ended lower at 1.5250 Swiss francs from 1.5267 on Friday and rose to 6.2935 French francs from 6.2810.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, gasoline prices rose sharply for a second straight day, fuelled by supply disruptions at home and abroad. At the New York Mercantile Exchange, gasoline for September delivery rose 1.67 cents a gallon, to 66.74 cents.</p>
<p>Overseas, Britain's FTSE 100 closed at 4895.7, down 3.6 points, or 0.07 percent. In Tokyo, the 225-share Nikkei average closed at 19,668.07, down 136.31 points, or 0.69 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
