<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775888" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton aide to hold talks with UPS, union.</title>
<headline>Clinton aide to hold talks with UPS, union.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top adviser to President Clinton will hold talks with officials from United Parcel Service of America Inc and its union Monday, but U.S. officials played down the chances of Clinton intervening to end the firm's strike.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry told reporters that Bruce Lindsey, the White House aide who also tracked the tobacco settlement talks for Clinton, would meet at the White House later on Monday with a representative from UPS.  </p>
<p>He said that Lindsey had already spoken by telephone with an official from the Teamsters union, which early on Monday went on strike at UPS.  The parcel company controls four-fifths of the U.S. package delivery business.</p>
<p>Earlier Monday Clinton said it was not appropriate for him to intervene in the strike now and McCurry echoed his remarks, saying the Taft-Hartley Act required that the nation's health or economy be imperilled before the president could step in.</p>
<p>&quot;The president has the authority in some situations under the Taft-Hartley Act to ... intervene in a strike,&quot; McCurry said, adding that the law was last invoked by former President Harry Truman to end a steel strike in 1952.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a rarely used device available to the president, and the president clearly chooses not to do so at this time,&quot; he added.  &quot;But we also are going to monitor the strike to see what impact it has ... and whether it does begin to affect the health, safety and welfare of the American people.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
