<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775872" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US economy bright, but inflation not dead--SF Fed.</title>
<headline>US economy bright, but inflation not dead--SF Fed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. economic picture has been bright, but that is not to say that inflation has been tamed for good, said Robert Parry, president of the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco.</p>
<p>&quot;The national economy has been performing extraordinarily well,&quot; Parry told an American Bar Association conference in San Francisco on Monday. A copy of his speech was made available in New York.  </p>
<p>&quot;But, like any economist, I'm also a little suspicious of claims that we've achieved some kind of nirvana, where inflation is dead and where the good times will roll on forever,&quot; the San Francisco Fed chief added.</p>
<p>He said the central bank must be watchful of inflationary threats, adding that the Fed was prepared to ward off upward price pressures that may arise.</p>
<p>&quot;We're prepared to head off an inflationary threat that may arise,&quot; Parry said. &quot;We want to keep this (economic) expansion going, and that means remaining alert to the risks of an inflationary economy.&quot;  </p>
<p>The San Francisco Fed chief said the central bank's key concern at this point is whether the economic slowdown which started in the second quarter would be enough to prevent an inflation problem from arising.</p>
<p>Parry went on to say that there are reasons to expect sustainable growth rates in the U.S. in the near future although early economic data appeared to show the economy has bounced back at the beginning of the current quarter.  </p>
<p>Among those reasons, the San Francisco Fed chief cited the continued strength of the dollar, restrained federal spending and recent strong spending for real assets, which has pushed stock of real assets to a level where a breather may follow.</p>
<p>Parry had said earlier on Monday that he expected annual U.S. growth rates at about 2.0 and 2.5 percent over the next year or more.</p>
<p>The U.S. economy slowed from a torrid 4.9 percent growth in the first three months of the year to a more sustainable 2.2 percent rate in the second quarter.</p>
<p>Parry also said the positive performance of the U.S. economy has boosted tax revenues, which in turn spells surpluses at the state level and rapidly declining deficits at the federal level.</p>
<p>Parry said a strong dollar, lower benefit costs and increases in productivity have, among other things, helped to keep U.S. inflation low.</p>
<p>The San Francisco Fed president said that while the dollar and lower benefit costs were seen as transitory factors, the gains in productivity were perceived &quot;to reflect fundamental improvements in productivity.&quot;</p>
<p>(( -- Jose Paulo Vicente, 212-859-1676 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
