<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775894" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ohio ballot won't include school funding reform.</title>
<headline>Ohio ballot won't include school funding reform.</headline>
<dateline>COLUMBUS, Ohio 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ohio lawmakers have failed to reach accord on financing school funding reforms and will not place referendums for the overhaul before voters in November, a legislative spokeswoman said Monday.</p>
<p>Ohio lawmakers reached an impasse late Sunday when the House approved a modified funding plan almost immediately rejected by the Senate, said Cheryl Burchard, spokeswoman for House Speaker Jo Ann Davidson, R-Reynoldsburg.</p>
<p>Legislative leaders and Gov. George Voinovich may meet again next week to map out a new school funding plan, Burchard said.</p>
<p>Ohio Supreme Court justices in March found that the state's education funding method relied too heavily on local property taxes and gave lawmakers one year to adopt a new method.</p>
<p>A Voinovich task force recommended raising the state sales tax to generate $1.1 billion of annual revenues to reduce dependence on property taxes. The task force also recommended $5.8 billion of bonds for school construction over 10 years.</p>
<p>Ohio Senate approved the sales tax increase last week, but the state House backed an alternative plan Sunday that was rejected by senators.</p>
<p>The Senate plan also included a property tax increase on businesses and a property tax cut for individuals that would have made the net school funding increase less than the task force recommendations.</p>
<p>The House proposal earmarked a percentage of the general revenue fund for education and pledged $300 million of bonds per year over 10 years for capital improvements.</p>
<p>Lawmakers approved plans requiring school districts to create &quot;rainy day&quot; funds and budget forecasts last week by simple majority votes. The proposed tax increases required 60 percent approval for placement on the ballot.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, Chicago Newsroom, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBUS, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
