<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="775895" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IRS says muni electric output rules a top priority.</title>
<headline>IRS says muni electric output rules a top priority.</headline>
<text>
<p>SAN FRANCISCO, Aug 4 (Reuter - The Internal Revenue Service's top priority in the municipal bond area is to issue private activity rules for electric and gas output facilities, an IRS official told bond lawyers Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our first priority in terms of regulation projects continues to be output regulations,&quot; said Michael Bailey, counsel to IRS' assistant chief counsel for financial institutions and products.</p>
<p>Bailey spoke at a meeting of the American Bar Association's committee on tax exempt financing.</p>
<p>Bailey said Donald Lubick, Treasury assistant secretary for tax policy, met with public power and California officials last week to discuss their fears about private-use curbs on tax-exempt bonds.</p>
<p>Groups are concerned that the restrictions will limit the ability of municipal utilities to compete in an electric power market hurdling toward deregulation.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a meeting held by the assistant secretary last week with a number of industry groups who expressed their concerns (about) how transactions entered into under the new open access regime will be treated under the private activity bond rules,&quot; Bailey said.</p>
<p>Treasury officials said they would try to respond to those concerns &quot;immediately,&quot; Bailey said.</p>
<p>&quot;The highest levels at Treasury know about the concerns that many municipaLly-owned utilities have about open access,&quot; Bailey said.</p>
<p>IRS proposed private activity bond regulations in late 1994, including special rules for electric and gas generation, transmission and distribution facilities.</p>
<p>But in the final package issued January 10, 1997, IRS said it was delaying final standards for output facilities until a later date.</p>
<p>Bailey said work on the output facility rules has priority over other pending muni bond standards, including rules for so-called mixed-use facilities and for bond refundings.</p>
<p>&quot;It's certainly the case that we may move ahead with the output regulations first if that's what's needed to get the project done promptly,&quot; Bailey said.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, U.S. Municipals Desk, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
