<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="776016" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: IBIS DAX narrows losses, closes above 4,300 level.</title>
<headline>IBIS DAX narrows losses, closes above 4,300 level.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares on Monday followed a broad downward trend as traders braced for unemployment and interest rate news expected later this week.</p>
<p>The DAX index of 30 German blue-chip stocks pared back earlier losses but still closed electronic trading down 34.48 points at 4,302.50.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very nervous right now,&quot; said one trader. &quot;We're watching to see what happens to U.S. interest rates and what happens with unemployment in Germany.&quot;</p>
<p>After little new data arrived on Monday to boost trading, traders were looking ahead to Wednesday's announcement of July unemployment data. In June seasonally adjusted joblessness rose by 11,000 to 4.374 million.</p>
<p>&quot;A drop would help private consumption,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Shares could also get a lift on Tuesday if a special session of parliament shows signs of a break-through on tax reform, traders said.</p>
<p>But another deadlock between the coalition and opposition Social Democrats would have little negative effect since most traders have already given up hope for tax cuts, they said.</p>
<p>At the close of Monday's electronic trading, German blue-chips were down across the board.</p>
<p>Volumes were heaviest in banks stocks, as Deutsche Bank AG slipped 1.40 marks to 118, and Dresdner Bank AG fell 2.10 to 80.70. Bayerische Hypo-Bank, soon to merge with fellow Bavarian bank Vereinsbank was among the chief losers in floor trade, down 1.30 marks at 72.80 marks.</p>
<p>Chemical giant BASF AG closed down 80 pfennigs at 69.95 marks and Bayer AG was down 1.54 at 74.66 marks. Pharmaceutical group Schering AG rose 5.15 marks to 202.15.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, traders saw potential boosts this week from a announcement by software group SAP AG. On Teusday it planned to detail a joint venture with chip maker Intel Corp.</p>
<p>SAP shares closed electronic trading on Monday unchanged at 428 marks.</p>
<p>Utility Veba AG, construction group Hochtief AG, athletic shoe maker Adidas AG and drug maker Schering AG planned to release mid-year results later this week.</p>
<p>-- Neal Boudette, Frankfurt Newsroom, +49-69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
