<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="776157" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's &quot;Bandit Queen&quot; threatens suicide.</title>
<headline>India's &quot;Bandit Queen&quot; threatens suicide.</headline>
<byline>Shahid Abbas</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Bandit Queen-turned-politician, Phoolan Devi, on Monday threatened to kill herself in protest against the revival of criminal charges against her.</p>
<p>Devi, who was elected a federal lawmaker for the low-caste Samajwadi Party in 1996, told parliament that the government in her state of Uttar Pradesh had reopened charges she said she had been assured would not be pressed when she surrendered to police in 1983.</p>
<p>Devi was jailed for 11 years without being charged and released in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;I was assured that all the cases against me would be withdrawn or tried in Madhya Pradesh (state). For 11 years I spent day and night in jail without being tried,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;What should I do Mr Speaker?,&quot; Devi asked in a voice choked with emotion. &quot;Should I commit suicide? Where do I seek justice?&quot;</p>
<p>As the parliament's lower house, Lok Sabha, watched in silence, Devi ranted against Uttar Pradesh's chief minister, Mayawati (one name), and the Bahujan Samaj Party's president, Kanshi Ram, saying they had betrayed their concern for low castes.</p>
<p>&quot;Give me justice or give me jail,&quot; Devi said. &quot;What kind of double standards is this?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I will go and die at Kanshi Ram's doorstep on the eve of the 50th anniversary of independence,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>India won independence from Britain on August 15, 1947.</p>
<p>Movie-maker Shekhar Kapur portrayed Devi in the film &quot;Bandit Queen&quot; as a rape victim from a low caste community of boatmen whose career of crime began as a search for revenge on her attackers.</p>
<p>Devi shot to notoriety in 1981 when 22 upper caste men were massacred in Uttar Pradesh.</p>
<p>She denied leading the killers but surrendered in 1983 to police in the neighbouring state of Madhya Pradesh, which contained part of the area where her gang operated.</p>
<p>The Uttar Pradesh high court revived charges against her in February this year at the request of a man who says he was one of her intended victims.</p>
<p>She faces a total of 57 counts including murder.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
