<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="776326" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: M-I Drilling Fluids acquires Nevada barite reserve.</title>
<headline>M-I Drilling Fluids acquires Nevada barite reserve.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Smith International Inc said Monday M-I Drilling Fluids LLC has acquired the Mountain Springs property in Lander County, Nevada, a proven high grade barite deposit.</p>
<p>This property is close to the Greystone mine currently owned and operated by M-I since 1954, which is the largest single producer of barite in the United States.</p>
<p>M-I Drilling Fluids, a leading supplier worldwide of drilling fluids, chemicals, services and equipment to the worldwide oilfield industry, is owned 64 percent by Smith International and 36 percent by Halliburton Co.  </p>
<p>Smith's statement gave no terms for the acquistion.</p>
<p>Ovid Johnson, Senior Vice President - Minerals and Chemicals Operations for M-I, said the acquisition &quot;enhances our current reserve position and ensures our ability to service the U.S. drilling industry well into the next century.&quot;</p>
<p>He further stated, &quot;Acquiring this property is in keeping with our long-term strategy of committing to supply our customer with a high grade product by avoiding the uncertainties associated with the quality and deliverability of imported ore.&quot;</p>
<p>Johnson said it is &quot;becoming more difficult to rely on quality imports to meet those needs. Our forecast for future barite demand indicates that maintaining a U.S. based supply of barite is critical to meet future drilling needs, especially in the Gulf of Mexico.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
