<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77657" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rockwell consolidates divisions. [CORRECTED 22:30 GMT]</title>
<headline>Rockwell consolidates divisions. [CORRECTED 22:30 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>SEAL BEACH, Calif. 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rockwell International Corp said Thursday it plans to consolidate its Collins commercial and government avionics businesses and its communication systems division into one organization.</p>
<p>Effective Oct. 1, both Collins divisions, based in Cedar Rapids, Iowa, and the communications systems division, based in Dallas, Texas, will be consolidated into a division called Avionics and Communications to be headquartered in Cedar Rapids.</p>
<p>A spokesman fo the company said the move is hoped to position the companies for future opportunities and that no job losses are anticipated.</p>
<p>The businesses are expected to generate sales of nearly $1.7 billion in fiscal 1996 and employ a total of 11,600 people, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>Jack Cosgrove, who had headed Collins Avionics and Communications, was named president of Avionics and Communications.</p>
<p>Collins Avionics and Communications and the communications systems division were formerly part of Rockwell's aerospace and defense organization, which was sold to the Boeing Co on August 1.</p>
<p>(Corrects to clarify which units were part of aerospace and defense operations)</p>
<p>Among other things the companies provide military communications systems, air traffic management systems and pioneered the development of Global Positioning System technology.</p>
<p>Shares of Rockwell closed 3/8 higher at 56-1/2 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEAL BEACH, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
