<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="776697" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: HSBC results please market, analysts.</title>
<headline>HSBC results please market, analysts.</headline>
<byline>Joe Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global banking giant HSBC Holdings Plc reported first half profits and dividend well ahead of forecasts on Monday, winning a positive response from the market and banking analysts.</p>
<p>Pre-tax profit in sterling terms rose 13 percent to 2.623 billion pounds ($4.3 billion) while the interim dividend was up 33 percent to 20 pence per share.</p>
<p>Analysts had forecast pre-tax profits of between 2.32 and 2.48 billion pounds and later moved to upgrade their 1997 full-year estimates.</p>
<p>BZW banking analyst Tim Sykes said he was raising his full year forecast to just under 5.22 billion pounds from 5.0 billion, with an estimate of 5.843 billion pounds for 1998 after 5.674.</p>
<p>John Leonard, banking analyst at Salomon Brothers, said he would raise his forecast for 1997 to 5.3 billion stg from 5.1 billion previously and dividend for the full year up to 50.5 or 51 pence per share from 47.</p>
<p>HSBC shares, which were lower ahead of the announcement, jumped to a high of 2326p but later fell back to stand 46p higher at 2239-1/2.</p>
<p>HSBC chairman Sir William Purves said the group had increased attributable profit by 11 percent &quot;despite the adverse exchange rate translation impact of stronger sterling&quot;, thought to have cut profits by upwards of 70 million pounds.</p>
<p>Purves said HSBC would consolidate recent buys in Latin America before moving on to acquire elsewhere, but noted banking assets in mature markets look expensive.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have a shopping list, we look at opportunities all round the world as we've done and followed through in Latin America,&quot; Purves said. &quot;We're not active in this field, we've done quite a lot this year and we'll see that consolidate before we get excited about other things.&quot;</p>
<p>Purves said in an interview he was not against investing in relatively mature markets in principle.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the prices I see, and the premiums you would have to pay for banks in some of these mature markets, I don't think would be in the best interests of our shareholders,&quot; Purves said.</p>
<p>He said the board will address the subject of excess capital when the bank believes it cannot invest it.</p>
<p>&quot;Our business continues to grow...we're not short of lending opportunities. We don't feel that the opportunities in the group are such that we can't use the capital.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the dividend rise, which was greater than analysts had expected, was a function of the bank's policy of making the interim payout a larger proportion of the full year.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think anybody should be thinking that the full-year dividend will be 33 percent up,&quot; Purves said.</p>
<p>HSBC's tier one capital ratio dipped to 9.4 percent at the half year from 9.9 percent at the end of last year due to its investment in Latin America. But Purves noted that the underlying trend was for capital to be generated strongly.</p>
<p>&quot;We've increased the dividend a bit, so you can read into that that we're aware of the capital growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>HSBC owns HongKong Bank in the Far East, Midland Bank in the UK, and its HSBC Americas unit includes Marine Midland. It also has a controlling stake in Hang Seng Bank.</p>
<p>Noting that all units had done well, Purves said HongKong Bank's results had been affected by a significant underwriting loss of some 40 million pounds at its investment banking subsidiary.</p>
<p>HSBC reported growth in loans, especially in Hong Kong, where the property market was buoyant, and in Britain, where corporate and mortgage lending was up.</p>
<p>Purves said the Hong Kong market was very competitive with margins narrowing in the mortgage market but added that the bank had maintained its market share.</p>
<p>He said margins were under pressure at Midland Bank as well though the bank had managed a sharp fall in cost income ratio. Profits at Midland were up 27 percent to 829 million pounds and the unit's performance received much praise from analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;I was very impressed by the ability to generate growth, especially at Midland,&quot; Sykes said. &quot;People found it hard to believe that they could turn Midland around when they bought it 1992, but they've done it.&quot; ($ = 0.613 British Pounds)</p>
<p>- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8864.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
