<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="776685" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - Coffee seen building support for upmove.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Coffee seen building support for upmove.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>--------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p> SEPT	Close  * Support * Resist * RSI14 *   MA10 *   MA40</p>
<p> COFFEE    1,618  *  1,550  *  1,700 *   43  *  1,599 *  1,707</p>
<p>---------------VIEWS FROM THE MARKET - AUG 4--------------</p>
<p>Coffee is likely to need to do more support-building ahead of any attack on strong resistance at $1,700, analysts said.</p>
<p>Traders called it to open $14 down on numbers, but were expecting to see it unchanged.</p>
<p>Coffee has been building support after its big fall from the highs seen at the end of May, Susan Rigg, analyst at Chart Analysis said.</p>
<p>New York coffee futures ended narrowly mixed in uneventful dealings on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very slow session,&quot; said one trader. &quot;The market just seems to be in a holding pattern waiting to see what develops with the (Brazil) weather next week.&quot;</p>
<p>Tight supplies of high-quality arabica coffee and continued dry weather in Central America could propel coffee futures on New York's Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange (CSCE) well over the $2 per lb level, U.S. investment bank Merrill Lynch said, said in a report dated July 31.</p>
<p>No damaging cold is in sight for Brazil's coffee areas over the next five days, independent forecaster Weather Services Corporation said on Monday.</p>
<p>Growers in Brazil's Cooxupe cooperative in Guaxupe, Minas Gerais state, revised downwards their estimate for their 1997/98 coffee crop to 395,065 60-kg bags from a forecast of 433,586 bags in April.</p>
<p>This represented a 49.36 percent drop in relation with 1996/97, Cooxupe said in a statement. The cooperative polled 400 growers.</p>
<p>Colombia's National Coffee Growers' Federation increased the internal coffee price Friday 0.6 percent to 318,875 pesos per 125-kg load.</p>
<p>The previous price for a load set last week was 317,000 pesos.</p>
<p>Indian coffee exporters and traders said they were exploring possibilities of setting up a futures exchange in a bid to minimise risks in a volatile market.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a need for trading in coffee futures in the new environment of liberalisation,&quot; said Arun Bidappa, chief executive of Karnataka Coffee Brokers' Pvt Ltd, a firm involved in coffee auctions.</p>
<p>--Christopher Lyddon, London newsroom +44 171 542 7928</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
