<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="776704" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold easier as palladium nears 17-year high.</title>
<headline>London gold easier as palladium nears 17-year high.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A limit up move on New York's Nymex futures market helped lift spot palladium to within a dollar of its highest London official fixing in 17 years on Monday afternoon against a backdrop of tight nearby supply of the rare white metal.</p>
<p>The fix came in at $239.00 per ounce against $240.00, the 17-year high set on June 6 this year. Its sister metal platinum fixed at $448.00, still well below the seven-year high also achieved on June 6.</p>
<p>The metals posted new contracts highs on the Nymex open and palladium futures as on Friday locked limit up.</p>
<p>NYMEX September palladium was up $9.00 at $215.60 an ounce, a new contract high, while December palladium was also up the expanded second-day limit of $9.00 at 207.60, also a new contract high. October platinum was up $10.00 at $448.50.</p>
<p>Short covering on Tokyo's Tocom futures overnight had sent palladium to limit up in Tokyo for the fourth consecutive day.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a continuation what happened on Tocom where the August shorts had to be covered. There might be some of that here too after spot sales were made in anticipation of Russian deliveries,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Russia only began its 1997 export campaign last month after administrative changes snagged shipments since last December and forcing consumers to use inventories and tightening supply.</p>
<p>So far only small parcels of palladium have been offered in Europe and a couple of shipments have arrived in Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is far from resolved so we can expect to see more price volatility. Whether the price goes up again before it goes down is not so clear,&quot; the dealer added.</p>
<p>Platinum prices were swept along behind palladium but dealers said platinum was also buoyed by industrial users having to buy metal to act as catalysts in chemical processes as leasing metal had become prohibitive, dealers said.</p>
<p>Platinum was quoted at a lease rate of around 30 percent for a month and palladium at over 70 percent for the same period.</p>
<p>Gold fixed slightly easier at $323.55 per ounce down from $324.05 this morning under pressure from a continuingly strong dollar.</p>
<p>Silver was about four cents firmer at $4.50/$4.52 and on the point of pushing into an area of high resistance.</p>
<p>Technically if the $4.50-$4.55 area is overcome, silver could be on its way to $4.80-$4.90, according to technical analysts.</p>
<p>--Brian Spoors London Newsroom +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
