<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="776935" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Teamsters union begins strike at UPS.</title>
<headline>Teamsters union begins strike at UPS.</headline>
<byline>Barbara Hagenbaugh</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Teamsters union began a strike at United Parcel Service on Monday, hours after negotiators failed to agree on a new contract at the largest U.S. small package carrier.</p>
<p>Striking drivers, package-sorters and loaders shut down UPS facilities across the country in a labour dispute over pay, benefits and job security with the company that controls four-fifths of the U.S. package delivery business.</p>
<p>Earlier, Teamsters President Ron Carey said contract talks had broken down and there was no sense in continuing negotiations with a federal mediator and company officials.</p>
<p>&quot;We have exhausted every possible approach to solve the problem,&quot; Carey told reporters as the union delegation left the talks just after 10 p.m. EDT (0200 GMT) on Sunday.</p>
<p>Chief UPS negotiator Dave Murray called the union's decision to abandon the talks &quot;highly irresponsible&quot; and said the union's leadership should let its members review the company's &quot;last, best and final offer,&quot; made last week.</p>
<p>Immediately after the talks broke down, Labour Secretary Alexis Herman called on the two sides to go back to the bargaining table and avoid disruption to the public.</p>
<p>&quot;UPS and Teamsters representatives should press on and not rest until they find the common ground that resolves this dispute with the least disruption,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>UPS handles 12 million packages a day and employs 301,000 people in the United States, 185,000 of whom are represented by the Teamsters.</p>
<p>&quot;We're striking for every worker in America. We can't have only low service-industry wages in this country,&quot; said Randy Walls, a 47-year-old UPS tractor-trailer driver on nighttime picket duty in Atlanta.</p>
<p>The Independent Pilots Association said its 2,000 UPS pilots would refuse work in the event of a strike.</p>
<p>Murray said the company would do all it could to ensure that hospital supplies, blood supplies and packages containing other critical supplies reached their destinations.</p>
<p>&quot;We have many contingency plans,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Federal mediator John Calhoun Wells said the strike would affect hundreds of thousands of workers and millions of UPS customers and affect the overall U.S. economy.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't succeed, that's deeply disappointing,&quot; said Wells, who directs the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service. &quot;They were far enough apart so that we were unable to bridge the gap this evening,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>UPS Chairman James Kelly and his negotiating team arrived about an hour before the union on Sunday to meet with the mediator and consider a new union proposal, but the talks stalled.</p>
<p>The White House has been keeping close tabs on the negotiations, but spokesman Barry Toiv said President Bill Clinton did not plan to intervene at this time.</p>
<p>&quot;At this time, the administration does not believe that the standard for intervention under the Taft-Hartley Act has been met,&quot; Toiv said, referring to a federal law that has not been used for decades.</p>
<p>Carey said the union was particularly concerned about preventing work going to subcontractors rather than union workers, the pension plan, and health and safety issues.</p>
<p>UPS said last week that the threat of a strike was costing it about $5 million a day in business lost to competitors such as the Postal Service and Federal Express Corp.</p>
<p>The Postal Service said it will limit the number of parcels customers can mail at a single time and take other steps to handle an expected increase in volume.</p>
<p>UPS spokeswoman Gina Ellrich said the carrier's daily shipping volume was already down by 1 million packages from 12 million, forcing it to lay off several thousand workers.</p>
<p>In its contract offer, UPS offered to boost pay for both full- and part-time workers by $1.50 to $2.50 per hour over five years. Under the company proposal, a profit-sharing plan would provide a first payment of $3,060 to full-time employees and $1,530 to part-time workers in 1997.</p>
<p>With revenue of $22.4 billion in 1996, UPS annually handles about 3 billion parcels and documents, shipped to more than 200 countries from 1,700 hubs and centres.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
