<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="776973" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: World Trade Center bomb trial opens.</title>
<headline>World Trade Center bomb trial opens.</headline>
<byline>Jeanne King</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The accused mastermind in the 1993 World Trade Centre bombing goes on trial on Monday, just days after authorities said they had foiled an alleged suicide bomb attack on the New York subway.</p>
<p>U.S. judge Kevin Duffy said on Friday he would question each juror about whether last week's events would prevent them from being impartial in the trial of Ramzi Yousef and co-defendant Eyad Ismoil.</p>
<p>Last Thursday, police raided a Brooklyn apartment, seizing five pipe bombs and arresting three Middle Eastern men, two of whom were shot in the raid. The two wounded men were charged with planning to bomb the New York subway system and the third is held on immigration charges, officials said.</p>
<p>In the trial starting Monday, Yousef is accused of planning and planting the 1,200 pound (545 kilogram) fertiliser bomb that exploded Feb. 26, 1993, killing six people and injuring more than 1,000 others in the 110-story twin towers.</p>
<p>Ismoil is accused of driving the van that carried the bomb into the trade centre basement garage.</p>
<p>Yousef is of Palestinian and Pakistani ancestry and Ismoil is Jordanian.</p>
<p>Judge Duffy said on Friday he would individually question each of the 12 permanent jurors and six alternates on Monday before the start of opening arguments in the case.</p>
<p>Duffy said after a four-day hearing last week that he would not bar government scientific experts from testifying about chemical residue found during the extensive probe.</p>
<p>Defence lawyers wanted the testimony excluded at the trial after a highly publicised report by the Justice Department's Inspector General last April criticised the FBI's handling of the case in their crime laboratories.</p>
<p>Yousef was indicted in 1993 on charges of taking part in the trade centre bombing, along with four Moslem fundamentalists who were convicted in 1994. The four were each sentenced to 240 years in prison for their roles in the devastating explosion.</p>
<p>Prosecutors say Yousef fled the country on a plane to Karachi, Pakistan, just hours after the explosion. Yousef was one of the world's most wanted fugitives, with a $2 million bounty on his head, until his February 1995 arrest in Pakistan.</p>
<p>In September 1996, Yousef and two other radical Moslems were convicted of planning to bomb 12 U.S. passenger jets over the Pacific Ocean to punish the United States for its support of Israel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
