<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777058" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German rye and barley harvests make swift progress.</title>
<headline>German rye and barley harvests make swift progress.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Barley and rye harvests across Germany have made good progress and will be completed over the next fortnight when wheat reaches maturity, farm sources said.</p>
<p>Barley prices were easing under harvest pressure and a lack of demand so most farmers were planning to store the grain to await market developments in the early autumn, they said.</p>
<p>Northern states reported roughly three quarters of barley had been cut, with some wheat and triticale also harvested.</p>
<p>Barley yields in the north were in a broad range between 5.5 and 8.00 tonnes per hectare (tph) versus the pan-German 1996 average of 5.61 tph.</p>
<p>Farmers in Schleswig-Holstein, in northern Germany, reported barley yield spikes of 8.00-9.00 tph on heavy soils.</p>
<p>Farmers in North Rhine-Westphalia, Rhineland-Palatinate and Hesse reported similar barley results, although rainfall in these regions in the middle of Germany had been more frequent and excessive, boosting moisture levels.</p>
<p>Spring barley with malting properties had been harvested with 10-11 percent protein in Saar state, 11.5 percent in the adjacent Rhineland, 9-11 percent in Baden-Wuerttenberg and 9-11.5 percent in Baden.</p>
<p>But Bavaria said malting qualities would be rare this year.</p>
<p>Farmers in other southern states had nearly completed the barley harvest and were reporting medium to good yields.</p>
<p>In eastern Germany, Thuringia state had only completed 50 percent of the barley harvest with yields in a 4.00-8.00 tph range and Saxony was also reporting a wide range of 5.6-10.0 tph.</p>
<p>Domestic wheat prices were slow to emerge ahead of the harvest because buyers and sellers could not agree on levels as early quality indications were too varied.</p>
<p>Initially low rye falling numbers, an indicator of baking qualities, depressed prices.</p>
<p>Falling numbers below 100/120 disqualify rye for flour use.</p>
<p>In Saxony and Thuringia, they varied between 80 and 180 and in North Rhine-Westphalia, they were between 120 and 160.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
