<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77717" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Able Telcom to buy Georgia Electric Co.</title>
<headline>Able Telcom to buy Georgia Electric Co.</headline>
<dateline>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla. 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Able Telcom Holding Corp said Thursday it had signed an agreement to buy Georgia Electric Co within the next 30 days.</p>
<p>Able Telcom said it expected the acquisition to have a &quot;positive effect&quot; on its net income and earnings per share.</p>
<p>It also said it expected to reach revenues on a consolidated basis of $75-$80 million, with improved operating margins, in fiscal 1997.  </p>
<p>Able Telcom said the purchase price for Georgia Electric would be a cash amount and a five-year earn-out arrangement based on achieving certain pre-tax income and margins. It gave no details.</p>
<p>Georgia Electric, which will operate as a wholly owned subsidiary of Able Telcom, is projected to have revenues of $27-$30 million in fiscal 1997, Able said.</p>
<p>Georgia Electric, which specializes in intelligent highway systems like computerized traffic lights, has averaged pre-tax margins of up to 12 percent during the past five fiscal years.  </p>
<p>Able Telcom said it had created a division called Traffic Management Services as a result of the acquisition. The division will consist of three traffic management companies -- Transportation Safety Contractors Inc, TSCI of Virginia and GEC.</p>
<p>Able Telcom installs telecommunications networks for telephone companies and provides highway signage, lighting and other traffic control systems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WEST PALM BEACH, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
