<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777128" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn rejects Iran demands on return of EU envoys.</title>
<headline>Bonn rejects Iran demands on return of EU envoys.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel said on Monday the European Union would not allow Tehran to dictate the terms of the return of EU ambassadors to Iran.</p>
<p>All EU states except Greece recalled their ambassadors from Tehran after a German court ruled in April that Iran's top leaders had ordered the 1992 assassination of four Iranian Kurdish dissidents in a Berlin restaurant.</p>
<p>Iran, which strongly rejected the court's conclusion, has said the envoys can return to Tehran but has indicated the German ambassador must be the last.</p>
<p>&quot;The German government, along with the other EU member states, is of the opinion that discrimination is out of the question when it comes to the return of the ambassadors,&quot; Kinkel said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;For this reason, a return of the EU ambassadors has not yet come about. We cannot and will not let the Iranian side dictate the conditions for this,&quot; said the minister, who also thanked Germany's European partners for their solidarity over the issue.</p>
<p>Kinkel made clear he was in favour of a return of the envoys, although not at the price demanded by Tehran.</p>
<p>&quot;After a longer pause for thought, the attempt should be made to get in contact with one another again,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
