<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777262" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Pearson aims to double value in five yrs.</title>
<headline>Pearson aims to double value in five yrs.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British media and leisure company Pearson Plc aims to double in value over the next five years, chief executive Marjorie Scardino said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal will be double digit earnings per share every year and a doubling of the value of the company during the next five years,&quot; Scardino said in a statement. Pearson reported first half pre-tax profit of 81 million pounds ($132.1 million) and adjusted earnings per share of 6.0p.  </p>
<p>&quot;These results represent the first step in our commitment to improve the company's performance,&quot; said Scardino, commenting on a first half performance which easily beat analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect further growth in group revenues and operating profits in the second half of the year, tempered by revenue investment in the Financial Times newspaper, Financial Times Information and Channel 5, as well as by the impact of sterling's strength,&quot; added Scardino, who took up her post in January.</p>
<p>&quot;The focus on improving performance, established as a priority at the start of the year, is evident in these results and should underpin future growth,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The company said it had acquired Resource Data International, a U.S. energy publishing business, for 15 million pounds ($24.5 million). ($ = 0.613 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
