<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777265" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sterling strength hits British Airways' profits.</title>
<headline>Sterling strength hits British Airways' profits.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways Plc announced a sharp fall in underlying profits on Monday with operating profits for the three months to June 30 dropping 55 million pounds ($89.7 million) to 140 million pounds, hit by the strength of sterling and industrial disputes.</p>
<p>Pretax profits jumped 46.7 percent to 220 million pounds thanks to an exceptional gain of 130 million pounds from the sale of its stake in former U.S. partner US Air. But the airline said that the strength of sterling depressed profits by 77 million pounds.  </p>
<p>Industrial disputes cost the company some 15 million pounds in lost revenue and contingency moves in the first quarter but BA said it expected the full impact of the three-day strike by cabin crew would wipe a further 110 million pounds off profits in the second quarter.</p>
<p>The airline was locked in talks all last week with it main cabin crew union BASSA in an effort to settle the dispute over plans to save 42 million pounds a year from restructuring cabin crew pay.</p>
<p>BA and the union have agreed not to comment on the progress of negotiations until they are complete.</p>
<p>The airline said that elsewhere in the group its efforts to cut a billion pounds off annual costs by the year 2000 through outsourcing and rationalisation were running to plan, with 200 million pounds of the target expected to be achieved in the current year.</p>
<p>The airline said productivity in the first-quarter improved 6.2 percent as a result. Employee costs rose 3.8 percent to 572 million pounds but said 2,200 people had joined the payroll since a year ago.</p>
<p>Total traffic for the three months to June 30 rose 7.8 percent and capacity by 6.7 percent with an average 73 percent of all seats sold on every flight, an increase of 0.7 percentage points on a year ago.</p>
<p>But the average fare paid per passenger for every kilometre flown fell 2.4 percent, which the airline said was &quot;more than explained&quot; by the increased strength of sterling. ($ = 0.613 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
