<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777246" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Metals Outlook--Aluminium, options in spotlight.</title>
<headline>Metals Outlook--Aluminium, options in spotlight.</headline>
<byline>Eric Onstad</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The metals markets are expected to zero in on aluminium this week when London Metal Exchange (LME) options are declared.</p>
<p>Eyes will also be on zinc as players nervously watch for any signs of aftershocks from the plunge from seven-year highs last week.</p>
<p>Three months aluminium surged to a 21-month high of $1,740 last Friday as a squeeze in the August date, said to be linked to options, constricted the market.</p>
<p>Funds and investment banks leapt in and help fuelled the move while consumers were said to be holding back, waiting for a dip as physical premiums held firm.</p>
<p>The next upside target was said to be the November 1995 peak of $1,745, but some analysts said the market was overbought and needed a rest.</p>
<p>The 14-day RSI ended last week at 81, well above the 70 region regarded as overbought.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a bit wary on how much the upside can do,&quot; said analyst Martin Squires of broker Rudolf Wolff.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm still overall bullish on the market and while it trends you should stick with it, but just beware it's getting to the point where you might see some profit taking,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The cash/three months spread flipped into a modest backwardation last week.</p>
<p>Some traders said a big player who was short of options had to cover the position by borrowing in the futures market.</p>
<p>The LME options declaration on Wednesday could spark interest in aluminium, with grantors said to be short above the $1,700 strike.</p>
<p>With large chunks of options open interest above the market in forward months, there are good prospects for more delta hedging to kick in.</p>
<p>The $1,700 strike in call options is the focus, with 1,555 lots in August, 2,452 lots in September, 3,174 lots in October and 2,166 lots in November.</p>
<p>In zinc, a nervous market was still unsure how much more covering had to be done by Chinese smelters, but tightness was still being felt, with the cash/threes spread ending last week at a $76/$86 backwardation.</p>
<p>Some players believe the three months will remain relatively stable after its $300 plunge to a low of $1,370 last week, and action will shift to the spreads.</p>
<p>&quot;The longs have sold the three months but they've kept the (September) date. So the market is open to another squeeze at some point before September,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think China has enough zinc, but they haven't got the right dates,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Squires said he believed three months could make a move up to $1,500 or $1,530 this week as short-covering continues. China appears to have rolled some of its position forward while some consumers may need to enter the market, he said.</p>
<p>Copper was less active last week as the backwardation contracted, with the cash/threes ending the week at $30/$35.</p>
<p>Three months, which ended Friday at $2,310, would try to consolidate above $2,300, but with stocks expected to keep rising, tests of the downside were expected eventually, analysts said.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542-8065</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
