<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777407" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: FOCUS - Ringgit soars as Malaysia reverts to curbs.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Ringgit soars as Malaysia reverts to curbs.</headline>
<byline>Syed Azman</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The ringgit jumped almost two percent against the dollar at one stage on Monday after Malaysia reverted to foreign exchange controls to curb speculation that has battered the local currency for the past month.</p>
<p>The ringgit surged to a high of 2.5800 to the dollar during Sydney trading against its close of 2.6290/320 in Kuala Lumpur on Friday. It fell back to around 2.6075 to the dollar at 0500 GMT.</p>
<p>On Sunday, the central Bank Negara Malaysia said that from Monday, local banks will have to limit their non-trade related swap transactions in the foreign exchange market to $2.0 million with each overseas customer.</p>
<p>The announcement came a few days after Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad's warning of possible action against those he recently lambasted as &quot;rogue speculators&quot;.</p>
<p>Mahathir also blamed Malaysians for being involved in recent speculative attack on the ringgit by making available the local currency to speculators.</p>
<p>The $2.0 million ceiling will limit the amount of ringgit overseas players can get hold of.</p>
<p>&quot;The authorities are sending a clear message to speculators,&quot; said P.K. Basu, regional economist at UBS in Singapore. &quot;The message is also clear that Malaysia does not want to see the ringgit falling below 2.60 (to the dollar).&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts said that although the move could be a step back in Malaysian efforts to become an international financial centre, it was necessary given the speculative pressure on the ringgit.</p>
<p>Stock investors did not take kindly to the capital controls, driving share values down even as the ringgit recouped. At midday, the Composite Index of 100 key blue chips was down 13.61 points or 1.36 percent to 989.02.</p>
<p>The central bank said banks which had exceeded the limit would not be allowed further swap transactions until the outstandings were reduced.</p>
<p>Hedging requirements of foreigners for trade-related and genuine portfolio and direct investments in Malaysia were not affected by this measure, the central bank said.</p>
<p>A swap is a forward rate agreement for exchanging one currency to another.</p>
<p>Malaysia imposed a similar restriction in February 1989.</p>
<p>Dealers said the curbs would bring down domestic swaps and push up overseas rates, effectively creating a two-tier market.</p>
<p>Southeast Asian currencies, including the ringgit, have been under speculative attack since mid-May, resulting in de facto devaluations of the Thai baht and the Philippine peso.</p>
<p>Indonesia widened the trading band for the rupiah and the Singapore dollar also fell sharply.</p>
<p>The ringgit fell over five percent during the period to a three-year low of 2.6530 to a dollar.</p>
<p>Bank Negara has spent $2.0-3.0 billion defending the ringgit in the past few weeks.</p>
<p>The dollar sales by the central bank mopped up six to eight billion ringgit from the market, leaving the domestic banking system heavily short of funds and causing interbank rates to shoot up.</p>
<p>Bank Negara is now trying to bring the rates back down.</p>
<p>The central bank said on Sunday the limit on swaps transactions was to help control interest rates more effectively. On Friday, Bank Negara asked commercial banks to hold their base lending rates (BLR) steady despite the recent surge in interbank rates.</p>
<p>&quot;First there was the move to cap the BLR and now the swap restrictions. It is quite obvious now that the authorities are looking to bring down interest rates, sooner rather than later,&quot; said an analyst at a research house in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;With the two-tier market, it means the authorities will not have to worry about lower interest rates threatening ringgit strength,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Economists said it was unlikely that more capital controls would be imposed.</p>
<p>&quot;The swaps restriction will certainly suffice to reduce speculation,&quot; Basu said. &quot;Also, too many capital controls will not be good for the country.&quot; He expects the authorities to remove the curbs after three months.</p>
<p>Finance Minister and Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim indicated on Monday that no further capital controls were planned. Asked if any more steps were in the works, Anwar told reporters, &quot;Not until today&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
