<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777400" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Hun Sen insists ousted prince must face trial.</title>
<headline>Hun Sen insists ousted prince must face trial.</headline>
<byline>Robert Birsel</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodian leader Hun Sen on Monday ruled out talks with Prince Norodom Ranariddh, the co-premier he ousted last month, at least until after the prince stood trial.</p>
<p>Hun Sen, who overthrew Ranariddh on July 6 after two days of fighting in Phnom Penh, said he might support a royal amnesty for Ranariddh if the prince's father, King Norodom Sihanouk, wanted to grant him a pardon if he was convicted in court.</p>
<p>&quot;After the court, not before the court,&quot; Hun Sen told reporters when asked if he would negotiate with Ranariddh. &quot;I don't need to discuss with Ranariddh but he must discuss with the court.&quot;</p>
<p>Ranariddh left Cambodia shortly before last month's fighting and has called from abroad for opposition to Hun Sen.</p>
<p>Hun Sen has said the prince was free to return home, but would have to face trial for his negotiations with the outlawed Khmer Rouge guerrilla group and for alleged weapons smuggling.</p>
<p>Since taking sole power, Hun Sen has said he wants his coalition with Ranariddh's royalist FUNCINPEC party to remain in place, for FUNCINPEC to choose a successor for Ranariddh as first prime minister, and for elections to be held in May as scheduled.</p>
<p>Three envoys from the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) raised the thorny question of a role for Ranariddh in talks with Hun Sen at the weekend.</p>
<p>The envoys, led by Indonesian Foreign Minister Ali Alatas, told Hun Sen that all political players in Cambodia should be allowed to take part in the election in May if it was to be credible.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Hun Sen) agreed with us that the general elections in May would have no meaning unless participated in by all political forces, and all political parties, freely,&quot; Alatas told a news conference.</p>
<p>Alatas declined to reveal more details of his talks with Hun Sen concerning Ranariddh, saying the prince had to be informed of the discussion first.</p>
<p>A diplomat from the region said on Monday he believed Hun Sen was willing to negotiate Ranariddh's future role, despite his apparent insistence that the prince stood trial.</p>
<p>&quot;That's not so surprising,&quot; the diplomat said when told of Hun Sen's comments on Monday concerning the prince facing trial.</p>
<p>&quot;But I think it's negotiable. I think Hun Sen is willing to talk about it,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>Hun Sen appealed on Monday to politicians who fled the country in the wake of Ranariddh's overthrow, to return.</p>
<p>Many members of the royalist FUNCINPEC party and its sympathisers left Cambodia after the prince's ouster including some 20 members of parliament, either members of FUNCINPEC or a smaller allied party.</p>
<p>Among those who fled was Son Soubert, one of two National Assembly vice presidents, whose approval of certain motions, including the appointment of a new first prime minister, is required under the assembly's rules.</p>
<p>Son Soubert's absence has brought into question the proper functioning of parliament, but Hun Sen said those who left could not hold the assembly hostage.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to appeal again to members of parliament who are staying outside the country in fear, please return,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said he guaranteed the safety of those returning but added that anyone coming back to get involved in politics must cut any links with the Khmer Rouge guerrilla group.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the condition... it's the law,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
