<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777448" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China takes cue from U.S. Fed, forms monetary body.</title>
<headline>China takes cue from U.S. Fed, forms monetary body.</headline>
<byline>William Kazer</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has taken a bold move to reduce political influence in setting money supply by creating a special policy body modelled after the U.S. Federal Reserve, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>The new group, which held its first meeting last week, is only an advisory body but it is headed by the central bank chief and is vaguely patterned after the policy-setting Federal Open Market Committee, which determines U.S. interest rate levels.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very positive step,&quot; said Chen Xingdong, chief economist (China) at Peregrine Brokerage Ltd in Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;This will make the setting of monetary policy more stable.&quot;</p>
<p>Monetary policy in China is highly politicised and is ultimately determined by the State Council (cabinet) with competing factions and regional interests exerting political leverage, often obstructing the views of the central bank, or People's Bank of China.</p>
<p>The banking system has been the lifeblood of many money-losing state enterprises, which wield considerable clout due to their role as major employers and vital components in maintaining social order.</p>
<p>They have traditionally pushed for policy loans to keep them afloat and easier monetary policies to reduce their heavy debt burden.</p>
<p>In the past, the central bank made its own policy recommendations but competing interests would plead their case with the State Council.</p>
<p>&quot;That's where the disputes would be,&quot; said Chen.</p>
<p>With the new body, known as the monetary policy committee of the People's Bank of China, monetary policy would be debated at a technical level and then a recommendation would be drafted for the State Council to review.</p>
<p>&quot;This body will be much like the Federal Open Market Committee,&quot; said an official at the China Everbright Bank, who declined to be identified by name.</p>
<p>&quot;This will mean the nation's monetary policy will be determined more on the basis of supply and demand for credit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The body, which will hold quarterly meetings, will be headed by central bank governor Dai Xianglong and vice governor Chen Yuan will act as deputy.</p>
<p>Its members include deputy director of the State Planning Commission Wang Chunzheng as well as senior officials of the State Economic and Trade Commission, the finance ministry, the securities watchdog the China Securities Regulatory Commission, the foreign exchange regulatory body, the heads of two of the nation's top commercial banks and a renowned academic.</p>
<p>At its first meeting, the policy committee agreed to continue the central bank's &quot;appropriately tight&quot; monetary policies, the official China Daily said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an advisory body,&quot; said Wu Xiaoqiu, director of the department of finance and securities at People's University, an academic institute in Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;But it will ensure medium and long term interests are considered in the setting of monetary policy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
