<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777459" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Product Swaps - Gas oil shrugs IOC, looks West.</title>
<headline>Asia Product Swaps - Gas oil shrugs IOC, looks West.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore gas oil swaps rose at midday on Monday in quiet trade despite an unexpectedly low award from India for September arrival cargoes as the market looked West for support, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The price increase is unexpected. It is due to the shutdown of the three cat-cracker units in Europe which have pushed the nunmbers up,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>August was last quoted at $22.60/$22.75, up from Friday's $22.45/$22.55, brokers said.  </p>
<p>August traded to an intra-day low of $22.45 on Friday after news of the low India award first filtered through the market, they said.</p>
<p>Two catalytic converters, one at the BP/Texaco Nerefco refinery in Rotterdam and one at the BP/Mobil Coryton refinery in the U.K. were shut down on Friday due to technical problems, taking out 115,000 barrel-per-day (bpd) of capacity until the middle of next week.</p>
<p>In addition, Shell confirmed on Friday that the cat-cracker at its Pernis refinery has closed for an unscheduled stoppage in August followed by a scheduled maintenance of two months.  </p>
<p>The shutdown of these two units led to August gas oil ending up $2.50 on London's International Petroleum Exchange on Friday to $171.50 per tonne.</p>
<p>Traders said the market discounted India's low purchase of 90,000 tonnes of high-speed diesel in two cargoes for September delivery, well below even the most conservative estimate of 200,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a low volume time of the year,&quot; one trader said. &quot;But the fact that India took the much lower volume is surprising. I think they are trying to talk down the market in anticipation of some term talks.&quot;  </p>
<p>August fuel oil was steady at $101.00/$101.75 per tonne, brokers said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
