<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777516" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta stocks seen stable, tone cautious.</title>
<headline>Jakarta stocks seen stable, tone cautious.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta stocks are seen stable in slow trading on Monday, with sentiment likely to be cautious on announcements of poor first half results, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment is likely to be cautious after announcements of poor first half results by some companies, particularly Semen Gresik,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Semen Gresik, one of the largest capitalised stocks on the market, announced on Monday a sharp drop in its first half net profit.</p>
<p>He added that the failure was partly due to the weak cement demand as developers postponed their projects because of the May general elections. Rachmat said Gresik was likely to remain under selling pressure in the next several days.</p>
<p>Other active stocks included Citra Marga, on reports that the toll road operator, controlled by President Suharto's daughter Siti Hardianti Rukmana, was likely to take over the operation of some lucrative inner city toll roads from state-owned Jasa Marga.</p>
<p>Citra Marga rose 50 rupiah to 1,375 rupiah, with some 4.7 million shares traded. </p>
<p>Brokers, however, said they expected local buying in some second-liners, due mostly to speculation, to limit the downside.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Jakarta composite index was up 0.50 points to close at 721.77 points.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
