<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777686" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: FOCUS-QNI -Gencor merger seen back on track.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-QNI -Gencor merger seen back on track.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Hickey</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The A$2.3 billion merger of Australian nickel producer QNI Ltd with Gencor Ltd's Billiton Nickel looks set to gain grudging shareholder approval after the deal was sweetened on Tuesday, analysts said.</p>
<p>QNI announced revised terms for the merger, reducing the number of shares to be issued to Billiton Nickel to 455.802 million shares (52.5 percent of the enlarged QNI) from 504.03 million (55 percent) and raising a planned capital return to 30 cents a share from 28 cents.</p>
<p>QNI's initial merger plan announced in mid-June met a wall of dissent from Australian shareholders, who said they were disappointed Gencor was not paying a takeover premium and that Gencor's assets were over-valued in the deal.</p>
<p>Angry analysts and institutional investors confronted QNI and Gencor managers at briefings in Melbourne and Sydney after the initial plan was announced, saying they were considering rejecting the deal at a shareholder meeting.</p>
<p>QNI and Gencor went back into a huddle through July as independent valuer Grant Samuel and Associates examined the deal to decide whether or not it was fair and reasonable.</p>
<p>In a report released with the revised deal, Grant Samuel said the deal was fair and reasonable, saying their valuation of Billiton Nickel's assets was within their valuation range for QNI's assets.</p>
<p>Analysts and brokers said investors were now likely to accept the deal at a shareholder meeting expected to be held on or about September 5. But they said the approval would be more grudging than enthusisatic.</p>
<p>&quot;I would think it will get through now, but only because the alternative doesn't look overly attractive,&quot; said one Sydney base metals analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;I suspect it will probably go through,&quot; said one senior broker. &quot;Even though people are saying, where's my takeover premium, there's nothing better that's going to come along.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts pointed to several comments in the Grant Samuel report which they said were unlikely to soothe many investors concerns about the deal.</p>
<p>Grant Samuel said the assumptions underpinning its A$933 million to A$1.103 billion valuation of Billiton Nickel's key asset, the Cerro Matoso nickel mine and smelter in Colombia, was not as conservative as other potential buyers could adopt.</p>
<p>&quot;This estimate is regarded as full value.&quot;</p>
<p>Grant Samuel also said Billiton would not be paying a premium for control.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition, a major part of QNI's assets will be located in Colombia involving both currency and country risks.&quot;</p>
<p>QNI itself was more confident the revised deal had convinced shareholders to support the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, we've had so far today an indication from a major institutional shareholder and it's favourable,&quot; QNI's chief financial officer Christopher Foll told a news briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;We've received quite a lot of support from Australian institutions,&quot; Foll said.</p>
<p>Investors trading QNI shares remained less than enthused however, pushing QNI's shares down 10 cents to A$2.40 at the close.</p>
<p>This values the 455.802 million shares to be issued to Billiton at A$1.09 billion, in the lower half of Grant Samuel's valuation range of A$1.00 billion to A$1.21 billion for Billiton Nickel's assets.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
