<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777637" id="root" date="1997-08-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Striking Teamsters idle UPS facilities across the U.S..</title>
<headline>Striking Teamsters idle UPS facilities across the U.S..</headline>
<byline>David Morgan</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Striking Teamsters shut down United Parcel Service Service facilities across the country on Monday, crippling the giant parcel delivery company in a labour dispute over pay, benefits and job security.</p>
<p>At a minute past midnight EDT (0400 GMT), thousands of drivers, package-sorters and loaders hoisted strike signs into the summer night and began an orderly march past idled shipping operations that ordinarily contol four-fifths of the package delivery business in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;We're striking for every worker in America. We can't have only low service-industry wages in this country,&quot; said Randy Walls, a 47-year-old UPS tractor-trailer driver on nighttime picket duty in Atlanta.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope for all people's benefit -- the company's as well as ours -- that it's a short walkout. But we're going to stay out as long as it takes,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>UPS, a $22.4 billion company based in Atlanta, delivers 12 million packages a day to corporate offices, small businesses, hospitals and ordinary households from Maine to California. It also generates more than $1 billion in profits each year for its private owners, union officials claim.</p>
<p>The Teamsters represent nearly two-thirds of the company's 301,000 U.S. workers, mainly those who sort and load the packages, haul the shipments and drive the company's huge fleet of brown delivery vans.</p>
<p>At a time of night when UPS loading docks should have been rumbling with tractor-trailers on their way to shipment centres for the next day's deliveries, state-of-the-art hub facilities stood silent as police kept watch at the gates.</p>
<p>Teamster officials, standing in shorts and union T-shirts opposite dark rows of empty delivery vans, said overnight picket lines would swell to full strength by daybreak as the bulk of their 185,000 UPS members came to protest as managers arrive for work.</p>
<p>The union was expected to stage demonstrations outside 1,700 UPS hub and shipping facilities and at airports where the company maintains air-delivery operations.</p>
<p>The strike began after a last-ditch effort to set a new five-year contract collapsed in Washington with the two sides far apart over union demands for stronger pension, health and safety benefits, higher pay and restrictions on non-unionized subcontractors.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm here because of subcontracting,&quot; said striking truck driver Paul Dorton. &quot;My biggest fear is that if they continue to subcontract for my job classification, I won't have this job in five years.&quot;</p>
<p>Teamster officials also were concerned about the company's use of part-time employees, who make up 60 percent of the workforce and often pull double four-hour shifts for an average $10.50 an hour in part-time pay and low benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;If they work their regular part-time shift every day in the year, they could stand to get 1-1/2 days of vacation,&quot; Teamsters spokesman Doug Mims said.</p>
<p>Strikers said they can earn a top wage of $20.52 an hour for full-time work at UPS. But while on the picket line, they look forward only to $55 a week in strike pay.</p>
<p>Teamster officials said the union was prepared to go to the AFL-CIO for additional funds if the walkout dragged on. Outside labour groups such as the United Food and Commercial Workers union also have pledged to make donations of food and other staples for Teamster families.</p>
<p>At the outset of the work stoppage on Monday, strikers showed no lack of resolve, fortified in part by news that 2,000 unionized UPS pilots would remain off the job in sympathy with their walkout.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm out for as long as it takes. I don't care what I have to do. I'll even get another job somewhere to make ends meet,&quot; part-time worker Alutriva Baker said. &quot;Upper management is just too greedy. As long as they make a profit, they don't care about the individual worker.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
