<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777649" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo Nikkei seen hovering around 19,500.</title>
<headline>Tokyo Nikkei seen hovering around 19,500.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Tokyo stock market's key index is likely to hover around the key 19,500 level on Wednesday, as the yen's fall against the dollar could encourage bargain hunting in high-technology issues that have been declining recently, brokers said.</p>
<p>But underlying worries about Japan's slow economic recovery would prevent the index rising sharply, they said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the 225-share Nikkei average shed 153.62 points, or 0.78 percent, to end at 19,514.45. It briefly dipped below 19,500 and hit 19,362.44. September futures were weaker, losing 350 points to finish at 19,440.  </p>
<p>&quot;The dollar's advance above 119.00 yen is likely to prompt buying-on-dips in high-techs,&quot; said Yasuo Ueki, general manager at Nikko Securities. &quot;But the Nikkei 225 is unlikely to start rebounding sharply given the summer lull. I expect the Nikkei to hover around 19,500 today.&quot;</p>
<p>Brokers said any rises would also be limited due to penalties against Nomura Securities, that take effect on Wednesday. The penalties include a halt in trading on its own account.</p>
<p>The dollar stood at around 119.30 yen in early Asia on Wednesday, against around 118.45 yen in late Tokyo on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>The broader-based TOPIX index was up 4.95 points or 0.33 percent at 1,492.08. The Nikkei 300 average edged up 1.58 points or 0.54 percent to end the morning session at 291.64.</p>
<p>The stock market largely shrugged off Japan's customs-cleared trade data for the first 20 days of July, released before the market opened, as the data did nothing to dent the dollar's strength, brokers said.</p>
<p>The surplus rose 126.4 percent from a year earlier to 480.57 billion yen during the 20-day period.</p>
<p>At the Tokyo midday, the dollar was quoted at about 119.40 yen, up from 118.45 yen in late Tokyo trade on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Export-oriented issues were supported by the yen's weak trend, while semiconductor-related shares were lifted by a newspaper report that Japanese manufacturers of chip-making equipment will boost output, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Institutional investors were seeking blue chips, such as Sony Corp, Advantest Corp and Nikon Corp &quot; Hatae said.</p>
<p>Shares of Nikon, a major camera maker that also produces semiconductor-related equipment, rallied in active trade, ending the morning session at an all-time high of 2,240 yen, up 120 yen from Tuesday.  </p>
<p>The newspaper report said chip equipment makers Nikon, Advantest, Canon Inc, and Tokyo Electron Ltd would boost output. All of their shares rose in the morning.</p>
<p>Carmakers also gained ground, backed by the yen's weakness, with Toyota Motor Corp up 40 yen at 3,200 yen and Honda Motor Co Ltd up 100 yen at 3,720 yen.</p>
<p>&quot;But the Nikkei 225 is unlikely to start rebounding sharply given the summer lull. I expect the Nikkei to hover around 19,500,&quot; said Yasuo Ueki, general manager at Nikko Securities.</p>
<p>The most actively traded issue on the first section was Nomura Securities Co Ltd at 3.116 million shares.  </p>
<p>Nomura's share price was up 40 yen at 1,670 yen, despite penalties against Nomura that took effect on Wednesday. The penalties, imposed as punishment for illegal payoffs to a racketeer, include a halt in trading on its own account.</p>
<p>&quot;The penalties would have a negative influence on the stock market's overall volume, but the share price rose, supported by Nomura's evaluation for the long term,&quot; Hatae said.</p>
<p>By sector, losers were led by transport equipment, textiles, fisheries, and iron/steel. The major gainers were precision instruments, pharmaceuticals, banks, and insurers.</p>
<p>-- Hiroko Nakata, Tokyo Equities Desk +81-3-3432-8027</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
