<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777759" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: O'Sullivan sees Q4 EPS exceeding $0.23.</title>
<headline>O'Sullivan sees Q4 EPS exceeding $0.23.</headline>
<dateline>LAMAR. MO. 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>O'Sullivan Industries Holdings Inc on Tuesday said it expected to post earnings for its fiscal fourth quarter ended June 30 of more than $0.23 a share.</p>
<p>Earnings would have been higher if not for the Chapter 11 bankruptcy filing by retailer Montgomery Ward Holding Corp, which resulted an after-tax charge for bad debt of about $0.04 a share, the company said.</p>
<p>O'Sullivan, which makes ready to assemble furniture, earned $0.09 a share in the previous fourth quarter.  </p>
<p>First-quarter 1998 sales are expected to be flat to slightly less than the $83.1 million posted in the year-earlier quarter, the company said, citing volatility and timing of orders from a major mass merchant and the Montgomery Ward bankruptcy. It said it lost $5.5 million in sales in the year-ago quarter from a now-liquidated catalog retailer.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at all of fiscal 1998, we expect another year of strong earnings growth with continued sales increases and further margin improvements,&quot; Daniel O'Sullivan, chairman and chief executive, said in a news release.</p>
<p>The company also said it reduced raw material costs and boosted capacity utilization in its three factories during the fiscal 1997 fourth quarter. It said it was successful in controlling factory overhead and related expenses.</p>
<p>O'Sullivan shares were down 1-1/16 at 12-3/16 late Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>((--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I46700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAMAR. MO."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
