<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77775" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rubin upbeat on U.S., less so on Europe, Japan.</title>
<headline>Rubin upbeat on U.S., less so on Europe, Japan.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin on Thursday called the world economic outlook encouraging although he said that growth in Europe and Japan still looks &quot;quite moderate.&quot;</p>
<p>In a wide-ranging briefing ahead of international meetings starting later this week, Rubin also reiterated his support for a strong dollar and his belief that the IMF will ultimately need to sell some gold to aid the world's poor.</p>
<p>Rubin was upbeat on the outlook for the U.S. economy, calling it &quot;very healthy&quot; and saying he sees no sign of inflation reigniting. Growth looks set to remain solid.  </p>
<p>Rubin said that many U.S. industries are competitive globally now and he reiterated his opposition to using the dollar as a tool to better America's trade position.</p>
<p>Currencies follow fundamentals, and U.S. fundamentals look &quot;very good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prospects have improved in Japan and Europe, but growth in those regions still looks quite moderate,&quot; Rubin added.</p>
<p>He said that it was &quot;critically important&quot; that Japan continue to pursue policies aimed at promoting domestic demand-led growth.  </p>
<p>&quot;As you get into a period now where there will be somewhat of a change in (Japanese) fiscal conditions if nothing is done, obviously one needs to be watchful,&quot; Rubin said.</p>
<p>With an election looming in Japan, Tokyo looks set to pass up a chance to issue a supplementary fall budget that some analysts argue is needed to keep its recovery on track.</p>
<p>&quot;We are of course always interested in growth in Europe, too,&quot; Rubin said. &quot;We look forward to a discussion by our European colleagues about their progress toward EMU (European Monetary Union) and the implications of these developments for the world economy.&quot;  </p>
<p>Rubin stressed the importance of European economic growth for the world and the U.S. economy and said he would be interested in hearing his European counterparts' views about the best policy mix to attain healthy growth.</p>
<p>On Saturday, Rubin will meet finance ministers and central bankers from the rest of the Group of Seven -- Britain, Canada, France, Germany, Italy and Japan. That gathering will take place on the fringes of the semi-annual meeting of the International Monetary Fund and World Bank.  </p>
<p>Rubin said that he believed that the IMF would need to sell some of its gold to finance continuation of its Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility (ESAF) and its participation in a multilateral debt relief plan.</p>
<p>ESAF, which lends money to the world's poorest nations at virtually no interest charge, has enough resources to last until the year 1999 or 2000, he noted. &quot;Once you get past that, you're going to need gold sales,&quot; Rubin said.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of how much they will be, I just don't know,&quot; he said. &quot;The IMF at that time will sit down with its members to determine how many countries are involved in this, how much is needed, then you make a judgment on how much gold needs to be sold.&quot;</p>
<p>Once the IMF decides to sell gold, the United States would be prepared to consult with Congress about the possibility of a U.S. bilateral contribution to the Fund's efforts to aid the world's poor, he said.</p>
<p>Rubin said the U.S. also backs expanding the scope of debt relief provided by Paris Club creditors to poor countries to up to 80 percent from the current 67 percent limit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
