<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="777917" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SF Fed's Parry says wages may rise at faster pace.</title>
<headline>SF Fed's Parry says wages may rise at faster pace.</headline>
<dateline>SALT LAKE CITY 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>President of the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco Robert Parry said Tuesday wages would probably rise at a somewhat faster pace in the coming months.</p>
<p>Speaking to reporters after an address to to the Rotary Club here, Parry said, &quot;I would think you'll probably see wages rising at a somewhat faster rate. There will be a time when there will be greater pressure on costs for companies and reduction of profit margins.&quot;</p>
<p>Parry added that he hopes the nation's economy can avoid &quot;the extreme swings associated with booms and busts.&quot;  </p>
<p>Turning to inflation, the San Francisco Fed chief said it was &quot;very dangerous&quot; for central bankers not to be on the lookout for inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>However, he hastened to add: &quot;But quite frankly, I don't see any clouds on the horizon in regards to the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>As for recent indications of increased productivity, Parry said, &quot;I have my doubts about the exact extent and how long (such increases) are going to continue.&quot;</p>
<p>Still, the regional Fed chief said he does not believe data on productivity have changed over the long haul.</p>
<p>Parry also commented briefly on the unemployment rate in the U.S. Joblessness currently is hovering at its lowest level in more than two decades.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some rate of unemployment that if you stay below it for some time, it will cause some inflationary pressure.&quot; However, the regional Fed bank president did not qualify what that rate might be.</p>
<p>As for his regional California economy, Parry said the Golden State currently was the ninth fastest growing economy in U.S., which is &quot;impressive&quot; for an economy of that size, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;In general terms, California's numbers look very good,&quot; Parry said.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SALT LAKE CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
