<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="778238" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIAN TREASURY FACES 64 BLN BFR END-AUGUST BILL.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN TREASURY FACES 64 BLN BFR END-AUGUST BILL.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Belgian Treasury will have to pay out around 64 billion Belgian francs in principal and coupons on OLO 8 at the end of August after the last exchange auction in the bond flopped on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The exchange which in OLO 8 totalled just 1.68 billion francs, reduced the amount outstanding in the 9.25 percent bond, which matures August 29, to 59 billion francs.</p>
<p>Although the Treasury is due to hold one more exchange auction between now and the end of the month, OLO 8 is not on offer. Instead, the Treasury plans to offer for the first time OLO 11, the 9.00 percent July 1998.  </p>
<p>OLO traders said, however, they were not surprised by the Treasury's failure to shift much of the outstanding OLO 8 paper, noting Tuesday's exchange came against the background of a market dogged by German interest rate fears.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very surprised they managed to exchange anything at all in a market which was going down,&quot; one trader said. &quot;It's strange they found any bidders.&quot;</p>
<p>After initially starting higher after Monday's losses, European bond markets turned south as the dollar surged on news the Bundesbank had left its repo rate unchanged for now. The fear in bond markets is the Buba might now act next week.  </p>
<p>European markets got no support from the U.S. where Treasuries started out lower on funding fears despite supportive leading indicator and house building data [US-ECI].</p>
<p>The benchmark 10-year OLO yield had risen to 5.80 percent in late trade from 5.74 late on Monday and 5.72 percent at the start of the session.</p>
<p>Money market rates were mixed despite the German rate fears.</p>
<p>The Treasury added liquidity to the market, selling about 132 billion francs of bills at the weekly auction compared with 224 billion francs of maturing paper -- a net injection of some 72 billion francs.  </p>
<p>The move helped very short term depo rates to ease slightly.</p>
<p>But yields at the auction crept up, with the three month average rate rising to 3.72 percent from 3.68 percent last week, while September Bibor futures fell five basis points to 96.30, implying a three month interest rate of 3.70 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers said the early focus of Wednesday's dealings would be German unemployment numbers, due around 0755 GMT.</p>
<p>-- Nick Antonovics, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
