<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="778250" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: POLL-Rate rises, strong stg threaten London's boom.</title>
<headline>POLL-Rate rises, strong stg threaten London's boom.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rising interest rates and the persistent strength of sterling are putting London's economic boom in jeopardy, the London Chamber of Commerce and Industry (LCCI) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>An LCCI survey showed that 55 percent of service sector companies reported that high interest rates were the biggest threat to economic prosperity, whilst amongst manufacturers, interest rate rises are second only to high exchange rates on the list of worries.</p>
<p>The Bank of England's Monetary policy Committee begins its August meeting on Wednesday, with the result due to be announced at 1100 GMT on Thursday. Analysts expect the UK's 6.75 percent official rates to rise to 7.0 percent, the fourth successive monthly increase.</p>
<p>The survey, for the second quarter of the year, showed the British capital's service sector roaring ahead, with a balance of 53 percent of firms reporting domestic growth and 37 percent reporting growth in exports.</p>
<p>But the picture is gloomier for manufacturers grappling with the problems of sterling's strength. A balance of only 12 percent of firms reported an increase in domestic business and only 10 percent of companies reported growth in exports -- the lowest balance since autumn, 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;Those at the Bank of England this week should take note of the increasing concern among companies about rising interest rates,&quot; said Simon Sperryn, chief executive of the LCCI.</p>
<p>&quot;These results reflect the sharp contrast of fortunes for London companies. The service sector is booming, whilst manufacturing is struggling.</p>
<p>The survey showed that confidence, as measured by profits and turnover, was exceptionally high, with 50 percent of service sector companies and 44 percent of manufacturers expecting profits to rise in the next year.</p>
<p>Also, 78 percent of service sector companies and 60 percent of manufacturers expect increased turnover in the next year.</p>
<p>Recruitment was strong, with both sectors reporting increases in employment. A balance of 84 percent of service companies and 73 percent of manufacturing firms were trying to recruit in the second quarter.</p>
<p>Investment intentions were also healthy, with a balance of 39 percent of service companies and 31 percent of manufacturers reported increased investment over the last quarter, while 31 percent of service companies and 34 percent of manufacturers expect investment to rise in the next year.</p>
<p>The LCCI surveyed 243 firms.</p>
<p>-- Cheryl Juckes, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
