<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="778360" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: OPINION - Zimbabwe's &quot;good&quot; budget.</title>
<headline>OPINION - Zimbabwe's &quot;good&quot; budget.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Tony Hawkins, Professor of Business Studies at The University of Zimbabwe</p>
<p>Zimbabwe Finance Minister Herbert Murerwa must be more than a little puzzled that his &quot;no-content&quot; budget should be getting such good reviews from the World Bank and IMF.</p>
<p>Even before having had time to read the budget, the World Bank's Harare representative pronounced himself happy with the budget and was reported as announcing the resumption of &quot;balance of payments&quot; lending to Zimbabwe, while the IMF's representative described the budget as &quot;good&quot;.</p>
<p>Just what was &quot;good&quot; about it is unclear. Overwhelmingly, the local response has been highly critical with economic consultant John Robertson pointing out that to finance the forecast deficit of 8.9 percent of gross domestic product, the government will have to borrow Z$1 billion a month from the domestic market.</p>
<p>This, says Jonee Blanchfield, President of the Confederation of Zimbabwe Industries will &quot;deny the private sector vital money needed for expansion and growth&quot;.</p>
<p>Bank economist Edmore Tobaiwa says... &quot;the more I read into the 1997/98 national budget...the more I become convinced that the government is not at all serious about the restoration of macroeconomic stability...&quot;</p>
<p>With other business organisations and economists similarly critical of the budget, the World Bank and the IMF's welcome means either that they have access to inside information that has been withheld from the Zimbabwe parliament and the electorate, or that they are blessed with deeper insights into the published figures than the local economists.</p>
<p>A more cynical interpretation of their reaction is that they are dancing a different agenda from that of local business. The fact that the World Bank announced a resumption of lending before it had even had time to read the published version of the budget -- who knows what the bank officials saw before then -- suggests that, contrary to its oft-expressed public concern about the budget deficit and macroeconomic stability, the Bank was prepared to support Zimbabwe regardless of the deficit's magnitude. &quot;Don't confuse us with the facts&quot; the Bank seems to be saying.</p>
<p>As for the IMF, last year's budget with a forecast deficit of 8.5 percent was unacceptable, but this year's with a forecast deficit of 8.9 percent is &quot;good&quot;. Perhaps the goalposts have been shifted.</p>
<p>What makes the IMF response all the more puzzling is that ahead of the budget it was reported to have urged Murerwa to impose tough new taxes especially fuel and excise duties on alcohol and tobacco products, and cut public spending. He did neither.</p>
<p>Instead he produced a &quot;free lunch&quot; budget, with no material tax increases for six months (January 1998) -- a budget in fact, driven by inflation. Public spending as a ratio of GDP is virtually unchanged while revenue's share in GDP is down slightly from last year.</p>
<p>On Murerwa's figures, real GDP is forecast to grow some seven percent over the eighteen months budgetary period yet revenue will increase an annualised 28 percent underscoring the role that inflation will play in helping the minister reach his budget targets.</p>
<p>The 15 percent tax on pension fund profits, from next January, is another instance of reliance on inflation, since the profits being taxed more often than not represent real losses to the long suffering pension fund investors.</p>
<p>The announced tax concessions -- from January 1999 -- will be offset should inflation exceed 22 percent in the next 18 months in the case of the new threshold at which income tax becomes payable and 25 percent for the band at which the top marginal rate of 42 percent (including the five percent development levy) applies.</p>
<p>With economists predicting inflation of between 25 percent and 30 percent over the 18 months, the minister's concessions are meaningless -- taxpayers will be worse off than they are today.</p>
<p>Despite all this, the IMF's Harare representative says it is a &quot;good&quot; budget. His comments are significant on at least three counts.</p>
<p>First, with some 85 percent of all resource flows to all developing countries coming from private sector sources, what IMF officials say and think is becoming increasingly irrelevant. As senior U.S. Treasury official Larry Summers points out, in the 1990s the views of fund managers and private sector investors count far more than those of international bureaucrats.</p>
<p>Secondly, such misjudgments help explain why private investment in sub-Saharan Africa is not responding to economic reform to the same degree that it has done elsewhere.</p>
<p>When, in deference to political correctness, IMF officials make claims that are so obviously out of touch with reality, they devalue their own currency. The result is that when the Fund really does have a good story to tell, investors, foreign and domestic alike, discount its views.</p>
<p>Third -- and most serious of all -- why bother with &quot;conditionalities&quot; -- such as budget deficit targets -- only to disregard them in favour of other unspecified non-economic &quot;priorities&quot;.</p>
<p>Above all, in the interest of the transparency that the IMF claims to espouse, it is surely appropriate for its spokesman to explain to Zimbabweans why and in what ways a budget so roundly condemned by the business community and private sector is, really a triumph for fiscal rectitude.</p>
<p>				  / / / / / / /</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article represent those of the author only. They should not be seen to represent the views of Reuters.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
