<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="778737" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia creates fund for aged care bonds.</title>
<headline>Australia creates fund for aged care bonds.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian government on Wednesday announced a new fund to invest and administer accommodation bonds paid by the elderly to hostels and other aged care providers.</p>
<p>Family Services Minister Judi Moylan said a single, national independent trust would be created to handle the bonds, which are paid by the elderly for entry into aged care facilities.</p>
<p>Annual income earned by the fund would reach about A$130 million within three to four years and A$1.5 billion within a decade, Moylan said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Income from the fund would be returned to nursing homes and hostels to help maintain and upgrade facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;The fund will be professionally managed under the supervision of a board which will include members from banking, legal and provider backgrounds,&quot; Moylan said.</p>
<p>Hostels and nursing homes would have to join the fund, or an alternative approved prudential scheme, in order to be allowed to charge bonds from October 1.</p>
<p>The new fund would guarantee the security of residents' bonds, Moylan said.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
