<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="778799" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai finance minister vows fiscal discipline.</title>
<headline>Thai finance minister vows fiscal discipline.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai finance minister Thanong Bidaya said on Tuesday the government would follow strict fiscal discipline and work to balance the budget as part of its efforts to improve the ailing economy.</p>
<p>Thanong said in a nationally televised address to explain the tough measures announced earlier by the government that the administration also planned to streamline the tax system and speed up the privatisation of state enterprises to take some of the heavy burden off the government.  </p>
<p>&quot;These economic revival measures may depress the economy in the short term, but it would be essential economic contraction in order to strengthen our economic foundation before we embark on further durable growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is one step backward in preparation for a future of steady advances,&quot; Thanong said.</p>
<p>Earlier Thanong and central bank governor Chaiyawat Wibulswasdi announced a series of tough measures, recommended by the International Monetary Fund (IMF), aimed at reviving the economy.</p>
<p>The measures included the suspension of operations of more than half the nation's 91 finance companies, a three percentage point hike in the value added tax (VAT), and strict monetary and fiscal targets for the next few years.</p>
<p>If the measures are properly implemented, the government hopes to get $12-$15 billion in loans from the IMF and foreign nations, Thanong said.</p>
<p>Thanong said Thai people had to be willing to accept tough measures in order to lift the economy out of its biggest slump in over a decade.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we must admit that the task of tackling economic problems is not easy, it is by no mean impossible,&quot; he said. &quot;On the contrary, I still fully believe in the fundamentals and capability of the Thai economy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Although our current problems have put the Thai economy into a recession, it does not mean that the economy has reached an untenable dead-end,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thanong touched on what he called sensitive issues of a VAT hike and budget cuts for fiscal 1997 and 1998 which would help sustain the country's long-standing balanced budget policy.</p>
<p>Thanong emphasised that the government carefully studied the plan and did not just take IMF recommendations without considering the consequences to the public.</p>
<p>&quot;Our consultation with the IMF has been based on mutual understanding,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They offered advice and recommendations, pointed out the pros and cons of each option and measure, of which the Thai side made the decision on the basis of long-term national interest...each issue was reviewed cautiously and carefully.&quot;</p>
<p>Thanong, who has been in office for about six weeks, made an impassioned promise at the end of his statement to work for the country without involving political ambition.</p>
<p>&quot;Now is the time for Thais to persevere and be disciplined, we Thais must be frugal, we Thais must be strong and steadfast in overcoming these hurdles,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most importantly, we Thais must be united for nobody but our Thai children in the future, in a country with a strong economy that can help its people stand up with pride in the world community.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
