<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77905" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: World wheat prices will come under pressure in 1997-IGC.</title>
<headline>World wheat prices will come under pressure in 1997-IGC.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>World wheat prices will come under pressure in 1997 from this year's bumper crops but low stock levels will continue and add to price volatilities, the International Grains Council (IGC) said on Thursday.</p>
<p>A monthly report by the IGC, an authoritative monitor of supply and demand in the grains trade, reported higher crop estimates for the European Union (EU), Argentina and Australia.</p>
<p>It raised its forecast for this year's total wheat harvest by 8.0 million tonnes from a previous estimate to 571 million.</p>
<p>But the bumper crops expected from Australia and Argentina, which rank among the world's top five wheat exporters, would weigh on prices early next year, the IGC said.</p>
<p>&quot;The southern hemisphere harvests as they become available will have a strong influence on prices,&quot; said Bill de Maria, IGC assistant executive director. &quot;There is the possibility of price pressure later in the season.&quot; Argentina's output was seen rising 5.8 million tonnes to 14.5 million tonnes but its wheat would mostly arrive after January.</p>
<p>&quot;They haven't got extensive storage facilities so the pressure for them will be to sell into the export market,&quot; de Maria told Reuters.</p>
<p>Australia, which is re-emerging as a big potential seller to China, was seen harvesting 19 million tonnes of wheat, two million more than in 1995, after increasing the area sown to wheat, the IGC said.</p>
<p>The present production trends reverse a price &quot;spike&quot; when drought in several key areas resulted in a drop in world grain stocks to the lowest since the 1970s.</p>
<p>But low stocks are likely to continue for some years yet and increase price volatility on world markets, the IGC said.</p>
<p>Although world stocks were forecast to rise by 10.0 million tonnes to 104 million by the end of this crop year, they would still be the lowest since 1980 except for last year.</p>
<p>&quot;What's happened is that farmers saw better prices so they went for production in a big way,&quot; de Maria said, adding that even a small shift in total supplies could affect price trends.</p>
<p>In its report, the London-based IGC said a &quot;significant rebuilding&quot; of global wheat stocks was expected.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though the growth in total availabilities of wheat in relation to global consumption is relatively small, it has already been sufficient to have had a pronounced influence on the course of international prices for wheat,&quot; the IGC said.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps the main lesson is that with lower levels of stocks, price volatility increases and current production prospects assume greater importance in assessments of world supply and demand for wheat.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
