<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779004" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Indiana police arrest alleged drug dealer-parolee.</title>
<headline>Indiana police arrest alleged drug dealer-parolee.</headline>
<dateline>HAMMOND, Ind 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police said Tuesday Ollie Smithey should have been in prison when officers raided the alleged drug-dealer's opulent home, equipped with hot tub, wall-size television and video surveillance system.</p>
<p>But Smithey, 61, was paroled from an Illinois prison in 1989 after serving four years of an 18-year sentence, and never returned to Louisiana to serve out a 297-year sentence there.</p>
<p>&quot;He was running free when he should have been in prison,&quot; Hammond narcotics detective John Doughty said. &quot;He was living the life of luxury in the guise of home improvement.&quot;</p>
<p>Police alleged that Smithey had been operating a $20,000-per-week marijuana-selling operation and laundering the proceeds through a phony contracting business.</p>
<p>In 1983, Smithey was convicted of several armed robberies in Louisiana and began serving three consecutive 99-year sentences, but he was shipped to Illinois a year later to face trial in Rockford for armed robbery and home invasion.</p>
<p>But after he served the Illinois sentence, Louisiana apparently withdrew its warrant to have him returned, Illinois authorities said.</p>
<p>&quot;My guess is we notified Louisiana and never heard back from them. Only God knows what happened,&quot; Illinois prison spokesman Nic Howell said of Smithey's premature freedom.</p>
<p>In Tuesday's raid on Smithey's home, which contained photographs of him cavorting with models, a room with a pool table and a huge fish tank, police said they found four ounces of marijuana, along with suspected cocaine and heroin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMMOND, Ind"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
