<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="77910" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Guinness sees tough European market.</title>
<headline>Guinness sees tough European market.</headline>
<byline>Tim Farrand</byline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>British brewing and spirits group Guinness Plc Thursday reported surprisingly strong half-year results, but Chairman Tony Greener said markets in Europe were tough and not expected to change this year.</p>
<p>Guinness pretax profits for the six months ending June 30 rose 5 percent from the year-ago period to 357 million pounds ($556 million), above expectations of 337-353 million pounds ($525 million to $550 million).</p>
<p>It paid out an interim dividend of 4.55 pence (7.1 cents) per share, up from the previos 4.20 pence (6.5 cents).</p>
<p>But Guinness shares fell 6 pence (9 cents) to 446 pence ($6.95) as doubts rose about the company's spirits sales. Scotch whisky sales were 4 percent behind last year at 10.2 million cases, mainly due to de-stocking in Latin American markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The company has committed itself to a substantial increase in spending on advertising and promotion in the second half but it is living in hope that sales will increase to offset that,&quot; said Charles Winston, analyst at BZW.</p>
<p>Greener said in an interview that overall, spirits prices were up 0.5 percent in the first half of the year to June 30 compared with the same period last year, but the full year effect would be a 2 percent increase on last year, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The future of the business lies in brands and building brands,&quot; said Greener. At United Distillers, the company's spirits arm, the group will spend 20 percent more this year on promoting its brands. It spent about 300 million pounds ($468 million) last year on spirits marketing.</p>
<p>In Britain, Guinness said it will launch a national television advertisement for both Bell's whisky and Gordon's gin for the Christmas buying season.</p>
<p>Greener said Guinness was taking a &quot;very tough line&quot; by cutting back on price promotions and investing more heavily in brands like Bell's.</p>
<p>Guinness stout's share of the draft beer market in Britain, reached a record 5 percent this year and continues to rise. The brewing arm posted a 5 percent rise in profits to 119 million pounds ($185.5 million).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
