<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779265" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton signs legislation to balance budget.</title>
<headline>Clinton signs legislation to balance budget.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amid patriotic music and high-flying rhetoric, President Bill Clinton on Tuesday signed legislation aimed at balancing the U.S. budget and giving Americans $95 billion in tax cuts.</p>
<p>In a ceremony on the South Lawn of the White House, Clinton penned his name to a budget bill that resulted from a rare display of unity between political opponents.  </p>
<p>&quot;We come here today, Democrats and Republicans, Congress and president, Americans of goodwill from all points of view and all walks of life, to celebrate a true milestone for our nation,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>In a show of bipartisanship Clinton, let the top Republican, House Speaker Newt Gingrich, have a lead speaking role. A crowd of 700, including members of Congress and Clinton Cabinet officers, was warmed up by a Marine Corps band that played &quot;God Bless America&quot; and other patriotic tunes.</p>
<p>&quot;This has been a long time coming,&quot; Gingrich said. &quot;It has been a difficult process. But in that process we have proven together that the American constitutional system works.&quot;</p>
<p>The legislation, approved last week by the Republican-controlled Congress, has the goal of balancing the budget by 2002 while giving Americans their biggest tax cut since 1981.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
