<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779394" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Nokia profit-takers dent Helsinki, seen adrift.</title>
<headline>Nokia profit-takers dent Helsinki, seen adrift.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares fell on Tuesday, the index decline almost entirely due to post-results profit-taking in Nokia, and investors otherwise queasy amid fears a German monetary tightening may quash the rally, brokers said.</p>
<p>The FOX portfolio index fell 0.59 percent or just over seven points to 1,234.22, the HEX all-share index shedding 0.78 percent to 3,604.70. Nokia had over half total trade.</p>
<p>Several analysts upgraded earnings forecasts for Nokia after its H1 report late on Monday just pipped expectations, but the absence of a knockout surprise had been expected to unlock some profit-taking, and it ended down 10.10 markka at 471.90.</p>
<p>One broker said Nokia looked to be stabilising around 470.00 markka, seeing the stock supported around 450 markka near term in the absence of any major event.</p>
<p>Nokia's A and K series shares amounted to over six points of the FOX's overall decline, with an uptick in banking group Merita the only remotely significant counterbalance.</p>
<p>Merita put on 0.50 markka to 23.20, recovering some ground after it ran into selling following sharp gains.</p>
<p>Otherwise forestries took a brief lift from slightly above-forecast H1 earnings from Stora, but a dip in UPM -- again heavily traded in late deals -- dragged the sector by the close.</p>
<p>UPM, which has been active but little changed since last week, fell 0.60 markka to 132.60. The only explanation brokers have so far been able to give for the action is &quot;overseas interest&quot; in the share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
