<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779340" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: BSL German Aircargo forwarders to buy barcode equi.</title>
<headline>BSL German Aircargo forwarders to buy barcode equi.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Air cargo forwarders in Germany will have to spend up to 6,000 marks per office on barcode equipment over the coming months under a Lufthansa Cargo technology drive, the forwarders' association BSL said.</p>
<p>New printers would be needed to put barcodes on all packages as well as scanners to copy the barcodes into in-house data Systems, BSL executive director designate Herbert Ferger said.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo announced in June that it would refuse air cargo shipments without barcode stickers from April 1998 under a quality drive to set up a full global tracking and tracing system. Up to 1,000 machines could be needed in the 880 branches of the 215 IATA air cargo agents in Germany to meet the Lufthansa requirements, Ferger told air cargo journalists in a BSL briefing.</p>
<p>Forwarders would have to pay 3,000 to 6,000 marks for barcode printers and scanners depending on the level of technology, he added.</p>
<p>Lufthansa would operate a forwarder hotline from September 1 to March 30, 1998, to handle queries while the BSL would also inform members about the technology.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to see if we can help small forwarders with the hardware acquisition to meet the Lufthansa deadline,&quot; Ferger added. Wolf-Dietrich von Helldorff, BSL air cargo committee chairman, urged the forwarding industry to use the Lufthansa deadline to introduce a single, global barcode standard.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an absolute must to have a standard, international air cargo barcode (system). We have an established, mature technology and it is the right step,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo was right to force the pace now in Germany and worldwide, and other airlines and also shippers should now tackle the subject, he added.</p>
<p>He expected 70-80 percent of the air cargo market to be covered by barcode technology within three to four years.</p>
<p>The forwarder who wants to stop this may just as well sit on a tree and communicate with a drum,&quot; von Helldorff pointed out. - Reuters Air Cargo Service Tel+ 44 171 542 7706 Fax +5017 - www.racs.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
