<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779343" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Forwarders seek joint air cargo products with airl.</title>
<headline>Forwarders seek joint air cargo products with airl.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new era of co-operation between forwarders and airlines is needed to offer better air cargo services to shippers, the German forwarders' association BSL said.</p>
<p>Wolf-Dietrich von Helldoff, BSL air cargo committee chairman, said forwarders should drop their traditional distrust of airlines and work more closely with them to create joint products</p>
<p>The traditional roles of forwarder and airline were changing as communications technology made the market more transparent and broke down barriers between their activities, he told air cargo journalists in a BSL briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have a new division of roles but what is important is that we create and develop joint products.</p>
<p>If we want to present a joint product to the shipper, then we must create the product together. We cannot do that alone, nor can the airline do it alone,&quot; he stressed.</p>
<p>&quot;When we talk about the development of strategic new markets, then joint discussions on planning, budgets, volumes, freighter schedules and all these things should belong to it.</p>
<p>&quot;Today each airline decides for itself. I have never been asked by an airline where I see the strategic development for the future, where freighter will develop and where capacity will be needed. This is anachronistic,&quot; he noted.</p>
<p>In future, forwarders with sufficient volume would increasingly buy up air cargo space, guarantee space to clients and pay airlines dead freight fees for no-shows, von Helldorif forecast.</p>
<p>This capacity block-purchasing gave forwarders guaranteed departure times, cheaper rates and more flexibility but also meant a higher risk and extra costs through the payment of no-show fees. he added.</p>
<p>Von Helldorff said the airline cargo rates were already transparent to shippers and forwarders had to convince shippers to pay extra for added-value services such as transport guarantees.</p>
<p>&quot;The big shippers already get the same rates as the top forwarders. The rates question is not a taboo for me,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As a forwarder I must demonstrate my service so that the shipper is ready to pay for it. The market will become more transparent,&quot; he added. - Reuters Air Cargo Service Tel+ 44 171 542 7706 Fax +5017 - www.racs.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
