<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779308" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: War on graft hotting up at IMF, World Bank.</title>
<headline>War on graft hotting up at IMF, World Bank.</headline>
<byline>Janet Guttsman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The war on graft is hotting up at institutions lending billions of dollars to the developing world, according to documents issued this week by the International Monetary Fund.</p>
<p>The IMF, in policy guidelines approved by its board late last month, said it would not abandon its traditional view that macroeconomic stability held the key to growth. But other issues could also be used as conditions for IMF loans.</p>
<p>&quot;Financial assistance from the IMF...could be suspended or delayed on account of poor governance if there is reason to believe it could have significant macroeconomic implications that threaten the successful implementation of the programme,&quot; according to the guidelines issued late Monday.</p>
<p>Good governance, an issue highlighted both by the IMF and by the World Bank in recent years, refers to the need for honest officials who do not take bribes as well as to cost-effective management systems and fair and open laws.</p>
<p>The thinking behind the IMF guidelines got its first public airing last week when the fund halted a lending programme to Kenya and said Nairobi's response to a July 24 deadline had been inadequate.</p>
<p>The IMF, clearly alarmed at large-scale Kenyan corruption, had asked the government to &quot;take decisive steps&quot; to improve transparency and accountability in the public sector.</p>
<p>The IMF did not mention Kenya by name in Monday's guidelines or in a news release accompanying the document.</p>
<p>In a clear attempt to deflect charges that it could be viewed as interfering in a country's internal affairs, it said its salvo against corruption was only targeted against graft directly influencing economic performance.</p>
<p>The fund said efforts to encourage countries to reduce inflation or introduce reforms needed for sustained economic growth would remain &quot;the first order of business&quot;.</p>
<p>The World Bank, sister organisation to the IMF, has also been examining the need to clamp down on corruption, highlighting the problems in its annual Development Report, which was released in June.</p>
<p>&quot;Where there is clear evidence that large amounts of public money is being syphoned off, I think the World Bank should be taking it up as a major issue because it is basically a core development issue,&quot; said Ajay Chhibber, team leader for the report.</p>
<p>The IMF said some of the technical advice given to member states had already stressed &quot;good governance&quot;, including promoting public sector accountability and transparency.</p>
<p>But the latest document encourages staff to draw problems to the attention of the authorities and point out the economic consequences of not addressing the issues.</p>
<p>&quot;The staff should address governance issues, including instances of corruption, on the basis of economic considerations within its mandate,&quot; the guidelines said.</p>
<p>But political impartiality would remain crucial. &quot;The IMF's judgments should not be influenced by the nature of a political regime in a country, nor should it interfere in domestic or foreign policies of any member,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>A U.S. Treasury official said the idea of good governance was an appropriate one for the IMF to look at.</p>
<p>&quot;Our view is that it is appropriate for the IMF to consider governance questions in its programmes because governance crucially affects economic management and confidence in economic institutions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If a country is seeking external finance from public sources for its macroeconomic stabilisation programme or to pursue its development objectives, it is fair and reasonable that the organisations that are helping put together these programmes...should have confidence the programmes will work.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
