<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779329" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FOCUS - KLM says strong Q1 performance to continue.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - KLM says strong Q1 performance to continue.</headline>
<byline>Lien van der Leij</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>KLM Royal Dutch Airlines on Tuesday surprised investors with sharply higher-than-expected first quarter operating profits and said its underlying performance would remain strong over the full year.</p>
<p>The Dutch flag carrier said operating income in its first 1997/98 quarter had more than tripled to 244 million guilders ($116.2 million) from a year-earlier 80 million as burgeoning traffic revenues outstripped cost increases.</p>
<p>&quot;The quality of earnings -- what we at KLM do ourselves -- has increased considerably,&quot; outgoing KLM President Pieter Bouw told shareholders at Tuesday's annual general meeting.</p>
<p>Net profits fell to 190 million guilders from 271 million in the year-earlier period, when book profits from the sale and revaluation of KLM's preference shares in U.S. partner Northwest Airlines had inflated its bottom line by 245 million.</p>
<p>Substantial book profits from KLM's 20 percent stake in Northwest have been the main factor propping up net earnings at the Dutch flag carrier in recent years as runaway costs ate into operating results.</p>
<p>But in the latest quarter, Northwest's contribution to profits dwindled to just 56 million guilders, a fraction of the year-earlier figure.</p>
<p>KLM had booked &quot;excellent results&quot; in the first quarter thanks to favourable economic circumstances, a strong dollar and measures to improve efficiency taken last year, Bouw said.</p>
<p>In Amsterdam, KLM shares jumped to a new year-high of 79.00 guilders on the news, but later closed the session off 0.40 guilders at 76.00.</p>
<p>KLM said it expected operating profits for the full 1997/98 financial year, ending March 30, to remain strong.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as operating income for the full fiscal year is concerned, we expect to approximate the level attained in the better years in KLM's recent history,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The airline said traffic revenues had soared due to capacity management focused on improving load factors, the proportion of seat and cargo capacity filled, and yields.</p>
<p>Its aircraft were 4.4 percent fuller on average than a year ago, resulting in an 11 percent rise in yields, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Together with continuous cost control, this (rise in traffic revenue) has contributed to an increase in operating income of 164 million guilders,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Currency exchange rates also helped, lifting operating income by 17 million guilders.</p>
<p>KLM said that unit costs rose 11 percent to 74.9 cents in the quarter, driven mainly by a higher wage bill, increased fuel costs and materials.</p>
<p>However passenger revenues jumped 24 percent in the same period while cargo revenues rose 16 percent.</p>
<p>Bouw told shareholders the airline had meanwhile taken steps to control its fuel bill, hedging 60 percent of its fuel needs for the current fiscal year at or around current prices.</p>
<p>It had also created a new Irish-based subsidiary, KLM Financial Services, in order to limit the effect of exchange rate fluctuations on results, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Through this subsidiary... aircraft expenses can be included in the balance sheet as U.S. dollar-denominated liabilities, thus reducing KLM's exchange rate risks,&quot; Bouw said.</p>
<p>Analysts hailed the figures, which came in well ahead of forecast net profit of 94-136 million guilders.</p>
<p>&quot;It beats my already positive expectations...although you have to bear in mind that the first quarter last year was very disappointing,&quot; said Richard Brakenhoff of MeesPierson.</p>
<p>&quot;Almost everything seems to have worked in their favour -- the impact of currencies, fuel prices and greater transportation of passengers,&quot; agreed Frank Hermelink of Gilissen Bankiers.</p>
<p>&quot;We currently have the stock on a hold, but we may have to reconsider that,&quot; he added. ($ = 2.099 Dutch Guilders)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
