<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779328" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German states balk at fees for Internet PCs.</title>
<headline>German states balk at fees for Internet PCs.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>MAINZ 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany on Tuesday managed to avoid becoming the first advanced country to tax people who have PCs connected to the Internet.</p>
<p>After threatening to hit Internet PCs with the same fee now charged for owning a television, representatives of German state governments bowed to pressure from politicians in Bonn and said they would not impose the tax.</p>
<p>&quot;No levying of fees purely for PCs with Internet connections shall be proposed,&quot; a working group of state representatives and Germany's two public broadcasting networks said in a terse statement after a meeting here.</p>
<p>Over the past two weeks, the ARD and ZDF public broadcasters had talked about extending the TV fee to Internet PCs used by businesses.</p>
<p>The idea was based on a regulatory gap between state laws imposing fees on TVs and radios, and a federal multimedia law that took effect August 1.</p>
<p>For years Germany's 16 states have charged owners of TV sets 28.25 marks ($15.15) a month to support ARD and ZDF. When the multimedia law set up ground rules for video services that could be provided over the Internet, ARD and ZDF began looking at ways of extending the TV fee to PCs with online links.</p>
<p>One proposal presented on Tuesday would have charged businesses &quot;three fee units&quot; -- about 1,000 marks year -- for every 100 PCs connected to the worldwide network.</p>
<p>Home Internet users would have been exempt, if they already paid the fees for TV sets. The proposal left unclear if schools, universities, hospitals, and government offices would have to pay for their Intenet PCs.</p>
<p>Ahead of Tuesday's meeting, Juergen Ruettgers, minister of education, science, research and technology, appealed to the states to refrain from imposing the fees, saying they would dissuade companies from investing in Germany and dampen development of Internet-related jobs and businesses.</p>
<p>Industry groups had also sharply criticised the idea. &quot;It would be a scandal,&quot; Hans-Juergen Mammitzsch, general manager of the German unit of Dell Computer Corp., told Reuters. &quot;It would be the dumbest thing ever.&quot;</p>
<p>The Internet fee certainly would have been an embarrassment for Germany, which hosted a conference last month where 40 nations agreed to keep cyberspace free of taxes.</p>
<p>neal.boudette@reuters.com (Bonn, +49-228 26097150)</p>
<p>($ = 1.863 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAINZ"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
