<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779433" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: PRESS DIGEST - Sri Lanka Newspapers - Aug 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sri Lanka Newspapers - Aug 5.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Sri Lankan political and business stories prepared for Reuters by NewsWatch, Colombo Tel/Fax: 94-1-735182 Internet: lucien@eureka.lk.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>------</p>
<p>DAILY NEWS</p>
<p>JAPAN'S NTT BUYS 35 PCT OF SRI LANKA TELECOM FOR $225 MLN</p>
<p>The government has sold a 35 percent stake and management in Sri Lanka Telecom to Japan's Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp (NTT) for $225 million. In what is the single-largest foreign investment in Sri Lanka, NTT's strategic partnership will result in a huge expansion of telephone lines in next few years.</p>
<p>------</p>
<p>THE ISLAND</p>
<p>GOVERNMENT PLANS STRICTER RULES TO EASE TRAFFIC IN COLOMBO</p>
<p>The government might bring in legislation to make it mandatory for all private vehicles entering the Colombo city to carry at least five passengers in a bid to ease traffic congestion, said Minister of Transport &amp; Highways A.H.M. Fowzie.</p>
<p>------</p>
<p>LANKADEEPA, THINAKARAN &amp; THINAKKURUL</p>
<p>FOURTEEN LTTE LEADERS AMONG THOSE KILLED AT OMANTHAI</p>
<p>Fourteen leaders were among the 126 Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE) fighters when the latest rebel attempt to breach the miltiary's forward positions was foiled last Friday. The Defence Ministry said 39 bodies of rebels killed in the confrontation were handed over to the International Committee of the Red Cross.</p>
<p>------</p>
<p>DINAMINA</p>
<p>LTTE TRYING TO SEND INJURED FIGHTERS FOR TREATMENT</p>
<p>The LTTE is said to be attempting to send their fighters wounded during the Omanthai battle abroad for treatment, a senior army official said. The rebels are facing a severe shortage of drugs and medical equipment required the wounded carried away from the battle site.</p>
<p>------</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
