<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779752" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: OPTIONS - Vol flurry hits Bunds after Ifo report.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - Vol flurry hits Bunds after Ifo report.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hedge fund selling in the futures pits fuelled a sharp rise in Bund options' volatility on Tuesday, after Germany's Ifo institute raised concerns interest rates will have to rise to defend the mark, traders said.</p>
<p>The Ifo report said European central banks were under pressure to raise rates because of recent currency movements, adding that the Bundesbank would &quot;take small steps to give a signal&quot; if the dollar rose above 1.90 marks.</p>
<p>&quot;Puts went crazy when the futures tanked out,&quot; said a trader at a British brokerage on the LIFFE floor. &quot;Then the hedge funds started bailing out and the downside (options) strategies seemed really attractive all of a sudden.&quot;</p>
<p>September at-the-money volatility sped up to 5.9/6.2 percent by 1330 GMT, compared with around 5.5 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I can see it nudging up to 6.5 percent,&quot; said Andy Ash, derivatives analyst at Monument Derivatives in London. &quot;Lots of people are picking up downside vol in the near month around 101.50 and 100.50.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar hit an eight-year high of 1.8820 marks earlier, and analysts said it could be on course for 1.90 and 1.92. Interest rates in Germany, Europe's largest economy, have been on hold since 1996.</p>
<p>Activity across the board was strenuous, but volume on the put side was about double that seen in calls. More than 28,000 puts were traded in the September series between the strikes of 98.50 and 103.00, according to LIFFE data.</p>
<p>September futures were down 0.37 at 101.78, after earlier falling to a low at 101.58.</p>
<p>The 101.50 September strike was the most active, with more than 9,700 puts done there, and more than 8,000 puts went through at the 100.50 strike. Calls were also active, with more than 14,000 lots traded between 101.50 and 104.50.</p>
<p>Traders said the flurry of activity was confined mostly to September, with the back months seeing only moderate trade.</p>
<p>-- Lisa Wilson, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6137</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
