<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779724" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: DUTCH COSUN WINS CONTROL OF SLOVENIA SUGAR REFINER.</title>
<headline>DUTCH COSUN WINS CONTROL OF SLOVENIA SUGAR REFINER.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch sugar group Cosun said on Tuesday it had increased its stake in Slovenian sugar refiner Tovarna sladkorja Ormoz d.d. to a majority holding, gaining a foothold in what it sees as a potentially lucrative market.</p>
<p>Cosun, a Dutch sugar, fruit and foodstuffs co-operative formerly known as Suiker Unie, last year began building a stake in the Slovenian refiner, which was privatised two years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;There are few growth prospects left in the European Union and there are 100 million consumers in eastern Europe,&quot; Cosun spokeswoman Willy van Oorschot told Reuters. &quot;We want to use our experience in marketing and selling sugar.&quot;</p>
<p>She said Cosun purchased Tovarna shares from insitutional investors and on the over-the-counter section of the Ljubljana bourse. She estimated the stake at somewhere near 54 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We may look at increasing this figure but we do not want to control 100 percent,&quot; Van Oorschot added.</p>
<p>Tovarna has the capacity to process some 4,000 tonnes of sugar beet a day, and in 1996 produced 70,000 tonnes of white sugar, Cosun said in a statement.</p>
<p>The factory has a workforce of some 330 and an annual turnover of 75 million guilders.</p>
<p>--Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
