<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779767" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NatWest H1 FX profits up, dealing down.</title>
<headline>NatWest H1 FX profits up, dealing down.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dealing profits at NatWest Markets, the investment banking arm of National Westminster Bank Plc, slid in the first-half of 1997 to 265 million pounds from 307 million in the same 1996 period, figures released on Tuesday showed.</p>
<p>Foreign exchange dealing profits rose by 23 million pounds - or 28 percent - to 104 million due mainly to increased revenue from options trading and forward foreign exchange, NatWest said in a statement accompanying six-month results.</p>
<p>Equity and debt securities' dealing profits, however, declined by 18 million pounds to 116 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Equity dealing profits were down on the exceptional first-half performance last year,&quot; said NatWest in a statement, adding that dealing in debt securities broke even before accounting for associate net interest income.</p>
<p>Other dealing profits declined by 47 million pounds to 45 million, reflecting continued difficult trading in interest rate risk management products following the announcement of the options losses, said the bank.</p>
<p>Dealing profits in the NatWest group as a whole slipped to 229 million in the first-half of 1997 from 353 million in the previous 1996 period. Foreign exchange profits were down, however, to 125 million pounds from 142 million pounds.</p>
<p>National Westminster Bank Plc said on Tuesday first half pre-tax profits at NatWest Markets were 58 million pounds compared with 219 million in the same 1996 period.</p>
<p>But the banking group said its Global Financial Markets (GFM) arm, which was separated from NatWest Markets in a restructuring announced last week, had recorded pre-tax profits for the period of 169 million pounds.</p>
<p>NatWest Bank, NatWest Market's parent company and one of Britain's largest banks, reported first-half pre-tax profits of 775 million pounds and said the group has been hit by the underperformance of its NatWest investment banking unit.</p>
<p>-- Julia Meehan, London newsroom +4471 542 6701</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
