<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="779822" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - NatWest shows depth of Markets woes.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - NatWest shows depth of Markets woes.</headline>
<byline>Alexander Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's National Westminster Bank Plc on Tuesday revealed the parlous state of its investment banking arm NatWest Markets, which saw its first half pre-tax profits tumble by 111 million pounds ($181 million).</p>
<p>While this included the already flagged 77 million pound loss resulting from the bank's options mispricing scandal, the fall in the investment banking wing's profitability, to 58 million pounds from 219 million pounds, was greater than expected.</p>
<p>The bank's half-year results showed NatWest Markets had suffered additional losses. Its global debt markets and global equities businesses both saw their operating income fall by 15 million pounds.</p>
<p>It blamed a decline in its debt derivatives business on the options loss and &quot;subsequent depressed trading&quot;. Bond trading revenues were lower while financing income were held at previous levels.</p>
<p>In equities, income from brokerage and primary capital markets remained at similar levels to 1996 but equity derivatives trading profits fell year on year.</p>
<p>NatWest said it had already begun to feel the benefits of its acquisition last October of corporate finance boutique Hambro Magan.</p>
<p>Operating income from global corporate advisory rose by 14 million pounds to 61 million, including a strong performance from Gleacher NatWest. At the time of the acquisition, analysts said Hambro Magan could have cost NatWest around 80 million pounds.</p>
<p>NatWest said operating income in its Global Financial Markets (GFM) arm grew by 46 million pounds to 271 million pounds, with money market operations producing a slightly improved income and spot foreign exchange income being maintained.</p>
<p>Profits from currency option trading and forward foreign exchange increased significantly, it said.</p>
<p>NatWest Markets' performance was expected to suffer as a result of the interest rate options losses uncovered in February, but the underperformance in the rest of its operation was highlighted by strong showings from other investment banks over the period.</p>
<p>Most have experienced rising costs, as booming markets ratcheted up staff costs. Operating expenses at NatWest Markets were up 202 million pounds, or 51 percent, to 600 million pounds. Some 118 million pounds of this was due to acquisitions.</p>
<p>Despite the poor result, NatWest's chief executive Derek Wanless said the operation had been repositioned by a restructuring announced last week. He denied this was a way of preparing the business for sale.</p>
<p>Asked if he intended selling the operation, Wanless said: &quot;No way, it's not up for sale.&quot;</p>
<p>He also denied the reorganisation was simply a cosmetic exercise, stressing that 10 billion pounds of capital would be removed from this area of the business over the next two years.</p>
<p>This capital would, he said, either be used in the rest of NatWest's business or, if found to be surplus, returned to shareholders.</p>
<p>Weighted risk assets for the investment banking arm, including Global Financial Markets, totalled 42.4 billion pounds, up from 34.7 million pounds a year earlier and only marginally short of the 43.1 billion for NatWest UK, the retail banking operation.</p>
<p>But this is set to fall after the restructuring.</p>
<p>&quot;The new streamlined NatWest Markets will be an investment bank starting with 31 billion pounds of WRAs. To ensure profitability is improved, both profit and capital need to be addressed,&quot; Wanless said.</p>
<p>The post-tax return on equity for NatWest Markets was 2.4 percent, compared with 14.7 and 9.6 percent for the first and second halves of 1996.</p>
<p>This compared with 25.2 percent for NatWest UK and 13.4 percent for all continuing group operations.</p>
<p>NatWest announced overall pre-tax profits of 775 million pounds from continuing operations for the first half of 1997, slightly above the 770 million pound figure it had forecast when it issued a profits warning in June.</p>
<p>The group said the GFM arm, which was separated from NatWest Markets in the restructuring, recorded pre-tax profits for the period of 169 million pounds.</p>
<p>Wanless said the recent changes, including the appointment of Konrad &quot;Chip&quot; Kruger as chief executive of NatWest Markets, would ensure the business developed &quot;in a profitable and controlled manner&quot;.</p>
<p>While the group recognised its investment banking aspirations needed to be more focused, it remains &quot;committed to developing a profitable investment banking operation&quot; building on customer strengths through its British corporate banking ties.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is to create a srong, profitable investment bank headquartered in London, with a number of well-defined international operations,&quot; Wanless said, adding it was well positioned to offer a full range of investment banking products in Europe.</p>
<p>($ = 0.613 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
