<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780027" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS - GEC Alsthom mulls Westinghouse power bid.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - GEC Alsthom mulls Westinghouse power bid.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Franco-British engineering group GEC Alsthom on Tuesday confirmed it was was thinking about buying the energy business of Westinghouse Electric Corp. but that there were no negotiations going on.</p>
<p>It said in a statement it was interested in the Westinghouse's conventional energy business -- Power Generation -- while France's Framatome was interested in the Energy Systems nuclear business.</p>
<p>The deal, if completed, would boost GEC Alsthom's rank in power generation against Swiss-Swedish Asea Brown Boveri and Germany's Siemens in Europe, Mitsubishi of Japan and General Electric Co. of the United States.</p>
<p>GEC Alsthom chairman Pierre Bilger has taken it as a personal challenge to compete with GE on the world market for industrial power and in the growing markets of Asia, South America and eastern Europe.</p>
<p>French newspaper Liberation on Tuesday published copies of GEC Alsthom documents saying a bid approach had been made on July 25 after a French delegation led by Bilger had been to the U.S. on July 7.</p>
<p>Westinghouse is in the process of splitting its industrial businesses from its media interests such as CBS television, to be renamed CBS Corp.</p>
<p>Framatome was quick to &quot;formally deny&quot; that any bid approach had been made to Westinghouse. It later issued a statement confirming its interest in the activities, if they are for sale.</p>
<p>&quot;Framatome, like many other international companies in its sector, has since a few months indicated its interest in the Westinghouse activities,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as Framatome knows, Westinghouse is in the process of speating its industrial and media activities which excludes any sale of strategic assets,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>GEC Alsthom, a joint-venture of Alcatel Alsthom and GEC Plc, in a statement confirmed it had been in contact with Westinghouse but denied it had been representing Framatome as well.</p>
<p>It said the documents found by Liberation were from &quot;an internal working document&quot; drawn up prior to contacts with Westinghouse.</p>
<p>Alcatel has a 44 percent stake in Framatome, the rest being in the hands of state-owned companies.</p>
<p>&quot;It is true GEC Alsthom expressed an interest in buying Westinghouse's Power Generation business,&quot; the high-speed train and power generation company said in its statement. &quot;But to this day Westinghouse has not followed up and no negotiations have been started.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The fact of Framatome having an interest in the Energy Systems (nuclear) business is something which would enhance prospects for the two French groups and the French industry in this affair,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>It also stressed that Framatome was a separate company and GEC Alsthom could never use Framatome's cash -- it has funds of 10 billion francs -- to buy Westinghouse units.</p>
<p>Liberation had put the price of the Westinghouse energy divisions, which includes 80 nuclear centres, at $1.47 and $1.55 billion.</p>
<p>GEC Alsthom is currently in a decisive phase concerning its future and corporate ownership. Until recently, the joint-venture group had been planning a merger with Framatome after which a part of the capital of the enlarged group could be listed in London and Paris.</p>
<p>In April, however, these talks were finished because the French state wanted French companies to keep at least 50 percent in the enlarged GEC Alsthom while keeping control of the nuclear assets, and GEC did not want to have less than 50 percent.</p>
<p>Since then, however, GEC managing director George Simpson said he was considering a flotation of GEC Alsthom and expected a decision within three months.</p>
<p>Alcatel chairman Serge Tchuruk had earlier said that he and GEC were in talks about the wider issue of co-operation in the joint-venture.</p>
<p>The possibility of a bid for, or alliance with, the Westinghouse power business, could be a means to restart discussions on a GEC Alsthom link with Framatome.</p>
<p>Bilger, who was an internal candidate to lead Alcatel Alsthom when Pierre Suard had to step down in June 1995 but lost to Total chairman Tchuruk, will have to prove his managerial mettle to the fullest to get the Westinghouse prize he admits to be after.</p>
<p>He will have to convince his shareholders GEC and Alcatel, both yearning to find ways to free funds for investments in other strategic areas, to support a bid.</p>
<p>On top of that he will have to convince the French state to accept a minority French stake in a GEC Alsthom/Framatome/Westinghouse group and finally he will have to convince the financial markets that his policy is right and GEC Alsthom shares will be attractive to buy in a float.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
