<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780024" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US West Coast crudes rise with broader market gain.</title>
<headline>US West Coast crudes rise with broader market gain.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-08-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast light crude prices jumped Monday with broader market rallies while local spot trade for Alaskan crude remained idle, traders said.</p>
<p>Crude oil for September delivery rose 47 cents a barrel on the New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX) to $20.75 after production of Colombian Cano Limon crude was shut-in due to rebel pipeline bombings.</p>
<p>In local trade, no barrels of Alaska North Slope (ANS) traded, but foreign grades began to trickle in for September, traders said.</p>
<p>A major refiner, headquartered in New York, bought a cargo of Maya (Mexico) Monday, traders said, but did not specify its volume or destination. The cargo is the second purchased by the refinery in the last two months.</p>
<p>About five cargoes of the heavy, sour crude are arriving into West Coast refineries this month and will be tested for compatibility in their processing units.</p>
<p>Another large West Coast refiner also bought a cargo of South Blend crude at a price of $3.10 under September West Texas Intermediate/Cushing (WTI), traders said.</p>
<p>Traders also said a large independent late last week bought a partial cargo of ANS at the going market spot price.</p>
<p>Kern River heavy grade rose after Chevron Corp raised its postings late Monday.</p>
<p>((David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau +1 213 380 2014))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
