<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780198" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Eurobourses up, dlr rises on fixed Buba rate.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Eurobourses up, dlr rises on fixed Buba rate.</headline>
<byline>Medora Lee</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bourses rose on Tuesday morning, boosted by corporate earnings and Wall Street's late recovery overnight from steep opening losses.</p>
<p>The dollar stayed mostly steady against the yen but resumed its climb against the mark after Germany's central bank stuck to its planned, fixed 3.0-percent weekly money market operation.</p>
<p>Some traders had speculated the Bundesbank would surprise the market and also announce a variable-rate operation to allow rates to drift up and lift the mark from near eight-year lows versus the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/mark will soon be testing new highs, given the Bundesbank has done nothing today and that it will be another week before we find out what they are going to do about rates,&quot; said Keith Edmonds, chief analyst at IBJ International.</p>
<p>Analysts  said the market was now aiming to push the dollar up to 1.90 marks from about 1.8695 in early trade, especially if German jobs data on Wednesday show little improvement in cutting joblessness.</p>
<p>A clearer path for the dollar to rise against the mark calmed Germany's stock market, which shed about two percent on Monday because of German interest rate jitters.</p>
<p>Mark weakness makes German goods cheaper abroad, which should boost exports.</p>
<p>Further comfort came from Wall Street's recovery late in the session. The Dow Jones Industrial Average closed up 4.41 points at 8,198.45 after being down more than 50 points shortly after the open.</p>
<p>The Dow got a lift from technology stocks, which soared to pull the technology-laden Nasdaq Composite index up 11 points to a record 1,605.</p>
<p>London shares also received underlying support from Wall Street, but focus was mostly on corporate earnings and prospects for a British interest rate rise when the Bank of England (BOE) meets on Wednesday and Thursday.</p>
<p>BAA Plc jumped after the airport management group said pre-tax profits for the three months ending June 30 rose to 136 million pounds ($222 million), in line with analysts forecasts between 134 million and 140 million sterling.</p>
<p>At midmorning, BAA shares were up 18-1/2 pence at 580, just off its session high of 582.</p>
<p>National Westminster Bank shares tumbled  after earnings failed to meet analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>The bank said first half pre-tax profits rose to 669 million sterling versus 302 million last year and pre-tax profits from continuing operations rose to 775 million from 662 million. That compares with analysts' forecasts for pre-tax profits between 757 million and 770 million sterling.</p>
<p>Natwest shares were down 20 pence at 850, off its day low of 842.</p>
<p>But traders said FTSE activity should be limited before the BOE's monetary policy-making meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm afraid that the uncertainty about interest rates will keep volumes low and markets volatile,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Swedish shares also gained, but traders were awaiting forestry company Stora's first-half results due in the afternoon. Analysts expected a 30-percent drop in profits after financial items to 1.13 billion crowns ($140.4 million).</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 0915 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at  1.8700 marks and 118.65 yen, compared to 1.8635 and 118.40 in late trading on Monday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 0915 GMT</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index was up 33.7 points at 4,929.40.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The DAX index was up 52.56 points at 4,349.50 in bourse trade.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 was up 15.67 points at 3008.08.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold opened in Zurich at $323.05, down from London's close at $323.65 on Monday.</p>
<p>($ = 0.613 British Pounds)</p>
<p>($ = 8.049 Swedish Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
