<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780343" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Alcan plans new Australia bauxite mine.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Alcan plans new Australia bauxite mine.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alcan Aluminium Ltd said on Tuesday it planned to spend US$130 million on a new bauxite mine at Ely, in northern Queensland.  </p>
<p>&quot;The new mine will result in a significant reduction in the cost of bauxite to Alcan's alumina plants at Gladstone in Queensland and elsewhere around the world,&quot; Alcan said.</p>
<p>The company said the mine, to be owned and operated by Alcan subsidiary Alcan South Pacific Pty Ltd, would have initial annual output of 2.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>It said construction would start in September and the first bauxite was expected to be shipped during the fourth quarter of 1999.  </p>
<p>&quot;This development is a component of Alcan's strategy to substantially reduce its cost of raw materials and consolidate its competitive position world wide,&quot; Alcan chief executive Jacques Bougie said in a statement. Bougie said Australian government approval of the project was expected shortly.</p>
<p>&quot;Local support for the project is strong and the final agreement with the Aboriginal community, based on the detailed March 1997 heads of agreement, is expected to be signed in August,&quot; Alcan said. Alcan South Pacific owns 21.4 percent of Queensland Alumina Ltd which operates the world's largest alumina refinery at Gladstone. -- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
