<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780417" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea reshuffles cabinet, keeps foreign minister.</title>
<headline>S.Korea reshuffles cabinet, keeps foreign minister.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean President Kim Young-sam on Tuesday carried out a cabinet reshuffle but kept most key ministers, including the foreign minister and the finance minister, a presidential aide said.</p>
<p>He gave no other details but Yonhap Television News said Kim replaced 11 ministers, including those for home affairs, justice, education and agriculture portfolios.  </p>
<p>In the shakeout affecting half of the 22-member cabinet, Kim retained the ministers responsible for foreign and security policies ahead of crucial four-nation talks, involving the two Koreas, the United States and China, Yonhap said.</p>
<p>Senior officials from the four countries are due to meet in New York later on Tuesday to set an agenda and other procedural details for their peace talks.</p>
<p>The talks are aimed at hammering out a lasting peace on the Korean peninsula, the last Cold War flashpoint, to replace the fraying 1953 armistice that ended the three-year Korean War.</p>
<p>The finance and trade ministers remained unchanged to underscore the continuity of current economic policies, Yonhap said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
