<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780691" id="root" date="1997-08-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: PRESS DIGEST - Germany - August 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Germany - August 5.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's German newspapers:</p>
<p>FRANKFURTER ALLGEMEINE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel rejects Iranian conditions for the return of EU ambassadors to Tehran, but sees glimmer of hope for revival of relations with Bonn as new President Mohammad Khatami takes office.</p>
<p>- Ruling coalition and opposition pessimistic over the chances of agreement at new meeting of parliamentary mediation committee on tax reform plans.</p>
<p>- Dollar continues to soar, reaching 1.8720 marks on Monday, its highest level for almost eight years.</p>
<p>- Situation in flood-hit eastern Germany continues to improve as water levels sink.</p>
<p>- The two leading opposition Social Democrat (SPD) chancellor candidates Gerhards Schroeder and Oskar Lafontaine agree on joint action in the run up to next year's general elections.</p>
<p>- Mainz court rejects motion brought by a father of a schoolgirl against new spelling reforms.</p>
<p>HANDELSBLATT</p>
<p>- Fear of climbing interest rates hits stock markets.</p>
<p>- Second meeting of parliamentary mediation committee to discuss government tax reforms looks set to fail before it has even begun with SPD leader Lafontaine saying his party will not agree to government plans.</p>
<p>- Kinkel rejects Tehran's conditions over return of EU envoys to Iran.</p>
<p>- Unions react with anger to suggestion by Christian Democrats (CDU) and Christian Social Union (CSU) for return to a 40-hour working week.</p>
<p>SUEDDEUTSCHE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Harmonious joint excursion for SPD's Schroeder and Lafontaine -- but they won't decide who will challenge Chancellor Helmut Kohl until next spring.</p>
<p>- Government confirms that the introduction of Europe's planned single currency could lead the loss of billions of marks of Bundesbank profits.</p>
<p>- Upper house of parliament due to pass scrapping of capital trading tax -- the only part of the government tax reform plans opposition and ruling coalition could agree to.</p>
<p>DIE WELT</p>
<p>- Ruling coalition argue about new parliamentary mediation talks on tax reform.</p>
<p>- SPD's Lafontaine and Schroeder agreed on joint way of proceeding ahead of next year's elections.</p>
<p>- Defence lawyers want Egon Krenz, last hardline leader of East Germany, to be acquitted on charges related to Cold War killing of people trying to escape to the West.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom +49 228 260 97160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
