<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780893" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FDA panel backs Medtronic incontinence device.</title>
<headline>FDA panel backs Medtronic incontinence device.</headline>
<dateline>ROCKVILLE, Md. 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. Food and Drug Administration advisory committee on Wednesday voted unanimously to recommend approval of an implantable, pacemaker-like device made by Medtronic Inc to control urge incontinence.  </p>
<p>The firm's Sacral Nerve Stimulation system, which uses its interstim device, is a more permanent and potentially more effective alternative to exercises, biofeedback, and diapers and other absorbent products, Medtronic said.</p>
<p>With SNS, a wire lead is placed through the patient's lower back; electrodes at the tip are attached to nerves radiating from the spine that control bladder and bowel function. The other end is snaked through to a pulse generator implanted under the stomach skin.</p>
<p>It is a two-hour operation.  </p>
<p>FDA reviewer Phyllis Silverman said the &quot;effectiveness results you've seen today are dramatic and compelling.&quot;</p>
<p>Medtronic said that at six months, 47 percent of implant patients were completely dry, and 80 percent had eliminated heavy leaking. Panelists were also impressed with effectiveness data and said the benefits outweighed the risks.</p>
<p>However, panelists and FDA reviewers were concerned about complication rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The re-opeation rate seems to be too high,&quot; said panelist Dr. Robert Hawes of the Medical University of South Carolina.  </p>
<p>The FDA said that 46.5 percent of patients had surgery related adverse events and that 51 of 157 patients with implants had to have additional surgery to alleviate pain or replace devices.</p>
<p>The committee recommended that Medtronic provide better training to physicians to reduce complications and that patients be informed of complication rates.</p>
<p>Medtronic plans a long-term, follow-up study to address these and other FDA and panel concerns.</p>
<p>The FDA is not bound by its panels' advice, but usually follows it.  </p>
<p>The market for incontinence products is at least $1 billion, with absorbents currently taking the lion's share, according to analysts.</p>
<p>Five million of the 13 million American adults with incontinence have the urge type, in which sudden spasms lead to an unavoidable urge to urinate.</p>
<p>It is caused by repeated urinary tract infections, stroke or other neurological damage, or bladder muscle weakness.</p>
<p>Females account for 85 percent of those with incontinence. Direct and indirect costs of treating incontinence are $11 to $16 billion a year, patient advocates said.  </p>
<p>Given the public health need, Medtronic asked FDA for an expedited approval in February.  FDA agreed, noting that early data was impressive.</p>
<p>For the pivotal trial, patients first had to go through peripheral nerve evaluation to determine if they would benefit from SNS.</p>
<p>Patients got a temporary implant and kept diaries of leaking episodes per day, severity of episodes, and number of absorbent pads used daily.  Those whose symptoms improved more than 50% were enrolled in the study.  Reflecting the incidence in the population, 80 percent of study patients were female.</p>
<p>Thirty-four patients who received implants were compared to 42 patients who were assigned to wait for an implant.</p>
<p>Again, both groups kept diaries.  At six months, implant patients had improved significantly, from 8.7 leaks per day at baseline to 2.6, and from 6.2 pads used per day to 1.1.  There was no significant improvement in the delay group, which used exercises and other conservative treatment.</p>
<p>Twenty-one percent of patients had pain at the surgery site in the back and 17 percent had pain at the generator implant site.</p>
<p>The Interstim device was recently approved by FDA for deep brain stimulation to control tremors, and has been available in Europe for incontinence.</p>
<p>-- Washington newsroom, ((202-898-8300))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROCKVILLE, Md."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
