<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780894" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sled Dogs signs forbearance pact.</title>
<headline>Sled Dogs signs forbearance pact.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sled Dogs Co, which makes snow skates and related accessories, said Wednesday it signed a forbearance agreement with Norwest Credit Inc, its asset-based lender.</p>
<p>Norwest agreed to forbear from exercising its rights and remedies as a secured creditor until either September 30, failure by the company to meet its obligations under the agreement, or default by the company under any other loan agreement, whichever is earlier.  </p>
<p>Sled Dogs chief financial officer Mike Wise said the company has been in default of its loan agreement since March 1997. As of March 31, it owed $620,000. The current balance due was not disclosed.</p>
<p>Under the forbearance agreeement, Sled Dogs must repay the amounts due under the loan on October 1.</p>
<p>If the loan is not repaid, Norwest Credit will have the option to take over Sled Dog's assets or to have Sled Dogs liquidate its assets.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hopeful that the company can meet its obligations under the forbearance agreement,&quot; chairman Kent Rodriguez said in a statement. &quot;The company continues to work on securing additional capital and is in the process of searching for another asset-based lender to step into (Norwest's) position.&quot;</p>
<p>Wise said Norwest is currently Sled Dog's only asset-based lender.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
