<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="780811" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - T-bond reversal fizzles as support forms.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - T-bond reversal fizzles as support forms.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury bond futures continued in a sideways consolidation pattern for a third straight day, casting doubt on the market's ability to extend Friday's downturn, technicians said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The 114-12/32 to 114-10/32 lows so far this week in September bond futures have formed a ridge of support coinciding with where the market was trading before the release of Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's bond-friendly Humphrey-Hawkins testimony in July, said Brad Tyl, analyst with Aubrey G. Lanston &amp; Co. on the floor of the Chicago Board of Trade.  </p>
<p>That indicates the market is struggling with whether to fade Greenspan's testimony, which had been viewed as suggesting another rate tightening was not in the cards near term, Tyl said.</p>
<p>Tyl said a break below 113-24/32 in September bonds would dim chances for the market to snap back and resume its uptrend.</p>
<p>Bond futures had gained more than 10 full points since April before Friday's strong employment and purchasing managers data cut the rally short.  </p>
<p>David Hightower, president of the Hightower Report, said he would interpret a drop to 113-15/32 as a negative sign.</p>
<p>&quot;If it rolls below that, we'll assume the uptrend is over,&quot; Hightower said.</p>
<p>Continued high open interest in bond futures raises the question of how long bulls will hold onto their positions and should be monitored, Hightower added.</p>
<p>Jim Hyerczyk, president of JAH Research and Trading, said futures could bounce back to 115-19/32, approximately the 50 percent retracement of the decline from last week's 116-31 high to this week's lows.  </p>
<p>However, he anticipated good selling interest to materialize should futures manage to claw back to that level.</p>
<p>The market could rebound to 116-04/32, if it can first punch above good resistance around today's high of 114-29/32, said Nick Kalivas, senior credit market analyst for Refco Inc.</p>
<p>He said he favored additional downward movement to alleviate the market's still-high bullish sentiment reading and was targeting 112-24/32, a previous breakout point. But the lack of momentum was a concern.  </p>
<p>&quot;The fact that we're consolidating and haven't got a lot of downside followthrough is making me nervous about being bearish,&quot; Kalivas said.</p>
<p>-- Susan Kelly/Chicago Derivatives Desk ((312-408-8750))</p>
<p>chicago.derivatives.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
