<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781271" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Foreigners sell record bonds on Nairobi bourse.</title>
<headline>Foreigners sell record bonds on Nairobi bourse.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Green</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign investors on the Nairobi Stock Exchange (NSE) sold a record number of treasury bonds on Wednesday as the Kenya shilling plunged to its lowest level in almost four years, bourse officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Foreigners sold 400 million shillings ($5.97 million) worth of the fourth issue of the Central Bank of Kenya floating-rate treasury bond at 102.7000 from 102.6650. Local speculators sold another 50,000 shillings worth of the bonds at the same rate.</p>
<p>The shilling has declined 12.6 percent since Friday's news that the International Monetary Fund had halted a $205 million loan under a three-year soft-lending Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility (ESAF) to Kenya in a row over corruption.</p>
<p>The shilling traded at 67 from an opening of 64 versus the dollar. There were asking prices of as low as 69. The shilling's all time low against the dollar stands at 69.22 in 1993.</p>
<p>The total bond turnover in the week to last Friday, when the IMF ruling filtered through, was 13.5 million shillings. From Friday to Wednesday, foreign investors have offloaded 996.4 million shillings, according to Nairobi Stock Exchange statistics.</p>
<p>Foreign investors offloaded a record turnover of bonds before buying hard currency and repatriating their profits, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>But on Wednesday, the NSE 20-share index made its first gain in four days, rising 17.9 points to stand at 3426.65. The IMF decision sent the market tumbling from 3453.18 at Friday's close to dip as low as 3408.75 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The central bank suggested on Wednesday that foreign investors offloading bonds were destabilising the shilling.</p>
<p>&quot;It is being reported by commercial banks that some foreign investors in Treasury Bills and Stocks are in the market to buy foreign exchange to repatriate their profits,&quot; Central Bank of Kenya Governor Micah Cheserem said in a statement.</p>
<p>Brokers said foreigners were offloading bonds because the government of President Daniel arap Moi had failed to reassure investors that they would take the right steps to win back IMF confidence. Moi has in fact told Kenyans to become self-reliant.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of old foreign contacts are calling us, appraising what is happening, then trying to get out of the market at an opportune time. It is a sensible thing to do,&quot; said a broker.</p>
<p>&quot;It's primarily because the kind of statements coming from the nation's policy-makers are not sending out signals that the IMF's decision will hurt us, but any financial person will tell you that is not the case,&quot; the broker added.</p>
<p>The only foreign deal on the bourse floor was in Kenya Commercial Bank, trading at 90.5-93 shillings from 91.50. On Monday no deals were made on the foreign board, and one deal was made by foreigners on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It was a slow day on the agricultural board, although Kakuzi gained two shillings to close at 108. George Williamson Kenya lost a shilling to close at 72.</p>
<p>Kenya Airways remained pegged at 8.0 on the fifth day of a go-slow by Kenyan air traffic controllers. Uchumi Supermarkets closed at 38.25 from 37.</p>
<p>($1=67 Kenyan shillings.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
