<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781390" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Montenegrin dissident party congress opens.</title>
<headline>Montenegrin dissident party congress opens.</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A dissident faction of the ruling Montenegrin party opened its congress in the northern town of Kolasin on Wednesday, further escalating tensions between Serbia and its tiny ally in the Yugoslav federation.</p>
<p>The dissident faction of the Democratic Party of Socialists is loyal to hardline president Momir Bulatovic who was ousted as party president last month.</p>
<p>The party congress, ignored in most parts, especially the southern, richer regions of the republic loyal to reformist Prime Minister Milo Djukanovic, was attended by Serbian Socialist Party (SPS) Vice-President Zoran Lilic.</p>
<p>Lilic told the congress that his party was committed to a unified, sovereign Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>Djukanovic's faction believes Serbia wants to dominate its junior partner and has criticized President Slobodan Milosevic for not backing democracy and privatisation.</p>
<p>Djukanovic, a 33-year old pro-Western politician, has urged Milosevic to meet his comitments from Dayton where he signed a peace deal in 1995 to end the wars in Bosnia and Croatia and move for greater democracy in the country.</p>
<p>His faction refused to allow Milosevic to amend the federal constitution before he became federal president last month.</p>
<p>The rift between the two men is reaching a point of no return, diplomats said, warning any further strain could lead to a &quot;Slovenia syndrome&quot;.</p>
<p>They were referring to a series of events which led to the secession of the northernmost republic in 1991. The secession was preceded by a tacit trade embargo by Belgrade on the Alpine republic.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the latest red light flashing in the Balkans,&quot; one told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Last weekend Montenegro's trade minister Branko Vujovic accused Serbia of disrupting trade between the two republics.</p>
<p>Montenegrin economists have accused Belgrade of taking its business elsewhere, using ports in Greece and Bulgaria instead of Montenegro's Bar.</p>
<p>Montenegro, the junior partner to Serbia in what remains of Yugoslavia after its violent 1991 break-up, is home to some 650,000 people and generates five percent of Yugoslavia's GDP.</p>
<p>Belgrade's backing of Bulatovic, who urges unreserved support for Milosevic, led to ugly scenes in the Montenegrin capital Podgorica last week.</p>
<p>Several thousand demonstrators threw stones, eggs and tomatoes at a motorcade of senior SPS officials.</p>
<p>The SPS visit to Podgorica was seen in the Belgrade press as an attempt to boost Bulatovic's beleaguered position.</p>
<p>Montenegrin parliament speaker Svetozar Marovic has called presidential elections for October 5, some three months before Bulatovic's current mandate expires.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
