<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781345" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: RWE HUNGARY PLANT SIGNS PPA WITH SUPPLIER.</title>
<headline>RWE HUNGARY PLANT SIGNS PPA WITH SUPPLIER.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>German consortium RWE Energie AG and EVS AG said on Wednesday it had signed a power purchase agreement with Hungarian electricity supply company MVM, clearing the way for a 250 billion forint investment programme.</p>
<p>The PPA, which runs until 2015, is for the operation of the Matra power station in north-east Hungary in which RWE/EVS has a 54 percent stake, Matra's general manager, Jozsef Valaska, told Hungarian economic news agency MTI-Econews.</p>
<p>The contract, for an estimated 410 billion forints' worth of power, removes the last barrier for RWE/EVS to participate in a current tender to build 1000 MW of new capacity, which it said it could only pursue provided it reached a PPA with MVM.</p>
<p>The consortium plans a bid to build two new lignite-powered 500 MW power plants at Bukkabrany, part of the Matra power plant site under the terms of one of two tenders MVM announced last week for the construction of 2000 megawatts of new Hungarian capacity.</p>
<p>The first tender will be for smaller capacity units of 20 to 200 MW for commissioning between 2001 and 2003 while the second will be for larger plants to go on line between 2003 and 2005.</p>
<p>According to the PPA, MVM will initially buy electricity from Matra at 7.60 forints/KWh, with quarterly adjustments to be made by the Hungarian Energy Office in line with a price formula taking into account world market prices, Hungarian production costs and the forint/dollar exchange rate.</p>
<p>The PPA is the second MVM has signed with a foreign investor. In June, Powergen, through its Hungarian subsidiary Csepel Aramtermelo Rt, signed a 20-year contract with MVM, paving the way for the development of a $261 million power plant in Budapest.</p>
<p>As well as RWE-EVS's coal-fired Matra power station, other plants with large foreign investments are the oil-fired Dunamenti plant, in central Hungary, run by Tractebel and Tisza, in the east, operated by AES.</p>
<p>-- Duncan Shiels, Budapest newsroom +361 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
