<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781499" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Two dead, 107 injured at chaotic Peru concert.</title>
<headline>Two dead, 107 injured at chaotic Peru concert.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two girls died from asphyxiation and 107 people were injured at the chaotic climax of a Latin music concert in Peru attended by more than twice the site's 40,000 capacity, authorities said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>One injured girl was in a coma and another six people were in critical condition after the tragic end to Tuesday night's concert by Venezuelan duo Servando y Florentino.</p>
<p>Police and firefighters pinned the blame on overcrowding, poor planning by organisers and hysteria among the estimated 100,000 concert-goers when the teen idols came back on stage for an encore at the end of their show.</p>
<p>Some of the injured were crushed, while others fainted, fell and were trampled inside Lima's Home Show park, witnesses said. There was also scuffling as sections of the crowd tried to move in opposite directions in the park, a large, open-air, cement-floored fairground often used for concerts.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a huge crowd ... I felt bad, I fainted, I fell to the ground, and the girls trod on me, they suffocated me,&quot; said 14-year-old Nidia Bravo from her hospital bed. &quot;A man carried me ... I fell again ... I nearly died yesterday.&quot;</p>
<p>According to some versions, the Venezuelan brothers continued playing despite the warning of security guards. A public prosecutor investigating the case tried to interview them before they left for New York on a flight early on Wednesday, but only managed to speak to their manager.</p>
<p>&quot;We are really sorry for what has happened at the concert,&quot; a grim-faced Servando told reporters as they left Lima airport. &quot;But I want to say to the fans: I love you a lot, thanks for turning up yesterday and we'll soon be back.&quot;</p>
<p>Fire chief Victor Podesta slammed the concert organisers for bad preparation. &quot;There was no coordination,&quot; he said. &quot;There were far more people in there than there should have been, and this caused avalanches of fans.&quot;</p>
<p>He also claimed one of the singers kicked a fireman, while a security guard working for the duo punched another. &quot;In my opinion, these gentlemen should be banned from the country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But concert organiser Michel Letterstein defended the Venezuelans: &quot;Servando y Florentino made an effort to quiet the girls, they pleaded for their support ... but the girls did not calm down.&quot;</p>
<p>Television pictures of the concert showed girls waving underwear, screaming hysterically, fainting and being carried out on stretchers. Witnesses said the concert was sold out but some of the youngest fans were let in free, while others hid in the park the night before the show.</p>
<p>Servando y Florentino, who are stars of the salsa genre -- a Latin American dance music of Afro-Cuban and Puerto Rican origin -- have one of their biggest followings in Peru.</p>
<p>The victims, Rosa Quispe Navarro, 18, and Elena Arana Pinedo, 19, died inside the concert site. Peruvian ombudsman Jorge Santistevan promised a thorough government investigation and punishment for those found responsible.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
