<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78156" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Gains to VUB push Slovak SAX index up 2.9 pts.</title>
<headline>Gains to VUB push Slovak SAX index up 2.9 pts.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Slovak shares closed mixed in thin trading on Bratislava Stock Exchange (BSE) on Thursday, but gains to VUB bank and the average price of steelworks VSZ pushed the SAX index up 2.9 points to 207.22.</p>
<p>Slovakia's largest commercial bank VUB gained 100 crowns to close at 1,750, with its average price -- by which the index is calculated -- adding most to the SAX's increase.</p>
<p>Steel maker VSZ led today's trading on the BSE floor -- with 1,708 shares changing hands -- closed down six crowns at 619, but its average price rose 4.17 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Put in the short-term perspective, VSZ is expected to fall as one or two active investors, who have held its price higher, apparently lost interest in trading with the issue,&quot; said Patrik Granec of Slovenska Sporitelna.</p>
<p>Oil and gas storage Nafta fell 10 crowns to 1,970, but brokers said the decline was only a short-term trend and predicted return of the Nafta price to levels of above 2,000 crowns in near future.</p>
<p>Oil refiner Slovnaft closed up five at 945 crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;Slovnaft largest shareholders are already holding the major stakes, and there should not be any significant moves with the price as no larger packages (of shares) are expected to hit the market,&quot; Granec said.</p>
<p>Overall volume fell to 164,329 shares on Thursday, from 242,127 shares traded on Wednesday, turnover decreased to 108.33 million crowns, from 214.36 million on Wednesday. -- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-536-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
