<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781638" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUAM: Official says no more survivors from Guam crash.</title>
<headline>Official says no more survivors from Guam crash.</headline>
<byline>Paul Eckert</byline>
<dateline>AGANA, Guam 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rescuers late on Wednesday all but gave up hope of finding more survivors from the crash in Guam of a Korean Air Lines jet, confirming the worst fears of hundreds of relatives starting to gather at this Pacific island resort.</p>
<p>Speaking amid the charred and still smouldering wreckage of the Boeing 747, U.S. Admiral Martin Janczak said: &quot;We have search and rescue dogs available to us, but it's our opinion that no one is still alive.&quot;</p>
<p>That left only 30 survivors from the 254 people on board the aircraft. He said 69 bodies had been recovered and 155 people were missing. Two passengers rescued alive died in hospital.</p>
<p>Officials in Seoul said Korean Air Lines Flight 801 was carrying 231 passengers and 23 crew, including dozens of vacationers, several South Korean politicians, three infants and at least 14 Americans.</p>
<p>Janczak denied reports that the pilot had called in an emergency or reported a fire aboard the plane before the night-time crash early on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The pilot did not say there was an emergency,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Flight 801 slammed into a hillside on its approach to Guam's main international airport in a flight from Seoul, South Korea.</p>
<p>The plane tried to land in a torrential downpour.</p>
<p>A special flight was scheduled by KAL to take some 200 South Korea relatives to Guam. Some 30 who had already arrived angrily confronted KAL officials, demanding to know the names of the survivors and disrupting a news conference by the officials.</p>
<p>Janczak said reports by residents of explosions accompanying the crash were most likely the sound of tyres exploding from the heat of the fire.</p>
<p>The aircraft was spread across a wide area of the hillside with the first-class section 25 yards (metres) from the main parts of the plane. The fuselage was left in four main chunks.</p>
<p>Several of the passengers managed to walk away from the crash unscathed.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw some people were able to walk away from the wreckage...it's a miracle that anyone could come out of this,&quot; said Dr Michael Lancer, a Guam resident who reached the wreckage while it was still burning.</p>
<p>A South Korean survivor said he pulled a woman from the crashed jet but fire stopped him from rescuing trapped children.</p>
<p>&quot;As I tried to get out of the plane in a hurry, fearing possible explosions, a lady pulled my foot,&quot; Hong Hyon-song, 35, said in a telephone interview with state television Korea Broadcasting System.</p>
<p>&quot;It was dark but I could figure that a lady was there. I pulled her arms and got out by clearing leaves around. I was worried the plane might explode,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said he and the woman, who was badly burned, had to wait in darkness for about an hour before being rescued.</p>
<p>Hong said an injured female flight attendant asked her to return to the wreckage to help others out.</p>
<p>&quot;When I shouted into the wreckage asking whether anybody was alive, children shouted for help. I asked them 'how many' and they said 'four'.</p>
<p>&quot;It was frustrating and unfortunate but I could not get back in because fire caused blasts inside the plane,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Guam Governor Carl Gutierrez, one of the first people to reach the crash scene, said he saved five people, including a Korean mother and daughter who &quot;wouldn't let go of each other&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;They were embedded into the steel and the cushions.&quot;</p>
<p>Eventually, a doctor &quot;yanked&quot; the girl out and the mother followed her, he said.</p>
<p>Gutierrez said he was told by survivor Barry Small of New Zealand, who was sitting in row 13 of the plane, that there were no indications of trouble in mid-flight or during the approach to the landing.</p>
<p>The crash was the airline's first since 1989, but the company's accident rate is seen as relatively high.</p>
<p>Marty Salfen, senior vice president of the International Airline Passengers Association, said KAL had an accident rate of 1.91 per million departures over the past 10 years against the worldwide rate of 0.581 per million.</p>
<p>Salfen's figure does not include the loss of KAL flight 007, a Boeing 747 that strayed into Soviet airspace in 1983 and was shot down. All 269 people aboard died.</p>
<p>Hours after the Guam crash a KAL Airbus A300 en route to Seoul from Osaka returned to Kansai airport in western Japan when it experienced engine trouble shortly after takeoff, an official of the airline said.</p>
<p>South Korean immigration officials said 14 Americans, one Japanese, the New Zealander and five unidentified foreign transiting passengers were on board the crashed plane.</p>
<p>Further information on the identities of the victims was not immediately available.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AGANA, Guam"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
