<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781766" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai, Shenzhen stock markets end down.</title>
<headline>Shanghai, Shenzhen stock markets end down.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's stock markets closed lower across-the-board on Wednesday with hard currency B shares hurt by new issues in Shanghai and declines in domestic currency A shares in Shenzhen.</p>
<p>Shanghai's foreign currency B shares inched down as investors turned to new issues, brokers said.</p>
<p>The B index lost 0.178 points or 0.24 percent to 74.303 points on volume of 23.944 million shares worth $9.841 million.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no investors entering the market, except to buy new share issues,&quot; said an analyst at China Guotai Securities. &quot;The market is weak because there is not enough capital.&quot;</p>
<p>Newcomer Shanghai Zhenhua Port Machinery Co Ltd stole the spotlight on its second day of trading as investors continued to buy the stock of the port machinery maker at the expense of other shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>Zhenhua Port was the top gainer in the falling market and also the most actively traded B share. The stock soared $0.048 or 10 percent to $0.528 on volume of around 9.4 million shares.</p>
<p>Inner Mongolia Yitai Coal Co Ltd was to list 166 million B shares in Shanghai on Friday and investors were waiting for the new issue before entering the market, brokers said.</p>
<p>A stellar performance by the Hong Kong stock market had also drained capital away from the Shanghai bourse, they said.</p>
<p>Of 46 B shares, 42 traded with 17 down, 14 flat and 11 up.</p>
<p>Shanghai Post &amp; Telecommunication Equipment Co was the biggest B share loser on talk of poor interim results. It slumped $0.022 or 6.67 percent to $0.308.</p>
<p>Shanghai A shares tumbled late in the session on institutional selling amid cautious market sentiment, brokers said.</p>
<p>The A index fell 26.065 points or 2.08 percent to 1,225.801 points on volume of 266.361 million shares worth 2.788 billion yuan.</p>
<p>The SSE30 blue chip index lost 60.546 points or 1.62 percent to 3,687.487 points.</p>
<p>Shenzhen's hard currency B share index also closed down, dragged lower by weakness on the domestic A share market, analysts said.</p>
<p>The B share index lost 1.49 points or 1.13 percent to 129.96 points on turnover of HK$46 million against HK$34 million on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall in B shares was mainly fuelled by the weakness of A shares,&quot; an analyst at China Guotai Securities said, adding that steep falls in B shares were unlikely in the near future.</p>
<p>The Shenzhen A share index shed 9.71 points or 2.35 percent to 403.52 points on turnover of 4.0 billion yuan against 4.1 billion yuan in the previous session.</p>
<p>Analysts said the A share drop was due in part to losses in market leader Shenzhen Development Bank, which fell 0.45 yuan to 33.65 yuan on volume of 2.4 million shares.</p>
<p>The bank has performed poorly since last month when it forecast slower than expected earnings growth for 1997.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Special Economic Zone Real Estate &amp; Properties (Group) Co Ltd was the biggest B share loser, sliding HK$0.18 or 6.84 percent to HK2.45 on solid volume 106,800 shares.</p>
<p>Brokers have said they expect the company, which is mainly involved in the development of office buildings, to report poor 1997 interim results because the Shenzhen commercial property market remained depressed.</p>
<p>($1=8.3 yuan, $1=HK$7.8)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
