<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781806" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan to sign accords with six C. American states.</title>
<headline>Taiwan to sign accords with six C. American states.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui plans to sign a series of accords with Central American nations to cement ties with the region, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;President Lee will sign memoranda on economic and trade cooperation with five Central American countries during his visit to Central America in September,&quot; economics minister Wang Chih-kang said on state television.</p>
<p>Wang identified the five countries as Costa Rica, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras and Nicaragua -- all among the 30 states that recognise Taipei instead of Beijing.</p>
<p>Lee also will sign a free trade agreement with Panama, another Taipei ally.</p>
<p>Lee was expected to leave for Panama in early September, and would transit in Hawaii to and from Central America. The U.S. State Department has said it will issue a transit visa for Lee to pass through Honolulu on September 4-5 and September 17-18.</p>
<p>It would be Lee's first overseas visit since a 1995 U.S. trip that infuriated Beijing.</p>
<p>Beijing, which views Taiwan as a renegade province not entitled to international relations since they split after a civil was in 1949, has urged Washington not to allow Lee to pursue pro-independence activities while in Hawaii.</p>
<p>Wang, who recently returned from a Central American visit to prepare for Lee's September trip, said the signing of the accords with the six countries was a good basis to further promote Taiwan's ties with its diplomatic allies.</p>
<p>Analysts say Beijing has stepped up efforts to increase its influence in Latin America, the site of 16 Taiwan allies. With foreign exchange reserves of more than US$100 billion, China can assert a major influence in the region, they say.</p>
<p>China's trade with Latin America stood at US$730 million in 1978. By 1995 it had rocketed 730 percent to US$6.11 billion, Taiwan's China Times daily reported.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ELSAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
