<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781925" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco companies revisit ruling in Florida lawsuit.</title>
<headline>Tobacco companies revisit ruling in Florida lawsuit.</headline>
<dateline>WEST PALM BEACH, Fla. 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tobacco companies need to be allowed to argue issues of &quot;common knowledge&quot; about the dangers of cigarette smoking in order to properly defend themselves against Florida's Medicaid lawsuit, tobacco lawyers told a Florida judge on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The lawyers told Palm Beach Circuit Judge Harold Cohen during an afternoon hearing that his ruling last week, in which he said tobacco companies could not use public knowledge of cigarette dangers as a defence, prevented them from adequately refuting 81 allegations of fraud and racketeering in the $1 billion lawsuit.</p>
<p>Lawyers for both sides said last week that the ruling was critical and virtually stripped the industry of its defences.</p>
<p>Florida's lawsuit seeks to recover public money used to treat people with smoking-related illnesses. But the suit also alleges the tobacco companies conspired to keep information about smoking's dangers from the public.</p>
<p>The racketeering counts could allow the state to collect billions of dollars in past profits from the industry.</p>
<p>Philip Morris Cos. Inc. attorney Murray Garnick argued that the industry should have the right to present evidence to the jury about what the public knew about smoking.</p>
<p>&quot;Their (Florida's) whole case is made up of circumstantial evidence with (industry) documents sprinkled through it,&quot; Garnick said.</p>
<p>Cohen said he would rule on the issue before attorneys for the two sides begin individual questioning of jury candidates on Aug. 18.</p>
<p>By the end of Wednesday's session, the fourth day of jury selection, Cohen had approved 50 potential candidates from the jury pool of more than 300. Six jurors and nine alternates will ultimately be chosen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WEST PALM BEACH, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
