<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="781974" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. 10-YR NOTE AUCTION FAILS TO MATCH HIGH HOPES.</title>
<headline>U.S. 10-YR NOTE AUCTION FAILS TO MATCH HIGH HOPES.</headline>
<byline>Steven Scheer</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>For the second straight day, tepid demand for U.S. Treasury securities disappointed market players after the much-hyped 10-year note sale failed to live up to its advance billing, much like the less-than-stellar three-year note auction results on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was terrible,&quot; said Terrence Pigott, senior trader at Daiwa Securities America Inc. He then corrected himself: &quot;Maybe it wasn't terrible but it was definitely sloppy, there's no doubt about it.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Treasury sold the $12.0 billion 10-year notes at an average 6.205 percent. But, it tailed to 6.215 percent.</p>
<p>The bid-to-cover ratio was at 2.24 and non-competitive bids were some $380 million.</p>
<p>&quot;People were expecting better,&quot; said one 10-year trader at a dealer. He added the market figured that with money flowing in from Europe amid fears of a German rate hike, the auction would have gone better.</p>
<p>Wednesday's 10-year sale was said to have been bought mostly by dealers, with a little bit of retail participation.  </p>
<p>&quot;People were talking up the auction this morning,&quot; said a trader. &quot;There was a lot of hype so people did not expect a tail to 6.215. It wasn't that bad but relative to expectations it was not that great.&quot;</p>
<p>The tone improved somewhat after the auction, with the when-issued 10-year note down to 6.20 percent at 1515 EDT/1915 GMT. Similarly, the three-year note, sold on Tuesday at 6.04 percent was trading at 6.02 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The uptrade is still intact, but it will take a while for the (new) paper to be digested,&quot; keeping the market under pressure, the trader said.  </p>
<p>Some traders suggested that in hindsight, the auction would have gone better at the even more expensive levels of about 6.00 percent seen late last week. That's because until Thursday, the market was banking on slower growth and a continuation of falling Treasuries yields.</p>
<p>&quot;There was huge buying Tuesday, Wednesday and Thursday,&quot; Pigott said. &quot;Everyone was buying.&quot;</p>
<p>But last Friday's strong economic data changed sentiment somewhat and the heavy buying stopped.</p>
<p>Even after disappointments on Tuesday and Wednesday, market players speculated that Thursday's $10 billion 30-year bond auction would do better than the previous two legs of the Treasury's quarterly refunding. They noted the bond has held resistence and demand for bonds lately has been good.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1867 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
