<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="782069" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW-PHILLIPS PARES DRILLING PORTFOLIO.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-PHILLIPS PARES DRILLING PORTFOLIO.</headline>
<byline>James Pierpoint</byline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>When Mike Coffelt took over Phillips Petroleum Co's worldwide exploration activities in 1995, his first order of business was to pare down a prospect portfolio that stretched across 16 countries.</p>
<p>He completed a move out of most North American onshore plays and sold off non-commercial prospects, but ended up adding another country to his travel schedule while rebuilding a portfolio of deepwater prospects that had all but dried up.</p>
<p>&quot;Our real reason for existing is to ring the bell,&quot; he said of Phillips' global exploration strategy. &quot;Exploration is one of the activities capable of moving the company's stock.&quot;</p>
<p>In the Gulf of Mexico, Phillips and partner Mobil Corp have pencilled in plans to drill their first joint deepwater well in early 1998. The partners will accelerate deepwater exploration after taking delivery of a refurbished drillship later in the year, Coffelt said in an interview with Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Phillips and Mobil jointly hold leases on 118 U.S. Gulf deepwater tracts, and are in the process of drawing up drilling plans. In shallower waters, the partners drilled to depth and are assessing results of their Chinook prospect.</p>
<p>Phillips recently pulled out of the Lion subsalt prospect, leaving partners Anadarko Petroleum Corp and operator Broken Hill Proprietary Co Ltd's U.S. unit to continue drilling below the initial target zone, he said.</p>
<p>In Alaska's North Cook Inlet, Phillips by year-end expects to complete a 15,000-foot delineated well from its Tyonek platform searching for oil under a dry gas field discovered in the 1960s. Drilling there has been slowed by coal formations.</p>
<p>But the Bartlesville, Okla.-based company has largely retreated from Canadian and U.S. fields while paring its international portfolio. &quot;We have not much acreage left that we would consider low potential,&quot; Coffelt said.</p>
<p>Phillips shares in five Atlantic margin deepwater tranches from the U.K.'s 17th round and five tracts from the Irish Rockall leasing round. To the south, Phillips and operator Marathon Oil are assessing the Kenmare exploratory well in 2,300 feet of water, with results due by year end.</p>
<p>Phillips is committed to participating in 10 wells in the Athena prospect off the coast of Australia, including two wells already drilled with BHP. &quot;We're going to have a huge drilling program over there in the next few years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although Phillips boosted its exploration and development budget to $1 billion from $905 million this year, most of the increase went to production projects. Coffelt expects his budget to remain at about $300 million for 1997 and 1998.</p>
<p>That's not to say he hasn't found a way to finance a couple of frontier plays. Phillips in January was awarded an exploration license off Greenland's west coast, where deepwater drilling is planned in a consortium with Statoil.</p>
<p>&quot;The biggest risk is that it will be gas prone. If it's there, it will be huge,&quot; he said of hydrocarbon-bearing formations appearing on seismic surveys.</p>
<p>The company also controls 14 million acres off the South Africa coast, another frontier play with high risks and potentially high returns.</p>
<p>&quot;Greenland and South Africa are the ones that keep me up at night. I really itch to get in there with a rig,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((-- Houston Bureau 1+ 713 210-8508))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
