<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78214" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poland to sign deal with KGHM sale adviser in Sept.</title>
<headline>Poland to sign deal with KGHM sale adviser in Sept.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's privatisation ministry will sign a formal agreement with its advisor in the sale of the KGHM copper concern by the end of the month, Privatisation Minister Wieslaw Kaczmarek said on Thursday.</p>
<p>In June Poland picked a consortium of Barclays de Zoete Wedd, Union Bank of Switzerland and Wielkopolski Bank Kredytowy SA brokerage to advise in the KGHM privatisation.</p>
<p>The sale of about 25 percent of the company, estimated to be worth $2-3 billion, earlier planned for late 1996 is now expected no sooner than the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>KGHM earlier said meeting the September deadline was crucial for the timing of its privatisation because a planned government reform that will dissolve the privatisation ministry, due to start next month, could delay the start of the work on the company's sell-off.</p>
<p>Under the government's tentative plan some 15 percent of KGHM would be floated in London in the form of Global Depositary Receipts (GDR). Another 10 percent would be placed on the Warsaw bourse and employees would get 15 percent.</p>
<p>But the final method of the sell-off would be decided in consultation with the adviser.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
