<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="782183" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Colour not to merge with Clariant.</title>
<headline>India Colour not to merge with Clariant.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colour-Chem Ltd, a subsidiary of Clariant AG, will not merge with Clariant's other Indian subsidiary Clariant India Ltd in the near future, Colour-Chem chairman B. Hofmann said in the company's 1996/97 annual report.  </p>
<p>&quot;The transfer of Hoechst AG's shareholding of 50.1 percent in Colour-Chem on September 30, 1997, will make it a second subsidiary of Clariant AG in India,&quot; Hofmann told shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;A merger of the two subsidiaries in this country is not in the immediate offing -- on account of a conflict of interest posed by the textile dyes business which Colour-Chem is in the process of exiting,&quot; Hofmann said.</p>
<p>Colour-Chem will, however, benefit in many ways from being associated with the new Clariant organisation, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;From being a relatively small constituent of a multi-product global conglomerate (Hoechst AG), it will become a sizeable player in the new integrated speciality chemicals global set-up, representing a region that is fast gaining recognition for its growth potential,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The change in India follows Hoechst AG's decision last month to combine its speciality chemicals business with Clariant AG, a former subsidiary of Sandoz AG.</p>
<p>The new integrated Clariant AG which came into existence on July 1, 1997, is expected to be the largest speciality chemicals company in the world with a turnover of over 8.5 billion Swiss francs, Hofmann said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25160">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
