<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="782573" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Less goverment debt to reshape Canadian markets.</title>
<headline>Less goverment debt to reshape Canadian markets.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Hodgson</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian debt markets are expected to undergo huge changes in the next few years as the Canadian government stops adding to its stockpile of debt for the first time since the 1970s.</p>
<p>Analysts predict the lack of new borrowing will reduce Canada's reliance on foreign lenders while creating a larger and more dynamic domestic corporate debt market.</p>
<p>Money managers are expected to put more assets in the stock market because there will be fewer government bonds to go around. Corporate profits and the overall economy are seen benefiting from lower real interest rates.</p>
<p>That would be a sharp change from a few years ago, when the Canadian government dominated debt markets by selling more than C$20 billion ($14.4 billion) in new bonds and T-bills yearly.</p>
<p>&quot;It's as if somebody turned the tap off, it's so amazing,&quot; said Doug Porter, economist with brokerage firm Nesbitt Burns. &quot;It's definitely a big long-term positive for the Canadian bond market.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists differ on how to measure when Ottawa will stop adding to its C$470 billion ($338 billion) in marketable debt outstanding, which includes almost C$300 billion ($216 billion) in bonds and C$135 billion ($97 billion) in T-bills.</p>
<p>Nesbitt Burns said last month that Bank of Canada figures showed the total supply of debt began to shrink in May for the first time since the 1970s. Not all economists agree with that measure, but they do agree that Ottawa's marketable debt will stop growing soon, if is has not already.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Paul Martin has predicted the government's financial requirements will be zero next year -- even with its conservative deficit target of C$9 billion ($6.5 billion) for fiscal 1998-99 -- because it could borrow from employee pension funds.</p>
<p>Analysts said that would mean big changes for people who make their living, buying, trading and investing in bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;You take the federal government borrowing out of the picture and you've got some pretty big shoes to fill,&quot; said Jeff Hall, a bond portfolio manager with Investors Group of Winnipeg.</p>
<p>While the Canadian government will continue to auction bonds and T-bills to finance its debt, analysts said it would not be enough to meet growing demand from investors such as insurance companies and pension funds.</p>
<p>In response, the Canadian bond market is expected to change in several ways. One is that Canadian investors will begin repatriating the estimated C$110 billion ($79 billion) in bonds and T-bills held by foreigners.</p>
<p>&quot;There's always going to be a need to have bonds in one's portfolio and as we roll over the existing stock of bonds it's possible that Canadian investors will demand more of it vis-a-vis foreign investors,&quot; said Andrew Pyle, head of fixed-income research with ABN AMRO Bank Canada.</p>
<p>The return of foreign-held bonds is seen as the first major &quot;safety valve&quot; to prevent shortages in the Canadian bond market. The other is a rise in the amount of bonds issued by corporations.</p>
<p>Corporate bonds make up a much smaller portion of the bond market in Canada than in most other industrialised countries, including the United States.</p>
<p>In the past there was so much risk-free Canadian government debt that it was a disincentive for investors to buy corporate bonds. That often discouraged corporations from issuing bonds or sent them to borrow in foreign markets.</p>
<p>The amount of corporate bonds issued in Canada is now expected to go up sharply. Nesbitt's Porter said as much as C$40 billion ($28.8 billion) in new corporate bonds could hit the market in the next 12 months, compared with about C$16 billion ($11.5 billion) in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who are investing in bonds are going to have to wake up to the fact that corporate issuers will become a growing force in our market,&quot; said Investors Group's Hall.</p>
<p>Some analysts predict that within a few years foreign corporations may begin making their way here to issue &quot;beaver bonds&quot; -- foreign bonds sold in Canada denominated in Canadian dollars. The equivalent markets in the United States and Japan are known as &quot;yankee&quot; and &quot;samurai&quot; bonds.</p>
<p>With fewer government bonds to go around, many portfolio managers could also begin placing a greater percentage of their funds in stocks, analysts predict.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
