<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="782511" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U S West Media says Amos Hostetter resigns.</title>
<headline>U S West Media says Amos Hostetter resigns.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U S WEST Media Group said Amos Hostetter Jr resigned as chief executive officer of its MediaOne unit because of irreconcilable differences over the company's decision to move from Boston to Denver, Colo.</p>
<p>A spokesman for MediaOne said he didn't know what Hostetter's plans were.  </p>
<p>U S WEST Media said it named Jan Peters MediaOne chief executive effective October 1.</p>
<p>Peters is U S WEST Media Group president, wireless operations, and managing director of London- based One 2 One.</p>
<p>MediaOne is the U S WEST Media Group's domestic cable operation formerly known as Continental Cablevision, Inc.</p>
<p>Chuck Lillis, Media Group president and chief executive, said Media Group will make several other changes in the senior corporate management of MediaOne and move the subsidiary's corporate headquarters from Boston to the Denver area.</p>
<p>In a press release, Hostetter cited &quot;irreconcilable differences with UMG leadership about the implications for MediaOne's business and its senior management team of UMG's recent decision to relocate MediaOne's headquarters from Boston to Denver.&quot;</p>
<p>The company has been headquartered in Boston since 1968 where it currently employs 160 people.</p>
<p>Hostetter said he expects to make no further comments about his resignation because of restrictions contained in earlier agreements with U S WEST.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
