<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="782617" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar ends mixed after reaching fresh peak versus mark.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends mixed after reaching fresh peak versus mark.</headline>
<byline>Chris Stetkiewicz</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar posted its fourth straight eight-year high against the German mark on Wednesday after fresh signs of German economic weakness, but slipped against the Japanese yen on rising U.S.-Japanese trade tensions.</p>
<p>Germany reported that its jobless rate rose to 11.5 percent in July, higher than expected, which dimmed the prospects for higher German interest rates and fuelled dollar buying, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank has recently encouraged speculation it would raise interest rates if the dollar's strength persisted, but on Tuesday it made a surprisingly large injection of funds into the German money market, signalling it had no intention of raising rates for now, dealers said.</p>
<p>Higher rates tend to strengthen a currency by increasing returns on investments denominated in that currency.</p>
<p>A German government spokesman also said the dollar's rise was driven by impulsive speculation and that Germany saw no reason to change its foreign exchange stance.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is blindly buying dollars. Those German numbers underscore what should be continuing bullish sentiment for the dollar,&quot; said Diego Giurleo, vice president at Royal Bank of Canada.</p>
<p>But the dollar failed to hold its early gains and slipped in U.S. trading, following a pattern seen for the last several sessions.</p>
<p>European investors appear more eager to buy dollars than their American counterparts, many of whom remain fearful that the Bundesbank could intervene in the market to bolster the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe is a bit more bullish on the dollar than the U.S. The odds the market places on central bank intervention go up dramatically with every big rally,&quot; said Richard Vullo, vice president at Bayerische Hypothenken und Weschelbank in New York.</p>
<p>The dollar reached an intraday high of 1.8913 marks, its highest since October 1989, before settling in New York at 1.8820 marks, up from 1.8795 late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Against the yen, the dollar reached an intraday high of 119.58, the strongest since May 12, but ended lower at 118.70 yen from 119.25 yen Tuesday.</p>
<p>The dollar gained in early trade against the yen when Japan's Vice Finance Minister Takeshi Komura told Reuters low Japanese interest rates were helping Japan's economy. But the dollar later slumped when United States Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky told reporters in Washington that U.S. officials were concerned that car exports to Japan had decreased and the trade deficit with Japan in general was deteriorating.</p>
<p>Japan overnight reported its customs-cleared trade surplus rose 126 percent in the first 20 days of July versus the same period a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;That's a very short-term window, but it caused people to express concern and that's why the dollar came off,&quot; said Seth Garrett, chief dealer at Credit Suisse First Boston.</p>
<p>Sterling declined as analysts speculated its recent sharp rally was restricting British exports, which could force the Bank of England to delay an expected interest rate hike.</p>
<p>The British pound fell to $1.6022 from $1.6245.</p>
<p>&quot;People are also saying it will be the last hike for some time and some investors took profits after the sharp rally in sterling recently,&quot; Garrett said.</p>
<p>The dollar fell to 1.5325 Swiss francs from 1.5345, and rose to Canadian $1.3872 from C$1.3802.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
