<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="782756" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK not satisfied Royal Sun meets deadline.</title>
<headline>UK not satisfied Royal Sun meets deadline.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Personal Investment Authority (PIA) said on Wednesday that based on information currently available to it, it was not satisfied that Royal &amp; Sun Alliance had met the first deadline in the pensions review timetable set for it.</p>
<p>The timetable required Royal Sun to complete 90 percent of its priority tranche one cases by July 31.  </p>
<p>The PIA said it was making further enquiries to decide whether it would take further action.</p>
<p>This could include a fine, in an extreme case suspension of business or even expulsion from the PIA, though the latter is unlikely.</p>
<p>The largest fine so far in the context of pension misselling has been 500,000 pounds.</p>
<p>The fine will be designed to reflect the size and severity of the problem, said a PIA spokeswoman.</p>
<p>On May 13 it published individual timetables for the 24 firms who have the most pension transfer and opt-out cases to assess.</p>
<p>Royal Sun was given the earliest deadlines of all the companies though this was set only after very detailed examination of the workload and resources each had.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said the deadline was designed to be &quot;challenging but achievable&quot;.</p>
<p>Priority 1 cases include investors who have died or already retired. It also includes investors aged 35 or more at the time of they opted out and still in the same employment</p>
<p>Britain's top financial watchdog, the Securities and Investments Board, launched the pensions review three years ago after it emerged that the financial services industry may have wrongly advised hundreds of thousands of people to take out personal pensions instead of staying in occupational schemes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
