<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="782712" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Life pushes Comm Union profits ahead.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Life pushes Comm Union profits ahead.</headline>
<byline>Arindam Nag</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong profits in life business and overseas general insurance operations boosted half-year results for British composite insurance group Commercial Union Plc on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The company also said it was on the lookout for further acquisitions in the life sector -- considered to be more lucrative than general insurance -- both in eastern and western Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;The life market will tend to grow more quickly and therefore one would expect to see our life business grow at a faster rate than our general insurance and that applies across the group,&quot; Commercial Union's finance director Peter Foster told Reuters.</p>
<p>But the company ruled out any possibility of a merger. Rumours of a possible merger with either ABN Amro or the insurance business owned by B.A.T Industries Plc, have recently swung back and forth in the market.</p>
<p>&quot;We do believe we have a very strong business and...overall, we do not believe that we need to merge with anybody else. We (also) do not believe that we need to make a major acquisition of that kind,&quot; Foster said.</p>
<p>The group's pre-tax operating profits rose 8.8 percent to 235 million pounds ($381.8 million) from last year's 216 million, reflecting a 25 percent rise at constant exchange rates.</p>
<p>The profit figures exceeded analysts' expectations which was in the range between 209 and 228 million pounds.</p>
<p>The news drove the share price, which has been lagging the competition in recent weeks, to a session high of 704 pence from Tuesday's closing of 689 1/2p.</p>
<p>Commercial Union's chief executive John Carter said the company's exposure to fast developing life and savings markets, particularly in Europe, &quot;is generating substantial growth which will be of increasing value to our shareholders&quot;.</p>
<p>The group announced an interim dividend of 12.25 pence a share, up from 11.45 pence in the previous year.</p>
<p>The dividend will be paid in the form of foreign income dividend, which is expected to reduce the impact of irrecoverable advance corporation tax on the group.</p>
<p>The group's total premium income rose to 4.27 billion pounds ($6.9 billion) from 4.04 billion pounds at constant exchange rates. Its earnings per share edged up to 21.5 pence from 17.2 p.</p>
<p>Life profits rose 24 percent to 125 million pounds on constant exchange rates with new business in this segment rising by 21 percent. Apart from the UK, life business was also strong in the Netherlands, Poland and Italy.</p>
<p>Its general insurance profits rose seven percent to 169 million pounds. The group witnessed a turnaround in the United States, helped by lower weather claims, and also saw profit increases in France and Australia.</p>
<p>With its recent purchase of majority stake in French group Union Financiere de France, the proportion of Commercial Union's life business as part of its total business had risen from 45 to 50 percent.</p>
<p>Commercial Union has started to restructure its UK general insurance business which is expected to produce some 100 million pounds of savings annually by 1999.</p>
<p>The group is also expecting to tighten its belt in France where life business has been sluggish due to political and economic uncertainties.</p>
<p>The group expects its French business to move forward strongly after 1998 following its reorganisation of sales force there.</p>
<p>($ = 0.615 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
