<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78294" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: COFFEE - Brazil state fights back with new tax.</title>
<headline>COFFEE - Brazil state fights back with new tax.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Bulloch</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian traders' predictions individual states would retaliate against the recent scrapping of the ICMS export tax proved correct this week when Espirito Santo announced an alternative internal tax.</p>
<p>The state's official diary yesterday published a new rule that all primary goods moved within the state would be subject to a 17 percent tax, effective immediately, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is absurd,&quot; said Jair Coser, president of leading exporter Unicafe and one of the state's producers.  </p>
<p>&quot;What is the point of removing an export tax when now coffee should arrive at the port already taxed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The new tax applies to all coffee being taken out of producers' hands and so would affect coffee for export.</p>
<p>Representatives from the Coffee Business Center in Vitoria have already had a meeting with state government officials today which seemed to have lead to a partial solution, Coser said.</p>
<p>At the meeting, government representatives agreed coffee transported within the state in the name of a co-operative or producer should be exempt from the tax, Coser said.  </p>
<p>This should mean coffee being taken to the ports for export should escape paying the extra duty, he added.</p>
<p>However the meeting failed to resolve the question of coffee in warehouses at the port of Vitoria since prior to the lifting of the ICMS export tax in mid-September which, under the new ruling, should also be subject to the 17 percent duty.</p>
<p>Traders do not believe that the state recommendations will last for long, but that political pressure from elsewhere in the country will prove too great.  </p>
<p>&quot;If not, then you will just see the Espirito Santo crop supposedly drop by two million bags next year while that of Minas Gerais will grow by the same amount as people move the coffee quietly next door,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>But the subject will be discussed tomorrow at a meeting of members of the Brazilian Coffee Exporters Association (Abecafe)and its lawyers, said Abecafe president Jorge Esteve.</p>
<p>Vitoria is Brazil's second largest coffee-exporting port, with shipments totalling 1.52 million bags between January and July this year, 31.25 percent of the national total, according to statistics from the Brazilian Coffee Exporters Federation.  </p>
<p>The benefits of the lifting of the tax totally in other states are being split amongst producers, exports and buyers, traders said.</p>
<p>The market has been reasonably quiet however, with expectations still of lower shipments in September than in August when the country exported 1.54 million 60-kg bags.</p>
<p>According to the September 26 report from the Rio Coffee Business Center, shipments based on bills of lading were 664,234 bags by September 24 but 1.05 million bags based on certificates of origin.  </p>
<p>On the export market, prices were little changed, with Santos brokers Wolthers &amp; Associates quoting speciality 17/18s coffees at 13 over New York for October shipment and fine 17/18s were three under, both the same as last week, while Swedish qualities had slipped to 11 under from last week's nine under.</p>
<p>In the domestic market, Santos brokers Escritorio Carvalhaes on September 26 quoted fine-to-extrafine Mogiana/Minas green beans at 118/119 reais per 60 kg against the 118/120 reais quoted on September 19.</p>
<p>-- Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
