<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="782908" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait regulator sees no need to amend loan curbs.</title>
<headline>Kuwait regulator sees no need to amend loan curbs.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwait's central bank governor said that there was no need now to amend curbs it had imposed on lending for equity trading.</p>
<p>&quot;Data submitted by banks did not reveal (anything that) would call for considering amending, changing or easing the directives in the current stage,&quot; Sheikh Salem Abdul-Aziz al-Sabah told al-Rai al-Aam newspaper.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;I would like to point out that the Central Bank of Kuwait constantly reviews all the directives it issues.&quot;</p>
<p>In May the central bank ordered local banks to stop extending margin loans and to diversify guarantees required against lending for equity trading.</p>
<p>Loans extended by local banks for equity trading at the time the directives were issued stood at about 422 million dinars ($1.383 million), of which 93 million were margin loans. The figure needs to be reduced by about 130 million by the end of 1997, the bank has said.</p>
<p>Sheikh Salem said there was no link between the curbs and a decline in trade on the Kuwait Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Dealers say the psychological impact of the curbs have led to hesitancy among some traders on investing large amounts of money, but economists have said the market had overreacted to the curbs whose actual impact was small.</p>
<p>The daily average of the value of traded shares in the last week of July amounted to 18.96 million dinars compared to the peak of 125.8 million dinars registered in April 28.</p>
<p>Asked about a possible involvement of non-Kuwaiti Gulf banks in loan extension to finance domestic equity trading activities, Sheikh Salem said: &quot;That matter is up to those banks to assess. They take their credit decisions ... and they shoulder the risk.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
