<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783089" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Aug 6.</title>
<headline>Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Aug 6.</headline>
<text>
<p>--------------GAM--------------------</p>
<p>REUTERS GERMAN ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST</p>
<p>-----------August 6, 1997-----------------</p>
<p>News from Reuters and the German press on Advertising, Marketing, Media, the Internet, Brand-name Products and Consumer Trends</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>MUNICH - Television group ProSieben Media AG says the future of television advertising lies in a mixture of new technology and traditional commercials. &quot;Advertising in the year 2000 will be a combination of mass ads on television, information offers on teletext and fully interactive options on online media,&quot; ProSieben board member and marketing director Michael Woelfle says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>DUESSELDORF - The anti-consumer Generation X, now adults in their 20s and 30s, has given way to a hedonistic class of 1990s teenagers in Germany, according to a new study. &quot;Teenagers today are no longer rebels,&quot; the German unit of advertising group Grey says. &quot;The main thing they want is to somehow have some fun.&quot; (Reuter)</p>
<p>**********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>MAINZ - Germany manages to avoid becoming the first advanced country to impose a tax on PCs connected to the Internet. After threatening to hit Internet PCs with the same fee now charged for owning a television, representatives of German state governments bow to pressure and say they will not impose the tax. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - Industrial group Siemens AG plans to spend at least 500 million marks ($266.3 million) to revamp internal communications and expand its use of the Internet. The company says it aims to boost productivity by wiring the company worldwide for email, video conferencing and other forms of electronic communications. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - Phone giant Deutsche Telekom AG says it ordered tens of thousands of Intel Corp. video conferencing systems for resale to customers in Germany. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MUNICH - Swiss media company Ringier says it plans to start a mass-market finance magazine in partnership with the ZDF television programme WiSo. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Food company Nestle says it is considering expanding product distribution by mail and over the Internet. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>MUNICH - Adidas AG says second quarter net income rose 20 percent to 69 million marks behind a 37 percent rise in net sales to 1.427 billion marks, particularly in North America where it has begun reaping the benefits of an aggressive advertising campaign. Apparel remained the major growth driver for the brand in the first six months of 1997. Footwear, helped the most by running shoes, rose 29 percent and outperformed the market.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>DRESDEN - Germany's accelerating economic recovery could be killed off if doubts about the stability of the planned European single currency force the Bundesbank to raise interest rates, a leading research institute says. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>MUNICH - Carmaker BMW AG hopes to deliver about 110,000 vehicles to customers in the United States during 1997, up from 105,800 in 1996. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - Pan-German industrial orders rose 1.5 percent in June although eastern Germany continued to show weakness, the Economics Ministry says. West German orders, showing increases across all manufacturing sectors, rose 1.7 percent, offsetting a 3.2 percent decline in orders in the former communist east. (Reuter)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>NUREMBERG - German unemployment rose to a seasonally adjusted 4.396 million in July, the Federal Labour Office says. The unemployment rate, which is based on unadjusted data, rose to 11.4 percent, compared with 11.0 percent in June. The number of unemployed workers rose by 17,000 from 4.374 million in June. (Reuter)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>PEOPLE NEWS:</p>
<p>METZINGEN - Werner Lackas will join the board of fashion group Hugo Boss AG on October 1, the company says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Andy Green will leave Nissan Motor in Germany at the end of August. He is one of the three chief executives at the German unit. (Horizont)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>Deborah Cole, Berlin Newsroom, 49-30-203-98114</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>For further information and news, see Reuters Advertising &amp;</p>
<p>Media Briefing. And visit us on the Internet: http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com ***********************************************</p>
<p>($ = 1.877 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
