<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78311" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine bonds rise, gains tempered by strike.</title>
<headline>Argentine bonds rise, gains tempered by strike.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine bonds rose Thursday on uplifting news from the Senate and the announcement of another privatization, but price rises were tempered by a 36-hour general strike protesting the government's economic policies.</p>
<p>The government announced it will sell 92 percent of state mortgage bank Banco Hipotecario for up to $3.0 billion. The first portion of the shares, between 20 and 30 percent, will be offered to the public in mid-1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The announcement was helpful to the market,&quot; said a trader at a foreign bank. &quot;The political effort is there.&quot;  </p>
<p>The dollar-denominated Bocon Previsional 2 due 2001 rose $0.10 to 118.60, while Argentina's FRB due 2005 rose 1/8 to 84-1/8.</p>
<p>The passage by the Senate late Wednesday into law of the government's package of tax hikes lent plenty of support, not least because at the end of the day the measures actually came into law much more quickly than expected. The tax hikes are expected to generate $1.6 billion in revenues.  </p>
<p>The bill authorized the government to issue another $4.0 billion of debt through the year, something which could speed up anticipated bond sales and facilitate a hoped-for buyback of older debt.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate the prospects for bonds are decent, and together with the possible buyback the prospects for investors are good,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>Strong performance by other Latin American markets and U.S. Treasuries helped Argentine debt as well Thursday.  </p>
<p>For all that, the 36-hour general strike that started at noon Thursday reminded players of the popular opposition to the government's economic policies. Next year's mid-term Congressional elections could reflect that discontent.</p>
<p>The strike kept market activity low, but there were still flows in the market, said traders. Friday's session could be In the money markets, call money rates rose to 5.95 percent from 5.50 percent.</p>
<p>-- Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 3180668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
