<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783160" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France welcomes OAU step to end Comoros protests.</title>
<headline>France welcomes OAU step to end Comoros protests.</headline>
<byline>Francois Raitberger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>France on Wednesday welcomed with relief a decision by the Organisation of African Unity to mediate talks between the government of Comoros and secessionists demanding a return to French rule.</p>
<p>As secessionist protests spread to a second island on the former French Indian Ocean archipelago colony, French Foreign Ministry spokesman Yves Doutriaux said the OAU's decision, which Paris had called for, testified to the continent's growing desire to head off conflicts through diplomacy.</p>
<p>&quot;We rejoice that the OAU has decided to appoint a special envoy to the Comoros, as Comorian authorities had called for, in order to help this country find a lasting solution to the crisis born from the situation on the island of Anjouan, &quot; he said.</p>
<p>The OAU has appealed for calm in the Comoros and said it would send a special envoy mandated to talk to both the government and the secessionists. Protests have spread from the island of Anjouan to the island of Moheli.</p>
<p>The protests, challenging the OAU-backed principle that borders from the colonial era must remain unchanged, have embarrassed France at a time when it is taking a lower profile in its former colonies.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Alain Richard said this week France would reduce its troops in Africa by at least a quarter from 8,100 and would end any military intervention in its former colonies.</p>
<p>Paris has carefully avoided encouraging the secessionists, saying the protests were an internal dispute fuelled by poverty and insisting it supported the Comoros' territorial integrity.</p>
<p>Doutriaux told a news briefing that France's envoy to the archipelago capital Moroni would meet the OAU envoy.</p>
<p>He noted France was the main aid donor to the Comoros, and wanted its 100 million-franc ($16.5 million) annual aid package to benefit the archipelago's 190,000 residents equally.</p>
<p>He evaded questions on whether France may step up its aid, saying talks between secessionists and the government of the Islamic republic must come first.</p>
<p>Secessionists say that the main island of Grande Comore has been favoured over other islands, and independence has brought only poverty to the island group, in contrast with the relative prosperity of Mayotte, the archipelago's only island which voted to remain French in a 1975 referendum on independence.</p>
<p>The French navy vessel La Boudeuse has started patrolling international waters off the Comoros amid reports that French authorities feared an influx of boat people to Mayotte.</p>
<p>Doutriaux said the ship was on a routine mission, and any boat people would be dealt with under French laws governing illegal immigration to the mainland and its overseas territories.</p>
<p>The Paris daily Liberation said the demonstrations for a return to French rule showed a twin failure of both a colony's independence without democracy or sound economic management, and of France's attempts to continue pulling the strings in its former African empire.</p>
<p>&quot;The utopian belief that you can cut the umbilical cord only half-way has failed,&quot; it said. France's problem was how to respond to the secessionists' longing to escape poverty, and how to retain influence while taking a lower profile.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
