<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783377" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks close on strong note.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks close on strong note.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>------------------(Snapshot 4.20 p.m. (0620 GMT)--------------</p>
<p>AORD		 2727.1  +19.50   DJIA cl	8187.54   -10.91</p>
<p>SPI futures	2744.0   +19.0   US 30yr cl	6.49    +0.01</p>
<p>10yrbond futs    93.495  -0.055   Gold NY 320.45 Lon fix 321.10</p>
<p>AUD     $0.7354 (Tues: $0.7395)   CRB Index cl  243.60    -1.66</p>
<p>NIKKEI	   19702.07 +187.62   FTSE cl	 4960.6    +64.9</p>
<p>S&amp;P500(Globex)   955.50   -1.00   NZSE40 cl    2532.71   -11.20</p>
<p>--------------------------(Aug 6)------------------------------</p>
<p>*Stocks end at day's high boosted by a strong start to the corporate reports season. Volume 391.39 million, value A$752.01 million, 1,156 stocks traded, 350 steady, 441 up, 365 down.</p>
<p>The Australian stock market closed after steady gains throughout Wednesday to end at its intra-day high, helped by the strong start to the corporate reporting season and renewed buying in resource stocks.</p>
<p>By 4.20 p.m. (0620 GMT), the All Ordinaries index was up 19.5 points at 2,727.1 with trade valued at over A$750 million.</p>
<p>September share price index futures were 19 points higher at 2,742, a 14.9 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>The rise wiped out losses made earlier this week and brings the All Ordinaries index back to the same level it was at the end of last week.  </p>
<p>&quot;I suppose with the early part of the reporting season you get the good reports,&quot; said Richard Nelson, a fund manager at BNP Investment Management.</p>
<p>Nelson said the good results from Wesfarmers and Pacific BBA on Tuesday and Henry Walker on Wednesday underpinned confidence in the local market.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly in the early stages results have been on par and above market expectations, but the well run companies tend to report early,&quot; Nelson said.</p>
<p>Brokers were still digesting the Coca-Cola Amatil first half result, which was released after the market close.  </p>
<p>C-C Amatil reported a net profit of A$58.1 million for the six months to June 30, slightly below market expectations, but up on the A$57.8 million result a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a bit disappointing, we were expecting something a bit higher,&quot; said one Sydney-based broker. &quot;They had a good run today, but they may come under a bit of pressure tomorrow,&quot; he said. C-C Amatil shares ended 35.1 cents up at A$16.43.</p>
<p>Brokers said there was also a lot of interest in Brambles ahead of the results from GKN Plc, its partner in the Chep pallets business.  </p>
<p>Global mining giant Rio Tinto posted good gains, up 32 cents to A$20.80 after firming in London trading on Tuesday, but brokers said investors were taking advantage of the recent price falls in the stock.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, nickel producer QNI retraced some earlier losses, but still ended the day four cents lower at A$2.36 following Tuesday's revamped Gencor merger plan. In other local markets, Australian bonds ended in negative territory after an uninspired day dominated by softer U.S. bonds. The market is waiting on Thursday's key labour market data.  </p>
<p>*C-C Amatil A$16.43 (+.35) 16.095/16.50 Vol: 980,881 Shares ended strong, but first result after market close was slightly below expectations. *Brambles A$27.98 (+.98) 27.59/28.05 Vol: 520,267 Strongest blue-chip gainer on big interest ahead of the results from GKN Plc, its partner in U.S. Chep pallets *Rio Tinto A$20.80 (+.32) 20.55/20.80 Vol: 609,409 Strong London trade boost global miner in local trade. *QNI A$2.36 (-.04) 2.20/2.397 Vol: 6,029,484 Gencor merger deal proves hard for market to digest. *Wesfarmers A$12.80 (+.20) 12.67/13.00 Vol: 241,851  </p>
<p>Tuesday's strong full-year profit pushes group higher. *BHP A$17.99 (+.12) 17.895/18.06 Vol: 2,575,525 *Nat Aust A$19.56 (+.12) 19.42/19.59 Vol: 2,910,449 *News A$6.10 (+.05) 6.044/6.12 Vol: 4,070,123 Leaders make light gains in trader's market.</p>
<p>-- Kevin Morrison 61-2 9373-1813</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
