<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783374" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</title>
<headline>Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>THREDBO DEATH TOLL STANDS AT 12</p>
<p>The Thredbo landslide death toll has risen to 12 with two more bodies pulled from the rubble last night.</p>
<p>The two male bodies were found as rescue coordinators moved into what they are calling the most dangerous section of the recovery operation, with heavy concrete slabs slowly being removed.</p>
<p>Eight men and four women are among the victims so far accounted for, and six people are still missing.</p>
<p>There has been one survivor of the landslide which caused the collapse of two ski lodges in the New South Wales resort town last Wednesday night.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, rescue workers have been stringing chain mesh across dirt slopes on the site to prevent further landslides when forecast rain hits Thredbo later today.</p>
<p>Police spokeswoman Stephanie Ryan said every effort is being made to prepare for the storm front.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THREE TO FACE COURT OVER DEATH OF BASE JUMPER</p>
<p>Three men will face court later this month, after the death of a man in a base jumping accident at Bungonia Gorge near Goulburn in New South Wales.</p>
<p>Police rescue teams yesterday recovered the body of a man, after his parachute failed to open while base jumping on Monday. It is believed he died instantly but it took rescue personnel more than 20-hours to retrieve his body.</p>
<p>His companions have been charged with engaging in an unsafe act, in contravention of National Parks and Wildlife Service regulations.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FEDERAL GOVERNMENT DOESN'T WANT PEOPLE PAYING MORE TAX</p>
<p>The Federal Government says it does not want people paying more tax if it takes over collection of state tobacco, alcohol and petrol taxes.</p>
<p>The High Court has ruled the State taxes constitutionally invalid.</p>
<p>If all states request the action, the Commonwealth will plug the $5 billion hole in state coffers left by the High Court ruling.</p>
<p>But it will have to levy the taxes at a uniform national rate then pass the revenue back to the states.</p>
<p>That will mean states which had lower rates than the uniform rate will get extra money.</p>
<p>But the Treasurer, Peter Costello, who has acknowledged the solution is complicated, wants the states to pass the excess revenue onto wholesalers.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FORMER PM GOES ONLINE DISCUSSING TRADE AND TECHNOLOGY</p>
<p>Former Prime Minister Paul Keating believes trade and technology policy is as important as defence policy, in ensuring Australia's national survival.</p>
<p>Mr Keating spoke at a company dinner in Sydney last night.</p>
<p>In a rare public appearance, he said Australia must develop its ability to provide information services if it is to continue to grow as a power.</p>
<p>He said improvements in Australian Information Technology potential will also benefit the country internally.</p>
<p>Responding to a question later, Mr Keating said I-T is important in producing jobs, but the only real way to ensure lower levels of unemployment is through all government policy being targeted at increasing levels of economic growth.</p>
<p>Only a few days after the current prime minister, John Howard, launched his Internet site, Mr Keating revealed his own web page last night.</p>
<p>A copy of his speech at the company dinner will be able to be accessed at the site later this morning.</p>
<p>The Keating site can be reached at:  www.keating.org.au</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
