<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783347" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT - Bunds eye downside to 101.42/43.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Bunds eye downside to 101.42/43.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>September Bund futures traded on LIFFE will ignore oversold indicators and continue to probe the downside towards 101.42/43, technical analysts said Wednesday.</p>
<p>That level was the 50 percent retracement of the rally from a low of 99.32 on May 5 to the contract high of 103.52 set on July 23.</p>
<p>&quot;Although it's oversold, there is still downside potential,&quot; said a broker at a European bank in London. &quot;I'd ideally like to see it hold the 50 percent retracement if it's going to bounce.&quot;</p>
<p>September Bund futures were down eight basis points at 101.63 by 0705 GMT.  </p>
<p>The 101.42/43 level was also reinforced by two daily lows at 101.43 set on June 30 and July 1.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite a strong level,&quot; the broker said. &quot;It's got a good chance of holding.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there had been initial support from congestion around the 101.59/60 level, but that was wiped out in early trade. The next support before the main level was the psychological 101.50.</p>
<p>David Sneddon, technical analyst at Credit Suisse First Boston in London said he pegged support in a band from 101.48 down to 101.42.  </p>
<p>&quot;Not only is the 50 percent retracement in there, but also the 38.2 percent of the move from the 98.19 low in April to the contract high,&quot; he said. &quot;There's also a late June reaction low and a (support) line on the weekly continuation chart.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Bunds were likely to hold that level, as they had already exceeded the measured target of 101.74 from the top put in place last week.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd buy on dips unless it breaks below 101.38, which will mean that band has been broken,&quot; said Sneddon.</p>
<p>A break of 101.38 would target 101.18, he said.</p>
<p>On the upside, resistance was at the 101.85 reaction high.  </p>
<p>Above there, the broker at the European bank said the 102.02 level, which had been a strong support on the way down, would now act as heavy resistance.</p>
<p>The next target would be 102.63, the July 25 low formed between the peaks of the double top.</p>
<p>At the short end, December Euromarks were down one basis point at 96.39.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
