<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783441" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: QNI down again after Gencor merger revamp.</title>
<headline>QNI down again after Gencor merger revamp.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in nickel producer QNI Ltd fell another 11 cents or 4.5 percent to A$2.29 in active Wednesday morning trade on continued scepticism about its revised plan to merge with Gencor Ltd's Billiton Nickel.  </p>
<p>QNI's shares had already fallen 10 cents to A$2.40 on Tuesday after it sweetened the deal to overcome institutional shareholder opposition to the original deal which they said favoured Gencor rather than Australian shareholders.</p>
<p>QNI announced revised terms for the merger, reducing the number of shares to be issued to Billiton Nickel to 455.802 million shares (52.5 percent of the enlarged QNI) from 504.03 million (55 percent) and raising a planned capital return to 30 cents a share from 28 cents.  </p>
<p>Analysts and some brokers said late on Tuesday they remained sceptical, but that the deal was likely to be approved at the necessary meeting in September because there were few alternatives.</p>
<p>QNI itself said it was confident institutional shareholders were warming to the new deal.</p>
<p>Brokers said however late on Wednesday morning the mood continued to remain sour.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a little bit sweeter, but the market still sees through it,&quot; said one Brisbane broker.  </p>
<p>&quot;People are still not impressed,&quot; another Brisbane broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a tinkering, rather then a major upgrade,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
