<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783473" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Headlines - Aug 6.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Headlines - Aug 6.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Hong Kong press. Reuter has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- HONGKONG STANDARD -- Top-level sources said that Chief Executive Tung Chee-hwa was considering sweeping structural reforms aimed at streamlining the three-tier colonial system of governance by abolishing the Urban and Regional councils.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- Local tycoon Li Ka-shing's dramatic move into the British hong Jardines group was seen as an opening salvo in what could be a protracted battle for control of one of the last remaining British hongs.</p>
<p>-- The Hong Kong Monetary Authority was to raise the exposure of the $569 billion exchange fund to the world's stock markets, by diversifying into European equities in an attempt to boost returns.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO -- According to sources, a major reshuffle would take place among Shanghai's top leadership before the 15th Communist Party Congress. The city's Party chief Huang Ju would be transfered to Beijing. He would be replaced by the present mayor Xu Kuangdi. The Governor of the People's Bank of China Dai Xianglong was one of the candidates for the post of the mayor.</p>
<p>-- SING TAO -- U.S. sources said that Chief Executive Tung Chee-hwa planned to visit the U.S. in November in a bid to convince influential political and business figures that Hong Kong had been stable since the handover and that it had a better economic prospects now.</p>
<p>-- ECONOMIC TIMES -- The Beijing municipal government's window company in Hong Kong, Beijing Enterprises, was planning massive acquisition projects, involving HK$4 billion, within the year.</p>
<p>-- TA KUNG PAO -- The People's Liberation Army's Hong Kong garrison has established two checkpoints at the Shenzhen border, to check PLA's staff and vehicles crossing the border.</p>
<p>-- The Foreign Ministry's Hong Kong commissioner Ma Yuzhen said that the Special Administrative Region government had achieved a lot since the handover.</p>
<p>-- EXPRESS NEWS -- The Guangdong police were actively cracking down on crimes conducted by foreigners. A police official said that in recent years, an increasing number of foreigners had been involved in crimes including murder, robbery, drug trafficking and swindling in China.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
