<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783520" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shenzhen B shares end down on A share losses.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen B shares end down on A share losses.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's hard currency B share index closed down on Wednesday, dragged lower by weakness on the domestic A share market, analysts said.</p>
<p>The B share index lost 1.49 points or 1.13 percent to 129.96 on turnover of HK$46 million against HK$34 million on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The A share index shed 9.71 points or 2.35 percent to 403.52 on turnover of 4.0 billion yuan against 4.1 billion yuan in the previous session.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall in B shares were mainly fuelled by the weakness of A shares,&quot; an analyst at China Guotai Securities said, adding that steep falls in B shares were unlikely in the near future.  </p>
<p>&quot;Prices of B shares are already low,&quot; an analyst at Everbright Securities said. &quot;The downside should be limited.&quot;</p>
<p>The A share drop was due in part to losses in market leader Shenzhen Development Bank, analysts said.</p>
<p>The stock fell 0.45 yuan to 33.65 yuan on volume of 2.4 million shares. The bank has performed poorly since last month when it forecast slower than expected eannings growth for 1997.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Special Economic Zone Real Estate &amp; Properties (Group) Co Ltd was the biggest B share loser, sliding HK$0.18 or 6.84 percent to HK$2.45 on solid volume 106,800 of shares.</p>
<p>Brokers have said they expected the company, which is mainly involved in the development of office buildings, to report poor 1997 interim results because the Shenzhen commercial property market remained depressed.  </p>
<p>Bengang Steel Plates reversed its recent upward trend with a loss of HK$0.03 to HK$2.09 on Wednesday. Volume hit 2.1 million shares, placing it at the top of the day's most active list.</p>
<p>The issue has traded below its offer price of HK$2.38 since its debut in early July.</p>
<p>Television tube maker Shenzhen SEG was the second most actively traded issue, gaining HK$0.24 to HK$5.94 on volume of 1.8 million shares. Brokers said institutional bargain hunting had pushed up the share this week.</p>
<p>&quot;I think some foreign institutions have been buying our company shares recently,&quot; a SEG official said. He declined to comment further.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
