<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783585" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan ready to play leading role in Thai package.</title>
<headline>Japan ready to play leading role in Thai package.</headline>
<byline>George Nishiyama</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan, anxious to justify its position as Asia's top economy, is ready to play a leading role alongside the International Monetary Fund in a rescue package for Thailand, Finance Ministry officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A senior ministry official said Tokyo's contribution to the package would be by far the most given by an individual country and would likely amount to a little under half the total amount provided the IMF and mostly Asian countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the magnitude of relations between Japan and Thailand, it is natural for Japan to extend the largest amount of financial help to the country,&quot; the official told a news conference.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka said in a statement that Japan had received a request from the IMF to extend support to Thailand and Tokyo &quot;strongly supports such moves&quot;.</p>
<p>The senior ministry official declined to say exactly how much Tokyo's contribution would be, but another official said: &quot;Chances are high that Japan's contribution will equal that of the IMF.&quot;</p>
<p>Ministry officials said the total amount of the whole financial package would not be far off the $12 billion to $15 billion in loans Thailand is seeking.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Thailand, in deep recession as a result of the collapse of a real estate and asset &quot;bubble&quot;, announced a series of economic reform measures and said it was seeking the loans from foreign countries and the IMF to stabilise its economy.</p>
<p>The measures included the suspension of more than half of its finance companies, a three percentage point rise in value-added tax, and strict monetary and fiscal targets for the next few years.</p>
<p>Japanese officials have said the Asian Development Bank (ADB) and members of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) were likely to take part in the rescue effort, but that the bulk of financial support would come from the IMF and Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;Any participation (by ADB and ASEAN nations) would be limited. What's important is that they're taking part, not the amount. Their contribution would be meagre,&quot; said another ministry official.</p>
<p>Japanese officials said Tokyo's contribution would be almost totally in the form of untied loans through the government-run Export-Import Bank of Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;Japanese support will focus on helping Thailand carry out structural reform of its economy. Taking that into account, many of the measures will likely be through the Ex-Im Bank,&quot; said the second official, adding that most of the loans would be over a period of about three years.</p>
<p>In addition to the government support, private Japanese banks are expected to provide several billion dollars more given their heavy loan exposure in Thailand and the hefty direct investment by Japanese firms.</p>
<p>Thailand has nearly $90 billion in foreign currency debt, and Japanese bankers estimate about $36 billion of that is owed to Japanese banks.</p>
<p>The senior Finance Ministry official said the amount of support from the Japanese government would be decided when details of the international package became concrete as a result of negotiations between the Thai government and the IMF.</p>
<p>IMF Managing Director Michel Camdessus said on Tuesday that an IMF team was in Thailand to work with Bangkok to see how the government's reform plan could be developed into &quot;a multiyear adjustment programme that could be supported by IMF resources&quot;.</p>
<p>He added that he expected such a programme to be presented to the IMF executive board for approval shortly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
