<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783648" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodian rebels blast new prime minister move.</title>
<headline>Cambodian rebels blast new prime minister move.</headline>
<byline>Robert Birsel</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodia's Khmer Rouge guerrilla group said on Wednesday Prince Norodom Ranariddh was still the country's legal first prime minister and a move to approve a new premier was a political game.</p>
<p>The Cambodian National Assembly was due to vote on the nomination of Foreign Minister Ung Huot as first prime minister later on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a complete violation of the constitution,&quot; the guerrillas' clandestine radio said in a broadcast monitored in Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>&quot;The appointment of Ung Huot as first prime minister will destroy the result of the 1993 election organised by the United Nations,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>Ung Huot has been nominated by members of Ranariddh's FUNCINPEC party remaining in the country to replace the prince as co-premier. Second Prime Minister Hun Sen, who ousted the prince on July 6, backs Ung Huot's nomination.</p>
<p>Assembly officials said on Tuesday that a vote by secret ballot on Ung Huot's nomination will be preceded by a show of hands on suspending the prince's parliamentary immunity in order to clear the way for his prosecution for alleged crimes.</p>
<p>But political analysts said there were articles in the constitution making it difficult to push through Ung Huot's selection as first prime minister fully in accordance with the charter.</p>
<p>King Norodom Sihanouk said late last month he would not recognise Ung Huot as first premier as the post belonged to Ranariddh. The king also said that a vote on a new first prime minister by an incomplete parliament would be invalid.</p>
<p>The rebel radio broadcast, issued in the name of Khmer Rouge political leader Khieu Samphan's new party, said Ung Huot's nomination was not supported by the king and had been widely criticised. It would also destroy international efforts to bring stability to Cambodia, the radio said.</p>
<p>&quot;This political game has been strongly criticised by both Cambodians and foreigners,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>&quot;The appointment of Ung Huot as first prime minister is to destroy all the efforts of ASEAN (the Association of South East Asian Nations) and the international community to solve the Cambodian problem,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>The radio said Khieu Samphan's National Solidarity Party would not recognise &quot;the traitor&quot; Ung Huot as prime minister and would continue to recognise Ranariddh.</p>
<p>Khmer Rouge guerrillas, who purged their notorious leader Pol Pot late last month, have repeatedly criticised Hun Sen for ousting Ranariddh.</p>
<p>The rebels have labelled Hun Sen a puppet of Vietnam and have called for united opposition to his rule, while Hun Sen has warned of military action against the rebels in their Anlong Veng base in the remote north of the country.</p>
<p>The rebels boycotted a 1993 election organised by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Ranariddh won the election but agreed to a power-sharing coalition with Hun Sen after he objected to the result and the country faced division along factional lines.</p>
<p>More than a million Cambodians died during Pol Pot's 1975-79 &quot;killing fields&quot; rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
