<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783800" id="root" date="1997-08-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Iraq moves closer to sell oil with new price plan.</title>
<headline>Iraq moves closer to sell oil with new price plan.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Connole</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-08-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq on Tuesday submitted its pricing plan for new oil sales under a U.N. oil-for-food programme after reducing some rates at the suggestion of U.N. oil experts, according to diplomats and industry sources.</p>
<p>The oil pricing formula moves Iraq closer to resuming sales under a plan that allows Baghdad to sell $2 billion worth of oil every six months to buy food, medicine and other goods. The programme is aimed at easing the effects of U.N. trade sanctions imposed seven years ago.</p>
<p>The next step, U.N. spokesman Hiro Ueki said, was for experts or overseers appointed by the United Nations to determine if the plan meets industry standards and then submit it to the Security Council's sanctions committee.</p>
<p>The committee, made up of all 15 Council members, is expected to receive the pricing formula on Wednesday, after which it has 48 hours, the equivalent of two working days, to raise any objections, Ueki said.</p>
<p>The United Nations did not reveal the prices.</p>
<p>But industry and diplomatic sources said Iraq reduced prices for Basrah Light and Kirkuk crude oil after objections from the U.N. overseers who conferred by telephone with officials from the Iraq State Oil and Marketing Organisation (SOMO) before Baghdad submitted the formula in writing.</p>
<p>Under the new rates, Basrah Light to the United States is priced at $4.50 under West Texas Intermediate for August on an FOB basis. Kirkuk to Europe is at Dated Brent -$1.90, and at WTI -$3.50 for the United States.</p>
<p>Asian customers received a price for Basrah Light at an average of Oman/Dubai -55 cents, the sources said, also on an FOB basis for August.</p>
<p>SOMO had first proposed a price of $4.40 per barrel under regional benchmark WTI for U.S. buyers of its Basrah Light, according to traders with oil companies that had contracts with Iraq earlier in the year.</p>
<p>That was up from a discount of $4.60 in May, when crude was last lifted from Mina al Bakr in the Middle East Gulf, and in line with the 20 cents rise in Saudi Arabian Light crude.</p>
<p>Oil traders said Iraq's original pricing formula was too high, given a recent rise in freight costs and the difficulty in marketing a large amount of Iraqi crude quickly.</p>
<p>Iraq had delayed in submitting the pricing formula until U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan approved Baghdad's programme to distribute the humanitarian goods. He did so on Monday and Iraq now has to sell $1 billion in oil by Sept. 5.</p>
<p>The oil-for-food plan first went into effect last December and was renewed for another six months on June 8, with oil sales divided into two 90-day or three month periods.</p>
<p>The programme is an exception to the sanctions imposed on Iraq after its troops invaded Kuwait in August 1990.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
