<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783834" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada's provincial premiers start annual meeting.</title>
<headline>Canada's provincial premiers start annual meeting.</headline>
<byline>Allan Dowd</byline>
<dateline>ST. ANDREWS, New Brunswick 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's premiers opened their annual meeting on Thursday with a less than graceful dance around the issue of national unity -- a subject they had promised themselves not to talk about.</p>
<p>The premiers headed straight into private meetings to discuss issues ranging from trade to rebalancing federal-provincial social programs, but acknowledged the issue of Quebec's future within Canada hovered over the entire meeting.</p>
<p>Host Premier Frank McKenna sought to downplay a political spat that erupted Wednesday with pro-separatist Quebec Premier Lucien Bouchard over a letter of support McKenna wrote to an anti-separatist group in the French-speaking province.</p>
<p>&quot;Every (premiers') conference I've come to we have an opening ritualistic tossing of the grenade, and everything gets interesting and then we sit down, roll up our sleeves and we do business,&quot; McKenna told reporters.</p>
<p>The meeting in this southern New Brunswick seaside resort was the 38th annual gathering for the provincial and territorial leaders -- their first since the Canadian federal election in June.</p>
<p>The formal agenda for gathering reflected Bouchard's demand that the premiers not discuss unity during their meetings. But several of the leaders aknowledged they were still not happy with that decision.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't intend to take a position where you can't talk about it because Premier Bouchard is here and you can't talk about it because he is not here,&quot; said Saskatchewan Premier Roy Romanov.</p>
<p>Nova Scotia Premier Russell MacLellan warned that formally talking about during the meetings would &quot;break faith&quot; with Bouchard and would not &quot;speak well for our intention to develop a consensus with Quebec.&quot;</p>
<p>Regional differences also flared over a proposal by the premiers of Ontario and Alberta for more provincial control over federal social programs. The poorer provinces of the Atlantic region have expressed concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;Well I think that we all have our interests as premiers of respective promises but I think there's a general concern that a reduction (of federal involvement) would be extremely harmful,&quot; MacLellan said.</p>
<p>Richer provinces like Alberta and Ontario are advocating more provincial control over critical national programs like health care and contend that a devolution of power could also slow Quebec's independence drive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. ANDREWS, New Brunswick"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
