<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="783924" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TABLE - Kerr Group Q2 shr loss widens.</title>
<headline>TABLE - Kerr Group Q2 shr loss widens.</headline>
<dateline>LANCASTER, Pa 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>KERR GROUP, INC.</p>
<p>		     Statements of Earnings (Loss) for the</p>
<p>Three Months and Six Months Ended June 30, 1997 and 1996</p>
<p>				     (In Thousands)</p>
<p>					  Three Months   Six Months</p>
<p>					 Ended June 30,  Ended June 30,</p>
<p>				     1997     1996     1997     1996</p>
<p>					   (Unaudited)   (Unaudited)</p>
<p> Net sales		    $28,848  $27,368  $57,580   $52,464</p>
<p> Cost of sales		 21,559   20,722   43,516    42,866</p>
<p>    Gross profit		7,289    6,646   14,064     9,598</p>
<p>Research and development</p>
<p>  expenses			  494	479	927	 969</p>
<p>Plant administrative</p>
<p>  expense			 1,573    1,354    2,882     2,840</p>
<p>Selling and warehouse</p>
<p>  expenses			2,180    1,951    4,325     4,037</p>
<p>General corporate expenses</p>
<p>				    2,370    2,706    4,693     5,613</p>
<p>Earnings (loss) before unusual items, interest and income</p>
<p>     taxes			  672	156    1,237   (3,861)</p>
<p> Unusual items (b)	    1,086	901    1,619     8,401</p>
<p> Interest expense, net	1,633    1,122    2,795     2,381</p>
<p>Loss from continuing operations before income</p>
<p>    taxes		     (2,047)  (1,867)  (3,177)  (14,643)</p>
<p>Provision (benefit) for</p>
<p>  income taxes (c)		  0    (747)	  0   (5,857)</p>
<p>Loss from continuing</p>
<p>  operations		  (2,047)  (1,120)  (3,177)   (8,786)</p>
<p>Discontinued Operations:(a)</p>
<p>Gain on sale of discontinued</p>
<p>    operations (d)		  0	  0	  0     1,564</p>
<p>Earnings (loss) from discontinued</p>
<p>    operations			0	  0	  0     (133)</p>
<p>Net earnings related to</p>
<p>	 discontinued operations  0	  0	  0     1,431</p>
<p>	Net loss		(2,047)  (1,120)  (3,177)   (7,355)</p>
<p>Preferred stock dividends (e)</p>
<p>					207	207	414	 414</p>
<p>Net loss applicable to</p>
<p>    common stockholders   (2,254)  (1,327)  (3,591)   (7,769)</p>
<p>Net earnings (loss) per common share,</p>
<p>primary and fully diluted: (e) (f)</p>
<p>From continuing</p>
<p>	operations	     (0.56)   (0.34)   (0.90)    (2.34)</p>
<p>From discontinued</p>
<p>	operations (a)	    .00	.00	.00	 .36</p>
<p>	  Net loss	     (0.56)   (0.34)   (0.90)    (1.98)</p>
<p>NOTE: (a) The company sold the manufacturing assets of its Consumer Products Business on March 15 and has reflected the gain on the sale and the results of this discontinued business separately from continuing operations in the above table.</p>
<p>(b) Unusual items consist of the following:</p>
<p>					 Three Months	 Six Months</p>
<p>					 Ended June 30,  Ended June 30,</p>
<p>				    1997	 1996	1997    1996</p>
<p>					    (Unaudited)    (Unaudited)</p>
<p> Financing costs (1)	$1,086	 $245    $1,619    $245</p>
<p> Loss on restructuring (2)     0	  656	   0   8,156</p>
<p>				   1,086	  901     1,619   8,401</p>
<p>(1) Financing costs represent professional fees related to the company's refinancing efforts, which primarily consist of fees paid to the owners of the company's unsecured debt and fees paid to its financial and legal advisors.</p>
<p>(2) During the second quarter of 1996, the company incurred an unusual pre-tax loss of $656,000 for restructuring costs primarily related to relocation of personnel and equipment. During the first quarter of 1996, it recorded an unusual pretax loss of $7,500,000 for the costs associated with the restructuring of the company, which included moving the corporate headquarters from Los Angeles, California to Lancaster, Pennsylvania and the relocation of the wide mouth jar operations from Santa Fe Springs, California to Bowling Green, Kentucky. The loss consisted of reserves of $7,500,000 for i) severance pay, workers' compensation claims and insurance continuation costs of $3,000,000, ii) costs associated with terminating the leases of the two vacated facilities of $2,300,000, iii) asset retirements of $1,600,000 and iv) other costs of $600,000.</p>
<p>(c) During the three and six months ended June 30, 1997, the company recorded income tax charges of $798,000 and $1,239,000, respectively, to increase the valuation reserve against the company's net deferred income tax asset. The increase in the valuation reserve eliminated the tax benefits the company would have generated during the second quarter of 1997, and was required because of the continuing unwaived covenant defaults under loan agreements governing the Company's $50,900,000 principal amount of unsecured debt.</p>
<p>During the third and fourth quarters of 1996, a valuation reserve was provided to eliminate the tax benefit recorded during the first and second quarters of 1996.</p>
<p>(d) Net earnings from discontinued operations includes an after-tax gain of $1,564,000 for the six months ended March 31, 1996. The gain on the sale of discontinued operations has been reduced by $5,800,000 of reserves consisting of i) retiree health care and pension expenses of $3,800,000, ii) severance pay, workers' compensation claims and insurance continuation costs of $1,000,000, iii) professional fees of $500,000, iv) asset retirements of $300,000, and v) other costs of $200,000.</p>
<p>(e) The company has not declared a dividend on its Class B, Series D Preferred Stock since the first quarter of 1996. The cumulative amount of undeclared dividends as of June 30, 1997 is $1,036,000. Under accounting rules, such dividends are not accrued until declared. Under the terms of the company's $8,500,000 Secured Revolving Credit Facility, the company is not permitted to declare or pay any dividends on its preferred stock.</p>
<p>(f) Weighted average number of common shares and common share equivalents, outstanding for the three months and six months ended June 30, 1997 was 4,006,000 and 3,970,000, respectively. Weighted average number of common shares outstanding for the three months and six months ended June 30, 1996, was 3,933,000. Fully diluted net earnings per common share reflect when dilutive, a) the incremental common shares issuable upon the assumed exercise of outstanding stock options, and b) the assumed conversion of the Class B, Series D Preferred Stock and the elimination of the related dividends. The calculation of fully diluted net earnings (loss) per common share for the three and six months ended June 30, 1997 and 1996 was not dilutive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LANCASTER, Pa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
