<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784296" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: ATHLETICS-BAGACH LOSES WORLD TITLE AFTER SECOND DRUG SCANDAL.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-BAGACH LOSES WORLD TITLE AFTER SECOND DRUG SCANDAL.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's world shot put champion Aleksandr Bagach has been stripped of his gold medal after failing a drug test, athletics sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Olympic bronze medallist has tested positive for a stimulant and will also lose his $60,000 winner's prize. The sources said the International Amateur Athletic Federation (IAAF) would make an official statement later on Thursday.</p>
<p>It is the second time that Bagach has been caught cheating with banned substances during his career.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian was banned for two years in 1989 after he was found to have excessive levels of the male hormone testosterone in his body when he was competing for the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Bagach, 30, would have been banned for life if he had tested positive for a serious drug like steroids but he will escape with a warning after a new rule introduced by the IAAF before the championships.</p>
<p>It is the first doping case at the Athens championships.</p>
<p>The gold and money will now go to American silver medallist John Godina, the 1995 champion. Germany's bronze medallist Oliver-Sven Buder will get the silver and American C.J. Hunter will receive the bronze.</p>
<p>The 30-year-old Bagach equalled his personal best by recording 21.47 metres at his third attempt to win the competition in Athens on Saturday. He said afterwards that he could not believe the performance.</p>
<p>The Ukrainian struggled to make his way back to the top after being banned for two years for testosterone following third place in the 1989 European Cup in Gateshead, England. As a result, the Soviet team lost their place in the World Cup.</p>
<p>Bagach, however, could clearly not resist the temptation to cheat his way to glory with banned substances again.</p>
<p>Under previous rules athletes caught using stimulants would be banned for three months but the IAAF's congress decided to soften the ban to a public warning at their meeting before the championships.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
