<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784520" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Avmin still committed to Zambia copper.</title>
<headline>Avmin still committed to Zambia copper.</headline>
<byline>Marius Bosch</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A consortium led by South African Avmin Ltd is still committed to spending over $1 billion on Zambia's copper crown jewels despite reports of a deadlock in talks with the Lusaka government, officials said.</p>
<p>Zambia's The Post newspaper reported on Wednesday that the Kafue consortium and the Zambian government had reached an impasse.</p>
<p>The report said the government was considering further splitting up the package of Zambia Consolidated Copper Mines Ltd assets the consortium submitted a bid for.</p>
<p>The Avmin consortium, including Phelps Dodge Corp, Noranda Inc and the Commonwealth Development Corp, bid for the Nchanga and Nkana divisions of ZCCM -- the state-owned mining company's prize assets accounting for almost half of its output.</p>
<p>Avmin spokesman Julian Gwillim said on Thursday the consortium had not been formally informed that the government was in the process of restructuring the ZCCM package.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still committed to Zambia and of course the rebirth of those copper assets,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Industry officials said the consortium remained committed to spending more than a billion dollars in Zambia, some $750 million on capital expenditure and the rest on debt assumption and social upliftment.</p>
<p>&quot;That is serious money by any standards and signifies their commitment to the success of the whole thing,&quot; said one official who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>The Post quoted a Zambia Mines Ministry official as saying the package for which the consortium submitted a bid was too large and it would have been better to have smaller units to widen the investment base.</p>
<p>&quot;If this deal falls through, we have no option but to unbundle the package and make it more accessible to potential investors,&quot; the ministry official said.</p>
<p>The Nchanga and Nkana divisions of ZCCM produced 225,000 tonnes of copper in the last financial year. The divisions include several open pit and underground copper mines, a copper tailings treatment plant, a cobalt treatment plant and smelter.</p>
<p>Avmin has already won the right to develop Zambia's Konkola North deposit, one of the deposits on which the country's flagging copper mining industry is pinning its hope for long-term survival.</p>
<p>A consortium led by Zambia Copper Investment Ltd -- 50.6 percent owned by Anglo American Corp of South Africa Ltd -- signed a memorandum of understanding with the Zambian government in February to develop the Konkola Deep mine.</p>
<p>A due diligence study into the project should be completed by the end of the year, Anglo said in June.</p>
<p>Analysts see the Zambian mining industry reviving after privatisation with production of copper surging to more than a million tonnes a year from current levels of around 400,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27-11 482-1003</p>
<p>	 E-mail: johannesburg.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
