<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784606" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania holds British child sex suspect.</title>
<headline>Romania holds British child sex suspect.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Briton who says he is a Protestant clergyman was charged with unlawful sex after police caught him having sex with a Romanian boy of 14, prosecutors said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Bucharest prosecutor handling the case said John Michael Taylor, 34, was in custody on a 30-day arrest warrant on charges of &quot;sexual relations with persons of the same sex and sexual corruption&quot;.</p>
<p>Taylor entered Romania last month as a tourist. Transport police arrested him on Tuesday at a flat near Bucharest's main railway station, a fertile hunting ground for paedophiles, where he was found in bed with the boy.</p>
<p>Bucharest Transport Police chief Ilie Corneciu said the Briton had admitted being homosexual and was aware that having sexual relations with a minor was a crime.</p>
<p>&quot;He is a little bit confused, but knows that he has done something wrong,&quot; Corneciu told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>A British embassy official said the consul had visited Taylor earlier on Thursday and that his next of kin had been informed. If convicted, Taylor faces up to seven years in jail under Romania's recently adopted criminal code.</p>
<p>Police said Taylor identified himself as a clergyman from the county of Essex, northeast of London.</p>
<p>He was the fifth foreigner arrested by police since last October on charges of unlawful sex with underaged boys.</p>
<p>Of the other suspects, -- Austrian, German, Swiss and and American, only the Austrian was sentenced to one year in prison. But the sentence was suspended and he was expelled.</p>
<p>Corneciu said his brigade had also arrested three Romanians in connection with child sex abuse in the past year in operations focusing on railway stations and the underground.</p>
<p>&quot;After the scandals in Belgium which sounded alarm bells, we began looking more closely into such cases,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pornography and child prostitution and trafficking in minors have become rampant in the Balkan country since the 1989 anti-communist revolt ended strict social controls.</p>
<p>Bucharest has become an attractive destination for well-organised paedophiles, with an estimated 2,000 children living in squalor on the city's streets and around the main railway station easy prey.</p>
<p>The charity Save the Children says some 50 paedophiles from Germany, France and Britain travel regularly to Romania, posing as tourists or businessmen and rent apartments where they abuse children after bribing or coercing them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
