<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784618" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Clinton assures Albania of U.S. support.</title>
<headline>Clinton assures Albania of U.S. support.</headline>
<byline>Llazar Semini</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton on Thursday assured Albania of U.S. support for its efforts to resuscitate its ravaged economy and restore peace after months of violent unrest.</p>
<p>In a letter to newly elected Prime Minister Fatos Nano Clinton advised the Socialist leader to pursue a policy of national reconciliation.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States and our partners in the international community are ready to assist your government in its pursuit of meaningful political and economic reform necessary to restore normal conditions in your country,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>&quot;Your pledge to include the broad spectrum of political forces in the governing process is very encouraging in light of the political polarization that has afflicted your society,&quot; the letter continued.</p>
<p>The collapse of shaky investment pyramid schemes earlier this year swallowed the life savings of hundreds of thousands of Albanians, and triggered months of anarchy which led to the fall of the right-wing government of former President Sali Berisha.</p>
<p>More than 1,500 people have been killed in the former communist country since the violence erupted in March.</p>
<p>&quot;The civil unrest and economic uncertainty affecting your country present your government with a tremendous task,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>Italy led a 7,000-strong multinational protection force deployed in Albania in April to help restore control in the country. The force is due to withdraw fully by mid-August.</p>
<p>The Albanian government is preparing a draft law to  be sent to parliament for the collection of weapons, most of which were stolen from army or police depots during the rebellion earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident that, as long as your country remains on the path of reconciliation and sound policies, Albania will have a stable and prosperous future,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund and World Bank have outlined an extensive programme to help lift Albania out of its economic crisis and open the way to foreign investment.</p>
<p>A meeting of foreign ministers will be held in Rome in September and international donors are due to meet in Brussels in October to examine ways to provide aid to Albania in the form of approved projects.</p>
<p>Italy and Greece have already begun assisting Albania with restructuring the economy, police and armed forces.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
