<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784739" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: FOCUS-NO REAL WINNERS FROM VENEZUELA WORK STOPPAGE.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-NO REAL WINNERS FROM VENEZUELA WORK STOPPAGE.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela's first national strike for eight years paralyzed much of the country Wednesday, but had no clear victors and left many Venezuelans wondering what it had all been about, analysts said.</p>
<p>Called by unions to pressure for private sector wage rises and protest a 27 percent rise in domestic gasoline prices, the 12-hour work stoppage closed down government offices and brought public transport services to a standstill.  </p>
<p>But rather than staging marches and violent protests, many Venezuelans took advantage of the strike to top up their tans at the beach, or carry out household chores.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike went like a holiday,&quot; was the headline on leading daily El Universal.</p>
<p>&quot;If it wasn't so serious for the economy and respect for institutions, it would be one of the funniest acts ever in Venezuelan politics,&quot; said political analyst Carlos Raul Hernandez.  </p>
<p>The fact that government ministers publicly endorsed the strike, calling it justified, underscored its essentially political nature, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still not even clear who the strike was against. And for there to be a victor there has to be a purpose,&quot; political analyst Antonio Cova said.</p>
<p>Union and business leaders traded claims and counter- claims on the size of the strike turnout. Federico Ramirez Leon, head of the Venezuelan Workers Confederation (CTV), which called the strike, said that anyone who doubted its success &quot;must have been on Mars or the Moon.&quot;  </p>
<p>But many Venezuelans were left wondering Thursday whether the strike had achieved any concrete goal.</p>
<p>&quot;That (the strike) doesn't change anything. Salaries are still on the floor and prices are still sky high,&quot; said petrol pump attendant Carlos Cordoba who added that he had joined the strike simply because he could not find transport to get to his workplace. &quot;If not, I would have come.&quot;</p>
<p>The key reason for the strike -- union allegations that businesses had reneged on a pledge to raise salaries -- remains deadlocked.  </p>
<p>While unions say that 85 percent of companies have not raised wages since a ground-breaking agreement to reform the severance payments system was approved in June, business chambers insist that 90 percent of their members have complied with the agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;We will go on raising salaries in accordance with companies' financial positions and labor productivity. We have not fallen behind,&quot; said Francisco Natera, head of leading business group Fedecamaras.  </p>
<p>The Caracas Stock Exchange quickly shrugged off the strike posting respectable gains on Wednesday and Thursday as investors breathed a sigh of relief it had passed off quietly.</p>
<p>&quot;I suppose the best thing that can be said is it (the strike) diffused a bit of the tension in the labor sector and now things can get back to normal,&quot; one western diplomat said.</p>
<p>But analysts said, broad-based political support for the strike call suggested that politicians had begun to set their sights firmly on winning over public support in the build-up to December 1998 elections. And although it was in their interest to continue talks to reform outdated labor laws, business leaders may be more reluctant to sign agreements with government and union leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;They (business leaders) have been made to look like the bad guys. A big wedge has been driven between them and the government which will be hard to repair,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>((-- Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
