<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78472" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Anti-Japan chants greet HK protest ship in Taiwan.</title>
<headline>Anti-Japan chants greet HK protest ship in Taiwan.</headline>
<dateline>KEELUNG, Taiwan 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Hong Kong ship berthed in Taiwan early on Friday carrying the body of drowned activist David Chan and was met by raucous chants of &quot;Down with Japanese imperialism!&quot;</p>
<p>The tanker Kien Hwa 2 came back into port carrying 80 activists, reporters and crew back from a disputed East China Sea archipelago where Chan drowned on Thursday in a protest to claim islands back from Japan for China.  </p>
<p>Chan drowned in a roiling East China Sea on Thursday after Japanese patrol boats thwarted his protest ship's bid to land on a disputed archipelago to claim it back for China.</p>
<p>When it put into Taiwan it complied with Taiwan's request not to enter flying the red flag of communist China, the island's arch rival since a civil war split them in 1949. A large flag that had flown on its bow was gone.</p>
<p>Even before the passengers could disembark, a crowd of some 200 Taiwan demonstrators chanted anti-Japanese slogans and waved flags of the island's exiled Republic of China government, which like Beijing claims the islands for China.</p>
<p>&quot;Down with Japanese imperialism!&quot; shouted dockside demonstrators from the opposition New Party, which favours Taiwan's reunification with China.</p>
<p>&quot;Protect Chinese sovereignty! Protect the Diaoyus!&quot; they chanted, using the Chinese name for the islands claimed by Japan since 1895 as the Senkakus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KEELUNG, Taiwan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
