<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784868" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: SEOUL STOCKS END BARELY DOWN, EARLY GAINS ERASED.</title>
<headline>SEOUL STOCKS END BARELY DOWN, EARLY GAINS ERASED.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seoul stocks closed slightly lower on Thursday despite an early rise, ending three straight days of gains, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said selling pressure at the 750-point level triggered the relapse.</p>
<p>&quot;Punters felt it was time for a little consolidation before it begins another march,&quot; said Choo Hee-yup of Dongwon Securities.</p>
<p>The composite stock index closed down 0.30 points to 745.35, with 34.2 million shares changing hands.  </p>
<p>Brokers said the market could attempt a rebound on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The consolidation could be short-lived. After all, the market has been consolidating for almost two months. Investors are now feeling a little more confident about the market,&quot; said Choo.</p>
<p>Shares of Dainong Corp and Midopa Department Store attracted much attention on the news that emergency funds had been supplied to the two troubled firms.</p>
<p>Dainong rose 190 won to its upper limit of 2,640 and Midopa gained 520 to its limit high of 7,020.  </p>
<p>Brokers said Shin Hwa was the most heavily traded stock with 872,330 shares changing hands. It closed up 900 won to 24,500, after peaking at 25,400 in early morning.</p>
<p>Shin Hwa had previously plunged on rumours of cash-flow troubles, but it bounced back after the rumours were proven untrue, they said.</p>
<p>Hanwha Chemical was another actively traded stock with 322,270 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>Brokers said some investors accumulated the stock on talk of Hanwha's improved first-half results but some sold off, seeing it as an opportunity to take profits.  </p>
<p>Hanwha Chemical lost 160 won to 6,740.</p>
<p>Brokers said Korean Air Lines shares managed to recover from a sharp loss on Wednesday following the crash of one of its jumbo jets in Guam. It gained 200 won to 15,500.</p>
<p>They said foreign investors bought up the shares on Thursday after dumping them on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The airliner's affiliate and insurer Oriental Fire and Marine Insurance ended flat at 21,500.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors think the damage on Oriental Fire would be limited because the company was reinsured,&quot; said Choo of Dongwon.  </p>
<p>Brokers said shares of struggling Kia Group units closed mixed after sharp falls in the last few days.</p>
<p>Kia Motors added 100 won to 13,000 and Asia Motors lost 120 to 4,500.</p>
<p>Kia Precision continued to benefit from a rumour that the nation's two carmakers Hyundai Motor and Daewoo Motor planned to buy stakes of the firm.</p>
<p>A group spokesman denied the speculation, but the stock ended at its upper limit of 9,790, up 720.</p>
<p>-- JEAN YOON (822) 727 5643</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
