<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784825" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-AUSTRALIAN GENERAL NEWS - AUGUST 8.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-AUSTRALIAN GENERAL NEWS - AUGUST 8.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Australian Bureau of Statistics figures published yesterday show a slow job market, with unemployment rising and employment levels the same as they were in late 1996. The figures will be a key issue at special two-day Cabinet meeting next week, which wil be chaired by Prime Minister John Howard. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>On the back of Australia's reputation for fresh food and innovative cuisine, British supermarket group Sainsbury's will next month send 13 top food buyers to Australia to see what can be picked up for export orders worth millions of dollars. The visit gies Australia the chance to lifts its international profile, and be part of Sainbury's A$25 billion a year business. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Federal Court judge Justice Jeffrey Spender's decision yesterday that an assessment of zero dollars is a taxable assessment spells bad news for companies that have never paid tax. The decision means companies that have not paid tax will be brought into te four-year limit for retrospective amendments that applies to all other taxpayers. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Processor David Flint, the new head of the Australian Broadcasting Authority, says Kerry Packer may be able to buy John Fairfax Holdings while still owning the Nine Network. Flint's comments come just weeks before the Federal Government is due to reveal ts new framework for media ownership. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>In a move following its increase in personal account fees, Australia's largest and most profitable bank, the National Australia Bank, has quietly imposed a cash-handling charge on small and medium-sized businesses, despite already earning millions on such deposits. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard was yesterday back on deck and receiving briefings from Federal Treasurer Peter Costello and senior advisers. Howard has been away from the spotlight following a bout of pneumonia that put him in hospital two weeks ago. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The rescue operation at the Thredbo landslide site ground to a halt yesterday, after the last body was dragged from the rubble early yesterday morning. Rescue teams thanked the people of Thredbo in yesterday's final, and emotional, press conference. Page1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Federal Treasurer Peter Costello was last night forced to look at alternatives to his A$6.5 billion tax rescue package that followed Tuesday's High Court ruling, after pressure from both tobacco companies, which halted the sale of their products, and breweries, which passed on the full 15 per cent tax rise on alcohol to retailers. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>The July labour force survey released yesterday by the Australian Bureau of Statistics showed the number of unemployed people rose by 23,000, which pushed Australia's unemployment rate back to 8.7 per cent. In response to the figures, the Federal Government has conceded the job market is &quot;flat&quot; and it will be a &quot;long and difficult&quot; task to improve it. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>American General Norman Schwarzkopf, who led the Allied forces in the Gulf War, yesterday spoke to a crowd of over 9,000 at the Sydney Entertainment Centre amid tight security. Schwarzkopf spoke to the audience, who paid an average price of A$270 a ticket, about leadership, values, ethics and integrity. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Government's plan to change State levies on tobacco, alcohol and petrol to a Federal tax in response to Tuesday's High Court decision has met with resistance from the tobacco and alcohol industries. Smokers face a shortage of cigarettes as toacco companies halted sales, and the price of beer increased after breweries passed on the 15 per cent Federal tax. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A joint report by the Sydney City Mission, the Society of St Vincent de Paul, the Salvation Army, the Wesley Mission, and the Haymarket Foundation has found large numbers of homeless people in Sydney have mental illness, yet services for these people are eing cut. The report said emergency crisis hostels faced dangerous situations as mentally ill people were being dumped on them without back-up treatment. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Police in Victoria believe they have smashed an international drug cartel after the discovery of a A$30 million, 32 kilogram consignment of heroin that was hidden in tins of water chestnuts imported from China. Melbourne customs officers pinpointed the tns, which remained unloaded at Swanston Dock, using specialist risk assessment techniques. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian Bureau of Statistics figures released yesterday showed the unemployment rate slipped back up to 8.7 per cent in July. The figures show that both employment and unemployment trends are flat, and indicate more people are giving up the search forwork. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>While six unions and the Public Transport Corporation agreed on a temporary truce in Victoria's transport dispute in the Industrial Relations Commission last night, the reprieve for commuters could be short-lived, with Victorian Premier Jeff Kennett refusng to budge on a pay and redundancy offer to 9500 public transport workers. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Victorian dating agencies Yvonne Allen and Associates, Dinner for Six, and J.J. Elliott Human Relations Consultants have applied to the Anti-Discrimination Tribunal for exemptions to the anti-discrimination laws that would allow them to refuse to serve groups such as the aged, homosexuals, and disabled people. Page 1.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
