<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784897" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: U.S. troops issue prevents progress in Korea talks.</title>
<headline>U.S. troops issue prevents progress in Korea talks.</headline>
<byline>Moon Ihlwan</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seoul blamed Pyongyang on Thursday for preventing four-nation talks from making progress, citing North Korea's demands that U.S. troops be withdrawn from South Korea and a bilateral peace deal be made with Washington.</p>
<p>Officials in Seoul said the demands were likely to force the United States, China and the two Koreas to have another round of &quot;talks about talks&quot; after their current session in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact the four nations met means that we have opened a new process,&quot; Foreign Ministry spokesman Lee Kyu-hyung said, adding he was not discouraged by the North's move.</p>
<p>North Korea's official media reported on Wednesday that the two demands should be included on the agenda for peace talks by the four nations.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously they are obstacles. It is absurd that they have agreed to hold four-nation talks to discuss peace and then say a peace arrangement be made only with the U.S.,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>The four countries have tentatively agreed that they will try to set an agenda by Friday but Lee said Seoul and Washington were adamant that they could not accept Pyongyang's demands on the issues of U.S. troops and the bilateral deal.</p>
<p>About 37,000 U.S. troops are stationed in South Korea to help defend the country.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not rule out a breakthrough but it is quite unlikely,&quot; Lee said when asked if the four nations could manage to set an agenda within this week.</p>
<p>But Seoul officials said they remained hopeful the four parties would open this year substantive negotiations aimed at forging a durable peace mechanism on the Korean peninsula to replace the fraying armistice that halted the 1950-53 Korean War.</p>
<p>&quot;We more or less expected the North to raise the issues. They know, of course, the demands will not be met,&quot; a senior Seoul government official said.</p>
<p>North Korea's official Rodong Sinmun newspaper said: &quot;Freeing the Korean peninsula from foreign troops is the way of ensuring a durable peace and a main task to be fulfilled by 'four-way talks'.&quot;</p>
<p>In Washington, Secretary of State Madeleine Albright said on Wednesday the United States would not consider a North Korean request to withdraw U.S. troops from the Korean peninsula.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to do that. This is the last area of the Cold War,&quot; Albright said.</p>
<p>South Korea's chief delegate to the New York talks, Deputy Foreign Minister Song Young-shik, said on Wednesday the atmosphere of their meeting was &quot;friendly and productive&quot;.</p>
<p>Spokesman Lee said the four nations have already agreed to hold peace talks in Geneva within six weeks of an end of their preparatory talks.</p>
<p>The four also agreed that foreign ministers either head their delegations at the peace talks or nominate high-level officials as chief delegates if they cannot attend.</p>
<p>But Seoul officials said the four delegations in New York decided nothing would be considered until all aspects of their discussion were settled.</p>
<p>&quot;We attach significance to the opening itself of the New York talks,&quot; the senior government official said.</p>
<p>Washington and Seoul worked for months to persuade Pyongyang's Stalinist regime to join the peace process proposed in 1996 by the U.S. and South Korean presidents.</p>
<p>The New York meeting marked a watershed because it included China for the first time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
