<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784967" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel and PLO spar ahead of U.S. mission.</title>
<headline>Israel and PLO spar ahead of U.S. mission.</headline>
<byline>Colleen Siegel</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel and the Palestinians traded accusations on Thursday ahead of a U.S. mission to salvage Middle East peacemaking battered by a twin suicide bombing and Jewish settlement of occupied Arab land.</p>
<p>The United States publicly faulted both sides over the war of words.</p>
<p>Yasser Arafat lashed out in a newspaper interview against measures imposed by Israel on Palestinians since two Islamic suicide bombers killed 13 people last week at an Israeli market.</p>
<p>&quot;(Prime Minister Benjamin) Netanyahu has declared war on us and we have to prepare for what will come. The situation is serious,&quot; the Palestinian president said in an interview published in Israel's daily Yedioth Ahronoth.</p>
<p>In response, Netanyahu said in a speech to members of his Likud party: &quot;I want to warn against any attempt by the Palestinian Authority to create so-called spontaneous violence.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu called on the Authority to wage &quot;a bitter war&quot; against the infrastructure of the militant Moslem groups Hamas and Islamic Jihad and &quot;end the climate of violence&quot;.</p>
<p>U.S. State Department spokesman James Rubin said Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, expected in the region later this month, urged Israel and the PLO in a speech on Wednesday to revive a spirit of partnership in peace.</p>
<p>Commenting on Arafat's reported use of the term &quot;declaration of war&quot;, Rubin said: &quot;To the extent that it is...interpreted as meaning battle with Israel, we regard (such statements) as counterproductive. And we think they should not be made.&quot;</p>
<p>Rubin was also asked about remarks Netanyahu made during a news conference with Jordan's Crown Prince Hassan on Wednesday in which he accused the Palestinian Authority of behaving &quot;like a regime facilitating terror, like Iran, or Iraq or Libya&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard to fathom how one could compare Chairman Arafat to Colonel (Muammar) Gaddafi,&quot; Rubin said. &quot;Chairman Arafat was on the White House lawn with the president. He signed a peace agreement with the Israelis. We regard him as a partner in our effort to find peace in the Middle East. Colonel Gaddafi is an international outlaw.&quot;</p>
<p>After the market attack, Israel halted peace talks with the PLO and sealed off the West Bank and Gaza, stopping trade and keeping thousands of Palestinians from jobs in Israel. Israel's Treasury froze transfer of tax duties it owes the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Israel has also rounded up scores of suspected Moslem militants and threatened to re-enter Palestinian-ruled areas if Arafat failed to crack down on them.</p>
<p>All sides welcomed Albright's saying she might at month's end visit the region. U.S. peace envoy Dennis Ross is due as early as Saturday night.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a call between her and me yesterday and I thanked her for her speech which she made yesterday that showed the care of the U.S. to push the peace process and save it from the current crisis,&quot; Arafat told reporters in Gaza.</p>
<p>&quot;We will welcome her and anyone else who can help restore security,&quot; Netanyahu said.</p>
<p>Albright has said her trip depended on an improved security situation. President Bill Clinton warned the peace process could not go on unless the Palestinians halted &quot;terrorist&quot; acts like the Jerusalem bombing.</p>
<p>Albright and Clinton also criticised Israel for taking unilateral steps, including building Jewish settlements on occupied Arab land, that enraged the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Palestinian sources said Israeli authorities demolished four Arab homes in the West Bank built without a licence. The army said it was checking the report.</p>
<p>In south Lebanon, pro-Iranian Hizbollah guerrillas killed a pro-Israeli Lebanese militiaman in a car-bomb attack. Israeli shelling then killed one Lebanese civilian and wounded two.</p>
<p>Later a roadside bomb exploded in south Lebanon beside a car travelling in Israel's occupation zone, killing a mother and her two children and wounding a man, Israeli military sources said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
