<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="784975" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey gives casinos six months to close.</title>
<headline>Turkey gives casinos six months to close.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's parliament on Thursday passed a law giving casinos six months to close down their operations, state-run Anatolian news agency said.</p>
<p>It said the Turkish President Suleyman Demirel had previously returned the bill to parliament for revision but the deputies passed it a second time with no changes.</p>
<p>The president is obliged to sign a bill passed unaltered by the assembly second time round.</p>
<p>The casinos would be given six months to close down after the date of publication of the law in the official gazette, or face prosecution, the agency said.</p>
<p>The bill was originally put forward by the previous Islamist-led government but was pursued by the successor secularist administration of Mesut Yilmaz.</p>
<p>Media reports said that casinos had become centres for money laundering and tax evasion as well as a cause of suicides among bankrupt gamblers faced with debts.</p>
<p>Gambling operations had already been curtailed by laws banning Turks from the casinos as well as dress codes and restricted weekday opening hours.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
