<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785168" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX NATGAS HOLDS LATE GAINS ON AGAS, FIRM CASH.</title>
<headline>NYMEX NATGAS HOLDS LATE GAINS ON AGAS, FIRM CASH.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures held sharp gains late Thursday in active trade, still underpinned by follow through buying on the heels of bullish weekly inventory data and stronger cash prices, sources said.</p>
<p>At 1400 EDT, September was still up by eight cents at $2.431 per million British thermal units after surging this morning to a new high of $2.515. October, which also hit a new benchmark of $2.50 today, was 8.4 cents higher at $2.44. Other deferreds were up by one to 7.1 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;If you told me a week ago we'd see a $2.50 print, I would have said no way, but the breakout could not be sustained if it wasn't supported by the cash. We've had three consecutive weeks of low injections, and people are getting concerned about how much gas is in storage,&quot; said one Texas trader.</p>
<p>Traders said Wednesday's AGA data showing another very low weekly stock build of 55 bcf helped trigger the latest surge.</p>
<p>While overall inventories are 133 bcf, or 7.5 percent, above last year's record lows, they still lag the 1994-1995 average by more than 400 bcf. Weekly Injections of 68 bcf through October are needed to get stocks back to 2.8 tcf.</p>
<p>And revised forecasts calling for warmer temperatures in parts of the East, Midwest and Texas by the weekend also should help support prices near-term, traders said. But the Southeast is expected to remain below-normal into next week.</p>
<p>With September again breaking to new highs today, chart traders had difficulty pegging resistance. After the new contract high of $2.515, which also coincides with $2.52, a spot continuation level from early February, next resistance was seen in the spot continuation gap between $2.64 and $2.89 from late January.</p>
<p>Minor support was pegged in the $2.34 area and then at $2.30, with better buying likely at $2.25-2.27. Further support points were at $2.20, $2.15-2.16 and then along the short-term up trendline at $2.14.</p>
<p>In the cash Wednesday, Gulf Coast prices jumped more than a dime to the mid-to-high $2.40s, while Midcon pipes were up a similar amount the low-$2.40s. New York city gate gas climbed into the low-$2.60s, up more than 10 cents on the day.</p>
<p>NYMEX volume and open interest figures were unavailable due to technical problems at NYMEX.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, September was still up by 6.5 cents at $2.33, while deferreds remained steady to 12 cents higher. The East/West spread widened by 1.5 cents to 10.1 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>((--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
