<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785194" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: July U.S. retailer sales solid but inflated.</title>
<headline>July U.S. retailer sales solid but inflated.</headline>
<byline>Laura Jacobs</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. retailers on Thursday reported solid if not spectacular sales in July, with gains exaggerated by lackluster results a year ago.</p>
<p>But analysts said leaner inventories hint at potentially firm results through the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;A solid performance but inflated by the easy comparison,&quot; said Mike Niemira, economist, Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi, of the general figures. &quot;But the overall picture is basically as expected.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, we think results are coming in pretty good,&quot; said Harry Ikenson, retail analyst at Rodman &amp; Renshaw Inc. &quot;We think that since the second week of June, most companies have seen results either on or above plan.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, many major retailers reported same-store sales -- at stores open at least one year -- that met or slightly exceeded expectations, with a few seeing sales well above or below forecasts.</p>
<p>Among the nation's largest retailers, Wal-Mart Stores Inc. said total company July same-store sales rose 6.0 percent, and Dayton Hudson said sales rose 5.6 percent, both in line with analysts' forecasts. Kmart Corp. gained 9.2 percent, and Federated Department Stores Inc. rose 8.6 percent, each slightly above forecasts.</p>
<p>Sears Roebuck &amp; Co. reported a 2.4-percent increase, slightly below forecasts, while Kohl's Corp. jumped 12.1 percent, and Gap Inc. GPS.N) rose 6.0 percent, both above most forecasts.</p>
<p>Several investment firms' proprietary indexes showed similar results.</p>
<p>Patrick McCormack, analyst at Alex Brown &amp; Sons, said his company's same-store 100 index rose 5.4 percent in July, a &quot;little better&quot; than the expected 5.0 percent rise.</p>
<p>He and others agreed that sales last month benefitted from comparison to soft July 1996 data, when shoppers stayed home to watch the Olympics, plus fairly heavy clearance activity.</p>
<p>&quot;So it's a good month, but you probably don't need to get too excited about it because it's not too important from a profit standpoint,&quot; McCormack added.</p>
<p>Salomon Brothers said Thursday its same-store sales index of some 30 companies rose 6.1 percent, a result that one of their analysts called &quot;pretty strong.&quot;</p>
<p>The firm's retail index, which also gauges performance relative to management's plans, stood at 4.0 percent, which &quot;also is a strong number, suggesting that we're above most management's plans,&quot; the analyst added.</p>
<p>Niemira said his firm's 82-store index rose 5.8 percent July over 12 months ago, near his forecast for a gain of up 5.5 percent to 6.0 percent.</p>
<p>Looking forward, analysts said retailers have marked down merchandise enough to keep inventories lean, which could help their performance into year-end.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally, I'd say the retailers have done a good job in terms of keeping inventories tight,&quot; said Maura Hunter Byrne, analyst J.P. Morgan Securities Inc. &quot;I think coming out of the first quarter, there was a concern on the inventory positions, and I think for the most part that has been cleaned up.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Consumers can be enticed to buy,&quot; added Niemira, agreeing that companies appear to have worked off any inventory bulges they were packing on during the spring. &quot;And that's really good news...as they move into the back-to-school (season).&quot;</p>
<p>A U.S. economy featuring low joblessness, high consumer confidence and real disposable income also bodes well for back-to-school season, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The decks have been cleared,&quot; said McCormack. &quot;That positions these companies well for back-to-school and Christmas.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
