<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785170" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MORTGAGE-BACKEDS SEEN OVERSOLD, OUTPACE TREASURIES.</title>
<headline>MORTGAGE-BACKEDS SEEN OVERSOLD, OUTPACE TREASURIES.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mortgage-backed securities (MBS) were little changed late Thursday, putting in a stronger performance than intermediate Treasuries as some participants viewed MBS as oversold.</p>
<p>July prepayment data from Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae) showed increases between 20 percent and 75 percent for 7 1/2 percent and higher coupons, market participants said.</p>
<p>Those increases, however, were largely factored into the market already, perhaps excessively, some traders said.  </p>
<p>At least one trader said &quot;we've had buyers all day.&quot;</p>
<p>MBS generally &quot;still look very attractive to short funding strategies for banks,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The market sold off sharply when interest rates plunged, prior to Friday's sharp reversal. But participants responded during the sell-off as if prepayment &quot;speeds will double and triple tomorrow and stay there, and they priced the market for those Armageddon&quot; scenarios, the trader said.</p>
<p>Even if prepayments do accelerate further, as many expect, analyst don't predict a dramatic or long-lived increase.  </p>
<p>Among active 30-year 7 1/2 percent MBS, Ginnie Maes were off 4/32 at 101-05/32 to yield 7.36 percent, 111 basis points over Treasuries. Fannie Maes were down 3/32 at 101-06/32 and Freddie Macs were 5/32 lower at 101-10/32.</p>
<p>Ten-year Treasury notes were 11/32 weaker on the day at 99-05/32 to yield 6.24 percent.</p>
<p>David Lereah, chief economist at the Mortgage Bankers Association of America, predicted that the MBA's weekly refinancing index would exceed 700 from the 689.3 level reached in the week ended August 7. After that peak, anticipated in next Thursday's MBA report, the index would settle around the 500 area, he said.</p>
<p>The trader, who deals mainly with bank customers, said he likes current coupon bonds for total-rate-of-return and higher coupons for buy-and-hold investors. He was avoiding 15-year MBS, which didn't fit in to preferred strategies of going short or long. &quot;You don't want to be stuck in the middle,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There was some market talk that investors were moving out of Treasuries and into MBS after the conclusion of the $38 billion refunding. The auctions concluded Thursday with the sale of $10 billion in 30-year bonds.</p>
<p>((  --Lynn Adler, N.A. Mortgage Unit, 212-859-1677 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
