<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785180" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME HOGS POST CLOSING GAINS, PORK BELLIES MIXED.</title>
<headline>CME HOGS POST CLOSING GAINS, PORK BELLIES MIXED.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog futures held firmer into the close on talk at least one major packer has increased slaughter operations, traders said. Falling cash pork belly prices pulled spot pork belly futures down the 3.000-cent-per-lb limit while other months settled mixed, traders said.</p>
<p>Hog futures closed 0.700 to 0.050 cent per lb higher with August up most at 80.750 cents. August pork bellies ended off the limit at 84.900 cents while other months finished up 0.050 to off 0.125 cent.</p>
<p>Floor talk that at least one major packer has stepped up kill hours after cutting hours last week, sparked part of the demand in August hogs and other months followed, traders said.</p>
<p>USDA estimated Thursday hog slaughter at 342,000 head, above 334,000 a week ago. The figure brought week-to-date slaughter to 1,278,000 head, also above 1,264,000 a week earlier.</p>
<p>Local short covering, support from an oversold condition and the discount futures hold to the CME lean hog index also reinforced gains and offset early fund selling in deferred months. The market was technically oversold, they added.</p>
<p>Rand Financials notably bought August and October much of the session, traders said, and Lind-Waldock and Saul Stone sold December while locals bought. RBH and ADM Investor Services bought October early.</p>
<p>In hog options, ADM Investor Services bought August 84 calls and sold October 70 puts.</p>
<p>Rand Financials sold December 66 puts. RBH actively bought October 75 calls late, pit sources said.  </p>
<p>August pork belly futures remained under commercial liquidation pressure following the weaker-than-expected cash belly market. A lack of deliveries had been expected to support August, but cash bellies traded as low as $85 per cwt which prompted selling in the futures pit.</p>
<p>Earlier expectations were for cash to only ease back to around $87 to $88 after trading up to as much as $92 late last week, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Ninety dollars chokes off demand,&quot; said Karl Skold, director of research for Frontier Risk Management.</p>
<p>Further losses were expected in August bellies on Friday as 50 unfilled sell orders were cited at the close, traders added.</p>
<p>Rosenthal Collins, Rand Financials and R.J. O'Brien notably sold August, traders said. Dean Witter and Refco bought February before Dean Witter turned seller along with Cargill Investor Services and locals. E.D.&amp;F. Man bought February late, considered to be fund support, pit sources said.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
