<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78526" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber ends lower on Tokyo's fall.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber ends lower on Tokyo's fall.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices ended lower, extending their falls as a lower Tokyo close and lack of active consumer demand pressured the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is following falls in Tokyo,&quot; a dealer said, adding that lack of demand also influenced sentiment.</p>
<p>There were some enquiries from South Korea and Taiwan for nearby SMR grades. The market is still waiting for fresh demand from Europe although dealers said there were enquiries for latex from few European firms.</p>
<p>Dealers offered SMR CV at 369 cents, SMR L at 349, SMR 5 at 320, SMR 10 at 309.50 and drum latex at between 238 and 242.  </p>
<p>Dealers said that with new supplies flowing into the market, further drop in prices was likely.</p>
<p>At the close, October RSS 1 buyer fell 1.50 cents to 320 cents ($1.28) a kg and October SMR 20 buyer was down a cent at 310.50 cents a kg.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day moving average was 246.39 Malaysian/Singapore cents per kg on Sept 24 from 247.20 on Sept 23. The daily indicator price was 244.19 against 245.75.</p>
<p>-- Tan Lee Lee (603-230-7510) ($1=2.5080 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
