<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785360" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: ANALYSTS MOSTLY POSITIVE ON ABB H1 RESULTS.</title>
<headline>ANALYSTS MOSTLY POSITIVE ON ABB H1 RESULTS.</headline>
<byline>Peter Nielsen</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Analysts were mixed, but mainly positive in their reaction to first half results by ABB Asea Brown Boveri AG, which were below forecasts.</p>
<p>Most analysts said they would maintain their current ratings on ABB -- buys or holds -- and any changes to forecast would first be done after Friday's briefing with ABB executives.</p>
<p>But Thomas Pfyl of Bank Vontobel said he had upped his earnings per share forecast for ABB based on an expected improvement in Western Europe in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe will clearly be better in 1998,&quot; Pfyl said, adding his 1997 EPS forecast for ABB AG was raised to 102 francs from 95 and 1998 EPS to 125 from 115.</p>
<p>ABB is 50-50 owned by Swiss ABB AG, which reported a 1996 EPS of 85.40 francs, and Sweden's ABB AB.</p>
<p>Pfyl also changed his rating on ABB to buy from hold.</p>
<p>The continued strong uptake of orders was the main reason for analysts' positive reading of ABB's first half results as this confirms expectations that ABB's profits in 1998 and 1999 will show strong growth after a weak 1997.</p>
<p>Another positive factor was the increase in first half operating margin to 7.1 percent from 6.7 percent, an increase that will help drive earnings higher once sales improve over the next two years.</p>
<p>The increase in operating margin was noticeable because it was taking place during a year that is characterised by weak business from Western Europe, still the bread and butter region for ABB.</p>
<p>&quot;The results were fine. Sure a little bit below forecast, but its terribly difficult to work out what the dollar does to them,&quot; said Angela Dean of Morgan Stanley.</p>
<p>But not all analysts were positive with at least one analyst -- Peter Gachnang of Bank Julius Baer -- disappointed by the continued weakness in Western Europe, lower sales in Asia and from the Power Generation business segment.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no reason to be fearful, but nevertheless the result was disappointing,&quot; said Gachnang, adding he would slightly reduce his earnings forecast.</p>
<p>Earlier ABB reported a two percent increase in first half group net profit to $567 million, below forecasts that on average looked for an increase of 4.5 percent to $581 million.</p>
<p>But in local currencies, net profit rose 12 percent.</p>
<p>First half orders rose 14 percent to $20.0 billion and by 21 percent in local currencies.</p>
<p>&quot;First half orders were very encouraging,&quot; Dean said.</p>
<p>Eric Steinhausen of Union Bank of Switzerland (UBS) also noted that second quarter orders did not include any new orders from the Bakun dam project in Malaysia, showing that ABB is also winning orders in other projects.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
