<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785348" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Brussels bourse rises, dollar-sensitives in focus.</title>
<headline>Brussels bourse rises, dollar-sensitives in focus.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brussels stocks were mixed to higher on Thursday, with financials leading the way, but dealers said dollar-sensitives remained the underlying story.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 index ended up 13.60 points, or 0.55 percent, at 2,479.77 points after strong gains in neighbouring Dutch financial stocks pulled up the Belgian sector.</p>
<p>Fortis AG rose 3.50 percent to 7,990 francs, slightly lagging its Dutch sister Fortis Amev, whose shares added 4.17 percent. Dealers said Fortis' gains helped rival insurer Royale Belge. Banks, with the exception of Kredietbank, were also higher.</p>
<p>Traders and analysts said, however, they were looking for industrials, especially dollar-sensitives, to outperform in coming days.</p>
<p>&quot;The strong dollar means a lot of results will be good, especially for cyclicals,&quot; Stefan Casteleyn, investment strategist at Corluy &amp; Co said. &quot;The correlation between the dollar and the Belgian market is quite high.&quot;</p>
<p>Although results have already been released by oil group PetroFina, and chemicals groups Solvay and UCB, the bulk are due to be announced from September.</p>
<p>Non-ferrous metals group Union Miniere, which added 15 francs to 3,350, PetroFina, up 25 francs at 14,675, and steel wire and cord maker Bekaert, up 200 francs at 25,000, were among those cited by Casteleyn, other analysts and traders.</p>
<p>One trader UM continued to be animated by a private placement last month of 25 percent by main shareholder Societe Generale de Belgique.</p>
<p>The weight of paper in the market was holding the share in a 3,250-3,400 franc range and he expected it to stay there for some time.</p>
<p>For him, glass maker Glaverbel, which ended up 60 francs at 5,460 after setting a year-high of 5,500 mid-session, was another interesting issue.</p>
<p>The main focus on Thursday - as on Wednesday - was hamburger chain Quick, up 4.76 percent at 2,200.</p>
<p>Having risen nearly 10 percent in two days, the stock would probably be hit by profit-taking on Friday, one trader said, noting it ended off its session high at 2,240 francs.</p>
<p>Despite a 'buy' recommendation from Bank Delen on Wednesday, traders and analysts were mixed on Quick's prospects.</p>
<p>One trader said he was positive on the stock, noting Burger King's decision to pull out of France and the fading impact of Europe's mad cow beef crisis were plus factors.</p>
<p>Corluy's Casteleyn, however, did not believe Quick's growth period would return. Generale Bank said in an investor note it would remain cautious ahead of interim results.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
