<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785359" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algerian chief says &quot;terrorism&quot; challenges humanity.</title>
<headline>Algerian chief says &quot;terrorism&quot; challenges humanity.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algerian President Liamine Zeroual said on Thursday that &quot;terrorism&quot; posed one of the most serious challenges to humanity at the end of this century and called for international cooperation to combat it.</p>
<p>Speaking against a background of years of bloodshed which Algerian officials blame on Moslem fundamentalists, Zeroual said Algeria had made &quot;heavy sacrifices in its struggle against the forces of evil&quot;.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, Algerian newspapers reported another 40 people killed in the past three days, adding to the slaughter of about 700 civilians by suspected Moslem rebels in the past two months.</p>
<p>Last Sunday, Zeroual said the killings defied human understanding.</p>
<p>The reports have detailed young children being decapitated, pregnant women disembowelled, scores of people having their throats cut, and young girls being taken off to &quot;serve&quot; gang leaders before being killed.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Zeroual in a speech delivered to African envoys of the international Interpol police body meeting in Algiers by Interior Minister Mustapha Ben Mansour, said &quot;terrorism&quot; and other crimes were a &quot;veritable scourge menacing the unity, cohesion and stability of African states&quot;.</p>
<p>The emergence of transnational criminality, with &quot;terrorism&quot; as its most dangerous aspect, showed the need for &quot;efficient international cooperation&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Terrorism, one of the most serious challenges to humanity at the end of this century, has shown its true criminal and destructive nature,&quot; Zeroual said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would not have been able to develop and evolve...if  it was not for its connection with drug trafficking, the use of false documents, corruption and other crimes.&quot;</p>
<p>Without naming any country, he added: &quot;Terrorism would not have been able to expand without the complaisance or complicity of certain countries whose objectives gave proved themselves to be in contradiction with international rules.&quot;</p>
<p>Algeria early in its battle against Moslem rebels accused both Iran and Sudan of supporting &quot;terrorism&quot;.</p>
<p>About 60,000 people have been killed since the authorities in the North African country in January 1992 cancelled a general election in which the fundamentalist Islamic Salvation Front (FIS) had taken a huge lead.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
