<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785330" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GIBRALTAR: Gibraltar says willing to probe reported ETA links.</title>
<headline>Gibraltar says willing to probe reported ETA links.</headline>
<dateline>GIBRALTAR 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Gibraltar government said on Thursday it knew nothing of alleged money-laundering in the British colony by the Basque separatist group ETA but would investigate if asked by Spain.</p>
<p>A Gibraltar government spokesman, responding to Spanish newspaper allegations, said he had no information that suspected ETA guerrilla Emilio Arrizabalaga had used businesses in the British colony to launder money obtained from extortion and kidnapping.</p>
<p>Arrizabalaga was arrested in northern Spain last month along with three other ETA rebels suspected of holding Spanish prison warden Jose Antonio Ortega Lara hostage for a year and a half.</p>
<p>Spanish government officials said earlier this week they had uncovered new information with the arrests which may show ETA is involved in money laundering and the drug trade.</p>
<p>The Madrid daily El Pais alleged on Wednesday that Arrizabalaga had a number of real estate businesses in southern Spain which may have had dealings in nearby Gibraltar. The newspaper said Spanish High Court judge Baltasar Garzon was investigating the Gibraltar connection.</p>
<p>&quot;His (Arrizabalaga's) presence in Gibraltar has not been detected and the police in Gibraltar do not open an investigation on the basis on newspaper reports,&quot; the Gibraltar spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gibraltar authorities will act immediately if approached by Spanish authorities,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Gibraltar spokesman said the disputed colony at Spain's southern tip had received no formal or informal request from Madrid to investigate possible links with Arrizabalaga.</p>
<p>Spain has long complained that the tiny strategic territory, which dominates the Straits of Gibraltar, is a haven for drug trafficking and money laundering. In the past year Gibraltar Chief Minister Peter Caruana's government has taken firm action to stem financial crime there.</p>
<p>ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) has come under increased pressure following its killing last month of Basque town councillor Miguel Angel Blanco which caused a national outcry. The government has vowed to crack down on the rebels.</p>
<p>Spanish officials say ETA has evolved into a criminal mafia financed through kidnapping, extortion, robbery and collection of a &quot;revolutionary tax&quot; from wealthy Basque businessmen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GIBRALTAR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GIBRALTAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
