<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785387" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: BOMBAY SHARES TAKE A BEATING, INDEX SLUMPS 1.7 PCT.</title>
<headline>BOMBAY SHARES TAKE A BEATING, INDEX SLUMPS 1.7 PCT.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bombay blue chips closed sharply lower on Thursday battered by aggressive profit-taking by local institutions and speculators, traders said.</p>
<p>Shares turned tail in afternoon trade as a wave of selling orders struck, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was unexpected. A lot of shakeout happened today,&quot; said Balaji Narayan, equities dealer at Prime Broking.</p>
<p>The strength of the reaction, which began late Wednesday, after uninterrupted advances toward all-time highs during the past few days was sudden and took a thin market by surprise, participants said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It appears that a lot of people who jumped on the buying bandwagon are getting out of the market,&quot; said Vetri Subramaniam, institutional sales dealer at SSKI Securities.</p>
<p>Foreign funds were mostly on the sidelines, dealers said.</p>
<p>Profit-taking began on Wednesday, curtailing a five-day old rally that pushed the blue chip index through the psychological 4,600 level at 4,605.41 -- just shy of its all-time high of 4,643.31 set on September 12, 1994.</p>
<p>The Bombay index surged nine percent in five consecutive days till Wednesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;A fall in prices will set the pace for a further jump. We should see some clarity tomorrow,&quot; said Ashith Kampani, head of dealing at JM Share &amp; Stock Brokers.</p>
<p>Indian Finance Minister P. Chidambaram on Thursday denied a newspaper report that he was considering resigning, a spokeswoman said. She told Reuters the finance minister had called the report &quot;false, baseless and mischievous&quot;.</p>
<p>The Business Standard newspaper said Chidambaram was considering the possibility of resigning after the government was forced to withdraw an insurance bill from parliament.</p>
<p>-- Anshuman Daga, Bombay equities desk +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
