<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785429" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan rivals' guns fall silent on Kabul front.</title>
<headline>Afghan rivals' guns fall silent on Kabul front.</headline>
<byline>Brian Williams</byline>
<dateline>QARABAGH, Afghanistan 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fighting died out on Thursday in the siege of Kabul with guns on both sides silent for the first time in a week.</p>
<p>After a series of recent forecasts by the opposition northern alliance about an imminent attack on the Afghan capital, its frontline commander General Besmullah Khan held back from predicting when a final push would be made to wrest control of Kabul from the Islamic fundamentalist Taleban.</p>
<p>Asked if his troops would be in Kabul before the end of this week, this month or the end of this year, Khan replied: &quot;I can't predict it. We spend all our time discussing it.&quot;</p>
<p>After daily battles 30 km (18 miles) northwest of Kabul for the past week, the guns fell silent on Wednesday night after a final flurry of fighting in which rebels said they gained control of the hills that look across flat plains to Kabul.</p>
<p>&quot;We have cleaned out pockets of Taleban resistance on their northwest front and have stabilised our lines on the entire front,&quot; Khan told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now in the strategic position we want to be,&quot; he said. &quot;We control high ground positions from where we can start our Kabul offensive whenever we want.&quot;</p>
<p>Khan said that in the week's fighting, a total of 85 Taleban soldiers, including 30 on Wednesday night, were killed and 12 tanks were either destroyed or badly damaged.</p>
<p>In Wednesday night's fighting, he said, four opposition fighters died and 12 were wounded, taking total alliance casualties in the week to 14 dead and 35 wounded.</p>
<p>Driving up to the front on Thursday, small groups of soldiers were seen for the first heading back from the front to nearby villages for rest and recuperation.</p>
<p>Some villagers were also seen heading for their homes in the main fighting area to see if any of their belongings remained.</p>
<p>Khan said that in a Taleban bombing attack on Wednesday night, four civilians were killed and 12 wounded, several of them buried under debris in a village near Kalakkan.</p>
<p>With the fighting on hold for the moment, there were hopes there could be progress on the diplomatic front by Pakistani and U.N. envoys to head off a bloody street battle for Kabul.</p>
<p>Pakistan has been trying to mediate intra-Afghan peace talks, and U.N. special envoy Norbert Holl was in the southern town of Kandahar on Thursday for talks with Taleban officials.</p>
<p>Khan said the alliance wanted to do everything possible to avoid civilian casualties if and when it attacked Kabul.</p>
<p>&quot;We would prefer to avoid even a nose bleed among Kabul residents,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Khan said the Taleban had thrown its best troops into the fighting but had been unable to drive the alliance back from advances during the past two months in which it had wrested control of many parts of the country. &quot;The Taleban are having to call up raw recruits into their forces now, (and) we are finding it easier to keep them at bay,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Khan said opposition monitoring of Taleban field radios indicated there had even been some infighting among government forces about how to conduct the frontline battle.</p>
<p>&quot;The Taleban morale has become low. We are always hearing arguments on the radio,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Taleban, who control two-thirds of Afghanistan, have vowed to take the whole country and rid it of warlords it blames for chaos since the defeat of the communist regime five years ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QARABAGH, Afghanistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
