<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785595" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EUROBOND ACTIVITY DOMINATED BY DOLLAR-BLOC DEALS.</title>
<headline>EUROBOND ACTIVITY DOMINATED BY DOLLAR-BLOC DEALS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Primary market activity focused on the dollar-bloc on Thursday as several retail-targeted issues were launched against the backdrop of firm U.S. assets.</p>
<p>Leading the way was the Inter-American Development Bank which partly rolled over a maturing $700 million bond with a $200 million three-year Eurobond reoffered at a yield flat to U.S. Treasuries via SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to see some redemption flow go into this issue particularly as they are the same (6.00 percent) coupon,&quot; a syndicate manager at the lead said, adding the launch had gone ahead with several orders already on the book.</p>
<p>SBC Warburg said it had seen good demand in the World Bank issue launched July 24 by Commerzbank which has tightened to two b.p. through U.S. Treasuries from its flat reoffer spread.</p>
<p>&quot;We felt that IADB at 2 b.p. cheaper would offer some value. Retail tend to stick to the shorter maturities in this curve environment, where everything is fairly flat and volatile-especially ahead of the numbers coming out next week.&quot;</p>
<p>Demand for today's deal came from Swiss and German investors, with some institutional demand from the Middle East.</p>
<p>During the afternoon session paper was bid flat to U.S. Treasuries on broker screens.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Merrill Lynch, which has had more than a modicum of success recently with several self-led deals, scored again with a $300 million four-year deal at a 41 b.p. spread over the three-year U.S. Treasury note.</p>
<p>Dealers said the issue quickly tightened through the 40 b.p. level. Merrill Lynch is rated Aa3/AA-.</p>
<p>Yamalo-Nenets joined a long queue of Russian regions and cities planning Eurobond issues.</p>
<p>The autonomous region, located in Russia's Far North, announced plans for a $100-150 million Eurobond later this year, with the lead manager due to be picked later this month.</p>
<p>Yamalo-Nenets contains most of Russia's gas reserves and is a rarity in not getting financial help from the federal budget.</p>
<p>It is also planning a domestic bond worth 1.5 trillion roubles ($260 billion) in by September.</p>
<p>-- Dan Lalor, London newsroom +44 171 542 8863</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
