<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785735" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold fixes easier, sector under pressure.</title>
<headline>London gold fixes easier, sector under pressure.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Precious metal prices were under some pressure on Thursday as Europe came into line with overnight moves elsewhere, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets are pretty quiet but they don't look that great,&quot; one dealer said, emphasising the platinum group metals (PGMs) looked particularly vulnerable.</p>
<p>Gold was fixed at $318.95 down 40 cents from Wednesday afternoon and compared with a close of $319.50/$320.00.</p>
<p>The dollar's ability to hold around 1.88 to the mark and near highs against the yen was deflecting interest from gold as the exchange rate pushed up prices in domestic currencies discouraging buying and even provoking long liquidation.</p>
<p>Gold's technical background was turning weaker also  suggesting a probe to $315.00-$317.00 and some dealers suggested the 12-year low just under $314.00 could be tested.</p>
<p>Another bear issue was the risk of producer hedging on any uptick. &quot;There is a lot of hedging still to be done out there,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The expiry of options on the New York's Comex gold and silver futures markets on Friday was likely to hold prices around current levels until next week, dealers said.</p>
<p>However they said any option-related play on Comex was more likely to take gold lower rather than higher.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold is in a $317-$320 range for the moment,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Platinum and palladium were both sharply lower after losing ground through long liquidation on Nymex and a limit-down move on Tokyo's Tocom futures exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese liquidation wiped out all the gains of the past three days and put the market under renewed pressure,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The Japanese selling followed the widening of daily limits on Tocom after six limit up sessions and a sell-off on Nymex which was said to include selling by a hedge fund</p>
<p>Russia's few deliveries to Japan and sporadic parcels being sold in Europe had taken some of the heat out of the markets' illiquidity.</p>
<p>Even so, one-month lease rates for platinum and palladium were still being quoted at a historically colossal 20 percent and 80 percent respectively.</p>
<p>Silver was two cents easier at $4.34/$4.36 after attempts to take it through the bullish $4.50-$4.55 chart point were abandoned on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It was forecast to settle into a $4.30-$4.40 range at least until the option expiry was out of the way after close of business on Friday.</p>
<p>--Brian Spoors London Newsroom +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
