<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78570" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PLO begins evacuating Israeli troops from Nablus.</title>
<headline>PLO begins evacuating Israeli troops from Nablus.</headline>
<byline>Atef Saed</byline>
<dateline>NABLUS, West Bank 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian security forces began evacuating Israeli soldiers trapped at a West Bank shrine after PLO policemen and Palestinian demonstrators overran an Israeli position on Thursday, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Palestinians said at least six soldiers were killed in gun battles with Palestinian policemen. Israeli military sources said another seven soldiers were wounded in the clashes which also included Palestinian stone-throwers.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the Palestinian governor of Nablus drove out four Israeli officers among the 42 soldiers who were trapped at the traditional tomb of the biblical Joseph in self-ruled Nablus.</p>
<p>Palestinian security sources said the Israelis did not want to completely abandon the site, relinquishing control to the PLO. But the Israelis wanted to ensure the safety of soldiers who would stay behind.</p>
<p>Israel deployed armoured personnel carriers outside Nablus. But a Palestinian flag flew over the domed tomb instead of the Israeli flag.</p>
<p>Under self-rule deals that expanded Palestinian self-rule in the West Bank, the tomb remained under Israeli control. Yasser Arafat's Palestinian Authority controls the rest of the city of 130,000 Arabs.</p>
<p>The force was trapped at the shrine, holy to Moslems and Jews, when PLO security forces and Palestinian demonstrators overran it earlier on Thursday.</p>
<p>Israeli army general Uzi Dayan said a &quot;real battle&quot; took place around the tomb. Israel Radio said Israeli efforts to rescue the soldiers failed and that a number of military vehicles were burned.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a real battle there,&quot; Dayan, the Israeli commander in charge of the West Bank, said of the fighting around the tomb.</p>
<p>Witnesses said they saw two Israeli armoured personnel carriers and at least six Israeli army jeeps consumed by fire around the site. Damage to the building was evident.</p>
<p>PLO policemen, who took charge of the site after the confrontation, shielded the Israeli soldiers while negotiations began on their evacuation.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to solve this ordeal peacefully,&quot; said Nablus governor Mahmoud al-Alloul. Officers said there were 42 soldiers inside the above-ground tomb made of yellow stone.</p>
<p>Witnesses said Palestinian policemen brought the trapped Israelis soft drinks and water and gave them cellular phones to call their families.</p>
<p>Israel Radio had earlier said Israeli attempts to retake the shrine had failed.</p>
<p>&quot;At Joseph's Tomb, near Nablus, there is a fierce fight...An attempt to break in and rescue the forces from Joseph's Tomb didn't go well and during it several Israeli army jeeps went up in flames,&quot; the radio said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NABLUS, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
