<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785884" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton confers with aides on line-item veto.</title>
<headline>Clinton confers with aides on line-item veto.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton planned to meet Thursday with his economic advisers to discuss a handful of items in the newly enacted tax bill that may fall victim to his line-item veto powers, the White House said.</p>
<p>Clinton, who signed budget and tax legislation on Wednesday, has until midnight Monday to use the authority he was given this year to veto particular items in the measures.</p>
<p>He said during a news conference Wednesday that he expected to issue a line-item veto -- aware that such a move was certain to prompt an immediate court challenge.</p>
<p>&quot;On line-item veto, our deliberations will continue through the weekend on that subject,&quot; White House Press Secretary Mike McCurry said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're down to just a small handful of things that are potential candidates for exercising a veto ... I'd say more one hand,&quot; McCurry said.</p>
<p>He said that Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin, White House Chief of Staff Erskine Bowles and others met at the White House Thursday morning to &quot;continue their analysis of some of the provisions.&quot;</p>
<p>McCurry declined to say when Clinton would act, other than &quot;sometime before midnight Monday.&quot; Aides said privately Clinton might announce his decision on Saturday, during his weekly radio address, or on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
