<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="785894" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: EPIX SEES HIGHER COSTS IN FUTURE PERIODS.</title>
<headline>EPIX SEES HIGHER COSTS IN FUTURE PERIODS.</headline>
<dateline>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>EPIX Medical Inc said Thursday it expects its operating expenses to increase in future periods as its MS-325 product continues to advance through clinical trials.</p>
<p>MS-325 is EPIX's injectable magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) contrast agent designed for multiple cardiovascular indications. EPIX is a developer of MRI contrast agents, which when administered to patients are designed to improve the quality of medical images. EPIX and its partner, Mallinckrodt Inc, announced in June start of Phase II clinical trials for MS-325.  </p>
<p>In addition to the clinical trials for MS-325, EPIX said that during the second quarter of 1997 it initiated a Phase I dose escalation study for MS-325 and formed a collaboration with  DYAX Corp to develop agents for the diagnosis of blood clots.</p>
<p>For the second second quarter ended June 30, EPIX said it posted a net loss of $1.5 million, or $0.17 per share, as compared with a net loss of $1.9 million, or $0.25 per share, on a pro forma basis, for the second quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Revenues for the second quarter ended June 30 were $1.1 million as compared with no revenues for the second quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>For the six months ended June 30, the net loss was $3.3 million, or $0.40 per share, as compared with a net loss of $1.3 million, or $0.16 per share, on a pro forma basis, for the corresponding period of 1996, it said.</p>
<p>The second quarter 1997 results included $900,000 of revenues from a milestone fee earned from Daiichi Radioisotope Laboratories Ltd, its partner in Japan, it said.</p>
<p>In addition, revenues for the second quarter and six month periods of 1997 included $200,000 and $500,000, respectively, from the MS-325 development contract with Mallinckrodt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAMBRIDGE, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
