<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78587" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Moroccan blue chips pull down bourse index.</title>
<headline>Moroccan blue chips pull down bourse index.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca bourse index dropped slightly on Thursday, pulled down mainly by market blue chips, including Societe Nationale d'Investissement and Samir refinery, traders said.</p>
<p>The all share index closed at 430.10 points, down 0.27 percent on the previous session.</p>
<p>The biggest fall was registered by SNI which lost eight dirhams in one session to close at 592 dirhams.</p>
<p>Banque Commerciale du Maroc lost five dirhams to close at 680 dirhams.</p>
<p>BCM is the bourse's largest stock which has a market capitalisation of more than 9.2 billion dirhams.</p>
<p>Morocco's main oil refinery, Samir lost three dirhams to close at one of its lowest levels, 252 dirhams.</p>
<p>This coincided with announcement of its half-year results, which showed a drop of 3.9 percent in turnover to 3.210 billion dirhams ($368.9 million) in the first half of the year compared with the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the government floated 30 percent of the refinery on the Casablanca bourse at 243 dirhams a share.</p>
<p>Wafabank, one of the market blue chips, made no change for the second consecutive session and closed at 505 dirhams.</p>
<p>ONA Group, Morocco's largest private group and one of the main market capitalisation companies, remained also unchanged at 450 dirhams.</p>
<p>First tranche of privatisation bonds, which were issued in January, traded at 1,132 dirhams, up eight dirhams on Wednesday's session.</p>
<p>The second tranche of the bonds, which was issued in May, remained unchanged at 1,076 dirhams.</p>
<p>Both bonds are negotiable on the market or can be converted into equity in future privatisations.</p>
<p>The bourse volume on the official market was 35.4 million up from 29.6 millionn Wednesday.</p>
<p>($1= 8.7 dirhams)</p>
<p>- Rabat newsroom (212-7) 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
