<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786031" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Wall Street lifts German shares near record zone.</title>
<headline>Wall Street lifts German shares near record zone.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>An overnight rally on Wall Street lifted the mood on the wary German share market on Thursday, helping to push prices to healthy gains.</p>
<p>News of a UK interest rate rise added to the positive feeling in Frankfurt, as dealers bet that this move marked the end of rate increases in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;If this had been a U.S. rate rise, people would have got scared,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;But this was neutral to positive for the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Buoyed in particular by a strong performance by utility and bank shares, the 30-share DAX index closed the bourse session up 78.96 points, or 1.8 percent, at 4,414.35 points.</p>
<p>As Wall Street opened higher again during the post-bourse electronic trade, the IBIS DAX index hit a high of 4,460.15 points, just off last month's all-time high of 4,477.70, before settling back to end at 4,428.08 points.</p>
<p>Utility shares, which dealers said had been neglected of late, took centre stage in bourse trade.</p>
<p>Veba AG gained 3.30 marks, or three percent, to 112.60 marks after a moderately well-received interim report.</p>
<p>The company said its first-half net profit advanced to 816 million marks from 743 million marks behind a rise in sales to 39.7 billion marks from 36.6 billion marks -- in line with forecasts.</p>
<p>Rival RWE AG leapt 5.3 percent to 86.90 marks.</p>
<p>Among banks, Deutsche Bank AG jumped 2.6 percent to 119.75 while Commerzbank AG, persistently cited as a takeover candidate, rose 3.3 percent to 63.45 marks.</p>
<p>Sportswear group Adidas AG surged 12.50 marks to 230.50 marks after reporting results on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Paribas Capital Markets raised Adidas to buy from no action, citing the outlook for Adidas to keep up high double-digit gains in sales and operating profit for 1997.</p>
<p>Commerzbank raised its six-month price target for the share to 250 marks.</p>
<p>Dealers said fears over the outlook for German interest rates were still hampering the market and were likely to brake prices from a sustained breach of old records this week.</p>
<p>However rate hike worries were waning somewhat as the dollar appeared to calm against the deutschemark, and traded well below this week's highs of 1.89 marks on Thursday at around 1.875 marks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
