<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786016" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chevron seeks removal of judge in pollution case.</title>
<headline>Chevron seeks removal of judge in pollution case.</headline>
<dateline>NEW ORLEANS 1997-08-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Attorneys for Chevron Corp. argued on Wednesday that a black federal judge presiding over a trial accusing the oil giant of &quot;environmental racism&quot; was biased and should be removed from the case.</p>
<p>In a hearing before a three-judge panel of the U.S. Fifth Circuit Court of Appeals, the attorneys said U.S. District Judge Kenneth Hoyt had made rulings and racist comments that precluded a fair trial.</p>
<p>The case involves a suit brought by residents of a black neighbourhood who say their homes were built over old oil pits which have caused health problems such as lupus.</p>
<p>&quot;What we're here about is a fundamental problem Judge Hoyt has about race in relation to science and medicine,&quot; Chevron attorney Marie Yeates told the panel.</p>
<p>Plaintiffs' attorney John O'Quinn said Hoyt should continue presiding over the trial, being held in Houston, because it was already two months old. It has been suspended until the court rules on Chevron's motion to remove Hoyt.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot find any case where a judge was removed for intemperate comments. The final test should be what does he do when the rubber meets the road,&quot; O'Quinn said.</p>
<p>Residents of the neighbourhood are suing Chevron for an estimated $500 million.</p>
<p>The pits were used in the 1920s by Gulf Oil to store crude oil, then emptied and used as a pasture until 1968 when a development company bought the land and built houses on it for what was intended to be a &quot;Negro neighbourhood,&quot; according to testimony.</p>
<p>Chevron is being sued because it bought Gulf in 1985, but denies that the pits caused excessive health problems.</p>
<p>Last month Hoyt refused to allow Chevron to put into evidence a study showing blacks generally have a higher rate of lupus. He said he would not admit it &quot;because white people wrote it.&quot;</p>
<p>Hoyt also said that physical differences among races were the product of their environments.</p>
<p>&quot;Why do you think Chinese people are short? Because there is so much damn wind over there they need to be short. Why are they so tall in Africa? Because they need to be tall. It's environmental,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I mean, you don't jump up and get a banana off a tree if you're only 4 feet. If you're 7 feet tall and you're standing in China, then you're going to get blown away by that Siberian wind, aren't you?&quot; Hoyt said.</p>
<p>Hoyt, in a memo to the appellate court, admitted his comments were &quot;callous,&quot; but said he feared that Chevron was looking for a more sympathetic judge.</p>
<p>The panel did not rule on Wednesday, but one of the judges, Jerry Smith, indicated that Hoyt had acted improperly.</p>
<p>&quot;If there were a white federal district judge who discounted a study because black people wrote it, I can guarantee you we wouldn't even be here hearing this argument,&quot; he said from the bench.</p>
<p>&quot;I can guarantee we'd send that judge packing in three minutes and may have sent him packing quicker if it was said in a joking way,&quot; Smith said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW ORLEANS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
