<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786047" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: KINNEVIK BOOSTS MTG CAPITAL FOR SPIN-OFF.</title>
<headline>KINNEVIK BOOSTS MTG CAPITAL FOR SPIN-OFF.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish holding company Kinnevik said on Thursday it would capitalise its media subsidiary Modern Times Group (MTG) in a bid to prepare it for the planned spin-off to shareholders on September 15.</p>
<p>Kinnevik said in an MTG earnings statement that it changed more than 750 million crowns of its net claims on MTG to shareholders' equity of 326 million crowns and a convertible promissory note of 424 million crowns.</p>
<p>The loan will expire at the end of 2000 and carries three percent interest.</p>
<p>Kinnevik will also transfer capital through an option for MTG to buy 1.55 million shares in Millicom International Cellular (MIC) at a redemption price of 100 million crowns, corresponding to a premium of about 600 million crowns.</p>
<p>The option corresponds to nine percent of Kinnevik's 34 percent stake in MIC whose value has risen to 7.5 billion crowns from 3.6 billion from the start of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;The choice to have an option for the additional funds can mainly be attributed to tax reasons,&quot; Kinnevik's chief executive Stig Nordin said in the statement.</p>
<p>After the capitalisation, MTG's equity-to-assets ratio will be 51 percent, excluding the option.</p>
<p>MTG's loss after financial items widened to 193 million crowns for the first half of 1997 from a loss of 74 million a year earlier, Kinnevik said.</p>
<p>Its operating result swung to a loss of 164 million crowns from a profit of 43 million crowns. The 1996 first half figure included a one-off net positive effect of 145 million crowns from changing over to a new satellite platform.</p>
<p>&quot;The considerable softening of the Scandinavian currencies against currencies in which MTG has a large part of its costs has had a significant impact on MTG's result in the period,&quot; Kinnevik said.</p>
<p>It added results from MTG's cost savings programme, initiated in 1996, were gradually showing and repeated that further cost savings were underway.</p>
<p>-- Birgitta Forsberg, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
