<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786077" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: SWEDISH RIKSBANK NERVOUS ABOUT CROWN/DLR - DEALERS.</title>
<headline>SWEDISH RIKSBANK NERVOUS ABOUT CROWN/DLR - DEALERS.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish foreign exchange dealers who have noticed the central bank, the Riksbank, intervening twice this week, said on Thursday the bank was probably concerned about the crown losing ground to the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;The Riksbank is probably a bit worried about the dollar-crown rate,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;The crown is very weak against the dollar and was at 8.10 crowns earlier today and then fell back to 8.08 after the Riksbank intervened.&quot;</p>
<p>As dollar-crowns are not traded in the market, the Riksbank bought crowns for mark at around 4.3120 crowns a mark earlier on Thursday and at about 4.3150-4.32 on Tuesday this week.</p>
<p>Traders stressed that the Riksbank did not trade large sums.</p>
<p>&quot;The Riksbank only wants to point to where it wants the crown to be,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>While the crown was relatively strong against the mark at 4.3000 at 1230 GMT compared with 4.4420 at the end of 1996, it has softened significantly against the dollar, to 8.0590 from 6.8459 on December 31, 1996.</p>
<p>Last week's crown move above 8.00 to the dollar was the first time the Swedish unit entered this level since March 1994.</p>
<p>Other dealers merely said that the Riksbank is active in the market when the crown makes sudden movements against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;The Riksbank steps in when the crown moves too quickly just to put the brakes on, not to show at what level the crown should be,&quot; a trader said, adding that trade was thin at the moment and the crown easily moved.</p>
<p>The Riksbank never comments on interventions but has previously said it will step into the market to smooth out sudden fluctuations.</p>
<p>-- Birgitta Forsberg, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
