<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786483" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: PRESS DIGEST -- HK NEWSPAPER HEADLINES -- AUG 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST -- HK NEWSPAPER HEADLINES -- AUG 7.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Hong Kong press. Reuter has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>--SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- Shares in Jardines companies surged yesterday as news of tycoon Li Ka-shing's stakes in the stocks dominated the market for a second day and attention turned to the next move.</p>
<p>--HONGKONG STANDARD -- Beijing had announced it would go ahead with a controversial plan to revamp its huge, ailing state sector by promoting a shareholding system in small and medium-sized state enterprises.</p>
<p>--Property tycoon Li Ka-shing could be forming a tactical alliance with Ho Ying-kit of Hong Kong Tobacco Co to increase the equity stakes of Cheung Kong and Hutchison Whampoa in Hongkong Land.</p>
<p>--TA KUNG PAO -- The new chief of the New China News Agency , Jiang Enzhu, stressed upon his arrival hin Hong Kong that the agency wouild not interfere in the Special Administrative Region's internal affairs.</p>
<p>--China's religious figures and experts attending a seminar in Beijing said that a recent American report that had accused China of not allowing religious freedom was unfounded.</p>
<p>--APPLE DAILY -- Sources said that an influential figure had decided to intervene to bring Macau's gangster war to an end. A sum of money would be paid to triad chief &quot;Broken Teeth Koi&quot; for him to withdraw, while his followers who were willing to stay on would have to obey new rules agreed by all parties.</p>
<p>--MING PAO -- Illegitimate children of Hong Kong men and their Filipino domestic helpers were planning to join the battle of Chinese illegal immigrant children, in demanding the right of abode in Hong Kong. A test case had been selected.</p>
<p>--SING TAO -- Mainland bookstores and restaurants were secretly selling banned books such as &quot;An Angry God&quot; and &quot;Princelings.&quot; which were popular among Chinese readers in China, Hong Kong and overseas. These books tell the inside stories of corruption among China's top leadership.</p>
<p>--WEN WEI PO -- Primary schools in Beijing were having problems enroling new pupils this year, because of a sharp drop in the number of six-year-old children who were born in 1991 which, according to Chinese traditional signs, was the year of the Goat. Because Beijingers believe that the year of Goat bring bad fortune, most parents avoided having children in that year. Newsroom (852) 28436441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
