<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786515" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: SHANGHAI T-BILL REPO RATES, SPOTS END MOSTLY DOWN.</title>
<headline>SHANGHAI T-BILL REPO RATES, SPOTS END MOSTLY DOWN.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Contracts on the treasury bill repurchase market in Shanghai closed mostly lower on Thursday on a technical correction after sharp gains in the past two days, traders said.</p>
<p>The annual rate for the most actively traded seven-day contract fell slightly to 10.70 percent from 10.78 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Total turnover on the six-contract market fell slightly to 2.16 million lots from 2.48 million lots.</p>
<p>One lot is 1,000 yuan face value of treasury bills.  </p>
<p>&quot;The repo rates saw a technical correction today,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Although several new firms will debut on the stock markets today and tomorrow, institutions had borrowed enough money in the past two days to cover trading in the new shares.&quot;</p>
<p>A domestic A share firm listed on the Shanghai stock exchange on Thursday and another is to debut on Friday.</p>
<p>An A share company is to list shares in Shenzhen on Friday and a B share firm is to make its debut in Shanghai.</p>
<p>Traders said the repo rates were likely to rise slightly on Friday, gaining some support from the new issues, which would boost fund demand on the repo market.  </p>
<p>Contracts on the T-bill spot market in Shanghai ended mostly down on Thursday in thin volume partly due to the strong performance of the domestic A share markets, which sucked funds out of the spot market, traders said.</p>
<p>The most actively traded seven-year bond that matures in August 2003 was at 99.78 yuan from 99.88 yuan.</p>
<p>Combined volume on the eight-contract market fell to 511,925 lots from 666,663 lots.</p>
<p>Traders said they saw spot contracts consolidating in the short term if A share markets continued to perform strongly.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
