<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78658" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Investment whiz kid charged in IPO, bank fraud.</title>
<headline>Investment whiz kid charged in IPO, bank fraud.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>A young money manager touted as the next Warren Buffett was charged with fraud Thursday in the 1995 public offering of a reinsurance company he founded and for lying to Chemical Bank to obtain $24 million in loans.</p>
<p>The charges accuse 31-year-old Christopher Bagdasarian along with a former partner at Deloitte &amp; Touche, LLP of providing false information in last year's offering of Omaha, Neb.-based Normandy America Inc.</p>
<p>In an unusual move, the initial public offering was pulled from the Nasdaq market on Aug. 16, 1995, after one day of trading. Lead underwriter Salomon Brothers had said at the time that the IPO was withdrawn due to market conditions.</p>
<p>Bagdasarian, the founder, chairman and chief executive officer of Normandy America was frequently compared in the financial press last year to Warren Buffett because of his flashy investment track record.</p>
<p>Bagdasarian, who lives in Montecito, Calif., had stated in his Securities and Exchange Commission filing prior to last year's IPO that he had been managing money for 10 years, providing his investors with an annualized return of 29 percent. He said that he began with $37 million in 1984 and ended up managing more than $700 million.</p>
<p>This would have meant the defendant was 19 when he had $37 million.</p>
<p>Bagdasarian was named in an eight-count criminal complaint filed by the Manhattan U.S. attorney's office and during a court hearing waived his right to an indictment by a federal grand jury.</p>
<p>His lawyer Michael Armstrong would not comment on whether Bagdasarian would later plead guilty to the charges, as sometimes happens when a defendant is charged in a complaint rather than by indictment.</p>
<p>If convicted, he faces up to 165 years in prison and a $5.75 million fine.</p>
<p>Samuel White, 35, of La Canada, Calif., a certified public accountant and former partner in Deloitte &amp; Touche's Los Angeles office was named in an eight-count indictment. White, who provided accounting and tax advise to Bagdasarian, faces the same penalties.</p>
<p>Both men are accused of conspiracy to commit securities fraud, bank fraud and perjury. They were also sued by the SEC on related civil charges.</p>
<p>Bagdasarian claimed his investment success as investment manager and president of California-based Criterion Holdings, Inc. He said he made investments on behalf of himself and others through Criterion and its broker-dealer subsidiary.</p>
<p>Prosecutors allege that the scheme began in February 1992, when Bagdasarian first approached Chemical seeking an $8 million standby letter of credit that he needed for his planned purchase of a Gulfstream IV aircraft.</p>
<p>In connection with his request, he represented himself as a highly successful investment manager and owned a portfolio of &quot;blue-chip&quot; securities valued at more than $130 million.</p>
<p>He was able to get about $24.55 million in loans and other credits from Chemical Bank from 1992 through 1994 by allegedly lying about the value of his securities and cash holdings. White allegedly assisted in the scheme by wrongfully verifying that Deloitte had confirmed Bagdasarian's holdings.</p>
<p>The men vastly overstated the value of Bagdasarian's portfolio claiming that it reached more than $521 million, prosecutors alleged.</p>
<p>In the second part of the scheme, Bagdasarian approached Salomon seeking its assistance in raising capital for Normandy America. Salomon, along with Alex Brown &amp; Co. and Schroder Wertheim &amp; Co. agreed to underwrite the $196.4 million initial public offering and a $20.6 million private placement.</p>
<p>The complaint alleges that in August 1994 he falsely represented to Salomon that he had achieved multi-year returns of about 30 percent per year on about $700 million in assets under his management. Bagdasarian and White allegedly represented that the securities were held in about 30 entities located outside the United States.</p>
<p>They resisted Salomon's request for details by claiming the structure of the offshore entities were created by and was proprietary to Deloitte.</p>
<p>Prosecutors also allege that when Salomon tried to interview people whose assets were invested with Bagdasarian, the defendant recruited a Normandy employee to impersonate an investor who claimed that he had achieved 20 percent returns on his investment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
