<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786521" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia seen importing rice if drought extends.</title>
<headline>Indonesia seen importing rice if drought extends.</headline>
<byline>K.T. Arasu</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia is likely to import rice if the El Nino weather pattern prolongs a drought sweeping across the archipelago, industry sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see some imports towards the end of this year if the weather turns against Indonesia,&quot; a senior trader said. &quot;This will certainly be against the wishes of the government, which takes pride in being self-sufficient in rice.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Indonesia's current stock of more than three million tonnes of rice is adequate, but if the famous El Nino hits here, the odds are the situation could very well get out of hand.&quot;</p>
<p>Another trader said he expected purchases to begin in the third quarter of this year if there are indications the drought would last beyond October.</p>
<p>&quot;We could very well see import business being done in the third quarter of this year,&quot; he added. &quot;There have been no purchases so far this year, although some orders placed one or two years ago arrived early this year.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Outstanding contracts, by and large, have been executed,&quot; he said, adding that the government would strive to ensure that local prices remain stable especially with the presidential elections scheduled for next March.</p>
<p>President Suharto, who takes a personal interest in the country's rice situation, is widely expected to be re-elected for a seventh term in office. The election is usually followed by the formation of a new cabinet of ministers.</p>
<p>&quot;Rice is a very political issue, more so now with the change in government that is going to take place,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>There is absolutely no way the authorities will run the risk of any shortfall as far as rice is concerned, he added.</p>
<p>The traders said it was still early to forecast the amount of rice Indonesia would need to import, adding that the country currently held relatively high levels of stocks.</p>
<p>Beddu Amang, head of the state logistics agency, BULOG, told parliament last month that rice stocks stood at 3.2 million tonnes, sufficient to supply the nation for six months.</p>
<p>&quot;This level is the highest we have had in the last 12 years. This will make our job of controlling rice prices much easier,&quot; Amang told the parliamentary commission hearing.</p>
<p>He said unhusked rice production was expected to decline 0.92 percent this year from 51.1 million tonnes in 1996.</p>
<p>A severe drought in 1994 forced Indonesia, the world's fourth-most populous country with more than 200 million people, to import rice for the first time in a decade since it became self-sufficient in the staple.</p>
<p>The El Nino effect is part of a natural cycle and normally occurs every three to five years and lasts for about 12 months. It can cause drought from China and Australia to Indonesia and India, with profound consequences on fishing and agriculture.</p>
<p>The warm-ocean phenomenon has been building up since April in the Pacific and could reach the record temperatures set in 1982/83 if current trends continue.</p>
<p>Peruvian fishermen dubbed the weather phenomenon &quot;El Nino&quot;, or &quot;the child&quot;, after the baby Jesus because it tends to peak at Christmas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
