<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786642" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: S.E. Asian currencies rest ahead of more Thai news.</title>
<headline>S.E. Asian currencies rest ahead of more Thai news.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Desai</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southeast Asian currencies continued to track now well-worn ranges on Thursday as players awaited news of the amount of aid Thailand would receive from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and other countries.</p>
<p>An international monetary source in Tokyo said Thailand and the IMF could reach agreement on a financial support package this week, and that the amount of the package was unlikely to exceed $15 billion.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market was also keeping an eye on possible political repercussions from Thailand's move to suspend an additional 42 finance firms as this had prompted a two-day run on deposits at smaller institutions.</p>
<p>In Thailand, the baht slipped on commercial dollar demand from importers and foreign loan borrowers. It was quoted at 31.60/75 to the dollar at 0430 GMT against 31.50/65 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The offshore rate was at 31.12/22 against 30.90/31.00.</p>
<p>Singapore dealers said vague rumours about political unrest continued to circulate despite recent denials by Thai officials.</p>
<p>&quot;There's overall concern about a cabinet reshuffle again. There could be a change in the political scenery because the Thais are quite unhappy,&quot; a senior European bank dealer said.</p>
<p>Chia Woon Khien, head of Asian research at Skandinaviska Enskilda Banken in Singapore, said the Thai government's package of tough measures to bring down the current account deficit and curb inflation would be very good for the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately the pressure (on Thailand) is not so much foreign now, it's domestic. In the Thai newspapers there are suggestions that the Prime Minister should step down,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;If Chavalit cannot hold on, the baht could be subject to more selling pressure,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The Taiwan dollar plunged to its lowest level since 1988 on heavy offshore buying of the U.S. dollar in the form of non-delivery forward trading.</p>
<p>Dealers said the Taiwan dollar had dipped briefly to a low of T$28.90 in morning trade and was expected to test T$29. It was quoted at T$28.84 at midday against Wednesday's T$28.656 close.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry announced a higher than expected 61.2 percent drop in Taiwan's July trade surplus, to T$14.09 billion from a T$36.28 billion surplus a year ago.</p>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah enjoyed some respite as fears the central bank might impose capital controls faded.</p>
<p>Jakarta dealers said sentiment on the rupiah turned upbeat after a central bank meeting with foreign bank representatives on Wednesday did not deal with foreign exchange controls.</p>
<p>Currency markets had been rife with rumours that Bank Indonesia planned to follow Malaysia in limiting non-trade related swap transactions by domestic banks.</p>
<p>Bank Indonesia said the talks with foreign bankers was just an exchange of views about the forex market.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah was at 2.583/88 at 0430 GMT against 2,591/96 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Malaysian ringgit suffered continued poor sentiment but talk that offshore players were looking to sell the dollar around 2.6400 ringgit capped its decline for the time being.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/ringgit still has potential to move up again. They have relatively bad fundamentals at the moment,&quot; the Singapore dealer said, citing Malaysia's yawning trade deficit for June and uncertainty over the future of the $5.5 billion Bakun hydroelectric dam project.</p>
<p>The ringgit was at 2.6345/85 to the dollar against 2.6345/75 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Singapore dollar benefitted from some early corporate sales of the U.S. dollar, which pushed it to a high of 1.4688. But it soon slipped back through the 1.47 level and was quoted at 1.4715/25, little changed from Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Philippine peso remained weak but confined to its expected range of 28.40-28.70 to the dollar. The central bank quoted an offer rate for the dollar at 28.70.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
