<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786746" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: FOCUS-Malaysia money growth raises overheating fear.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Malaysia money growth raises overheating fear.</headline>
<byline>Madhav Reddy</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's surprisingly high loans and money-supply growth figures for June, despite measures by the central Bank Negara to curb them, mean there is still a risk of overheating in the economy, economists said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Bank Negara announced late on Wednesday that broad money supply M3 grew by 21.9 percent year-on-year in June against 20.3 percent in May and 22.9 percent in the same month last year.</p>
<p>Loans growth in June rose to an annualised 30 percent from 29.5 percent at the end of May.</p>
<p>The economists said while the figures by themselves would not have any major impact on the country's economy, a sustained high growth in money supply could be worrisome for Malaysia.</p>
<p>&quot;This just shows all the measures that they have been trying out are not biting hard enough,&quot; said Chia Woon Khien, economist with Skandinaviska Enskilda Banken in Singapore.</p>
<p>Bank Negara has engineered a relatively high interest rate regime since the beginning of last year and in March this year announced curbs on lending for property and share purchases.</p>
<p>Chia said the money supply numbers showed that funds have been shifting out of a falling stock market and inflating liquidity in the banking system.</p>
<p>At the same time, the banking system was able to find borrowers despite the relatively high interest rates, which have risen by over one percentage point in the last one year.</p>
<p>&quot;It boils down to the fact that interest rates are just not high enough to curb spending in the economy,&quot; she said, adding that the Malaysian economy was showing signs of overheating.</p>
<p>Responding to international concerns of overheating and inflationary pressures in the economy, Malaysia brought down the economy's growth to 8.2 percent last year from 9.5 percent in 1995, in large part by raising interest rates.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Bank Negara also promised to rein in credit growth and broad money supply by maintaining a tight monetary policy. Last year, M3 expanded by 22.7 percent, and the central bank set a target of bringing it down to 20 percent.</p>
<p>But, Chia said there was no reason to believe that monetary growth was easing. &quot;Loan growth came off a bit at the beginning of the year to 28.5 pct in April, but has picked up since.&quot;</p>
<p>But some economists said the June monetary figures were just a monthly aberration and the situation was well under control.</p>
<p>&quot;The number came in a bit stronger than we had been expecting,&quot; said David Cohen, senior economist with MMS International in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;But this will not make much of a difference in the short term. Near-term pressure on ringgit is more than enough to keep a tighter grip on money supply,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The ringgit has been under heavy selling pressure for over a month, losing over five percent against the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>An economist at a foreign brokerage in Kuala Lumpur said loan growth could be peaking, though a trend would only emerge once July and August numbers were known.</p>
<p>&quot;The June growth may look a bit frightening but I don't think it's alarming. The economy is not heating up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank Negara curbs on loans should start to show on the year-on-year figures by August. We are looking at loan growth in the mid-20s by year-end,&quot; the economist said.</p>
<p>He believes the pick-up in June growth was partly due to loans taken by Ekran Bhd chairman Ting Pek Khiing to finance his purchase of the unsubscribed portion of the company's rights issue.</p>
<p>Ekran recently completed a rights issue of 257.1 million shares. It was undersubscribed by 62.77 percent, forcing Ting to pick up over 90 percent of the unwanted portion for 859.8 million ringgit ($325.68 million).</p>
<p>($1=2.64 ringgit)</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
