<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786883" id="root" date="1997-08-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: FEATURE - Bulgarian car thieves don't spare Ladas, Trabants.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Bulgarian car thieves don't spare Ladas, Trabants.</headline>
<byline>Liliana Semerdjieva</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Even the humble Trabant is not immune from Bulgaria's car thieves.</p>
<p>The far from environmentally friendly little car is no longer made in former East Germany but spare parts are in demand to keep Bulgaria's Trabbies on the road.</p>
<p>A Lada may attract only jokes in Western Europe, but here it is more often than not fitted with a car alarm, though they do not always prevent theft.</p>
<p>The alarms are frequently ignored as even the vibration of a passing tram can set them off, and sophisticated young Bulgarians know how to neutralise them from a distance.</p>
<p>More than 10,000 cars disappear from Bulgaria's streets each year and some are re-exported. Car thefts make up one fifth of all reported crime.</p>
<p>Organised groups, often working with gangs in Western Europe, modify their appearance, change the licence plates, scrape off engine and chassis numbers and engrave new ones to match forged documents, police say.</p>
<p>Police said in June they were looking for 51,400 stolen cars, all luxury makes such as Mercedes, BMW, Audi and Porsche.</p>
<p>A recent check of 10 luxury vehicles in the Danube river port of Silistra showed that six had been stolen in Germany, France and Italy.</p>
<p>The new government which took office in May has vowed to fight organised crime, which flourished in the adminstrative chaos that followed the end of one-party rule in 1989.</p>
<p>The first step was to bring outdated crime laws in line with European Union legal codes. Parliament adopted amendments to the penal and criminal codes in July.</p>
<p>ECONOMIC CRISIS A FACTOR</p>
<p>Any improvement in the figures is due as much to economic crisis as better policing.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason for the current fall in the number of stolen cars is that police have tightened their control on the one hand, but on the other there is a drop in luxury car purchases as the economic crisis soars,&quot; said an interior ministry official.</p>
<p>In the first six months of the year some 5,200 cars of the 1.7 million registered in Bulgaria were stolen, against some 5,700 in the same period last year.</p>
<p>In 1991, some 8,300 cars were stolen, and the number grew steadily to reach a peak of more than 19,000 in 1994. In 1996 some 12,200 owners lost their cars.</p>
<p>Few are recovered. Police found 13.3 percent of stolen cars in the first half of this year compared with 14.8 percent during the same period last year.</p>
<p>Thieves are skilled at disguising or dismantling stolen cars, but since July 1 potential buyers can check the engine and body numbers of vehicles offered for sale.</p>
<p>The first volunteer, from the northern Bulgarian town of Antonovo, found the original engine numbers of the four-wheel-drive Opel Frontera had been treated with chemicals and new ones engraved.</p>
<p>Police said further investigation revealed that the vehicle had been stolen and re-sold four times in the last three years.</p>
<p>&quot;My Ford Escort was stolen in front of the National Palace of Culture in Sofia centre during the day while it was parked only for two hours,&quot; said Stoyan Stoyanov, a businessman from the town of Plovdiv.</p>
<p>&quot;Since then I come here always with somebody to stay in the car while I do business.&quot;</p>
<p>Theft of radios, tyres, petrol or accumulators from parked cars is so commonplace in Sofia that most people don't even bother to report them.</p>
<p>One remedy is the sticker of certain powerful insurance companies, which can serve as a territorial marker warning car thieves to stay away.</p>
<p>When the government tried to ban the stickers earlier this year, saying they could hinder drivers' vision, the insurers hit back with a version that sticks on the back of the rear view mirror.</p>
<p>&quot;I prefer to have an insurers' sticker to keep thieves away,&quot; said engineer Roumen Velchev, who drives an Opel. &quot;Even if my car is stolen, my insurers will find it quickly or replace it with another one.&quot;</p>
<p>In July, police set up a rapid response squad of motorcyclists, equipped with Scorpion automatic rifles, bullet-proof jackets and radios, to crack down on street crime.</p>
<p>But the 100-strong Sigma squad will chase car thieves only during the day. Police say riding a motorcycle through Sofia's potholed streets in the dark is too dangerous.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
