<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="786992" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electricity ends higher in thin volume.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electricity ends higher in thin volume.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures ended higher in thin volume Friday with upward strength coming from some shortcovering, industry sources said.</p>
<p>NYMEX Palo Verde (PV) futures ended up 82 cents at $31.77 per megawatt hour (MWh) following trade at $31.25-31.95, while October finished up 60 cents at $24.10 after trades at $23.60-24.20 per MWh.</p>
<p>Remaining PV deferreds finished between five and 55 cents higher.</p>
<p>September California Oregon Border (COB) closed up 25 cents at $23.40 per MWh following trades at $23.20-23.60, while October closed up 45 cents at $22.95 following exchanges at $22.40-23.50 per MWh.</p>
<p>NYMEX volumes were not immediately available, but were said to be very thin with many players attending a conference in Vancouver, B.C.</p>
<p>Some early strength in PV futures came from rumors of an outage at the Four Corners coal-fired power plant in New Mexico, sources said.</p>
<p>However, the outage is expected to be short lived.</p>
<p>The 750 megawatt (MW) unit 5 at the Four Corners plant, shut late Thursday for repairs, was expected to resume operation Saturday, the operator said Friday.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the 220 MW Four Corners unit 3, resumed operation as expected early today. The other three Four Corners units, the 750 MW unit 4 and two 185 MW units (units 1 and 2) continued to operate at full output, he said.</p>
<p>Shortcovering was also said to be helping push prices higher.</p>
<p>Sizzling heat that smothered most of the Southwest was showing signs of losing its grip.</p>
<p>While some interior sections of the Southwest were still called to see triple-digit heat today, a cooling trend was expected to take root this weekend and bring temperatures back to seasonal summer levels, especially along the coast.</p>
<p>In the Pacific Northwest, descent of an Arctic air mass early next week was forecast to push readings to as much as 10 degrees Fahrenheit below normal in western Canada, Montana and Wyoming. The rest of the region was expected to experience near to slightly above normal temperatures.</p>
<p>Electricity output from the 1,221 MW Palo Verde nuclear power unit 3 in Wintersburg, Ariz., resumed full ouput early Friday after repairs to a condensate pump.</p>
<p>The adjacent 1,221 MW Palo Verde nuclear power unit 2 was operating at 90 percent of capacity as the unit coasts down to a scheduled refueling outage September 6.</p>
<p>The neighboring unit 1, also at 1,221 MW, dipped slightly to 98 percent power as of early Friday.</p>
<p>((--Chris Reese, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1627))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
