<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787005" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Northeast states want Midwest to curb smog fast.</title>
<headline>Northeast states want Midwest to curb smog fast.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Paul</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least five northeastern states plan to ask the U.S. government to force power plants and factories in the Midwest to cut their pollution to help ease smog problems downwind, state officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>The petitions, which could be filed next week, are the latest attempt by the northeastern states to target sources of pollution outside their region in their struggle to meet federal air quality standards.</p>
<p>The five states -- Maine, Vermont, New Hampshire, Massachusetts, and New York -- were part of a group of 32 eastern states which agreed last June to take steps to help each other fight smog in cities with the dirtiest air.</p>
<p>Pennsylvania also is considering filing a petition, a state environmental spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The northeastern states decided to break ranks with the other eastern states because they want air quality to improve faster than under the June agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel we can't wait any longer, that we need immediate action,&quot; said Jennifer Post, a spokeswoman for New York's Department of Environmental Conservation.</p>
<p>Under the Clean Air Act, states can ask the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency to decide in 60 days whether big polluters in one area are adding to smog problems in another state, and then require specific polluters to cut their emissions within three years to help stop the drift.</p>
<p>If the problem is serious enough, the EPA can force the targeted plants to shut down within three months.</p>
<p>&quot;We're trying to take every legal avenue available to address this problem,&quot; Post said.</p>
<p>She said New York did not petition the EPA earlier because the agency had asked the state to take part in a study of eastern regional pollution problems over the last two years.</p>
<p>Based on the study's recommendations, the EPA plans to tell each of the states in September how much of their smog-forming emissions they will have to trim to meet federal ozone limits and help other states meet the standards.</p>
<p>States will then have to decide what steps to take. The group said the cheapest way to meet the standards would be to cut some emissions from power plants by 50 percent to 85 percent.</p>
<p>New Jersey's environmental chief said he would not press the EPA for quicker action, unless the guidelines the agency set out in September were too weak to curb smog flows from the Midwest, because he did not want to alienate other states that helped reach the June agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a lot of good faith involved in that effort,&quot; said New Jersey Environmental Protection Commissioner Robert Shinn.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
