<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78718" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. access to emergency health treatment expanded.</title>
<headline>U.S. access to emergency health treatment expanded.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Doctors were given more leeway to try experimental emergency treatments on critically ill or injured patients who cannot give their informed consent under new rules announced by U.S. health officials Thursday.</p>
<p>The Food and Drug Administration issued final rules to make it easier for people to get experimental drugs and medical devices in life-threatening emergencies. The National Institutes of Health released a companion document on emergency consent waivers.</p>
<p>&quot;These rules address a difficult ethical situation and they apply fair, common sense tests for allowing the use of experimental treatments in life-threatening emergencies,&quot; said Secretary of Health and Human Services Donna Shalala.</p>
<p>Such treatment would only be allowed under strictly defined conditions, when alternatives were unproven or unsatisfactory and where the research followed established rules for clinical trials.</p>
<p>The medical and scientific community have been struggling to determine how to conduct such badly needed research without violating patients' rights to informed consent.</p>
<p>Earlier drafts of the rules were debated and discussed extensively. The final rule will be published in the Federal Register on Oct. 2, and become effective 30 days later.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
