<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787177" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BOXING-JONES TAKES BACK WBC LIGHT HEAVY CROWN, ERASES STIGMA.</title>
<headline>BOXING-JONES TAKES BACK WBC LIGHT HEAVY CROWN, ERASES STIGMA.</headline>
<dateline>LEDYARD, Connecticut 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roy Jones Jr erased the stigma of his loss to Montell Griffin in their first fight by knocking him out in the opening round of their rematch Thursday to reclaim the World Boxing Council light heavyweight crown.</p>
<p>&quot;You can take something away, but I'm going to come and get it back,&quot; Jones said.</p>
<p>Jones, 35-1 with 30 wins inside the distance, had suffered his only pro defeat when he was disqualified for hitting Griffin with two late blows in the ninth round of their first bout in March.</p>
<p>That loss dimmed his mystique as the world's best &quot;pound for pound&quot; fighter, a mythical title the 28-year-old American had laid claim to after winning crowns in the middleweight, super middleweight and light heavyweight divisions.</p>
<p>Jones earned back much of his lost stature with quick vengeance against his fellow American at the Foxwoods Casino.</p>
<p>&quot;I got in the ring with a bad attitude so that's why there was only one round,&quot; said Jones.</p>
<p>Jones put away Griffin, who had already survived a standing eight count, with a thunderous left hook flush to the chin. Griffin fell on the seat of his pants and tried to get up, but could not get off his knees before referee Arthur Mercante Sr counted him out at 2:31 of the first round.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm still number one,&quot; said Jones. &quot;I came here to get one thing. You can beat me, but don't steal nothing from me. I deserve to be the pound for pound best boxer. I'm the best until somebody beats me.&quot;</p>
<p>Since the first fight Jones had steadfastly proclaimed his innocence in hitting Griffin twice when he was already down. Jones criticised referee Tony Perez for not stepping right in and sending him to a neutral corner when Griffin went to one knee to take a respite after absorbing a barrage of blows.</p>
<p>This time, Jones left no doubt, scoring with his first two punches, both left hooks flush to the side of the head. Griffin's legs buckled from the first punch. After the second, he stumbled back across the ring with only the ropes holding him up and Mercante gave Griffin a standing eight count.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no excuses,&quot; said Griffin. &quot;The guy came out quick like I knew he was going to. I tried my best.&quot;</p>
<p>The quick start by Jones was expected, according to Griffin's trainer Thell Torrence.</p>
<p>&quot;Roy did exactly what we thought he would,&quot; said Torrence. &quot;We knew he was going to throw punches and try to get lucky in the early rounds. We are not surprised by the punch that he threw. But it's tough when you get caught cold like that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEDYARD, Connecticut"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
