<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787142" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US T-bond down full point on technicals, supply.</title>
<headline>US T-bond down full point on technicals, supply.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The benchmark U.S. Treasury bond extended early losses to more than a full point decline in late morning trade, hurt technical factors, the weight of recently auctioned supply and a crumbling dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;The selling is sort of snowballing,&quot; said Kevin Flanagan, first vice president and money market economist at Dean Witter Securities Inc. &quot;You don't have a fundamental problem. It's the weight of supply. A lot of weak hands are capitulating. The dollar is moving lower. Bonds are moving lower. Stocks are moving lower. Dollar-denominated assets are getting hit.&quot;  </p>
<p>At 1115 EDT/1515 GMT, the benchmark 30-year bond was down 1-4/32 to 97 even, yielding 6.61 percent, the highest yield the bond has seen since the close on July 3.</p>
<p>Analysts said the market was also a little nervous about data coming next week on July retail sales and industrial production. Investors want to see how strongly consumers will spend in the third quarter after slowing down in the second.</p>
<p>But Flanagan maintained, &quot;It's not a sea change in attitude. The market was overbought. (The declines) are technically driven.&quot;</p>
<p>(( -- Ellen Freilich, North American Treasury Desk 212-859-1679))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
