<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787223" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: ATHLETICS-BIDOUANE PUTS MOROCCAN WOMEN BACK ON MAP.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-BIDOUANE PUTS MOROCCAN WOMEN BACK ON MAP.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nezha Bidouane produced the biggest surprise of the world championships in the women's 400 metres hurdles final on Friday to put a Moroccan woman at the centre of world athletics for only the second time in history.</p>
<p>After hitting the home straight several strides away from Olympic champion Deon Hemmings and defending champion Kim Batten, the 27-year-old Moroccan produced a remarkable last 100 metres and pipped Hemmings on the line with a late burst after the final hurdle.</p>
<p>The triumph gave Morocco only their second women's global title since the 1984 Los Angeles Olympics when the diminutive Nawal El Moutawakel put the country on the athletics map with a triumph in the same event, 13 years ago to the day.</p>
<p>Three days later in Los Angeles, Said Aouita won the men's 5,000 metres and later went on to win the country's only other world title at the 1987 championships in Rome.</p>
<p>&quot;I am the first woman to win a world title for Morocco and I am very proud,&quot; said Bidouane who missed last year's Atlanta Olympics because of an Achilles tendon injury. &quot;The race went the way I had planned it. I knew I had a strong finish.</p>
<p>&quot;The semifinals gave me confidence. I was sad to miss Atlanta but this has made me forget last season,&quot; said the hurdler who is married to steeplechaser Abdelaziz Sahere.</p>
<p>Bidouane, who has never done anything at a major championships before, came home in 52.97 seconds with Hemmings second in 53.09 and world record holder Batten third in 53.52.</p>
<p>Hemmings seemed to be in control of the race at the start at the home straight. But as she tired in the last 10 metres, the Moroccan sneaked through on her inside.</p>
<p>It was the same kind of late dramatic late surge off the final hurdle which Zambia's former male world champion Samuel Matete has made his trademark.</p>
<p>&quot;She did it to us in Rome, I was paying attention to her because I feared that she might do it again,&quot; Hemmings said. &quot;But I didn't think that she could run that fast. She was way behind and she came from nowhere and just passed me. It's amazing.</p>
<p>&quot;In this form she could be in contention for the world record also.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
