<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787356" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE GAS OIL CLOSES AT $169.50, BRENT DOWN 25 CTS.</title>
<headline>IPE GAS OIL CLOSES AT $169.50, BRENT DOWN 25 CTS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE gas oil futures closed down $3 and towards the lows on Friday on good technical selling and weaker underlying physical crude and products, brokers said.</p>
<p>Front month August gas oil settled at $169.50 a tonne, a dollar off the low, after touching a high of $171.00. September settled at $171.00, also down $3.</p>
<p>Chartists put support for August at $169.00 with initial resistance at $171, followed by a gap to $172.</p>
<p>September Brent was trading down 25 cents at $18.65 a barrel on news that Iraq was given the green light by the United Nations to sell oil for the first time since the end of May.</p>
<p>The crude is expected to start flowing next week.</p>
<p>The Brent front month had dipped to a fresh intra-day low of $18.56 after word that the U.N. Sanctions Committee had raised no objections to price formulas for the Iraqi exports.</p>
<p>The underlying Brent cargo market was also weak despite good refining margins on both sides of the Atlantic.</p>
<p>Dated Brent was offered at around September -20 cents, the level Brent was traded on Thursday and some 38 cents lower than the previous reported deal. Offers were around -30 cents.</p>
<p>Oil products were also weak in Europe. A sharp drop in gasoline helped undermine Brent and gas oil barges were narrowly easier, although cargo differentials held firm.</p>
<p>Dealers said there was good demand for diesel into France but German demand was muted with many traders away from the office on holiday.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
