<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787374" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FX IN EUROPE - DLR STUMBLES AS STERLING TUMBLES.</title>
<headline>FX IN EUROPE - DLR STUMBLES AS STERLING TUMBLES.</headline>
<byline>Astrid Zweynert</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar's drop on the back of a tumbling pound took on a life of its own in Europe on Friday as broad-based dollar selling gathered momentum, traders said.</p>
<p>The dollar fell to a two-week trough against the yen and finished at its weakest in a week against the mark and the Swiss franc. It also reversed most of its gains this week against the French franc and the lira.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar's downmove is a reflection of overweight positions in the short term but the price action is not decisive yet,&quot; said Joe Prendergast at Credit Suisse First Boston.  </p>
<p>Prendergast, who is head of global foreign exchange strategy at CSFB, said while the medium-term outlook remained dollar positive there was scope for a move back to the lower 1.80s against the mark. Key support is in the 1.8450/20 zone.</p>
<p>At 1515 GMT the dollar was at 1.8435/45 marks, down from 1.8675/85 in late European trading on Thursday. Against the yen it was at 115.05/12 from 118.37/42.</p>
<p>Next week will be crucial for the dollar's near-term outlook, analysts said. Key will be what the Bundesbank decides on Tuesday when it announces its next repo move amid lingering speculation that it might switch to a variable rate tender.  </p>
<p>&quot;The most likely outcome is another set of fixed repos,&quot; said Ken Wattret, international economist at Paribas in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Assuming the dollar doesn't rapidly gain momentum and threaten 2.0 to the mark, the Bundesbank will tolerate a temporary overshoot of the exchange rate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Forex traders will also keep a close eye on U.S. retail sales and inflation data for July, due out on Wednesday and Thursday respectively, for signs of further robust growth and subdued inflation to gauge the next move in U.S. rates.</p>
<p>Sharp falls in U.S. asset markets on Friday also weighed on the dollar, traders said.  </p>
<p>The third consecutive rise in Japan's current account surplus depressed dollar/yen. The surplus for June rose 55.8 percent from a year earlier to 1.02 trillion yen.</p>
<p>Mark/yen slid below 63 yen again, hitting 62.76 in late trade here, within a whisker of its recent two-year low. The yen was also boosted by sterling/yen selling, which dragged the pound to two-month lows at 180.93. Sterling/mark steadied in late trade after tumbling almost seven pfennigs in a bout of long liquidation. Pound selling against the mark and the dollar had been gathering momentum since Wednesday and accelerated on Thursday when the Bank of England accompanied its quarter point rate rise with an indication that rates have peaked for now at 7.00 percent. The BOE said rates were now consistent with the government's 2.5 percent inflation target.</p>
<p>A short breather at current levels is now expected but some analysts expected the pound to resume its downturn.</p>
<p>&quot;I see a bottom around here for now, for the time being ... But we have a year-end target of 2.80 marks,&quot; said Tony Norfield, treasury economist at ABN AMRO in London.</p>
<p>But others think the BOE will embark on another round of monetary tightening later in the year as consumer spending is expected to remain buoyant, which should lend support to the pound. &quot;Rates will probably start going up again in November after the advance third quarter GDP data show growth cranking up to 4.0 percent,&quot; said Ian Amstad, international economist at Bankers Trust in London. The BOE's quarterly inflation report and minutes from the last monetary policy committee meeting - due for release on Wednesday - will be key for sterling next week, traders said.</p>
<p>Sterling/mark was at 2.9163/70, down from 2.9690/9700 in late Europe on Thursday. Against the dollar, it recouped most of its losses and was at 1.5847/52 from 1.5880/90.</p>
<p>A robust rise in Dutch consumer price inflation to 2.4 percent in July from 2.2 percent in June added pressure on the central bank to raise rates, dealers said. Mark/guilder was at 1.126725/6800 from 1.1267/68.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom + 44 171 542 7792</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
