<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787460" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - AUGUST 8.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - AUGUST 8.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Friday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- The Inkatha Freedom Party (IFP) suspended peace talks with the African National Congress (ANC) in KwaZulu-Natal on Thursday because of the claims made against the party and its leader Mangosuthu Buthelezi at a truth commission hearing in Durban.</p>
<p>- Information technology groups Persetel Holdings and Q Data are to merge, creating SA's leading computer company with a market value of 12 billion rand.</p>
<p>- Dow Chemical Company had soaked up batches of shares in local chemicals company Sentrachem before an announcement this week that the U.S.-based group has offered to buy Sentrachem for 10,50 rand a share, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>- Defence Minister Joe Modise will fly to the Middle East in a bid to salvage two multibillion-rand arms deals which he claims have been jeopardised by premature disclosure in the media.</p>
<p>- The public service strike spread to hospitals around the country on Thursday as thousands of health workers joined striking teachers to put pressure on the state to revise their offer of 7,5 percent, plus rank promotions.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- There is mounting pressure for Chris Stals, the governor of the Reserve Bank, to hand over decisions on interest rate moves to a committee of private-sector economists and senior bank officials, government and union officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>- The U.S. had reacted coolly to the person nominated to oversee the agreement that would end the U.S. arms embargo against South Africa, Joe Modise, the defence minister, said on Thursday.</p>
<p>- Alcatel Altech Telecos, a joint venture between French-based telecommunications equipment supplier Alcatel and South African electronic company Altech, said on Thursday it had been awarded a 208 million dollar contract for the Atlantis-2 submarine cable system linking Africa, South America and Europe.</p>
<p>- Persetel and Q Data, two of South Africa's three largest information technology companies by market capitalisation, have agreed to a 2 billion rand merger of their operations, Persetel said on Thursday.</p>
<p>- Women are gaining ground in the local business world, with the number of women on boards of listed companies having doubled over the past two years to May, Simon McGregor, a director of McGregor Information Services, said on Thursday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAKE BEELD</p>
<p>- The government will soon announce the biggest job-creating programme in South Africa's history.</p>
<p>- Fedsure has increased its interim attributable income by 36 percent to 79.9 million rand for the six months to end June, even after its strong growth over the same period last year.</p>
<p>- The government's unemployment insurance fund, which has often had to battle big losses over the past few years, loses several million rands every year due to weak controls and staff shortages.</p>
<p>- The exchange rate of the rand weakened on Thursday to more than 4,70 rand to the dollar at one stage, before the South African currency strengthened again.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Greater Johannesburg residents and businesses, who owe more than half of Gauteng's 3 billion rand in service arrears, have been given until Friday night to pay up or face having their electricity cut off.</p>
<p>- Still confined to his hospital bed, Pretoria's assistant fire chief Gordon Kuhn has finally spoken of the events that led to his being shot during last week's multimillion-rand N4 highway robbery.</p>
<p>- It's the love story that has become the talk of South Africa. And although PW Botha (81) and young widow Renette Te Water Naude (46) are coy about their marriage plans, everyone is wishing them well.</p>
<p>- Cape Town's 2004 Olympic bid received a huge shot in the arm on Thursday when the African Amateur Athletics Confederation unanimously endorsed the bid as &quot;one for Africa and one which is right&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
