<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787508" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Deaf and dumb Romanian may be world's oldest human.</title>
<headline>Deaf and dumb Romanian may be world's oldest human.</headline>
<byline>Karin Popescu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Romanian deaf and dumb woman aged 115  may be the oldest person alive after the death of Frenchwoman Jeanne Calment at 122 in southern France last week.</p>
<p>Anicuta Butariu's birth certificate shows she was born on June 17, 1882 in the remote mountain village of Madrigesti, near the Hungarian border, her doctor Victor Arsenie said on Friday.</p>
<p>That would make Butariu older than Danish-born American Christian Martensen, who is due to celebrate his 115th birthday on August 16 in a California retirement home.</p>
<p>He was initially believed to have become the oldest living person after the death of Calment, who reached the highest age ever certified in a human being.</p>
<p>&quot;Both her birth certificate and identity card show that date of birth,&quot; Arsenie said by telephone from the retirement home he runs in Lipova, 500 km (300 miles) northwest of Bucharest.</p>
<p>&quot;Going by that, she seems to be the oldest person in the world now.&quot;</p>
<p>Butariu worked as a housekeeper until 1964, the year when late communist dictator Nicolae Ceausescu started his 25-year reign. At age 82, police brought her to the retirement home, owned by Franciscan monks until it was confiscated in 1949 by the communist government.</p>
<p>Butariu shares a room with 14 other elderly people and became confined to a wheelchair only recently.</p>
<p>&quot;She is a small, small bent woman,&quot; Arsenie said. &quot;Everyone is astonished to see her eyes full of life.&quot;</p>
<p>Investigations in Butariu's native village showed that she might have had a brother or a sister. But Arsenie said all her known relatives had died.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I know, not a single relative has visited her here all these years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that she had not been told of her new-found status.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very difficult to communicate with her,&quot; he said. &quot;We have a minimum of gestures we regularly use to get along.&quot;</p>
<p>Arsenie said Butariu was &quot;perfectly balanced from the medical point of view, with no chronic suffering&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a pity she cannot talk to tell us what her life was like in this stormy century. Her vivid eyes seem to want to say a lot.&quot;</p>
<p>He had no ready explanation for her longevity.</p>
<p>&quot;She must have a certain genetic structure that allowed her to live to such an age,&quot; he said. &quot;But in practice, it is a simple coincidence. Anyone could have lived to that age.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
