<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787581" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Diana arrives in Bosnia to crusade against mines.</title>
<headline>Diana arrives in Bosnia to crusade against mines.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Princess Diana arrived in the battle-scarred Bosnian capital of Sarajevo on Friday to crusade against landmines.</p>
<p>The divorced princess, trying to forge a role as a roving humanitarian ambassador, planned to visit victims of mines and to meet rehabilitation specialists on a three-day trip to a country still recovering from a devastating war.</p>
<p>Diana's white private Lear jet touched down shortly after midday as a gaggle of press waited on the tarmac of Sarajevo Airport, once the scene of vicious fighting between rival armies during the Bosnian war.</p>
<p>Diana, dressed in trousers, blue blazer and light blue shirt, looking fit and tanned, shook hands with the British Ambassador and got in a van headed for the central town of Tuzla.</p>
<p>On the morning of her departure, British tabloids were full of speculation about Diana's friendship with divorced, polo-playing film producer Dodi Fayed, 41, and said the divorced princess had been seen entering his luxury London apartment for a dinner date.</p>
<p>The Daily Mail's front page headline read: &quot;Diana - it's a real romance&quot;, while The Sun said: &quot;Romantic meal in new love's London flat -- then farewell kiss before Bosnia&quot;.</p>
<p>Her 15-year marriage to British royal heir Prince Charles ended in divorce last year.</p>
<p>Diana, 36, was invited to Sarajevo on a &quot;private visit&quot; by the Washington-based Landmine Survivors' Network to highlight the plight of victims of landmines.</p>
<p>The Foreign Office earlier gave its clearance for the trip to go ahead, despite security concerns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
