<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787690" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: ARGENTINE ALLIANCE PROMISES PESO PARITY TO 2000.</title>
<headline>ARGENTINE ALLIANCE PROMISES PESO PARITY TO 2000.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jose Luis Machinea, the man chosen by Argentina's new opposition alliance to draw up its economic platform, on Friday defended Convertibility, the policy of pegging the peso at par with the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;We will enter the year 2000 with Convertibility,&quot; the former central bank chief told the daily newspaper Clarin in one of a series of media interviews.</p>
<p>He was responding to Economy Minister Roque Fernandez's attempts to cast doubt on the commitment of the new Radical Party and Frepaso alliance to the policy, which is credited with nearly eradicating inflation in Argentina since 1991.  </p>
<p>&quot;Keeping Convertibility is not simply a pose for the next elections. It is the deep conviction of the public figures of the Radical Party and Frepaso,&quot; Machinea said.</p>
<p>He was quoted in the financial daily El Cronista as saying, &quot;Dropping Convertibility would not help one bit&quot; to alleviate with the country's high unemployment and growing poverty.</p>
<p>The Radical/Frepaso alliance burst on to the political scene last weekend, rewriting the outlook for midterm elections for Congress in October and presidential elections in 1999, when President Carlos Menem must step down.  </p>
<p>Santiago Soldati, head of the Argentine Business Council, told reporters the advent of the alliance was &quot;good for democracy&quot; and Machinea was &quot;a good choice.&quot; The Association of Argentina Banks described him as a &quot;great choice.&quot;</p>
<p>To be sure, Machinea, who is 50 and holds a doctorate from the University of Minnesota, said that support for Converbitility did not mean the alliance swallowed the government's current economic policy whole.</p>
<p>&quot;Agreeing with keeping Convertibility does not mean we are in agreement with the economic model in place in the country,&quot; Machinea told El Cronista.  </p>
<p>Among the concrete measures he is already proposing are tax reforms putting more emphasis in income tax, and value-added tax (VAT) reimbursements for exporters, which he said &quot;would not have a high fiscal cost.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;More income tax, less VAT which is very high (21 percent) and wide-ranging reductions on payroll taxes,&quot; he told another financial daily, Ambito Financiero.</p>
<p>Machinea also addressed the thorny issue of labor legislation reforms, which Menem's government has been trying to push through for a year as a way of reducing unemployment, which is now hovering at about 16 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
