<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78778" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Senate sustains Clinton veto of abortion bill. [CORRECTED 21:53 GMT]</title>
<headline>Senate sustains Clinton veto of abortion bill. [CORRECTED 21:53 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Senate voted on Thursday to sustain President Bill Clinton's veto of legislation banning so-called &quot;partial term&quot; abortions, killing the measure.</p>
<p>The Senate voted 57-41 to uphold the veto, as opponents fell short of the two-thirds majority needed to override a presidential veto. The politically charged debate followed last week's 285-137 House vote to override Clinton's veto of the measure.  </p>
<p>Two Democrats and one Republican who had previously voted against the legislation changed position on the emotional election-year issue and voted to override the veto.</p>
<p>(Corrects positions).</p>
<p>Despite the switches, opponents of the bill could not garner the necessary 66 votes.</p>
<p>The vote by no means ends the debate. Republicans hope to use the issue in the coming November elections and abortion opponents have indicated they will try to pass the bill, and possibly attempt to ban other abortion methods, next year.</p>
<p>The Catholic Church sent 10 million postcards to lawmakers calling for an override. Further, Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole has said he would sign the bill if elected.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
