<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787829" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodia, China sign well-digging aid deal.</title>
<headline>Cambodia, China sign well-digging aid deal.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>China is to dig 300 wells in rural areas of Cambodia under an aid agreement signed on Friday by Cambodia's newly appointed First Prime Minister, Ung Huot, and Chinese ambassador, Yan Ting Ai.</p>
<p>It was the first aid agreement signed by Cambodia since the bloody overthrow of former co-premier Prince Norodom Ranariddh by Second Prime Minister Hun Sen on July 6.</p>
<p>China has already dug 200 wells for rural Cambodians and the agreement on Friday will take that total to 500, Ung Huot told reporters. He said the total package was worth some $6 million.</p>
<p>Ung Huot also said he hoped that $450 million pledged by aid donors at a meeting in Paris just before last month's coup would materialise over coming months.</p>
<p>&quot;The world community pledged to provide $450 million, so I hope the $450 million will be translated into concrete projects in months to come,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cambodia is one of the most aid-dependent countries, with about half its budget coming in the form of donor assistance.</p>
<p>The United States suspended aid to Cambodia for 30 days after last month's coup while it assessed the situation and Hun Sen's pledge to comply with the 1991 Paris accords that ended Cambodia's civil war. That period expires this weekend.</p>
<p>A U. S. State Department official told reporters in Washington on Thursday that he did not expect assistance to the Cambodian government to resume soon.</p>
<p>But Washington would continue humanitarian aid to Cambodia through non-governmental groups, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
