<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787852" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli planes strike south of Beirut.</title>
<headline>Israeli planes strike south of Beirut.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli planes rocketed Palestinian guerrilla targets in hills south of Beirut on Friday, a Palestinian group said.</p>
<p>Lebanese security sources later confirmed the attack. The Israeli army had no comment on the report.</p>
<p>Two jets fired two rockets into the Na'ameh hills where the radical Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine General Command (PFLP-GC) has bases -- 15 km (nine miles) south of Beirut.</p>
<p>&quot;Israeli U.S.-made F16 warplanes fired at 7:10 pm (1610 GMT) two heavy rockets into administrative, social and medical centres belonging to the PFLP-GC. The rockets caused damage only in the fields,&quot; the group said.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no casualties in the attack,&quot; it added in a statement faxed to an international news agency in Beirut.</p>
<p>The attack was the 49th Israeli air strike on Lebanon since the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>Earlier, Katyusha rockets slammed into northern Israel, slightly wounding an Israeli woman. Pro-Iranian Hizbollah (Party of God), the most formidable guerrilla force fighting Israeli occupation of south Lebanon, said it did not fire the rockets.</p>
<p>The attacks on Friday came amid the worst cross-border violence in south Lebanon since Israel's 17-day offensive in April last year.</p>
<p>A U.S.-brokered ceasefire understanding which ended the blitz then barred both Hizbollah and Israeli troops from targeting civilians on both sides of the border.</p>
<p>Between Monday and Thursday 13 Lebanese -- including seven civilians -- were killed by bombs, Israeli artillery and Israeli rocket attacks.</p>
<p>One member of the Israeli-backed South Lebanon Army militia was killed by a bomb and Israeli commandos killed five members of Hizbollah with a roadside bomb.</p>
<p>Hizbollah said on Friday it would resume Katyusha rocket attacks on northern Israel because the ceasefire understanding had failed to protect Lebanese civilians.</p>
<p>&quot;We say the understanding has ceased to protect civilians. We say the resumption of using other means to protect civilians has become necessary,&quot; Hizbollah secretary-general Sheikh Hassan Nasrallah told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;But the timing of using Katyushas to protect civilians has to do with the situation on the field...and a number of other similar considerations,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
