<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787964" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ARZAN INTERNATIONAL DISMISSES AUDITOR.</title>
<headline>ARZAN INTERNATIONAL DISMISSES AUDITOR.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arzan International Ltd said Friday that it dismissed Shachak, Peer, Reznick &amp; Co as auditor after the firm indicated it could not render an unqualified report with respect to the company's inventory.</p>
<p>The company released a Form 6-K filing it made with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission saying it had retained Almagor &amp; Co of Tel Aviv, Israel, a member of BDO International, as the independent auditor subject to ratification by stockholders.  </p>
<p>On June 30, in connection its audit of Arzan's 1996 financial statements, Shachak requested Arzan perform additional procedures, principally a listing all purchases and sales of inventory during the year, the company said.</p>
<p>Shachak indicated that it could not render an unqualified report prior to reviewing the results of this effort and in the absence of this additional data it could not render an unqualified report, Arzan said. Without the additional data, Shachak indicated it would make reference to that factor in connection with its report.  </p>
<p>Notwithstanding the belief of its board the additional data was not needed, Arzan continued, directors made a determination to undertake similar procedures following the dismissal of Shachak.</p>
<p>The company said representatives of its board, and the board's audit committee, have discussed such disagreements with Shachak.</p>
<p>Arzan said Almagor was retained on August 6. Upon the receipt of the additional data, Almagor will complete the preparation of the company's 1996 financial statements, the 6K filing said.</p>
<p>The company said it has authorized Shachak to respond fully to the inquiries of Almagor concerning the subject matter of such disagreements.</p>
<p>Except as described in the 6K, it continued, the auditors have no disagreements with Arzan with respect to the financial condition and the results of operations of the company.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
