<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="787921" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS -- PRICES END SHARPLY LOWER.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS -- PRICES END SHARPLY LOWER.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bonds ended down a point to 1-1/4 points Friday amid building concern that next week's $4.4 billion calendar will provide an unwelcome reality check for those unwilling to adjust prices to reflect this week's selloff.</p>
<p>While reluctant to guess what next week will bring, one trader expects muni prices to go lower still, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;What happens in our market is guys don't really cut things realistically till the gun gets put to their head, and that gun generally is new issue prices,&quot; the trader said. &quot;As new issues get priced next week, they are going to get priced to move, and it's going to crush the secondary.&quot;</p>
<p>As for Friday's market, the trader said while prices probably ended down about a point, thin trade made gauging levels difficult.</p>
<p>&quot;A couple of trades I've seen, maybe things are off like 10 basis points just today,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A municipal analyst said high-grade issues worsened by 10 basis points, while dollar bonds ended down 1-1/8 points. Activity was &quot;very light,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dollar bonds were slow to open, but started the session quoted down 5/8 of a point. They were down a full point by noon, and down 1-1/4 by early afternoon. Some late-session improvement brought them back to down 1-1/8 by the close, he said.</p>
<p>In the government market, the benchmark 30-year bond was down 1-15/32 at 96-19/32 to yield 6.64 percent. In debt futures, the September municipal contract ended down 1-9/32 at 118-29/32.</p>
<p>The September T-bond contract ended down 1-17/32 at 112-22/32. The MOB spread was 199 ticks.</p>
<p>Turning to new issues, sales for next week are expected to total $4.4 billion in 126 offerings, according to Reuters Municipal Bond Information Group.</p>
<p>Negotiated offerings are expected to tally $3.7 billion in 56 sales, with a $660 million New York Metropoltian Transportation Authority offering through Smith Barney Inc. topping the list. </p>
<p>On the competitive side, 70 sales totaling $708 million are scheduled. A $141 million Delaware Transportation Authority offering on Tuesday is the largest. </p>
<p>An additional 13 sales totaling $46 million are on the possible calender, meaning underwriters have said they may price the issues next week depending on market conditions.</p>
<p>((--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
