<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788053" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kohl upbeat on reform logjam, EMU target.</title>
<headline>Kohl upbeat on reform logjam, EMU target.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl expressed confidence on Friday that Germany would both break through a logjam of economic reforms and meet the membership criteria for the European Union's planned single currency.</p>
<p>The chancellor, in a television interview from his Austrian holiday home on the lakeshore of the Wolfgangsee, said he was hopeful the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) would not block plans for a sweeping overhaul of the tax system a second time.</p>
<p>The SPD has used its dominance in the parliament's upper house and its mediation committee to bring the plans to a standstill. Kohl said the SPD would have to answer to the electorate if it blocked them in a second mediation process.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not so sceptical at all,&quot; Kohl told RTL television in the interview, excerpts of which were played to Reuters ahead of broadcast later in the day. &quot;It will be difficult to reject this once again at the next attempt.&quot;</p>
<p>The SPD called on Kohl to present a new tax package, which was socially just and solidly financed.</p>
<p>&quot;If Helmut Kohl wants to use tax policy against workers and families, the SPD believes it has a duty to stop these irresponsible plans,&quot; SPD paty manager Franz Muentefering said.</p>
<p>But Kohl made clear that while he was willing to compromise on certain points, the concept of the package as a whole -- which aims to stimulate the economy and attract more investment with 30 billion marks ($16 billion) of tax cuts -- was not up for debate.</p>
<p>&quot;We made a very good tax proposal. There is no doubt among experts that the government's offer is sensible,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kohl, widely seen as the driving force behind European economic and monetary union (EMU), said he was sure Germany would meet the membership targets for the project, achieving a budget deficit of 3.0 percent of gross domestic product (GDP).</p>
<p>&quot;I've said we'll meet the criteria and we'll meet them with 3.0,&quot; the chancellor said.</p>
<p>The European Union's Maastricht Treaty sets down a limit of three percent of GDP for EMU membership.</p>
<p>Some German politicians have argued this target should be interpreted loosely but other members of Kohl's centre-right coalition, such as Bavarian state premier Edmund Stoiber, have said it must mean 3.0 to ensure the new currency is strong.</p>
<p>Asked if he would be prepared to accept a budget deficit figure of 3.1 percent of GDP, Kohl replied: &quot;I've told you we'll make 3.0. Why do you want to talk the whole time about something I'm convinced won't happen?&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl also said he was optimistic about Germany's economic performance for the rest of this year and next.</p>
<p>&quot;We will surely have growth of 2.5, 2.6, 2.7 percent in gross national product this year. I am sure that next year we will reach three percent. That is a good goal, but we will only reach it if we support it with tax changes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the SPD was blocking the reforms because of internal rivalry between party leader Oskar Lafontaine and Lower Saxony premier Gerhard Schroeder. He vowed to make the issue a theme in elections in September next year if the SPD refused to budge.</p>
<p>The chancellor said his coalition would also push through a reform of the pensions system despite SPD opposition and stressed the tax-cutting reform was also vital to maintain Germany's industrial competitiveness.</p>
<p>&quot;If the SPD rejects (it) just because it has an argument about who should be its candidate for chancellor... then they should do that and we'll decide via the election,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kohl, who also rejected SPD calls to bring forward the elections, said he was sticking to his goal of halving unemployment by the year 2000, although he recognised that the chance of reaching it was much lower than before.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't reach the goal right away, and if we reach only a third instead of half, we will still have achieved something,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
