<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788054" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy army cleared of widespread abuse in Somalia.</title>
<headline>Italy army cleared of widespread abuse in Somalia.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy confirmed on Friday that its soldiers tortured Somalis while on a peacekeeping mission in the African state, but an official report said the abuses were not widespread and senior army officers were largely blameless.</p>
<p>The findings were greeted with relief by the army, whose reputation was on the line following accusations that Italian troops committed gross human rights violations while serving in a U.S.-led humanitarian mission to Somalia from 1992 to 1994.</p>
<p>However, local Somali associations blasted the 46-page report as a shameful whitewash. The document was prepared by a five-member commission which included two women and two generals.</p>
<p>The commission, headed by Ettore Gallo, a former president of Italy's Constitutional Court, was set up in June after the press printed detailed allegations that soldiers had raped, tortured and murdered Somalis.</p>
<p>While the report urged improved training and communication within the army, Gallo said the military as a whole had acquitted itself with honour in difficult circumstances.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm proud to say that our Italian soldiers always gave precedence to the humanitarian nature of the mission...and in this respect was the best force (in Somalia),&quot; Gallo told a news conference.</p>
<p>Two generals who led the Italian forces to Somalia resigned in June when the allegations surfaced, but Gallo said generals Bruno Loi and Carmine Fiore could not be held responsible.</p>
<p>&quot;How can the head of the whole operation know what every junior officer is up to?&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>The army association Cocer demanded the men's reinstatement.</p>
<p>&quot;This report does justice to the army and its operations, which are professional and carry out a service for the country,&quot; Cocer chairman, Colonel Ettore Cozzi, told reporters.</p>
<p>By contrast, the head of the Somali community in Italy branded the report scandalous. &quot;It has buried everything. It was a hurried inquiry, which has absolved leaders, generals and commanders,&quot; Fatuma Hagi Yassin told reporters. &quot;It's shameful&quot;.</p>
<p>The commission, which interviewed 145 people and travelled to Africa to meet witnesses, dismissed certain charges against the army, including an allegation that a senior Italian officer had raped and murdered a small boy.</p>
<p>But it said some claims were credible, such as the torture of a Somali youth with electrodes and the sexual abuse of a woman with a stick of explosive.</p>
<p>&quot;If she had been Italian or French or German this would not have happened,&quot; Gallo said.</p>
<p>The report added that a lack of discipline meant that drugs and prostitutes had circulated freely in some quarters.</p>
<p>It suggested that in future magistrates and human-rights experts should travel with soldiers on peacekeeping missions to guarantee international law was upheld.</p>
<p>But it also noted that the Somalia operation, code-named &quot;Restore Hope&quot;, was not the genuine peacekeeping mission that the Italians had hoped for.</p>
<p>&quot;Instead (soldiers) were suddenly caught up in a repressive policy which they never believed in and which exposed them to grave risks,&quot; the commission wrote.</p>
<p>The Somali operation, authorised by the United Nations, was intended to bring food relief to the east African country, but the multinational force rapidly got drawn into a vicious conflict with Somali warlords.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SOMAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
