<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788047" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Iraq clears last UN obstacle to selling oil again.</title>
<headline>Iraq clears last UN obstacle to selling oil again.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq on Friday cleared the last obstacle for a resumption of oil sales after a U.N. Security Council panel approved a formula for setting crude prices under an &quot;oil-for-food&quot; plan.</p>
<p>Iraq last signed oil contracts in May when it reached its quota permitted under the first six months of the plan that allows oil sales of $2 billion every six months to buy vital supplies needed to ease the impact of seven-year old U.N. trade sanctions.</p>
<p>Chief U.N. spokesman Fred Eckhard said the pricing plan, that has to conform to industry standards, was automatically approved by the Security Council's sanctions committee after none of its 15 members raised objections.</p>
<p>&quot;The deadline was 11 a.m. (1500 GMT) this morning so the formula was approved,&quot; he said. &quot;Iraq can now begin signing contracts,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Iraq had delayed submitting the pricing formula until U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan approved Baghdad's programme to distribute the humanitarian goods bought with the oil revenues. He did this on Monday and Iraq now has to rush and sell $1 billion in oil by Sept. 5.</p>
<p>The &quot;oil-for-food&quot; programme went into effect last December and was renewed for another six months on June 8. But oil sales are divided equally into two 90-day or three-month periods and the expiry date for selling the first $1 billion worth of oil is on Sept. 5.</p>
<p>Two thirds of the proceeds are for humanitarian supplies for civilians who have suffered under U.N. sanctions since August 1990 when Baghdad's troops invaded Kuwait. The remainder is to pay for compensation to victims of the invasion and some U.N. costs.</p>
<p>Speculation is rife about who will get the contracts after industry sources said Iraq appeared to be punishing companies from the United States, Britain and Japan, who at varying times objected to or delayed some of the supplies Iraq had ordered with the oil proceeds.</p>
<p>But at the same time they said some large U.S.-based oil companies, such as Coastal Corp, Bayoil and Chevron Corp, might have contracts while Texaco Inc and Mobil Corp appeared to be shut out.</p>
<p>Oil traders speculated that Coastal and Bayoil have long-standing relationships with Iraq while Chevron would bring Iraqi crude to the U.S. West Coast, an important new market for Baghdad.</p>
<p>Diplomats, however, said Iraq's State Oil Marketing Organisation (SOMO) might change its mind about Britain and Japan, whose governments have raised far fewer objections in the council's sanctions committee than the United States.</p>
<p>One envoy, speaking on condition of anonymity, said: &quot;This may well be a storm in teacup,&quot; adding that Iraq would have difficulty selling $1 billion worth of oil quickly without the British and Japanese-based firms.</p>
<p>They include the British Petroleum Co and the Anglo-Dutch Shell Group, Mitsubishi Corp, Idemitsu Kosan Co Ltd and Cosmo Oil Ltd. All have been told their contracts would not be renewed immediately.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
