<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788490" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco offers $3.0 mln shares to Sonasid workers.</title>
<headline>Morocco offers $3.0 mln shares to Sonasid workers.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morocco offered three percent of giant steel mill Sonasid to workers worth $3 million, as part of the firm's privatisation plan, a Moroccan official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the example of previous privatised companies, the government offered 117,000 Sonasid shares or three percent of its capital to the firm's workers,&quot; a privatisation ministry official who declined to be named said.</p>
<p>The shares block, which is estimated at 30 million dirhams ($3 million), was offered with flexible options, he said, but gave no other details.</p>
<p>&quot;The government move towards workers is a sign that the long-delayed cession of more than 51 percent of Sonasid shareholders equity would be soon ceded to strategic investors,&quot; a Casablanca-based stockbroker said.</p>
<p>Morocco offered 35 percent of state-owned Sonasid last year in a floatation worth 420 million dirhams.</p>
<p>Established in 1974 in the northern province of Nador, the Societe Nationale de Siderurgie (Sonasid) manufactures concrete steel and wire rod, with an average output of 420,000 tonnes satisfying more than 70 percent of domestic demand</p>
<p>One of 48 listed stocks on the Casablanca bourse, Sonasid rose 16 dirhams on Friday to close at 572 dirhams, traders said.</p>
<p>($1= 10.01 dirhams)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
