<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788473" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada's provincial leaders eye tobacco lawsuits.</title>
<headline>Canada's provincial leaders eye tobacco lawsuits.</headline>
<byline>Allan Dowd</byline>
<dateline>ST. ANDREWS, New Brunswick 1997-08-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian provincial premiers debated on Thursday whether they should follow the lead of 40 states in the United States and seek damages from the tobacco industry in court.</p>
<p>The leaders of the four Atlantic provinces agreed to push the issue during the premiers' annual meeting, but at least one provincial leader said it would be hypocritical to sue an industry that Canada depends on for tax revenue.</p>
<p>New Brunswick Premier Frank McKenna said he expected the tobacco issue would be addressed again on Friday morning when the provincial leaders resume their meeting.</p>
<p>British Columbia has introduced legislation to allow it to file a class-action suit against the tobacco industry to recoup health costs related to smoking. The Canadian province thereby became the first government outside the U.S. to take such action.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like the premiers to show some consensus. We know that British Columbia acted in this area and I would really be surprised if the other provinces didn't show some support for it,&quot; said Prince Edward Island premier Pat Binns.</p>
<p>The 40 states reached a landmark settlement with the industry in June under which the cigarette makers agreed to pay $368.5 billion and submit to federal regulations. The agreement must be approved by the U.S. Congress and President Clinton.</p>
<p>The states' lawsuits sought to recoup Medicaid costs of treating smokers.</p>
<p>The incentive to sue in Canada could be even greater because health care here is provided universally and funded publicly.</p>
<p>British Columbia has said its health care program pays out between C$420 million (U.S. $303 million) to C$560 million ($403 million) a year year for smoking related illnesses.</p>
<p>At least one premier panned the idea.</p>
<p>&quot;Governments have no problem taking the money in taxation. And they talk about the sins of smoking. It seems to me to be somewhat hyprocritical,&quot; Premier Ralph Klein of Alberta told reporters.</p>
<p>Saskatchewan Premier Roy Romanow achowledged the provinces could face a conflict sueing an industry they depend on for revenues and suggested that the best course might be simply &quot;monitor&quot; British Columbia's effort.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. ANDREWS, New Brunswick"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
