<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788475" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BROOKE TO RESOLVE ISSUES AGAINST SETTLEMENT.</title>
<headline>BROOKE TO RESOLVE ISSUES AGAINST SETTLEMENT.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brooke Group Ltd on Friday said it would resolve the issues raised by a federal judge who revoked preliminary approval of a proposal to settle a class-action suit against Brooke's Liggett Group Inc cigarette unit.</p>
<p>A federal judge in West Virginia threw out a preliminary class-action settlement against the company.</p>
<p>The agreement would have prevented smokers, victims of second hand smoke, states that pay Medicaid bills for smoking-related diseases and others from suing Liggett Group for 25 years.</p>
<p>The company, in turn, would have paid 25 percent of its net pre-tax profits for the next 25 years to people suffering from smoking-related illnesses.</p>
<p>A statement from Brooke said the West Virginia court revoked its preliminary approval on largely technical grounds.</p>
<p>It said a limited-fund class settlement was &quot;the only practical way&quot; to fairly resolve class members' claims and said it would seek to resolve the issues raised.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that we will be able to address and resolve the technical issues the court has raised and that Liggett's limited-fund settlement will ultimately be upheld by the courts,&quot; the company statement said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
