<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788762" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE-Bets ride on Bible theme park in U.S. gambling capital.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Bets ride on Bible theme park in U.S. gambling capital.</headline>
<byline>Thomas Moore</byline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Walk with Jesus, watch the waters of the Red Sea part, stand in awe as Lazarus rises from the dead.</p>
<p>A group of Hollywood investors thinks the public has had enough of Mickey Mouse theme parks and is ready for a more spiritual ride. Welcome to &quot;Holy Land&quot; -- a high-minded dream that seeks to be become a full-blown reality and open its pearly gates just an hour's drive from the fleshpots and poker tables of America's gambling capital.</p>
<p>If the city of Mesquite, Nevada, approves the plans, the $1.1 billion religious theme park could be competing for the souls of Las Vegas gamblers.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to reconstruct the Holy Bible,&quot; Daxx Edder, CEO of Quorum International Ltd., said. &quot;The idea is it will be a historical document that you'll be able to walk through instead of read. All we need right now is the land. We've got the funds available,&quot; added Edder, who took the proposal to the Mesquite city council, which has asked for more details.</p>
<p>Mayor Ken Carter was keen: &quot;If it is real, of course I have some real optimism about the theme park as a very successful business venture for our area.&quot;</p>
<p>Carl Godfrey, a financial consultant hired by Quorum, said the 3,000-acre (1,200 hectare) park will operate like Epcot Centre, Disney's science-based attraction in Florida. &quot;You'll walk into a large capacity room where you'll get schedules and maps for the shows and ceremonies. Then you would leave this central hall and walk around the park visiting various religious shrines.&quot;</p>
<p>NO PLANS FOR GIANT WALK-IN JESUS</p>
<p>Godfrey denied newspaper reports that the park would feature a 33-storey high statue of Jesus that people could climb inside. &quot;There will be some amusement rides of that nature but not what you would think (of) as coming from a large amusement park,&quot; he said. &quot;We are thinking about creating the parting of the Red Sea and you would ride a tram past it like they do in Universal Studios theme park.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition to the parting of the Red Sea, he said, the park will feature virtual reality, holographic, theatrical and statuary recreations of scenes from the Bible. Visitors might see a Russian Orthodox church, a Moslem mosque or a Japanese Shinto shrine, complete with priests, and American Indians will be invited to display expressions of their beliefs.</p>
<p>Godfrey said each religion would pay for the building of its pavilion or temple and would be represented in the park only if it consented. Other than that, he and Edder were reluctant to talk about who exactly is financing the project.</p>
<p>Edder said Quorum was a group of 58 individuals who also invest in other projects and movie production caompanies. &quot;We just invest in motion picture companies and they do the work and we take a percentage,&quot; he said. &quot;We do insist that all the movies be clean. It's mostly small independent producers.&quot;</p>
<p>NO NAMES PLEASE</p>
<p>Edder would say no more and Godfrey would say only that the investors were well-known figures from the motion picture industry and business people. &quot;The people who are involved in this go all the way from retired actors and actresses to Hollywood producers, and we have quite a few real estate devlopers. These are people whose names are well-known.&quot;</p>
<p>The Rev. Pat Leary, vicar general of the Roman Catholic diocese of Las Vegas, said he saw no problem with the park, as long as it is in good taste. &quot;Jesus said, 'By their fruits ye shall know them,'&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;So if it helps people, if it brings them to a deeper understanding of faith or Christ, it's fine. However, I don't know that much about it. I hear it's a commercial endeavour. Sometimes such endeavours border on bad taste. Still, there's nothing intrinsically wrong or right about it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Godfrey also said he saw nothing wrong with using religion as the basis for a theme park.</p>
<p>&quot;How many movies and television shows have we seen about religious subjects? Everybody out there is making money off religion. The Catholic Church is the richest business in the world and the world's largest landowner,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not trying to embrace any one religion. All we're trying to do is present it in the best light we can so people can experience these religions. If people had a chance to study and understand, I think it would make this world a better place to live.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
