<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78886" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Normandy America chief to be charged.</title>
<headline>Normandy America chief to be charged.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Christopher Bagdasarian, chairman and chief executive of Normandy America Inc., whose initial public offering was pulled from the Nasdaq market last year after one day of trading, is to be charged Thursday with securities fraud, federal prosecutors said.</p>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Commission also filed a civil suit against Bagdsarian in Manhattan federal court Thursday, alleging that he filed false information about his background in his registration with the commission ahead of Normandy America's public offering.</p>
<p>Samuel White, who had been a partner in the Los Angeles office of Deloitte &amp; Touche, was also named in the SEC civil suit and is also to be named in criminal charges.</p>
<p>Although details of the criminal charges were not immediately available, the SEC alleges Bagdasarian gave false and misleading information to underwriters and counsel by claiming he had managed personal and third party assets worth hundreds of millions of dollars.</p>
<p>He allegedly said he had achieved a 10-year average annual return of about 29 percent managing a portfolio of more than $731 million.</p>
<p>The SEC complaint alleges that White, a certified public accountant in La Canada, Calif., verified to underwriters the amount of assets under Bagdasarian's management and the performance of his investments. White was asked to resign from Deloitte &amp; Touche this year.</p>
<p>Bagdasarian, 31, of Santa Barbara, Calif., formed the Omaha, Neb.-based reinsurer Normandy America in 1994. The initial public offering was pulled from the market on Aug. 16 1995 after one day of trading.</p>
<p>Lead underwriter Salomon Brothers had said the IPO was withdrawn due to market conditions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
