<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788949" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Olympics forecast to create 135,000 jobs in Italy.</title>
<headline>Olympics forecast to create 135,000 jobs in Italy.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Winning the right to stage the 2004 Olympic Games would create 135,000 new jobs in Italy and attract an extra eight million extra tourists to Rome, representatives of the city's business community said on Friday.</p>
<p>The Games would also boost state coffers by five trillion lire ($2.7 billion) in tax receipts and leave the Italian capital with dozens of high quality sports venues, they said.</p>
<p>Speaking at a news conference to promote Rome's Olympic bid, Antonio Nori, president of Italian retailers' confederation Confesercenti, said the 2004 Games offered an opportunity to relaunch Rome as one of the world's great capital cities.</p>
<p>&quot;The business community wants to demonstrate its will to make the city thrive, to improve services, to give a new boost to tourism and to present Rome in its entirety, not just as the capital of Christianity, but also as the home of 50 percent of the world's archaeological and historical patrimony,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Francesco Fabbi, vice-chairman of the commerce, tourism and services association, Confcommercio, said Rome could only benefit by hosting the first Games of the 21st century.</p>
<p>Rome, which staged the 1960 Olympics, is one of five cities bidding for the 2004 Games and has been quoted by bookmakers as 2-1 favourite. The others cities are Athens, Buenos Aires, Cape Town and Stockholm.</p>
<p>The International Olympic Committee is due to name the winning city at a meeting in Lausanne, Switzerland, on September 5.</p>
<p>A report released at the news conference said the Games would generate 20,300 new jobs in the construction industry in Italy over the next seven years and 14,800 in small businesses.</p>
<p>The study, compiled by a private research institute, said the vast majority of the new jobs would be in Rome and the surrounding region of Lazio.</p>
<p>Critics of Rome's bid say many of the jobs would be only temporary and the Olympic venues would be underused and expensive to maintain once the Games were over.</p>
<p>They say Rome, already one of the world's most popular tourist destinations, does not need a massive influx of visitors in the summer of 2004.</p>
<p>The money earmarked for the Games should be spent on improving the city's infrastructure and restoring the Roman ruins and Renaissance palaces scattered across the city.</p>
<p>&quot;We're told there's no money to create new exhibition spaces, no money to restore works of art, no money even to paint the walls of the city's public buildings,&quot; a spokesman for the campaign against Rome's Olympic bid told Reuters this week.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, suddenly, there's money available for the Olympics.&quot;</p>
<p>Raffaele Ranucci, the director of Rome's Olympic bid, gave assurances at Friday's news conference that the financing of the Games would be kept in check.</p>
<p>&quot;We want everything to be as correct as possible,&quot; he said. &quot;Transparency is important not just for this bid but for this city too.&quot;</p>
<p>Organisers of the last major sports event to be hosted in Italy, the 1990 soccer World Cup finals, were heavily criticised for overspending.</p>
<p>Rome's Olympic stadium, which would be the centre-piece of the 2004 Games, was revamped at a reported cost of 220 billion lire ($120 million), over three times the original budget.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
