<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="788908" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: German funds target Brussels property market.</title>
<headline>German funds target Brussels property market.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cash rich German property funds, on the look out for new office buildings with long leases, have set their sights on Brussels, according to international real estate agents Jones Lang Wootton.</p>
<p>Already the funds -- the main players of which are BfG, Westinvest, Despa, DEGI, DGI and DIFA -- have ploughed some eight billion francs ($207.6 million) into the Belgian market and there is plenty more to come, JLW's Michel Pilette said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Five years ago they began moving in on London where they were investing about one billion pounds ($1.6 billion) a year. They then moved on to the Netherlands, where they were buying at a rate of about one billion guilders ($475.6 million) a year,&quot; Pilette said.</p>
<p>&quot;Now they have begun moving into the Brussels office market. We estimate they will be here for about two more years before moving on again -- probably to Paris,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Between them, the German property funds have immense amounts of new cash to invest each year.</p>
<p>In the first five months of 1997 alone the collective net inflow of money to all the funds totalled 5.7 billion marks ($3.1 billion), according to JLW's research department.</p>
<p>Among the most recent transactions, Despa acquired leases on three central Brussels poperties at an estimated total cost of 1.9 billion francs, and Westinvest paid 900 million francs for a lease on a building on the outskirts of the Belgian capital.</p>
<p>Of the five basic property investment categories -- office, industrial, retail, hotels and the emerging leisure category -- office space is the easiest for a fund to run, according to Pilette.</p>
<p>Running and management costs are low and rentals less open to the vagaries of short-term local economic conditions.</p>
<p>In German cities such as Berlin, Dusseldorf, Frankfurt, Hamburg, Munich and the French city of Lyon, office rents are still in a mild down trend.</p>
<p>In Paris, Budapest, Milan and Barcelona the cycle of falling rents has reached an end, according to JLW research data for the first quarter of this year.</p>
<p>However, in Vienna, Madrid, Luxembourg, Brussels, Amsterdam, Dublin and London rents are on an accelerating uptrend -- making them attractive to institutional investors.</p>
<p>The attraction of Brussels, according to Pilette, is that there is enough new office space available to soak up the new German interest withouth forcing lease prices up to a level where the rental yield falls too far.</p>
<p>Top rents of office space in Brussels are around 8,250 francs per square metre per year, and the prime yield is about 6.75 percent -- a fair premium to 10-year Belgian bond yields at around 5.80 percent -- according to the JLW figures.</p>
<p>That situation is bound to change as the German buying continues, soaking up new building stock and making the rate of growth in lease prices outstrip that in rental rates -- part of the natural real estate cycle.</p>
<p>However, if the JLW analysis is correct, Brussels has at least another two years of boom before the German juggernaut moves on to Paris.</p>
<p>($ = 38.53 Belgian Francs)</p>
<p>($ = 0.636 British Pounds)</p>
<p>($ = 2.102 Dutch Guilders)</p>
<p>($ = 1.866 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500021">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
