<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="789066" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: DOLLAR/MARK PROVES RESILIENT TO BUBA COMMENTS.</title>
<headline>DOLLAR/MARK PROVES RESILIENT TO BUBA COMMENTS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar pared losses against the mark as expectations Germany's economy is too weak to withstand higher interest rates overshadowed comments by a German central banker indicating the Bundesbank does not want a weaker mark.</p>
<p>Council member Ernst Welteke said on Friday the Bundesbank had already signalled it thought dollar/mark's correction was completed at 1.70 marks. This drove the dollar down as low as 1.8625 marks.</p>
<p>But the dollar rebounded as traders focused on another of Weltke's comments that slow growth and high unemployment meant it was not appropriate to &quot;turn the interest rate screw.&quot;  </p>
<p>Speculation the Bundesbank is not about to raise rates was also stoked as Welteke said the German central bank should not raise rates as long as there was no sign of price pressures and that the exchange-rate moves had so far had limited impact on the German cost of living.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/mark will stay fairly volatile as it was a mixed bag from Welteke,&quot; said Keith Edmonds, chief analyst at IBJ. &quot;He was clearly saying the dollar correction was over but on the other hand was fairly dovish about inflation prospects.&quot;</p>
<p>Dollar/mark was at 1.8708/13 marks at 0745 GMT from 1.8675/85 late Thursday in Europe.  </p>
<p>The U.S. currency was at 118.50/60 yen from 118.37/42 yesterday. It was steady at 1.5302/12 Swiss francs from 1.5290/95 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Speculation that the Bundesbank will engineer higher money-market rates has grown as the dollar has ratcheted up to near-eight-year highs in recent weeks. The U.S. currency has surged more than 11 percent in the past two months, climbing to a peak of 1.8913 marks earlier this week.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank has so far refrained from calling for a variable-rate repurchase tender, a move expected to pave the way for a rise in the repo rate from a record low of 3.0 percent.  </p>
<p>But such a move could come as soon as next week, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank might like to move to a variable-rate repo quite soon because they can then say the market is moving the rate around and that will take the spotlight off them,&quot; said Marian Bell, treasury economist at Royal Bank of Scotland.</p>
<p>&quot;Intervention might also be a possibility but they will wait until the market gets ahead of itself.&quot;</p>
<p>Speculation the Bundesbank could intervene to stem the mark's slide grew after Welteke said the Bundesbank had no exact date for intervening in currency markets.  </p>
<p>But dollar bulls said they continued to target a move up to 1.90 marks, given the contrast between strong U.S. growth and the still fragile German economic recovery.</p>
<p>Traders were more cautious about dollar/yen amid concern a widening Japanese trade surplus with the U.S. will revive tensions between the two nations.</p>
<p>A report overnight showed Japan's current account surplus leapt nearly 56 percent in June from a year ago while the trade surplus rose nearly 19 percent in the same period.</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect nastier noises from the U.S. in the coming months, which will push the yen lower,&quot; said Bell.  </p>
<p>U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky said on Wednesday Japan should not rely too much on exports to promote growth and she was disappointed by the recent drop in U.S. automotive sales to Japan.</p>
<p>Traders expect Japanese officials will protest against any dollar gains above 120 yen to pre-empt U.S. president Bill Clinton's administration from adopting a tougher stance.</p>
<p>-- Swaha Pattanaik, London newsroom +44 171 542 6284</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
