<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="789112" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: FOCUS-COURT RULING MAKES TEN FLOAT MORE LIKELY.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-COURT RULING MAKES TEN FLOAT MORE LIKELY.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's Federal Court ruled on Friday that Canadian media group CanWest Global Communications Corp had illegal control of TEN, which analysts said may pave the way for the float of the commercial television network.</p>
<p>The court ruled in favour of the industry regulator, the Australian Broadcasting Authority (ABA), which was taken to court by the company after it found that CanWest held voting interests in TEN of 52.49 percent. This was well above the limit of 15 percent under Australia's foreign investment rules.  </p>
<p>The ABA has ordered CanWest to reduce its voting interest in TEN by October 3 this year.</p>
<p>But Justice Hill also ruled against Australian treasurer Peter Costello's decision that CanWest must reduce its economic interest in TEN from 76 percent to 57.5 percent.</p>
<p>The divided ruling is the latest in a long-running saga between CanWest and the Australian government and its ABA regulator. The government and ABA say CanWest is breaking foreign ownerships laws, while CanWest says it is within the law.  </p>
<p>In late 1996, the Winnipeg-based media group increased its economic interest by 18.5 percent in TEN to its current level. The extra holding was purchased by Donholken Pty Ltd and Selli Pty Ltd, with debt financed by firms linked to CanWest.</p>
<p>Media analysts said the court ruling means that CanWest must either unwind these positions in Donholken and Selli or sell the shares that represent the extra 37.49 percent voting interest it holds through a public share float of TEN.</p>
<p>&quot;This will probably speed up the float,&quot; said one Sydney-based analyst.  </p>
<p>A float proposal has been pushed by fellow TEN investors Brian Sherman and Laurence Friedman through their vehicle Telecasters North Queensland Ltd (TNQ).</p>
<p>However, analysts said CanWest is unlikely to take the TNQ road, preferring instead to go for a straight float of TEN, Australia's third ranking commercial television network.</p>
<p>&quot;The way the current maket is priced, they will make a profit from a float,&quot; said the Sydney-based analyst. Analysts valued TEN at about A$1.5 billion. In 1992, CanWest and a group of investors bought TEN out of receivership for A$260 million.  </p>
<p>CanWest chairman Izzy Asper said in a statement issued in Sydney: &quot;All we have sought is an orderly process, with a reasonable period of time, to implement a restructuring of Network TEN.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are, indeed, in intensive discussions with the authorities to achieve a mutually satisfdactory conclusion,&quot; Asper said. &quot;Today's decision helps advance that objective.&quot;</p>
<p>Sources close to CanWest said the Canadian group only exercises voting control over 15 percent of TEN.</p>
<p>ABA chairman Peter Webb welcomed the ruling.  </p>
<p>&quot;The ABA welcomes the court's decision which vindicates its investigation process and findings,&quot; Webb said.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision means that the ABA's orginal six month timetable remains undisturbed and continues to be due to expire in the first week of October. CanWest remains under an obligation to rectify the breach within this period,&quot; Webb said.</p>
<p>ABA said it examined share transactions which took place in November 1996 and January 1997. Shares in TEN, which were previously held by interests associated with John Singleton, Robert Whyte, Jack Cowin and others were sold to companies whose purchase was financed by CanWest.  </p>
<p>ABA said these shares totalled 37.49 percent of the issued capital of TEN.</p>
<p>On Thursday, TEN reported a 11 percent rise in earnings before interest and tax to A$154.5 million in the 1996/97 year, which analysts said was a good result to base a float on.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
