<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="789370" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: MANILA T-BILL MKT QUIET, BANKS AWAIT CLEAR TREND.</title>
<headline>MANILA T-BILL MKT QUIET, BANKS AWAIT CLEAR TREND.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines' secondary market for Treasury bills saw lacklustre trading on Friday, as banks bided time until a clear trend was established in the currency market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is holding on to their government securities first. With the central bank gradually lowering overnight rates, they just want to see if this would be a definite trend,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>They expect foreign banks to trade at the foreign exchange spot market next week, which would show whether the peso had already normalised and pave the way for lower interest rates.  </p>
<p>Foreign banks were not allowed to trade two weeks ago to ease the pressure on the peso which was effectively devalued on July 11. But on Thursday, a Bankers Association of the Philippines official said foreign banks should be invited again to trade.</p>
<p>The average interbank call loan rate eased to 18.0625 percent from 18.09375 percent since most banks have squared their positions for the week.</p>
<p>Volume fell to 12.37 billion pesos from 16.92 billion. Out of the 45 participating financial institutions, 25 were lenders.</p>
<p>-- Manila Newsroom (632) 841-8937; Fax (632) 817-62-67</p>
<p>-- Email: manila.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
