<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="789519" id="root" date="1997-08-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: IRISH POUND DRIFTS AS STG AND DOLLAR REVIVE.</title>
<headline>IRISH POUND DRIFTS AS STG AND DOLLAR REVIVE.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-08-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A sluggish Irish pound drifted off a little against sterling as the British unit took heart from dollar/mark gains sparked by comments from a Bundesbank official on Friday.</p>
<p>Sterling, which tumbled nearly five pfennigs following the Bank of England's quarter-point rate rise on Thursday, was helped on Friday by dollar/mark which came off lows set after the Bundesbank's Ernst Welteke signalled the dollar/mark correction was complete at $1.70.</p>
<p>The dollar rebounded as traders focused on another of Welteke's comments that slow growth and high unemployment meant it was not appropriate to 'turn the interest rate screw'.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sterling and the dollar have regained some to their lost ground of yesterday on the back of Welteke's comments.&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;But I still feel sterling is going to have more potential on the downside over the next couple of weeks, assuming any figures that come out of the UK are showing inflationary tendencies or overly strong growth,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Stg/mark reached a low of 2.9640 from 3.0130 just before BoE announcement, but later crept back up over 2.97. Cable slid below $1.60 to as low as $1.5780 but steadied later just above $1.58.</p>
<p>By 0821 GMT, the punt was at 0.9033 sterling against a close of 0.9046 stg.</p>
<p>The punt stood at 2.6880 marks against 2.6883 marks at the close, while it stood at $1.4370 from a close of $1.4350.</p>
<p>&quot;What is surprising is that the Irish pound is not moving down in tandem with the stg/mark.&quot; the dealer said. &quot;I think the market has probably been caught a little short of Irish against sterling going into the BoE announcement yesterday and that is what is keeping the mark/Irish up.&quot;</p>
<p>The dealer said he expected sterling/mark to struggle to break back above the 3.02 level against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;So that basically means that we are going to see the stg/Irish cross hold in or around these levels if not drift a little higher,&quot; the dealer said. &quot;It is possible we could get over the 91 pence level assuming stg/mark heads down to the 2.95 marks level.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Carmel Linnane, Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9775</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
