<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78972" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Sanctions on Yugoslavia likely to be lifted soon.</title>
<headline>Sanctions on Yugoslavia likely to be lifted soon.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign ministers of major powers said on Thursday that U.N. sanctions against rump Yugoslavia would shortly be lifted, following elections earlier this month in Bosnia.</p>
<p>They were speaking after the United States, key European allies and Russia met to discuss how to shore up peace in Bosnia following the vote to elect joint institutions to run the multi-ethnic state foreseen in last year's Dayton peace accord.</p>
<p>A statement on the meeting said the ministers in the so- called Contact Group &quot;looked forward to early certification of the Sept. 14 Bosnian elections and to the lifting of sanctions by the U.N. Security Council soon thereafter.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think there was agreement right round the table that the conditions laid down in Dayton have been broadly satisfied and that it's appropriate for the sanctions to be lifted pretty soon,&quot; British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's days we're talking about, not weeks,&quot; Rifkind told reporters. U.S. Assistant Secretary of State John Kornblum said he expected Security Council action to begin next week.</p>
<p>The United Nations imposed the sanctions in 1992 because of Serbia's role in fomenting the Bosnian war. They were suspended after the Dayton agreement but have yet to be finally lifted.</p>
<p>Ministers of Contact Group nations -- the United States, Russia, Britain, France and Germany -- met at the U.S. Mission to the United Nations, on the margins of the U.N. General Assembly in New York.</p>
<p>Later, U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher met successively with Bosnia's Moslem President Alija Izetbegovic, Serbian Foreign Minister Milan Milutinovic and Croatian Foreign Minister Mate Granic.</p>
<p>The Security Council cannot lift the sanctions until the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), which supervised the elections, has certified that they met the standards laid down by Dayton.</p>
<p>But Robert Frowick, head of the OSCE mission in Bosnia, told the meeting he expected to do this within 48 hours.</p>
<p>The statement called on Bosnia's Moslem, Serb and Croat factions to redouble efforts to create a unified, multi-ethnic Bosnia, to set up the joint presidency elected Sept. 14 and to hold the first presidency meeting in Sarajevo next week.</p>
<p>Bosnia peace coordinator Carl Bildt said he wanted to see the U.N. specify that it was ready to re-impose sanctions if necessary, an idea also supported by the United States.</p>
<p>This could be done &quot;against anyone that would undertake actions that would threaten the unity of Bosnia-Herzegovina or in other ways seriously jeopardise the implementation of the peace agreement&quot;, Bildt told reporters.</p>
<p>Bosnia's Serbs and Croats are widely suspected of wanting to merge the parts of Bosnia that they control with Serbia and Croatia respectively at some point in the future, although Dayton forbids them to do so.</p>
<p>The United States plans to retain its own &quot;outer wall&quot; of sanctions to debar rump Yugoslavia -- Serbia and Montenegro -- from access to international financial institutions or from taking former Yugoslavia's U.N. seat.</p>
<p>Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring, representing the European Union, said there had been no discussion by the Contact Group of an international peacekeeping force to replace the NATO-led IFOR, whose mandate expires in December.</p>
<p>But he said: &quot;I think there is a general view emerging from all of our discussions in New York this week that there will have to be a new post-IFOR mandate. The shape of that or the actual scale of it has not been discussed in any detail yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Izetbegovic told reporters some kind of force would have to remain. &quot;We believe that the extension of the IFOR presence is necessary for at least two more years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.N. diplomats said two meetings -- one in November and one in December -- were planned to work out the basis for a continuing international involvement in Bosnia.</p>
<p>The first, expected to be held Nov. 14 in Paris, would involve the Group of Seven top industrial nations, Russia and an Islamic representative. The second would be held in London with exact dates and participation still to be decided.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
