<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="78980" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy to unveil tough budget in dash for EMU.</title>
<headline>Italy to unveil tough budget in dash for EMU.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Hurst</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's government said on Thursday it was ready to unveil a 50 trillion lire 1997 budget ($32.9 billion) in a bid to join a single European currency after a key hard-left ally softened opposition to welfare cuts.</p>
<p>Foreign Trade Minister August Fantozzi told reporters after a summit meeting of party leaders in the centre-left coalition led by Prime Minister Romano Prodi that the budget would cut Italy's deficit to gross domestic (GDP) ratio to three percent.</p>
<p>The planned budget, which will include a special &quot;Euro-tax,&quot; is well in excess of the 32.4 trillion lire the government had originally intended to slash from the public sector deficit.</p>
<p>Achievement of the three percent deficit target would put Italy on course to join an advance party of countries setting up a single European currency in 1999, Fantozzi said.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers to get into Europe are there and they will take us to three percent,&quot; Fantozzi said. &quot;They will allow us to be with the other countries from the start.&quot;</p>
<p>The cabinet is due to approve the budget on Friday before submitting it to parliament, which must pass it into law by the end of December.</p>
<p>The Euro-tax would raise between 10 and 12 trillion lire next year while two trillion lire in savings would come through streamlining pensions spending and a further two trillion lire from savings on healthcare, a government source said.</p>
<p>The government has not said where the Euro-tax would fall but newspapers have reported that it would be in the form of a once-off increase in income tax.</p>
<p>Financial markets, which have been electrified by the prospect of a tough budget, greeted the announcement with a fresh burst of euphoria. The lira rose to 994.4 against the mark, its highest level for more than two years, while bond prices surged to new record highs.</p>
<p>Fausto Bertinotti, leader of the hard-left Communist Refoundation party, who was bitterly opposed to Treasury plans to cut health and pensions spending, said after meeting Prodi that budget talks with government allies had made progress.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if there continue to be problems, we have made a significant step forward,&quot; Bertinotti told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Naturally until we have crossed the finishing line, and we will cross the finishing line tomorrow evening with the presentation of the budget, there will continue to be problems,&quot; said Bertinotti.</p>
<p>Prodi's government, appointed in May, relies on Communist Refoundation for its majority in the lower house of parliament.</p>
<p>Right-wing opposition leaders said that Prodi had caved in to pressure from the hard left. &quot;You cannot go into Europe with accounting tricks,&quot; said Maurizio Gasparri, a senior member of the post-fascist National Alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we want to see the text because the impression is that it's a cosmetic agreement while it is clear that we are faced with a (government) majority which is more than ever blackmailed by Bertinotti,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The planned Euro tax may receive a hostile reception in a country which already bears one of Europe's steepest tax burdens. A Datamedia poll conducted on Wednesday showed 56.4 percent of a sample of 1,002 Italians were not prepared to pay.</p>
<p>One economist voiced concern at the possible impact of fiscal entrenchment on an already faltering economy. &quot;One has to be extremely concerned as to the impact of this on the economy. It could be very bad for growth,&quot; said Darren Williams, a London-based economist with Swiss bank UBS.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
