<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790018" id="root" date="1997-08-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: HK demo urges London to resolve boatpeople legacy.</title>
<headline>HK demo urges London to resolve boatpeople legacy.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Lau</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 80 people  mounted a noisy protest outside Hong Kong's British Consulate on Sunday, calling on London to take in Vietnamese migrants stranded in the territory.</p>
<p>The demonstration, organised by a pro-China political party, earlier petitioned the office of the territory's new leader Tung Chee-hwa, urging the Beijing-backed government to end Hong Kong's &quot;first port of asylum status&quot;, a legacy of British rule.</p>
<p>&quot;Hong Kong people have been compelled to deal with the Vietnamese boat people problem under the first asylum port policy imposed by the British Government in 1979,&quot; the Democratic Alliance for the Betterment of Hong Kong said in an open letter to British Foreign Secretary Robin Cook.</p>
<p>&quot;We demand the British Government to take back all boat people remaining in Hong Kong and arrange their repatriation, and take positive measures to recover the United Nations' debt.&quot;</p>
<p>Some 3,000 Vietnamese migrants, commonly called boat people because many arrived by sea, remain in Hong Kong despite China's repeated call to Britain to clear the detention centres where they are held before Beijing took over the territory on July 1.</p>
<p>Beijing appears to have taken no action on the issue, leaving it to Hong Kong authorities to continue the repatriation programme as best it can.</p>
<p>The U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees owes Hong Kong HK$1.1 billion (US$142 million) for the upkeep of the refugee camps.</p>
<p>Hong Kong became a first port of asylum in 1979, making it a clearing centre for the boat people before they were taken in by third countries.</p>
<p>Many Hong Kong people opposed this measure and believe London should be responsible for those remained after the handover.</p>
<p>The boat people drama began almost two decades ago, when tens of thousands fled after the 1975 Communist victory in the Vietnam War.</p>
<p>Tung is also facing a legal challenge to a new law to deport illegal child immigrants from China.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's High Court will decide on Monday whether to proceed with a challenge by young illegal immigrants from China that the law violates their constitutional rights.</p>
<p>The problem arose when the government passed a law to deport hundreds, and possibly thousands, of children who sneaked in to Hong Kong to avoid immigration formalities which take years to complete.</p>
<p>The children were smuggled into Hong Kong to join parents already here. Hong Kong wants them to go back to the mainland and apply for immigration papers through the proper channels.</p>
<p>If they have a Hong Kong parent with residency rights, then under the post-colonial constitution, they have the right of abode.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
