<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790044" id="root" date="1997-08-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: U.S. envoy meets Israeli, Palestinian leaders.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy meets Israeli, Palestinian leaders.</headline>
<byline>Howard Goller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-08-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton's special envoy launched a Middle East peace mission on Sunday, trying to restore Israeli-PLO security cooperation following a bloody suicide attack.</p>
<p>&quot;The president and the secretary want me to focus on the security questions and I will be doing that,&quot; envoy Dennis Ross told reporters after meeting Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu for 2-1/2 hours.</p>
<p>Clinton and Secretary of State Madeleine Albright dispatched Ross to ease tensions heightened by a July 30 suicide attack which killed 15 people including the two Islamic militant bombers at a Jerusalem market.</p>
<p>Underscoring the difficulties facing Ross, Palestinian officials insisted as he headed into a meeting with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat that the envoy's mission must not be limited to security concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot confine the talks to security issues,&quot; Information Minister Yasser Abed Rabbo told Reuters before the meeting in the self-ruled West Bank town of Ramallah.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the Palestinian leadership's decision -- that all issues should be discussed with Ross in order to reach positive results,&quot; Abed Rabbo said.</p>
<p>Ross said earlier that Clinton and Albright recognised there was &quot;a political dimension that has to be addressed but they also understand that there is an essential security underpinning to the (peace) process&quot;.</p>
<p>Arafat wants Israel to ease a security clampdown on Palestinians. Netanyahu closed off the West Bank and Gaza after the market attack and conditioned any resumption of talks on Arafat cracking down on Islamic militant groups.</p>
<p>In a television interview with Reuters and CNN on Saturday, Arafat said he was making a &quot;100 percent effort&quot; to arrest militants trying to wreck peace moves.</p>
<p>Ignoring a public U.S. appeal to both sides to tone down their war of words, Arafat on Saturday accused Israel of waging &quot;state terrorism&quot; against his people as punishment for the market attack.</p>
<p>&quot;What we see are tricks, misleading actions and evasions and an attempt to divert world attention and even the Israeli public,&quot; countered Netanyahu's foreign policy adviser Uzi Arad in an army radio interview on Sunday.</p>
<p>Arafat also said on Saturday that he would raise with Ross the issue of Israel's Jewish settlement policy on land occupied since the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's decision to start work on the Jewish settlement of Har Homa in Arab East Jerusalem in March led to a freeze in substantive peace negotiations with Arafat's PLO.</p>
<p>Palestinians view the construction on a hill they call Jabal Abu Ghneim as a unilateral violation of their peace deals.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no connection between the construction in Har Homa and the settlements...and the terrorism,&quot; Netanyahu's communications chief David Bar-Illan said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no chance that we will stop the construction on Har Homa or that the Americans would demand that,&quot; Bar-Illan told Israel's Channel One television.</p>
<p>The Israeli army lifted an &quot;inner closure&quot; in parts of the West Bank on Sunday, allowing Palestinians to travel between three besieged self-ruled cities, Jenin, Tulkarm and Qalqilya. It gave no reason for the move.</p>
<p>It opened crossings linking the West Bank and Gaza with Jordan and Egypt for travel by Palestinians and others.</p>
<p>Israeli soldiers would continue to surround the West Bank cities of Hebron, Ramallah and Bethlehem and an overall ban on Palestinians entering Israel remained in effect, the army said. A siege of Jericho and Nablus was lifted on Friday.</p>
<p>Ross, on his first mission since May, said he would also be preparing for a possible first visit to the region by Albright. She had said she was prepared to visit at the end of the month provided progress was made on security.</p>
<p>Her trip would likely be aimed at finding ways to wrap up outstanding issues from interim Israel-PLO deals and pursue accelerated talks on a final peace settlement.</p>
<p>On Friday Arafat said Israel had informed him the bombers came from abroad. Arafat also suggested in television interviews on Saturday that the pro-Iranian Hizbollah group in Lebanon may have been linked to the attack.</p>
<p>Israeli security officials say they do not know the bombers' origins and say the attackers in any event get orders and support from areas under Arafat's control.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
