<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790127" id="root" date="1997-08-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt issues investment incentives law.</title>
<headline>Egypt issues investment incentives law.</headline>
<byline>Christine Hauser</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-08-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt has issued an incentives law intended to attract direct investment and breathe life into its economic reform programme, which aims to scrap remnants of central planning and give a greater role to the private sector.</p>
<p>The ministerial decree on the Investment Incentives Law regulations was published on Sunday. The law was signed in May but its predecessor was in force until now.</p>
<p>&quot;It first of all gives official birth to the new law,&quot; Ibrahim Fawzy, president of Egypt's General Authority for Investment (GAFI), told Reuters.</p>
<p>The law reflects Egypt's aim to liberalise the economy and develop priority sectors by luring investors with incentives.</p>
<p>&quot;They are rationalising their activities according to the economic direction the government would like to go,&quot; said Abdallah al-Adly, vice chairman of the tax committee for the American Chamber of Commerce in Egypt.</p>
<p>The law gives a 20-year tax break for investors in two areas in the south, Toskha and the New Valley, which Egypt wants to develop as industrial centres. Satellite cities, remote areas and new industrial zones get a 10-year break and city investors five.</p>
<p>Fawzy said the law cuts red tape because investors simply notify GAFI that the project they want to set up is among 16 priority sectors, such as industry or mining.</p>
<p>In the tourism industry, one of Egypt's main hard currency earners, the regulations detail how many units at a tourist facility can be sold to investors. &quot;Fifty percent of a built area can be sold to the public,&quot; Fawzy said.</p>
<p>Under the old law, permission was needed when an investor wanted to expand a project.</p>
<p>&quot;The new law does not request approval of projects specifically. We approve fields. So in 10 years they can expand and do whatever they want so long as they operate in the field they requested permission in,&quot; Fawzy said.</p>
<p>It also changes the old law on tax incentives, which said investors could expand their projects in the first 10 years to extend a 10-year tax exemption another five years.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the old law someone could have expanded in the ninth year and got exemptions for a further five years,&quot; said Fawzy. &quot;But under the new law he has 10 years to operate freely but after 10 years no exemption.&quot;</p>
<p>The law also reflects Egypt's aim to liberalise by dropping a reference to repatriation of profits and capital. Adly said that previously, investors had to go through lengthy procedures and submit financial statements.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no provisions regarding repatriation,&quot; Adly said. &quot;Before, they would do extensive studies and ask for more provisions and for companies not to repatriate totally.&quot;</p>
<p>Reactions to the law have been mixed. Ahmed Abouali, Hassouna and Abouali Law Office partner, said the absence of a reference to profits repatriation, while reflecting a desire to liberalise, was confusing.</p>
<p>&quot;The law lacks a clear statement that investors who wish to withdraw from the Egyptian market can repatriate their profits or capital...what if liberalisation were reversed?&quot; he was quoted in the American chamber's Business Monthly as saying.</p>
<p>Some questioned how existing projects would benefit. The previous law extended tax incentives for any capital increase or extension of an existing project.</p>
<p>&quot;What older projects would have to do is shut down shop and start up a new company to take advantage of the new law,&quot; said international lawyer Bridget McKinney. &quot;You still want to encourage investment in what is already here. That brings technology transfer, expertise and money.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
