<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790139" id="root" date="1997-08-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MACHINE TOOL DEMAND UP IN FIRST HALF OF 1997.</title>
<headline>U.S. MACHINE TOOL DEMAND UP IN FIRST HALF OF 1997.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Demand for machine tools rose nearly 20 percent in the first half of the year in comparison with the same period of 1996, two industry groups said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The American Machine Tool Distributors' Association and the Association for Manufacturing Technology said in a joint report that January-June machine tool demand rose to $4.411 billion from $3.685 billion in the first six months of 1996.  </p>
<p>&quot;Consumer and export demands for manufactured goods continue growing at double-digit rates. Manufacturers cannot keep pace with this growth using the same machines their fathers operated,&quot; AMT President Albert Moore said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Until manufacturers can bring production capacity in line with the demand for their products, orders for machine tools will remain strong,&quot; Moore added.</p>
<p>Total demand in June increased 38.9 percent to an estimated $894 million from a revised $644 million in May. The figure was up 81.3 percent from the $493 million estimated for June 1996.  </p>
<p>The May estimate was revised down from $678 million reported a month ago.</p>
<p>Machine tools are used to shape metal in making everything from bicycles to aircraft. Demand for these tools are viewed as a leading indicator of the pace of manufacturing.</p>
<p>By region, the report said the Midwest accounted for 35.3 percent of national demand in June, followed by 24.7 percent in the South and 15.5 percent in the Central region. The Northeast accounted for 13.6 percent and the West 10.9 percent, the report said.</p>
<p>Export orders placed with U.S. machine tool makers totaled 229 units in June, up from 201 units in May, it said. Year-earlier export orders were not available.</p>
<p>Total export orders in the first six months of 1997 were 1,516 units, the report said.</p>
<p>The latest figures were from the 13th U.S. Machine Tool Consumption report, which replaced monthly data on U.S. machine tool orders, shipments and exports issued by the Association for Manufacturing Technology.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
