<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79015" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish stock market hits fourth record in 16 days.</title>
<headline>Danish stock market hits fourth record in 16 days.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish share prices set a new closing record on Thursday -- the fourth this month -- but dealers suspected that profit-taking on Friday might close the week on a more subdued note.</p>
<p>&quot;We are up in the thin stratosphere with the KFX index and if one looks a little speculatively at the market one would consider taking some profit home,&quot; a dealer said, adding that overnight Wall Street gains, taking bonds along, could send the Copenhagen index to test 123 points.</p>
<p>&quot;But the most likely is that we shall start off quietly tomorrow with perhaps a slight downward tendency,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index gained 1.19 point to 122.80 in overall bourse turnover of 719 million crowns. The KFX December future rose 0.50 point to 123.65, with 60 contracts each worth 100,000 crowns traded.</p>
<p>Its previous record of 122.35 was set on September 20 and followed the highs of September 17 and 10.</p>
<p>Behind Thursday's upward drive were rises in bank shares, food and drink-maker Danisco and biotech innovator Novo Nordisk.</p>
<p>A solid bond market and continuing foreign demand for Danish bank paper pushed Unibank up five crowns to 279, with 123,000 shares traded. Its rival Den Danske Bank got a seven-crown rise to 431 crowns, in one third of the turnover.</p>
<p>Danisco rose nine crowns to 334.</p>
<p>Novo rose six crowns to 916. In recent weeks it has won a labelling battle against Eli Lilly and announced expansion plans in China and on Wednesday it unveiled a product development pact with Germany's Schering.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
