<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790252" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. LPGs mostly bearish in light trade.</title>
<headline>U.S. LPGs mostly bearish in light trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. spot liquefied petroleum gas market weakened in thin trade on Monday as last week's EIA report, which showed near-record builds in July for propane, finally took its toll, traders said.</p>
<p>Last Wednesday's report said July inventories increased by 7.1 billion barrels.</p>
<p>In Mont Belvieu, Texas, propane traded at 36.25 cents and 36.38 cents a gallon. The latter parcel was 15,000 barrels.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people are hanging in there watching what the market is going to do,&quot; said one Houston trader. He said he would be &quot;real surprised&quot; to see anybody go up to 36.50 cents for propane.</p>
<p>Traders pegged propane's range at 36.00/36.50 cents, about a quarter cent below Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices are so low compared to the rest of the world that international players don't want to pay the freight charge for Houston LPG's,&quot; said another Houston player.</p>
<p>In Belvieu, ethane purity was the only other product heard done. It was done at 21.25 cents.</p>
<p>Belvieu butane and isobutane were pegged 0.25 and 0.50 cents below Friday's values, respectively.</p>
<p>In Conway, Kansas, the market was also slow. Propane was done at 35.75 cents, about 0.25 cent lower than Friday.</p>
<p>Conway natural gasoline and ethane sold for 46.75 and 19.25 cents, respectively, slightly down from Friday's ask prices. --Tim Gardner, New York Oil Desk +1 212 859 1632 --</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
