<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790237" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian dollar opens weaker in light trading.</title>
<headline>Canadian dollar opens weaker in light trading.</headline>
<text>
<p>FORECAST RANGE   1.3915/1.3955	   ASIAN CLOSE     1.3890</p>
<p>RESISTANCE 1.3825   SUPPORT 1.3976     HI 1.3923   LO  1.3892</p>
<p>CANADA OPEN  1.3923/28   HI 1.3923     EUROPE OPEN     1.3902</p>
<p>PREV CLOSE   1.3901/06   LO 1.3892     HI 1.3912   LO  1.3900</p>
<p>----------------------MARKET COMMENT-------------------------</p>
<p>* The Canadian dollar opened weaker at C$1.3923 (US$0.7182) in</p>
<p>light trading on Monday as market hopes of a Bank of Canada</p>
<p>interest rate hike all but disappeared, traders said. * They</p>
<p>said the Canadian dollar is expected to trade toward the weak end of the C$1.3915 (US$0.7186) to C$1.3955 (US$0.7165) range for the remainder of today's session.  </p>
<p>Analysts said they expected the Canada unit to keep weakening through the C$1.3935 level, near the point where the Bank of Canada last raised interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;People are going to keep leaning on the Canada (dollar) and see what they can get out of it. The right side (of the range) is vulnerable because people are looking for the Bank (of Canada) to tighten ahead of the C$1.3950 (US$0.7168) level,&quot; said a trader with a Canadian bank.</p>
<p>&quot;If that doesn't happen, they'll be disappointed and bump it higher, probably triggering some stops along the way,&quot; the trader added.  </p>
<p>Housing data released on Monday did little to move the Canadian dollar.</p>
<p>Canada Mortgage and Housing Corp reported that Canadian housing starts rose by 2.7 percent in July to a seasonally adjusted rate of 144,700 units from a revised 140,900 in June.</p>
<p>A Reuters survey of economists had forecast a gain of 147,125 units for July.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we are going to see a huge reaction in the markets because these numbers are pretty good when you compare them to a year ago,&quot; said Peter Drake, deputy chief economist with Toronto-Dominion Bank.  </p>
<p>&quot;I still think the fundamentals for the Canadian dollar are good, but the question now is whether the fundamentals are going to pick it up over the next several months or whether the Bank of Canada is going to have to help,&quot; Drake said.</p>
<p>On the crosses, the Canada dollar climbed to 83.22 Japanese yen from 82.34 on Friday and rose to 1.3318 marks from Friday's 1.3269 marks.</p>
<p>((Paul Simao, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8104)) (c) Reuters Limited 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
