<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790219" id="root" date="1997-08-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIA CONGRESS CHIEF VOWS TO WIN ELECTIONS.</title>
<headline>INDIA CONGRESS CHIEF VOWS TO WIN ELECTIONS.</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1997-08-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Congress party president Sitaram Kesri pledged on Sunday to deliver victory at India's next general election and urged the party's workers to close ranks and strengthen the organisation.</p>
<p>Congress, which has ruled India for all but five of the 50 years since independence, finished a humiliating second in a general election last year but it provides make-or-break backing to Prime Minister Inder Kumar Gujral's 15-party coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;You discipline yourselves, give me your support, I will give you power in Delhi,&quot; Kesri said in a closing address at the party's plenary session.</p>
<p>&quot;You will give us the strength to march towards Delhi and unfurl the national flag at Red Fort.&quot; The historic Red Fort is the traditional venue where the nation's prime minister unfurls the national flag on Independence Day (August 15).</p>
<p>The Congress chief has repeatedly vowed during the three-day meeting to lead the party back into power.</p>
<p>Kesri said he did not want to grab power by dislodging the present government. &quot;My eyes are on Delhi but not by removing this government but through people's mandate,&quot; he told Reuters after giving a general media briefing.</p>
<p>Kesri ignited a political crisis in March when he abruptly withdrew support for the then prime minister, H.D. Deve Gowda, who was later toppled in a parliamentary vote of confidence.</p>
<p>The centre-left United Front then turned to Gujral, who has since enjoyed Congress' support but has been undermined by tensions within his own party and coalition.</p>
<p>Kesri said the coalition government was unable to provide stability and fulfill the aspirations of the people. He predicted an early election but ruled it out in the immediate future. A government can remain in office for up to five years.</p>
<p>&quot;I am ready and I have started my preparations. But I must also say elections are not going to come soon,&quot; he earlier told the briefing.</p>
<p>Kesri, who was re-elected as party president in June, promised to tour all the states with an eye on the polls.</p>
<p>He said Congress must be on its guard and fight the right-wing Hindu opposition Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) and left-wing parties.</p>
<p>&quot;Be cautious aginst these forces. We have to fight against the BJP and the left,&quot; Kesri said.</p>
<p>BJP, the main opposition, is the single largest party in parliament.</p>
<p>Kesri rebutted allegations of corruption against Congress, saying the party never spared the corrupt. &quot;Congress is more honest than other parties, cleaner than others.&quot;</p>
<p>The indictment of many party leaders in corruption scandals put paid to party's bid for power at the last general election.</p>
<p>More than half a dozen ministers of the 112-year-old Congress, once synonymous with the freedom movement, resigned after being charged in a money-laundering scandal.</p>
<p>Kesri appeared to have crossed a major hurdle on Saturday when seven of his supporters were leading in an election to the party's elite decision-making body, the Congress Working Committee (CWC).</p>
<p>The CWC has 20 members, of which 10 are elected and the rest nominated by the party chief.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
