<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790559" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: ATHLETICS-SMITH'S SPRINTERS NOW THE BEST IN THE WORLD.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-SMITH'S SPRINTERS NOW THE BEST IN THE WORLD.</headline>
<byline>Gene Cherry</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Among the brash young men and women at a Los Angeles' sprint camp, stands John Smith; coach, counselor and producer of 15 Olymic and world gold medals since the 1988 Seoul Games.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot find another coach that has had more gold medals, more world records in so many different events with so many different athletes with so many different backgrounds,&quot; proclaimed Trinidadian Ato Boldon, who became Smith's latest charge to claim gold when he won the world 200 metres title at Athens' Olympic Stadium.</p>
<p>The victory gave Smith a second sprint title at the world championships after American Maurice Greene won the 100 metres.</p>
<p>So enthralled was Boldon with Smith's talent that he abandoned his coach of 15 years and persuaded his parents to drive him across country to work with Boldon, sprinter Jon Drummond and French double Olympic women's champion Marie-Jose Perec.</p>
<p>&quot;No one has the credentials that he has,&quot; said Greene, who will attack the 100 metres world record at Zurich on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Smith's closeness to his athletes and his willingness to channel their energies into a productive direction are major reasons for the former 400 metre runner's success as a coach, Boldon said.</p>
<p>&quot;He is able to coach the part of an athlete which most coaches deem uncoachable,&quot; said the 1996 Olympic 100 and 200 metre bronze medallist. &quot;There are a lot of races that I have won because John was able to get in there and make my ego come out.&quot;</p>
<p>World record-holder in the now abandoned 440 yards, Smith sees the pending retirement of nine times Olympic gold medallist Carl Lewis as a perfect opportunity for his young athletes to cross new frontiers in the sprints, posting times never before seriously considered. </p>
<p>&quot;They are my motivation,&quot; said the assistant coach at the University of California. &quot;I have never won a (major) gold medal.&quot;</p>
<p>The world number one over 400 metres in 1971, he lost his opportunity for gold to a hamstring injury in the Munich Olympics, failing to finish the 400 metres final.</p>
<p>His work ethic is notorious, and several times it has driven elite athletes from his camp.</p>
<p>&quot;I grew up in a post-war era where you worked a solid day,&quot; explained Smith, who celebrated his 47th birthday at the championships.</p>
<p>&quot;I never expected anyone to take care of me and I always wanted to do things differently,&quot; said Smith, an innovator on and off the track.</p>
<p>Another coach commented: &quot;His athletes are well-trained and physically fit, and he teaches them to come as close to the maximum as is possible without surpassing it in the hopes that they will be able to maintain that level longer than someone who has reached a peak and gone downhill.&quot;</p>
<p>Smith said he has a passion for his work.</p>
<p>&quot;That's my magic. One day I came to work and I fell in love with my work.&quot;</p>
<p>Steve Lewis provided his first individual Olympic gold, breaking through to win the 1988 400 metre title. Since then his athletes have claimed at least one gold at every major championship with Perec earning double gold at the Atlanta Games.</p>
<p>&quot;I stage my whole philosophy as an art form so I allow (my sprinters) to express themselves as the people they are,&quot; the part-time actor said.</p>
<p>His success is self-evident. John Smith's sprinters are now the best in the world.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
