<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790855" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK background inflation pressures still dormant.</title>
<headline>UK background inflation pressures still dormant.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices of goods leaving British factory gates remained dormant in July, official figures out on Monday showed.</p>
<p>The Office for National Statistics said output prices rose just 0.2 percent in July, leaving them just 1.4 percent higher than a year ago.</p>
<p>Input prices -- measuring the cost of raw materials paid by Britain's manufacturers -- dropped a seasonally adjusted 0.4 percent on the month and were a staggering nine percent lower than in July last year.  </p>
<p>Economists said the meteoric rise in the value of the pound -- it spurted another four percent higher in July -- was keeping pipeline inflation pressures well and truly under wraps.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of sterling is killing input prices at the moment while the strength of domestic demand is allowing output prices to creep up,&quot; said Robin Marshall, chief economist at Chase Investment Bank. &quot;At the moment, sterling is winning out overall.&quot; But producer prices, subdued for as long as most people can remember, are unlikely to hold much sway over monetary policy. The Bank of England raised interest rates for the fourth time in as many months last week, but hinted that it would be the last tightening for some time.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not producer prices that is worrying the Bank of England, it's the pace of consumer demand,&quot; said Ciaran Barr, UK economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell. --London Newsroom +44 171 542 2774</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
