<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790866" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ SPORT - AB'S RETURN TO BASICS FREED UP CULLEN.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT - AB'S RETURN TO BASICS FREED UP CULLEN.</headline>
<text>
<p>WELLINGTON, Aug 11 - A return to the basics by the All Blacks freed brilliant attacking fullback Christian Cullen to get back to his best against South Africa on Saturday, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>Cullen scored two tries and had a hand in a couple more simply because he was given the ball quicker and at pace during the All Blacks' 55-35 tri-series win at Auckland's Eden Park.</p>
<p>He has scored 17 tries in 17 tests and is chasing team-mates Jeff Wilson on 21 and Frank Bunce on 20.  </p>
<p>John Kirwan holds the All Blacks' all-time try-scoring record with 35, followed by Wilson, Bunce, and then Cullen, who is tied in third place with Zinzan Brooke.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been working all week on the presentation of the ball, getting the passes in front, so we don't have to stop and catch them and then run,&quot; said Cullen.</p>
<p>&quot;It seemed to work pretty well out there.&quot;</p>
<p>The All Blacks often passed across second five-eighth Alama Ieremia to give centre Bunce a crack at opposing centre Percy Montgomery, a player of uncertain defensive ability.</p>
<p>It was a move that allowed Cullen extra freedom.  </p>
<p>&quot;It kept us away from a strong defender in Henry Honiball and let Frankie have a one-on-one with Percival,&quot; said Ieremia.</p>
<p>&quot;And we tried to use Christian outside Buncy. Percy wasn't a one-out defender. We knew if we could contain him and Honiball in the middle, that the outside lane would be available for Christian.</p>
<p>&quot;So we tried to use that a lot.&quot;</p>
<p>The day was not all roses for Cullen, however.</p>
<p>He had a second quarter to forget, when he contributed to two South African tries by firstly losing the ball in a tackle and then not quite getting to a high kick on the full.  </p>
<p>Gary Teichmann's try came when Cullen was tackled and bounced the ball, instead of placing it. The Springbok No 8 toed the loose ball ahead and picked up a lucky bounce to run clear and score.</p>
<p>&quot;Just a freak bounce, I guess,&quot; said Cullen. &quot;I'll take the blame for it. I don't mind.&quot;</p>
<p>The second try came from a miscued Montgomery bomb which bounced and was regained by the kicker. It was a fullback's nightmare -- even the kicker didn't know where the ball was going.  </p>
<p>&quot;He was kicking for the corner, I was going the wrong way and I just couldn't get there. It caught everybody off-foot, we were all caught on the wrong foot. I'll take the blame,&quot; said Cullen.</p>
<p>The fullback also shared the All Blacks' disappointment at conceding five tries.</p>
<p>&quot;We could have beaten them 55-20 except for those soft tries. We made a lot of mistakes. Thirty-five points is too high. So we're not overly happy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
