<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="790953" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NAMIBIA: PRESS DIGEST - NAMIBIA - AUG 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - NAMIBIA - AUG 11.</headline>
<dateline>WINDHOEK 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the stories making headlines in the Namibian newspapers on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE NAMIBIAN</p>
<p>- A 29-year-old primary school teacher Nathaniel Kamatuka has been charged with sodomising five pupils at the Otavi Primary School in the second child sex abuse scandal rocking the Ministry of Basic Education and Culture this year. In June a hostel father at the Khomasdal Institute for Special Education was charged with sodomy and rape involving disabled minors.</p>
<p>- Botswana's parliament passed a key constitutional reform bill last week limiting the president's term of office to ten years and reducing the voting age from 21 to 18.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>DIE ALLGEMEINE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- The National Society for Human Rights (NSHR) and the  Democratic Turnhalle Alliance (DTA) have in separate statements warned the government that its politics could lead to ethnic division in Namibia.</p>
<p>- Agriculture Minister Helmuth Angula has told farmers that they can in future no longer expect the support from the government. He told farmers at Keetmanshoop they would have to become more efficient and productive and could no longer rely on government subsidies.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>DIE REPUBLIKEIN</p>
<p>- Several million dollars are to be paid out of government coffers to retiring politicians as gratification bonusses and as retirement schemes for the president, cabinet members and members of parliament.</p>
<p>- The Namibian police have arrested two men in the latest drug trafficking attempt. They uncovered 17,5 kg of cocaine worth N$ 7,8 million hidden in electrical transformers, which were underway to Johannesburg.</p>
<p>-- Windhoek newsroom +26461 24-5260</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NAMIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINDHOEK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NAMIBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
