<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791074" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - CROATIA - AUG 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - CROATIA - AUG 11.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the leading stories in Croatian dailies on Monday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Foreign tourist rush on the Croatian coast and islands continued at the weekend. Some 36,000 vehicles drove through Karlovac on the main highway to the seaside while 29,000 returned.</p>
<p>- Ognjen Preost, a 28-year old officer of the Croatian army, wins the 282nd annual Sinjska Alka tournament.</p>
<p>- Vlado Gotovac's visit to the Split liberals confirms a split within his Social-Liberal Party.</p>
<p>- Money market: Interests continue to fall, overnight trade minimal.</p>
<p>- Croatian economy in the red for a total of 5.2 billion kuna in 1996, according to the central payments agency ZAP. Only private sector ended the year with higher income than overall costs.</p>
<p>- Stock market: Varazdinska Banka ordinaries join record breakers, rising to 275 from 239 kuna last week.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Public utilities owed most money in Zagreb, least in Rijeka. The state electricity board (HEP) alone seeks payment of 97.2 million kuna by households in the capital.</p>
<p>- July pension payments were delayed because of slower inflow of pension contributions from companies due to holidays, says Damir Zoric, head of the state pension fund MIORH. At the same time MIORH had to allot more money after pensions were raised by 3.7 percent.</p>
<p>- Damages to the electricity grid in Eastern Slavonia estimated at $150 million. The main 400-kiloVolt transformer station in Ernestinovo, which would enable reconnecting of the Croatian and Yugoslav power networks, in a very bad shape.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Sinjska Alka tournament stands a a symbol of Croatian endurance, heroism and resistance, says President Tudjman.</p>
<p>- Interview with the Immigration Minister Marijan Petrovic: Most expatriates returning to Croatia want to live in Zagreb and at the seaside.</p>
<p>- Bosnian army general Mehmed Alagic in his war memoirs mentioning battles against Croats in central Bosnia wrote his own indictment for the international war crimes tribunal. -- Zagreb newsroom +385 1 455 7075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
