<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791167" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: MEXICO STOCKS SAG ON LONG BOND WOES.</title>
<headline>MEXICO STOCKS SAG ON LONG BOND WOES.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks were substantially down, but hovering above the 5,000 point market at midday trading on Monday.</p>
<p>Dealers said share prices had fallen on light profit- taking spurred by higher U.S. long bond yields.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a further adjustment after the recent rally, prices were really inflated. We are also seeing a continuation of Friday's jitters over the long bond,&quot; a floor trader said.</p>
<p>The leading IPC share index  .MXX was down 57.12 points, or 1.17 percent, at 5,017.93. Trading volume  .TV.MX was slow at 25.4 million shares.  </p>
<p>U.S. 30-year Treasury bonds were down 16/32 to yield 6.68 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers noted the IPC was slightly above an earlier low of 5,014.56 points.</p>
<p>&quot;Buyers have stepped back in for some financial stocks, but its too early to say it's a rebound. With volume this thin, the market could swing either way,&quot; another floor trader said. Telefonos de Mexico (Telmex), which accounted for more than 15 percent of all shares traded, was down 35 centavos at a session low of 20.55. The telecomms stock's ADRs had declined 1-1/4 to 52-9/13.  </p>
<p>Financial group Banomer A shares were down seven centavos at 3.53 pesos in relatively brisk trade, but traded as low as 3.38 mid-morning.</p>
<p>Steelmaker Altos Hornos de Mexico (Ahmsa) and retailer Comercial Mexicana were the only blue chips in positive territory. Dealers said the two stocks were market stragglers and only Ahmsa, up 10 centavos at 21.50 pesos, had experienced appreciable trading.</p>
<p>On the broad market, declines outweighed gains 51 to eight. Some 83 stocks changed hands.</p>
<p>(( --Martin Roberts, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7907))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
