<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791287" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - ASIA WATCHES RESCUE PACKAGE.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - ASIA WATCHES RESCUE PACKAGE.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Thai rescue package drafted by regional central bankers was the main focus of Asian debt markets on Monday.</p>
<p>Activity was relatively muted as bankers waited to see how much their respective economies were committing to the package.</p>
<p>Asian central bankers and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) ultimately agreed to a US$16 billion rescue package.</p>
<p>The package includes contributions from Australia, Hong Kong, Singapore Malaysia, Indonesia, Korea, Japan and the IMF, and China is considering joining the rescue.</p>
<p>It is already the single largest loan package to a single country since the IMF and donors led by the United States made nearly US$40 billion available to Mexico in 1995.</p>
<p>Bankers said the size of the various contributions reflected the exposure of various countries, particularly Japan, whose banks have been major lenders to Thai banks.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of who has more at stake, it's pretty clear, Japan has more at stake,&quot; said a Tokyo-based economist at a US investment bank.</p>
<p>The package is seen as the first sign that Thai's currency woes may be ending, and its top banks may be in a position to raise medium-term cash again in U.S. dollars.</p>
<p>Currency and credit fears have paralysed parts of the market, with some issues either being pulled and repriced or else offered with special credit clauses.</p>
<p>In other news, an underwriting group has been formed for a unit of Cheung Kong Infrastructure Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>The five-year facility has a margin of 39 basis points over the Hong Kong Interbank Offered Rate.</p>
<p>It is divided into a HK$2.0 billiion term loan and a HK$1.8 billion revolving credit which converts into a term loan after 2-1/2 years.</p>
<p>In China, the Shanghai branch of China's biggest bank, the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, will lend 500 million yuan (US$60 million) to a local electric company this year, according to reports from a Chinese news agency.</p>
<p>-- Sean Kennedy (852) 2843 6346</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
