<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791248" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBS TO CONSOLIDATE, TOPSIDE HEAVY.</title>
<headline>JGBS TO CONSOLIDATE, TOPSIDE HEAVY.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese government bonds (JGBs) are expected to consolidate at relatively high levels during Tokyo trade Tuesday, but substantial rises unlikely as many investors are out on summer vacations, traders said.</p>
<p>The market will closely watch moves in Tokyo stocks after Monday's fall of nearly four percent, but buying on this alone unlikely unless Nikkei shows signs of breaking below 18,000.</p>
<p>JGBs showed little response to Monday's fall, which saw the Nikkei close at 18,824.18, down 780.28, mainly due to a lack of investor participation on the summer holiday. Dealer wariness of bidding bonds much higher also weigh down gains.  </p>
<p>Brokers said moves in stocks today were expected to be mixed, with caution over active buying likely to offset any temptation for bargain-hunting.</p>
<p>Bond traders said there was a slight chance that further stock falls could lead to bond sales as operators sought to balance out their losses, but most felt the downside would hold near 126.40.</p>
<p>The dollar's rise above 116 yen means it is unlikely to have much impact as a direct factor for bonds. But this could possibly weigh on the topside should a dollar rise help stocks recover, keeping bond rises capped near 126.80.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
