<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791236" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia stocks end lower on Dow, local factors.</title>
<headline>Asia stocks end lower on Dow, local factors.</headline>
<byline>Marguerite Nugent</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian stock markets fell sharply on Monday, with several indices dropping below key support levels as the shakeout on Wall Street added to unease already plaguing the region.</p>
<p>Japanese stocks shed nearly four percent on Monday to close at their lowest level since the end of April.</p>
<p>The key 225-share Nikkei stock index was off 780.28 points or 3.98 percent at 18,824.18. It was the largest point loss for the index this year and the lowest close since April 28, when it ended at 18,670.37.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors have been worried about the recovery of the economy...and then Wall Street plunged...and the dollar weakened against the yen, both factors hurting investor sentiment further,&quot; said Nikko Securities general manager Mikio Takada.</p>
<p>The rising yen hurt Japan's export-related stocks, particularly electronics shares.</p>
<p>Fears of higher U.S. interest rates hit Hong Kong stocks at the opening, although a surge in Hang Seng Bank shares helped pull the market back up.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index ended down 187.07 points or 1.12 percent at 16,460.47. It had fallen to 16,328.72 earlier in the session.</p>
<p>In a dramatic about-face, Wall Street stocks shed nearly two percent on Friday as bond yields soared.</p>
<p>The catalyst for the rise in yields was speculation that U.S. economic growth may accelerate from its recent steady path and force the Federal Reserve to raise interest rates.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial average shed 156.78 points or 1.91 percent to end last week at 8,031.22. The U.S. Treasury's key 30-year bond lost 1-1/2 points, bringing the yield to 6.64 percent from 6.52 percent on Thursday.</p>
<p>The rise in yields failed to buffer the dollar, which fell on profit-taking and suffered its largest one-day decline against the mark in three months.</p>
<p>The dollar ended in New York at 1.8450/60 marks against 1.8600/05 at Friday's opening there and at 114.75/85 yen compared with 117.22/27.</p>
<p>The U.S. currency firmed slightly in early Asia trading on Monday and was quoted around 1.8500 marks and 115.54 yen.</p>
<p>Market talk that July U.S. retail sales rose more than an expected 0.5 to 0.6 percent spooked the bond market and contributed to the rise in yields. The figures are due Wednesday.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in Asia, Malaysian stocks were hit by a fall in the ringgit to a 42-month low of 2.7300 to the dollar, with the composite stock index falling below the key psychological barrier of 900 in mid-afternoon trading.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems like foreigners want to get out of the ringgit,&quot; said a dealing manager at a local brokerage.</p>
<p>The index bounced back slightly from the day's low of 896.59, rising to close at 902.91, down 30.22 points or 3.24 percent.</p>
<p>Philippine stocks were equally hard-hit, with the stock index closing down 75.39 points or 2.85 percent at 2,572.43.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a bloody market. Foreign investors are still cautious on the outcome of the peso's de facto devaluation,&quot; said Carl Valentin, a trader at Asia Pacific Capital Equities.</p>
<p>Stocks in Singapore fell past the year's low of 1,913.55 and then through a key support level of 1,900.</p>
<p>Continuing confusion over the fate of dual listings of Singapore blue-chip stocks contributed to weak sentiment. The Straits Times Index ended off 54.48 points or 2.80 percent at 1,889.44, near a five-year low.</p>
<p>Indonesian shares were hurt by high interest rates and the weak sentiment in neighbouring markets, which dragged the composite index down 17.27 points or 2.56 percent to 658.17.</p>
<p>Thai stocks moved in a narrow range as investors assessed the outcome of talks in Tokyo on Monday between Thailand and the International Monetary Fund on an aid package.</p>
<p>The SET composite index was off 2.27 points or 0.36 percent at 634.58.</p>
<p>Stocks in Seoul ended higher, aided by gains in the insurance sector, with the composite index closing 4.23 points higher at 765.07.</p>
<p>Taiwan's red-hot electronics stocks fell victim to heavy profit-taking, dragging the overall market lower. The main index ended down 96.27 points or 0.96 percent at 9,897.27.</p>
<p>The sell-off in New York pushed Australia's All Ordinaries Index down 44.2 points or 1.63 percent to 2,667.2, and New Zealand's main index down 30.05 points to 2,508.40.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
