<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791205" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-AUSTRALIAN BUSINESS NEWS - AUG 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-AUSTRALIAN BUSINESS NEWS - AUG 12.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Federal Treasurer Peter Costello will release a draft proposal to reform the corporations law in the next few weeks, scrapping the 20 percent takeover limit, allowing corporate raiders to buy control of a target company before launching a formal take-over bid, and giving the takeovers panel a greater role in matters that currently go to court. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Axiom Funds Management is set to take advantage of the strength of the property trust sector on the stockmarket by listing a new A$150 million industrial property trust. Like several other insurers and funds managers, Axiom is seeking to reduce its direct property holdings and realise large gains on property assets through floats. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Izzy Asper's Canadian CanWest Global Communications is reconsidering selling its 37.5 per cent excess stake in the TEN group through a Telecasters North Queensland Ltd float in the face of a Federal Court deadline giving the company seven weeks to cut its interest in TEN to 15 per cent. Page 17.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Alan Jackson will use about A$7.6 million of the funds raised by his A$43 million sale of half his stake in Austrim to exercise the current 2-for-5 rights issue that will raise A$206 million. Jackson did not comment on his intentions for the rest of the funds raised but said he needed to restructure his portfolio on an investment-type base. Page 17.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Creditors of the failed Network Entertainment group yesterday voted to allow administrator Greg Hall, of Price Waterhouse, to sell Network's business under a deed of company arrangement, leaving them with a maximum payout of 10 cents in the dollar. Three ompanies have offered to buy Network's video distribution business. Page 17.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The development of a A$3 billion Liquefied Natural Gas project in the Bayu-Undan gas fields in the Timor Sea, north of Darwin, has been threatened by an apparent rift between joint operators BHP Co Ltd and the United States company Phillips Petroleum, wit neither willing to compromise on their development plans. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>National Australia Bank chief Don Argus told a Securities Institute lunch in Sydney yesterday that the lowering of the bank's cost base was taking too long, but margins were stable after a period of erosion. Argus said the NAB was still seeking to cut its cost-to-income ratio to 40 per cent by 2000. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Victorian Treasury energy projects division deputy project leader Geoff Swier said yesterday the Government would review upstream reform issues within the next six months to a year. Swier said 40 per cent of total industry costs were in the upstream gas market, and he urged gas customers to encourage reform. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The ANZ Bank announced a plan to expand its small network of &quot;supermarket&quot; outlets and overhaul the existing 1225 Australian and New Zealand branches, transforming their role more toward sales. The ANZ said most of their branches would remain open, and staff would be retrained in sales skills and customer service. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Telstra Multimedia head Gerry Moriarty who is in charge of the Foxtel cable rollout, said yesterday that Telstra expects to lay broadband cable, capable of carrying cable-TV and other services developed by the company to more than the 2.5 million households agreed with News Corporation last month. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The New South Wales Roads and Traffic Authority's environmental consultants Rust PPK has warned the Authority that the volume of traffic forecast for Sydney's proposed Eastern Distributor tollway will be greater than the road's capacity, echoing similar avice from the State Department of Urban Affairs and Planning. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Qantas consultant and former head of operations Ian Oldmeadow said yesterday that to justify the joint A$3.3 billion price of the newly privatised Melbourne, Brisbane and Perth airports, the new owners would have to substantially increase some airport chages. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Telstra multimedia chief executive Gerry Moriarty says Telstra may recommence its roll-out of broadband cables or consider implementing an alternate Internet delivery program to take advantage of the on-line revolution. The decision comes after Telstra ageed to forego A$300 million in pay-TV revenue to News Corporation. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Metal Trades Industry Association has released a report recommending Australia adopts similar investment policies to Malaysia, Singapore and Ireland, where all three countries give foreign investors tax concessions. This recommendation follows the recommendations released in the Mortimer Report, but their successful application to Australia's economy seems unlikely. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Westpac is aiming to have Mondex smart card technology, which is seen as a replacement for cash, ready for market release by the middle of next year. The bank has begun a pilot testing program using 250 staff and believes the Mondex product will be superior to Visa International's system. Page 28.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The overall value of Telstra is expected to be as high as A$42 billion as consumer confidence for the A$10 billion sharemarket float in November continues to rise. The Federal Government hopes Telstra will become the most widely owned listed company in Australia with 65 per cent of the available shares to be sold to Australian investors. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>National Australia Bank managing director Don Argus, speaking at a Securities Institute of Australia lunch, has promised National Australia Bank shareholders they won't be disappointed with the company's full year profit result, which will be good despite increasing competition in the home loan lending market. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries Index lost 44.2 points to close at 2667.2 yesterday in its worst one day fall in four months. The result follows the fall of 156.7 points in the United States sharemarket on Friday, as fears over a possible rise in United States interest rates and a possible sell off on Wall Street continue. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>BHP chairman Jerry Ellis has reassured shareholders over the recent resignation of three company executives, saying the departures were part of the company's tough attitude towards accountability. BHP shares rose by two cents to A$17.01 yesterday as small investors supported the stock despite the general market index falling and continuing concerns over Wall Street's fall. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The share price of WMC dropped another 10 cents yesterday resulting in a year low price of A$7.39, as sales of the company entered its seventh week. Investors in WMC are preparing themselves for a lower than expected June-year profit as the price of nickel and copper continues to weaken. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Consumer confidence for the one-third sale of Telstra is extremely strong despite the actual value of the company being uncertain. This confidence may be attributed to the fact voters believe the Federal Government wouldn't sell them an over priced company, particularly as it seems likely they will want to sell the remaining two-thirds of the company in the future. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>National Australia Bank managing director Don Argus said yesterday NRMA's plans to offer home loans would make an already tough market harder still. Argus said he doubted NAB's margins would deteriorate further, and intends to cut its return on equity from 17 to 15 per cent and reduce its cost-to-income ratio from 53 per cent to 40 per cent. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Melbourne-based civil engineering contractor McConnell Dowell has won part of a A$83 million Saudi Arabian infrastructure contract, at the same time speculation increases that its troubled United States parent company Dominion Bridge Corporation may be about to be put up for sale. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Westpac will run Australia's first pilot the Mondex smart card, which is designed to replace cash. Staff at the bank's Epping-based operation will use telephones and specially designed electronic wallets to &quot;charge&quot; the reloadable cards, in a test run ahead of a full roll-out from the middle of next year. Page B3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
