<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791328" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: THAI CREDITORS PLEDGE $16 BLN IN RESCUE--IMF.</title>
<headline>THAI CREDITORS PLEDGE $16 BLN IN RESCUE--IMF.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's potential creditors on Monday pledged to extend about $16 billion in loans in a package to help shore up the ailing tiger economy, International Monetary Fund Deputy Managing Director Shigemitsu Sugisaki told a news conference.  </p>
<p>Seven economies -- Japan, Hong Kong, South Korea, Australia, Indonesia, Malaysia and Singapore -- and the IMF have pledged to contribute a total of $13 billion, Sugisaki said.</p>
<p>The World Bank, the Asian Development Bank, China and others may contribute a total of about $3 billion, he said.</p>
<p>Sugisaki said the IMF had estimated that an aid package of $14 billion was required for 1997 and 1998 and participants supported the request.</p>
<p>&quot;The meeting proceeded very smoothly and positively. Some $16 billion in financial support was promised, including the proposed IMF contribution of $4 billion,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Japan and the IMF would put up $4 billion each, while Australia, Hong Kong, Malaysia and Singapore would each extend $1 billion. Indonesia and South Korea would each provide $500 million, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;China is seriously and actively considering financing (a contribution to the Thai package),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The participants agreed that the package should be finalised shortly, he said.</p>
<p>Japanese Finance Ministry official Eisuke Sakakibara said Thailand now had more than sufficient funds and needed no additional funding.  </p>
<p>Sugisaki said loans provided under the package would be payable in three to five years and carry market interest rates.</p>
<p>Sakakibara said the package showed showed the determination of the region to cooperate in future in solving similar problems.</p>
<p>He said he expected planned talks between Thailand and Japanese private-sector banks on an a separate aid package to proceed smoothly.</p>
<p>Thai Finance Minister Thanong Bidaya said he would meet officials of Japanese private banks on Tuesday to inform them of an agreement between Thailand and the IMF on economic adjustment programmes for Thailand, and to ask for their support and for them to roll over existing loans.</p>
<p>He said he would tell the Japanese banks that Thailand was making efforts to restore its economy.  </p>
<p>&quot;We will...try to assure them that the IMF programme has been done. We have been trying our best to restore the economic condition of Thailand back to normal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the package agreed on Monday would be mostly used for the accumulation of foreign reserves and to correct balance of payments problems.</p>
<p>Thailand's foreign debt stood at $89 billion, its private-sector debt was $73 billion and its public-sector debt was $16 billion, Thanong said.</p>
<p>He said Thailand was trying to keep inflation at single-digit levels. The Thai authorities would not intervene in the currency markets except for &quot;smoothing&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>Sugisaki said the U.S. and other countries would cooperate through the IMF and other multilateral institutions to support the Thai package agreed on Monday.</p>
<p>Germany, France, Britain and Canada also participated in the meeting, although the IMF did not mention them as among countries that had pledged financing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
