<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791376" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli Druze outraged over officer's remarks.</title>
<headline>Israeli Druze outraged over officer's remarks.</headline>
<byline>Daniel Sternoff</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Ezer Weizman apologised to Israel's Arab Druze minority on Monday for an officer's remark that members of the group had been recruited into the army to keep them out of &quot;terrorism&quot;.</p>
<p>Weizman stepped in to calm a furore among Druze while visiting Druze soldiers serving in the Jewish state's army who were wounded in fighting in Lebanon last week.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope that the community won't take this as a spokeswoman for the state of Israel. It's a stupid remark by one person,&quot; Weizman told Israel Radio. &quot;The Druze community makes a powerful contribution to the state of Israel,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The woman officer, a major, made the remark in a lecture to non-commissioned officers at a base near Tel Aviv last week on the recruitment of minorities into the standing army.</p>
<p>&quot;The goal of this (Druze) recruitment is so that soldiers will go to the army instead of to Hamas or any other terrorist organisation,&quot; the officer was quoted as saying by a Druze soldier who attended the lecture.</p>
<p>She made the comment at a time of deep sensitivity in Israel over Islamic militant groups following a double suicide bombing in Jerusalem last month. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said Hamas was probably responsible.</p>
<p>The Druze, a secretive 11th Century offshoot of Islam, are Israel's only non-Jewish minority required to serve in the army.</p>
<p>&quot;There is shock and revulsion that a senior army officer responsible for manpower could make a remark like this,&quot; Assad Assad, a Druze adviser to Netanyahu, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;This is pure racism and she has no place in the army. We are demanding that she be expelled,&quot; Assad said.</p>
<p>Israel's some 60,000 Druze speak both Hebrew and Arabic.</p>
<p>&quot;How many Druze have spied until today? Zero. How many Jews? Many. How many Druze have committed treason? Zero. How many Jews? Many,&quot; Rafik Halabi, a Druze who heads the news department of state-owned Israel television, told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>An army spokesman said Chief of Staff Amnon Shahak viewed the incident &quot;with great severity&quot; and had launched an investigation.</p>
<p>The incident was the latest in a recent series of spats between Druze and Israeli Jews.</p>
<p>In July, Druze stoned and injured 17 border policemen in a protest at a court injunction against building on land near a Druze town they said had been declared a nature reserve without consulting them.</p>
<p>Druze soldiers also complained last month that they had been excluded from nightclubs in northern Jewish towns they helped protect because they spoke Arabic.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be stupid if we now alienate the one ally we have,&quot; the Israeli daily Yedioth Ahronoth said in an editorial.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
