<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791345" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: U.S. envoy sees Israel, PLO closer on security.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy sees Israel, PLO closer on security.</headline>
<byline>Howard Goller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. envoy Dennis Ross said on Monday his Middle East peace mission had brought Israelis and Palestinians a step closer to reviving security ties following a bloody suicide attack.</p>
<p>Within hours of his arrival on Sunday, Ross had brought together Palestinian President Yasser Arafat and Israeli officials for the first time since the Jerusalem marketplace bombing on July 30 deepened a crisis in peacemaking.</p>
<p>&quot;The meeting that took place last night and will be taking place are a step in the direction of re-establishing that (security) relationship,&quot; Ross told reporters after he met Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy.</p>
<p>PLO officials said the Israeli-PLO meeting late on Sunday -- and another set for Monday -- enabled the sides to exchange information on the attack and to coordinate security. But a swift solution seemed unlikely.</p>
<p>&quot;Until now there is no political or security achievement,&quot; Arafat adviser Nabil Abu Rdainah told reporters.</p>
<p>A senior adviser to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the meeting of Arafat and Israeli officials joined by Ross had failed to salvage peace efforts because Arafat refused to clamp down on &quot;terrorism&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Until now we've seen no real change on the part of the Palestinian Authority in everything that has to do with its war on terrorism,&quot; the adviser, Cabinet Secretary Danny Naveh, told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>Officials said Ross brought three Israeli officials, among them Shin Bet secret police chief Ami Ayalon, with him to the meeting with Arafat in Palestinian-ruled Ramallah in the West Bank.</p>
<p>It was unclear who would attend Monday night's meeting.</p>
<p>Like Ross, European envoy Miguel Angel Moratinos was shuttling between Jerusalem and Ramallah trying to ease tensions heightened by the market attack which killed 15 people, including the two bombers.</p>
<p>Moratinos met Arafat for 15 minutes on Monday before telling reporters that the European Union would send in a Swedish expert to help Palestinians fight &quot;terrorism&quot; -- an offer swiftly spurned.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not need to learn anything from anybody. We are doing our duties and are committed to the agreements. It is Israel that has to learn to implement its commitments,&quot; said the Arafat adviser, Abu Rdainah.</p>
<p>Israel has accused Arafat of having a &quot;revolving door&quot; for militants in his prisons and has conditioned a resumption of peace talks on a clampdown against them. Arafat says he has met his responsibilities.</p>
<p>&quot;We are at the moment of truth,&quot; Netanyahu's foreign policy adviser Uzi Arad told CNN.</p>
<p>&quot;That moment of truth should reflect itself in the Palestinian determination to make a change of course to apply and implement all the commitments that it already undertook to fight terrorism,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mystery has surrounded the origin and identity of the two bombers.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said on Sunday that Israel had growing indications that the Islamic militant group Hamas carried out the attack even though Israeli and Palestinian officials have questioned the authenticity of the claim.</p>
<p>Negotiations, already in crisis over a Jewish settlement Israel began building in Arab East Jerusalem in March, hit a new low after the market bombing. Netanyahu suspended peace talks and sealed off the West Bank and Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>Arafat wants Israel to stop the East Jerusalem settlement, end Palestinian house demolitions and land confiscations, and lift its security closure. Israel vows to continue the East Jerusalem settlement.</p>
<p>Ross said he did not expect to stay &quot;too much longer&quot; but did not elaborate. He said U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright was prepared to make her first trip to the region at the end of the month provided progress was made on security.</p>
<p>On Sunday Lebanese Shi'ite Hizbollah fighters killed an Israeli soldier, raising to 15 the toll in the deadliest week in south Lebanon since an Israeli offensive in April 1996. A pro-Israeli fighter, six Hizbollah men and seven Lebanese civilians have also died.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
