<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791469" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks rebound to end higher as bonds recover.</title>
<headline>Stocks rebound to end higher as bonds recover.</headline>
<byline>Wendy Pollack</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks rose on Monday, bouncing back from a steep two-session decline, as a late-session recovery in bonds helped bolster investor confidence in the market.</p>
<p>Strength on stocks and bonds helped push the dollar higher, while soybeans fell after the Midwest received a dose of much-needed rainfall.</p>
<p>After sliding below the 8,000 level early in the day, the Dow Jones industrial average rallied back to close at 8,062.11, up 30.89 points from Friday. The blue-chip index of 30 stocks had lost 228 points in the previous two sessions after long-term interest rates soared unexpectedly.</p>
<p>In the broader market, declining issues led advancers 1,483 to 1,344 on moderate volume of 480 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The late-session recovery in the blue-chip stocks did touch all sectors, however, with the Nasdaq composite index finishing down 11.78 points at 1,586.74 on further profit taking in high-technology stocks.</p>
<p>Despite the mixed performance, traders said they did not see much of a carryover from Friday's 157-point Dow sell-off. Several said trading was typical of a summer Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We really didn't get much of a follow-through to that scare on Friday,&quot; said Bill Allyn, head of trading at Jefferies &amp; Co. &quot;That in itself is good news.&quot;</p>
<p>As they did last week, stocks took their cue from bonds Monday. The bond market in turn got a boost from remarks by Federal Reserve Governor Susan Phillips suggesting that there was no immediate need for a credit tightening.</p>
<p>Recent economic data that pointed to a strengthening economy have rekindled market speculation that the Fed will need to raise interest rates to keep inflation at bay.</p>
<p>The Federal Open Market Committee -- the central bank's policy-setting body -- meets Aug. 19 to decide on the direction of interest rates.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond fell 2/32, or 62.5 cents on a $1,000 bond, to yield 6.64 percent, after hitting 6.69 percent early in the day, the highest since July 2. Bond prices and yields move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected tentative trading until Wednesday's report on retail sales and July wholesale inflation. Figures on retail inflation are due Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't expect it to get much clearer until Wednesday and Thursday,&quot; said Guy Truicko, equity portfolio manager at Unity Management. &quot;Then we'll see where we go from there.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the dollar recouped some of Friday's sharp losses against the German mark and Japanese yen.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to 1.8640 marks Monday from 1.8452 marks on Friday and to 116.18 yen from 114.80. It climbed to 1.5263 Swiss francs from 1.5097 on Friday.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, soybean prices fell sharply as much needed rains soaked crops in the Midwest, improving the prospects for this year's harvest. At the Chicago Board of Trade, soybeans for November delivery closed down 27-1/2 cents a bushel at $6.10.</p>
<p>Overseas, Britain's FTSE 100 closed at 5,031.9, up 0.6 points, or 0.01 percent. Tokyo's 225-stock Nikkei average closed at 18,824.18, down 780.28 points, or 3.98 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
