<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791510" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. protects dwindling steelhead salmon.</title>
<headline>U.S. protects dwindling steelhead salmon.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Croft</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. National Marine Fisheries Service said Monday it was protecting five groups of Pacific coast steelhead salmon under the Endangered Species Act because of a sharp drop in their numbers.</p>
<p>The service, part of the Commerce Department, listed steelhead populations in the Upper Columbia River in Washington state and in southern California as &quot;endangered&quot; -- meaning they are at risk of becoming extinct in the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>Steelhead in the Snake River Basin, including parts of Idaho, Washington and Oregon, the central California coast and the south-central California coast were listed as &quot;threatened&quot;, meaning the fish were likely to become endangered in the foreseeable future. The fisheries service said the listings would take effect in 60 days.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no dispute that these fish are in serious trouble,&quot; Terry Garcia, acting Commerce Department assistant secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, said in a statement. &quot;Our commitment to salmon and steelhead conservation is clear: we must restore these magnificent fish.&quot;</p>
<p>The fisheries service said it would defer for six months a decision on five other steelhead populations in Oregon, Washington and California because of considerable scientific disagreement about the health of these stocks.</p>
<p>Fisheries service spokesman Brian Gorman said those populations were likely to receive protection too in six months' time unless states came up with a comprehensive conservation plan in the meantime.</p>
<p>The fisheries service said steelhead were completely gone from large areas of their former range and the different groups of remaining steelhead from California to Canada were depleted in varying degrees. It blamed the decline on a combination of human activities and poor natural conditions.</p>
<p>The fisheries service said the number of steelhead returning to spawn in central California rivers had fallen from a historic high of 94,000 to about 9,000 now. In southern California rivers, the number had fallen from 55,000 to 500.</p>
<p>The Endangered Species Act prohibits anyone from directly killing an endangered species or harming its habitat.</p>
<p>Because there is no commercial fishing for steelhead, the most direct impact of the listing would be felt by sport fishers later this year, when rules would go into effect prohibiting intentionally catching listed steelhead, the fisheries service said.</p>
<p>In letters to the governors of Washington, Idaho, Oregon and California, the fisheries service urged a state-federal partnership in developing conservation plans to aid the recovery of Pacific steelhead.</p>
<p>The agency cited a range of causes for steelhead decline that would have to be addressed, including timber harvest, agriculture, water diversions, hydropower operations, gravel mining, urbanization, hatchery practices and fishing.</p>
<p>Elyssa Rosen, an official with the Sierra Club environmental group, said the listing of the southern California steelhead as endangered was &quot;encouraging.&quot; But she cautioned: &quot;None of what I have seen so far today is going to be meaningful unless there are teeth in the deal and so far there aren't any.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I03000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
