<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791624" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PACIFICORP SEES $65 MLN Q3 CURRENCY LOSS.</title>
<headline>PACIFICORP SEES $65 MLN Q3 CURRENCY LOSS.</headline>
<dateline>PORTLAND, Ore. 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>PacifiCorp Holdings, Inc., a wholly-owned subsidiary of PacifiCorp, said Monday it will record a near $65 million after-tax loss in the third quarter from a currency hedge transaction related to its tender offer for The Energy Group.</p>
<p>The loss stems from a delay in United Kingdom clearance of the deal, which required the company to close out currency options positions, PacifiCorp said in a statement.</p>
<p>In June, when the tender offer was made, PacifiCorp anticipated its currency exchange costs would total about $27 million after-tax.  </p>
<p>The Portland, Ore.-based company said rules of the U.K. Takeover Code required it to show it had enough British currency to purchase the TEG shares and to eliminate the risk of a fluctuation in exchange rates between the time of the offer announcement and the expected close of the offer.</p>
<p>PacifiCorp's financial policies also require hedging of exchange rate fluctuation risk, the company said.</p>
<p>As a result, PacifiCorp purchased options to buy about 1.45 billion stg at an effective exchange rate of $1.64. The options were subsequently converted to forward purchase commitments in an attempt to minimize the cost of the hedge transaction.</p>
<p>PacifiCorp offered about $9.6 billion, including assumption of debt, for the U.K. firm, which owns Eastern Electricity, Britain's largest utility in terms of distribution territory, as well as Peabody Coal Co, the world's largest privately-owned coal producer.</p>
<p>But on August 1, the president of Britain's Board of Trade referred the TEG deal to the Monopolies and Mergers Commission citing concerns relating to the adequacy of regulatory control over the merged company. The referral automatically lapsed PacifiCorp's tender offer.</p>
<p>Because the tender offer lapsed, PacifiCorp said financial policies required closing the currency exchange positions since they were no longer hedging an expected transaction and would, therefore, be speculative.</p>
<p>PacifiCorp said that when it initiated steps to close out the currency exchange positions, the dollar-sterling exchange rate was around $1.63. But by the time the positions were closed, the rate had fallen to around $1.58, resulting in an after-tax loss of near $56 million.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the cost of the initial options was approximately $9 million after-tax.</p>
<p>If PacifiCorp successfully renews its offer for TEG following the U.K. review, it will again be required to enter into foreign exchange positions to adhere to both U.K. Takeover Code provisions and its own financial policies, the company said.</p>
<p>((--Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORTLAND, Ore."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
