<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791710" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CEPAHLON GIRDS FOR FDA MYOTROPHIN VERDICT.</title>
<headline>CEPAHLON GIRDS FOR FDA MYOTROPHIN VERDICT.</headline>
<byline>Ransdell Pierson</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cephalon Inc is bracing for a decision by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, possibly today, on whether to approve Myotrophin, an experimental drug to slow the progress of Lou Gehrig's disease.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an uphill battle for Cephalon because arguments for Myotrophin from a scientific point of view aren't very strong,&quot; said Mehta and Isaly drug analyst Michael Sheffery. &quot;Based upon data I've seen, it's not clear the drug does much of anything, but most people agree it does no harm.&quot;  </p>
<p>Cephalon and partner Chiron Corp suffered a setback May 8 when an FDA advisory panel voted 6-3 against recommending approval of the drug for the fatal muscle-wasting disease formally known as amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS).</p>
<p>Although the FDA usually follows the advice of its advisory panels, Cephalon decided to press ahead with the New Drug Application it submitted on February 11.</p>
<p>The FDA agreed to review the application on an expedited basis, meaning it would render its decision within six months rather than after the usual 12-month review period.  </p>
<p>&quot;Monday is the deadline so we are hoping to hear the FDA's decision early in the week. We're hopeful the drug will be approved,&quot; said Jason Rubin, a spokesman for Cephalon, a biotech startup based in West Chester, Pa.</p>
<p>&quot;We'd like to begin marketing it as soon as possible after product labeling and packaging,&quot; Rubin told Reuters.</p>
<p>Emeryville, Calif.-based Chiron would manufacture the nerve growth drug and both companies would share equally in profits, he said.  </p>
<p>Rubin said about 30,000 people in the U.S. suffer from ALS, which almost always leads to death within five years as muscles fail to the point that breathing becomes impossible.</p>
<p>In June 1996, the same FDA advisory panel allowed Cephalon limited compassionate-use distribution of Myotrophin based on statistically significant results of a Phase III North American study of 266 patients completed in 1995.</p>
<p>Several panel members expressed concern, however, about the drug's failure to achieve statistical significance in a second trial among 183 patients in Europe. They urged Cephalon to conduct a third study to clarify the ambiguous data.  </p>
<p>But Cephalon refused, giving the panel a &quot;hardball take it or leave it&quot; response, said Sheffery.</p>
<p>&quot;Cephalon essentially said they were not going to put any more money into a third trial and came back with a new drug application&quot; in February, the analyst added.</p>
<p>&quot;They came back and filed an NDA based on the same data the advisory panel had already seen and had expressed their displeasure with,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cephalon's tough approach surprised many Wall Street observers, Sheffery said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If you had been at the June 1996 advisory panel meeting, you'd have shaken your head and said if those guys (Cephalon) don't do a third trial, they're in big trouble,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said Cephalon and Chiron have been flooding the FDA in recent months with supplementary data from the earlier trials, hoping to bolster their application.</p>
<p>Cowen &amp; Co drug analyst Joyce Lonergan said the FDA was in a &quot;scary&quot; position, caught between its own panel's negative stance and the outspoken desire by many Lou Gehrig's sufferers and their families for approval of Myotrophin.  </p>
<p>Another factor, she said, is pressure for approval by Republican Sen Orin Hatch of Utah, who urged the FDA in a letter &quot;to provide patients with a drug they need at no risk to public health.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody makes any friends by taking a stance on this,&quot; Lonergan said. She added that the FDA was having to resolve the high-profile drama although no successor has yet been named to former FDA chief David Kessler, who resigned in March.</p>
<p>Cephalon, whose shares peaked in late 1995 at 40-3/4 on favorable results of its U.S. pivotal trial, closed Friday at 11-3/16.</p>
<p>Lonergan said shares could rise to between $15 and $20 by late 1998 regardless of Myotrophin's fate, based on Cephalon's &quot;extensive pipeline&quot; of other drugs -- including narcolepsy drug Provigil, now awaiting FDA approval.</p>
<p>She said approval of Myotrophin would be icing on the cake. Sales of the drug have a potential annual worldwide market of $500 million, she said.</p>
<p>((--New York Newsdesk, 212 859-1736))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
