<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79184" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India pours in paramilitary for huge state polls.</title>
<headline>India pours in paramilitary for huge state polls.</headline>
<byline>Sharat Pradhan</byline>
<dateline>LUCKNOW, India 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>India on Thursday dispatched tens of thousands of paramilitary troops to guard key local polls in the northern state of Uttar Pradesh, a violence-prone region more populous than Japan or Pakistan.</p>
<p>Politicians said the three-phase polls starting on Monday and involving 90 million voters would test Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's ability to ride out a challenge by the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP).</p>
<p>The BJP is India's main opposition party.</p>
<p>It derives its strength from Uttar Pradesh where its campaign to build a Hindu temple at the site of a 16th century mosque catapulted it to power in several north Indian states and made it the main opposition in parliament in 1991.</p>
<p>The assembly polls will see Deve Gowda's fractious United Front alliance take on the Congress party, which supports his minority government in Delhi, and the BJP, in a triangular fight for the state's 425-member Vidhan Sabha, the lower house.</p>
<p>The BJP is campaigning for mid-term polls to the federal parliament, a demand gradually drawing the support of Congress members as well, though the party continues officially to support Prime Minister Deve Gowda's government.</p>
<p>Uttar Pradesh sends 85 deputies to the Indian parliament's 545-member lower house, the biggest contingent from any of the country's 26 states, currently dominated by the BJP.</p>
<p>Analysts say the state, once a bastion of the Congress party which has ruled India for all but four years since independence in 1947, could boost a recent trend of coalition politics that helped Deve Gowda form a minority government in June.</p>
<p>On the other hand, a survey by New Delhi's Outlook magazine predicted a possible victory for the BJP.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever be the margin of our victory, the party is preparing for mid-term polls,&quot; a BJP leader told Reuters in the state capital of Lucknow this week.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda formed a minority government in June after Rao promised to support him following inconclusive general elections, and depends on Congress to survive the BJP's unceasing challenge in parliament.</p>
<p>The polls in northern Uttar Pradesh would test that equation, analysts said. Seven of India's 10 prime ministers have come from Uttar Pradesh, which according to a 1991 census had 140 million out of India's more than 920 million people.</p>
<p>Uttar Pradesh was the main support base of the Congress until 1989 when its fortunes began to wane in successive local polls, variously against the BJP and the regional Samajawadi Party of socialist Defence Minister Mulayam Singh Yadav.</p>
<p>The Samajawadi Party won 16 seats in parliament in the general polls, highest after the BJP's 52 of a total of 85.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda's Janata Dal party won two seats and the Congress five, a far cry from all the 85 seats it won in 1984.</p>
<p>The BJP emerged as the single largest group in parliament in the April/May elections, with the largest share of its 160 deputies coming from Uttar Pradesh. The BJP won 34 percent votes in the state in the general elections.</p>
<p>The Congress which got eight percent votes in the general polls in Uttar Pradesh has struck an alliance with the Bahujan Samaj Party (BSP) of mostly low caste Hindus.</p>
<p>The state was put under Delhi's direct rule after the BSP ditched Yadav and formed its own government last year. But unable to prove its majority, the BSP government resigned.</p>
<p>Yadav's Samajawadi Party and the BSP had an equal share of 21 percent votes each. Deve Gowda's Janata Dal party with four percent of the votes won two seats in the state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUCKNOW, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
