<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791971" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: ANALYSTS COMMENTS ON CS/WINTERTHUR MERGER PLAN.</title>
<headline>ANALYSTS COMMENTS ON CS/WINTERTHUR MERGER PLAN.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are analysts' comments on the merger plans by Credit Suisse Group and Winterthur.</p>
<p>Christoph Bieri, Zurich Kantonalbank:</p>
<p>&quot;This is surprising. It seems to be a break with the strategy (by Credit Suisse chief executive Lukas Muehlemann).&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This does not make a whole lot of sense to me. Cooperation between the bank and the insurer was functioning already. You don't necessarily need a merger to exploit the synergies between an insurer and bank.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;A new situation arose with the large stake taken by (BZ Group's Martin) Ebner. This appears to have forced CS and Winterthur to act. The situation was becoming too threatening in the sense that Ebner could have given control of Winterthur to an outsider or sought to take power himself.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is not necessarily positive for CS.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;I think this puts pressure on the other big Swiss banks. Swiss Bank Corp is a little bit on its own. It has close ties with Zurich Insurance, but Zurich is going its own way in terms of asset management after acquiring (U.S. asset managers) Kemper and Scudder recently.</p>
<p>&quot;UBS has one participation, with Swiss Life. They have a stake there of 25 percent. Maybe they could use this for plans in the same direction as Credit Suisse or they could sell because they have a very interesting entry price. They also have an option to increase the stake to 49 percent if Swiss Life becomes a takeover takeover target.&quot;</p>
<p>John Leonard, Salomon Brothers, London:</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously any recommendations are under review. My initial take is that this is positive.</p>
<p>&quot;My initial view is this is a good quality business (Winterthur). My insurance teams tells me it has substantial unrecognised values in the balance sheet.</p>
<p>&quot;While the price for Winterthur has run a long way in the past year, you're paying in Credit Suisse shares that have not performed badly themselves. So I'm not sure the exchange ratio today is a lot more shares than it would have been a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Initially it dilutes earnings per share, maybe six percent on next year's estimates. It they can get the 350 million Swiss francs in costs savings and synergies, then it's effectively back to neutral.</p>
<p>&quot;Most bancassurance ventures have focused on life assurance. With Winterthur, you get what seems like a very sound life assurance position. The general insurance that comes with it is rarer in the bancassurance world, although the nature of the business they are doing appears to be of a kind that is relatively unthreatening and non-volatile.</p>
<p>&quot;UBS has probably made its commitment with Swiss Life right now. Whether that is in its final form now, time will tell.</p>
<p>&quot;At SBC, I don't get the sense they feel this is a top priority, but if approached, I think they probably would be open to having at least a conversation.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this deal makes a lot of difference to the European banking scene. This deal is very specific to the Swiss market.&quot;</p>
<p>Thomas Della Putta, Pictet &amp; Cie, Geneva:</p>
<p>&quot;In the insurance area, Winterthur has very sizeable market shares in all the markets they're active in. Outside Switzerland, they have a very good position in Germany. They have a fairly good market share in Italy and Spain as well. In France, they probably need to do more.</p>
<p>&quot;Strategically, this makes sense for Credit Suisse. The general trend in Europe clearly goes towards bancassurance. It's not the insurance companies that need the banks, it's the banks that need the insurance companies to be more competitive.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks' margins are shrinking. The margins of an insurance product are clearly higher than the margins of a plain vanilla banking product. It clearly gives the banks more scope to exploit their base know-how in asset management.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Zurich Newsroom, +41-1-631 7340 (c) Reuters Limited 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
