<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791985" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: BOMBAY STOCKS ADVANCE AS HEAVYWEIGHTS NOTCH GAINS.</title>
<headline>BOMBAY STOCKS ADVANCE AS HEAVYWEIGHTS NOTCH GAINS.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>**  (0515 GMT) - Shares at Bombay bourse rise as operators</p>
<p>	  build up fresh positions on start of weekly account</p>
<p>**  Bombay's benchmark index gains 41.75 pts, or 0.95 pct,</p>
<p>	  at 4,439.29 after surging 1.46 pct shortly after start</p>
<p>**  Textile &amp; petrochemical firm, Bombay Dyeing tumbles</p>
<p>	  six pct after firm shuts plant following fire</p>
<p>**  Index heavyweight, BHEL posts sharp gains as stock</p>
<p>	  enters no-delivery period at Bombay exchange</p>
<p>**  Market rally triggered by technical factors after index</p>
<p>	  loses 3.3 percent in last three consecutive sessions</p>
<p>**  National exchange index off 5.65 pts, at 1,251.30  </p>
<p>Bombay shares started on a firm note on Monday with select blue chips leading a technical rally at the start of the new account trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has opened slightly stronger. Low badla (interest rates for carry-foward trades) indicate that there was not many outstanding buy positions, &quot; said Piyush Vora, a member-broker of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE).</p>
<p>Bombay's benchmark index surged 64.30 points, or 1.46 pct, to 4,461.84 shortly after opening but was off its peaks in mid-morning trade.</p>
<p>The market rally was largely attributed to a technical rebound after the index slumped 151 points, or 3.3 percent in three consecutive sessions last week, brokers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Things are very quiet. Most of the activity is largely speculator-driven aided by technical factors,&quot; said the head of dealing at a foreign brokerage.</p>
<p>Most analysts feel the volatile market is likely to consolidate this week after a surge to 34-month highs met with resistance.</p>
<p>The BSE's top index ended with a net gain of 50.22 points, or 1.15 percent, at 4,397.54 last week after hitting 4,605.41 -- just shy of the 4,653.31 all-time high set on September 12, 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;These reactions are a must for the market. All the weak players have to get out,&quot; said Nand Kishore Gupta, chief executive officer at Ind-Sec Share &amp; Stock Brokers. &quot;The outlook remains good.&quot;</p>
<p>Much of the momemtum for the bull run had come in anticipation of a turnaround in the Indian economy forecast for the third quarter of 1997/98 (April-March), analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates are coming down, the rupee is holding ground against other currencies and there is a possible turnaround in the second half,&quot; said Jaspreet Ahuja, head of sales at Caspian Research (India) Pvt Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;Given this why wouldn't India look attractive vis-a-vis the other Asian markets? That's the pattern that investors are looking at,&quot; Ahuja said.</p>
<p>Among individual stocks, Bombay Dyeing &amp; Manufacturing Company Ltd shed 6.50 rupees at 111.25 at the Bombay bourse on Monday following news that the textiles and petrochemicals firm had shut down its plant after a fire broke out on Saturday.</p>
<p>Company officias on Saturday said the cause of the fire which broke out in a plant at Patalganga, about 100 kilometres (62.5 miles) from Bombay was not known. It was expected to take days or weeks before production could be restored in the plant, the Bombay Dyeing official told Reuters.</p>
<p>The plant manufactured di-methyl terephthalate (DMT) and its raw material, paraxylene. DMT is a raw material used in textiles.</p>
<p>-- Anshuman Daga, Bombay newsroom (91) 22-265-9000 (91) 22-264 1699</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
