<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="791936" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Continental pumps up first half profit.</title>
<headline>Continental pumps up first half profit.</headline>
<dateline>HANOVER, Germany 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tyre-maker Continental AG said on Monday pre-tax profit soared 73 percent to 208 million marks in the first half of 1997 and it expected a &quot;significant rise in net profit&quot; for the year as a whole.</p>
<p>The sharp profit increase, which came on sales growth of only five percent to 5.35 billion marks, was due to improved efficiency and strong profit growth at its Continental General Tire division, the company said in a statement to shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;Continental is on a good path,&quot; the statement said. &quot;The goal is to make all areas of the company profitable.&quot;</p>
<p>Conti declined to give a specific profit figure for the year as a whole, but said it expected group sales to climb five percent to around 11 billion marks in 1997.</p>
<p>The company had previously signalled it expected strong profit growth this year but its share price was up one mark in morning trade to 49.20 marks.</p>
<p>In April this year Continental reported group net profit of 192.5 million marks for 1996, up from 155.2 million in 1995. Sales rose 1.7 percent to 10.4 billion marks in 1996.</p>
<p>Conti also said on Monday the European Commission did not intend to block its planned venture with French tyre group Michelin.</p>
<p>&quot;The European Commission in Brussels in an administrative letter said it has concluded its examination of the planned cooperation with Michelin in tyres and sees no reason to block it,&quot; Conti said in a statement.</p>
<p>The Commission said last August that it expected to clear the joint venture after seeking comment from interested parties.</p>
<p>Monday's results appeared to support Conti's ambitious plans for the years ahead.</p>
<p>Management board chairman Hubertus von Gruenberg said in this week's edition of Focus magazine the company planed to increase sales to 20 billion marks within ten years, and to increase net profits to 800 million marks.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to elevate the group from the one-to-five percent annual growth zone to where growth increases by five to ten percent each year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Monday's results were especially noteworthy for the increase in operating profit at U.S. unit Continental General Tyre which saw operating profit surge to 63 million marks from 39 million marks in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>Overall operating profit from car tyres climbed to 144 million million marks from 117 million marks.</p>
<p>Operating profit at the company's ContiTech unit, meanwhile, climbed to 127 million marks from 103 million marks.</p>
<p>The story was not so upbeat for Conti's truck tyre business where operating profit slumped to three million marks from six million marks.</p>
<p>The company said a sluggish economy was behind the weak demand for truck tyres, but that it expected healthier economic conditions, especially in Eruope, to boost the division's performance in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>--Scott Miller, Frankfurt Newsroom + 49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I48110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOVER, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
