<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="792018" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: FOREIGN FUNDS WELCOME INDIA DEBT FORWARD COVER.</title>
<headline>FOREIGN FUNDS WELCOME INDIA DEBT FORWARD COVER.</headline>
<byline>Shyam Kumar</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign institutional investors hailed Reserve Bank of India (RBI) Monday decision to allow them to take forward cover on their Indian debt investments.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a positive step and was expected,&quot; said an official at a leading foreign fund which has committed large funds for investment in Indian debt but has not started its investments.</p>
<p>The RBI said it decided to permit authorised foreign exchange dealers in India to provide forward cover to foreign institutional investors (FIIs) for their debt investments.</p>
<p>&quot;The extent of the cover would be limited to the current market value of the investments in debt instruments translated in dollar terms,&quot; RBI said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The tenor of the cover shall not exceed the remaining period to maturity of the debt instruments in which the FII has invested,&quot; the central bank said.</p>
<p>Foreign funds have committed over $2.0 billion to be invested in Indian debt market.</p>
<p>Some forex dealers wondered whether foreign institutional investors (FII) will go for forward cover as the rupee has been stable for the past one year at 35.70/85 against the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course we will,&quot; said an official at an FII.</p>
<p>&quot;The rupee has been so stable, it is causing nervousness,&quot; he said, on condition of anonymity.</p>
<p>&quot;The experience over the past seven years tells us chances of one-time depreciation are strong,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>International investors were not convinced about the rupee continuing strong over the long-term, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Look at the U.S. funds -- they took a beating in Thailand and rest of South-East Asia,&quot; said another fund manager.</p>
<p>A host of 100 percent Indian debt funds announced by European and American investment banks has come one more step closer to the take off stage following today's announcement, fund managers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of the reason for not investing in India, despite the permission, was lack of a hedging facility,&quot; said an analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the only hedging they are allowed,&quot; said a bank dealer at a private Indian bank. &quot;I am sure they'll go for it.&quot;</p>
<p>A bank dealer said the overseas dollar interest at about 5.5 percent per annum plus the current six month annualised forward premium for dollars in India at 4.25 percent worked out close to 10 percent a year.</p>
<p>&quot;You get an average 12 to 13 percent (annual yield) on private debt,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;That leaves a spread of almost three percent, which is very good by world standards.&quot;</p>
<p>Significantly, the RBI has allowed forward cover only on debt instruments and not on equities.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom(91)-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
