<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="792122" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. retail sales data seen shaping new Fed view.</title>
<headline>U.S. retail sales data seen shaping new Fed view.</headline>
<byline>Steven Scheer</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Retail sales data due Wednesday are expected to give the bond market a fresh view on the strength of the economy's third-quarter growth and also shape Federal Reserve policy.</p>
<p>&quot;This number is important for both market psychology and to test what has been discounted&quot; as far as monetary policy, said Steven Ricchiuto, chief economist at ABN AMRO Chicago Corp.</p>
<p>Less than two weeks ago, &quot;the market said the Fed is on hold forever and they were never going to tighten again. This (data) will determine how much tightening it put back in,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Economists noted a shift in sentiment away from the rosy economic scenario, which was popular until the beginning of August.</p>
<p>Wall Street had long believed the economy could continue to grow strongly without boosting inflation. But various purchasing managers' reports, which showed solid economic growth and higher prices, and strong July employment data have changed that view.</p>
<p>Now, rather than expecting the Fed to stay on hold and possibly ease the cost of borrowing next year, the market has started to talk about a tightening as early as September.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a pivotal number to analyse psychology,&quot; said Ricchiuto.</p>
<p>The Commerce Department is set to report on retail sales Wednesday at 8:30 a.m. (1230 GMT). Overall sales in July are expected to have risen 0.7 percent, with sales excluding autos seen up 0.4 percent, according to a Reuters poll of economists.</p>
<p>But in the wake of strong auto and chain store sales figures, some analysts are looking for stronger numbers.</p>
<p>Brian Jones, economist at Salomon Brothers, predicts a 1.1 percent overall retail sales gain and a 0.5 percent rise in the core rate along with upward revisions to June data.</p>
<p>Even so, he said, &quot;retail sales may understate consumer spending,&quot; since the series incorporates spending on goods but not on services.</p>
<p>Goods spending comprises only 40 percent of the total, leaving the remaining 60 percent spending on services unaccounted for until the end of the month, when personal spending expenditures data are released.</p>
<p>In addition to auto and department store spending, sales at drugstores, gas stations and on building materials and furniture are expected to have boosted retail sales in July, economists said.</p>
<p>Although bond yields already reflect expectations of a strong set of numbers, Treasury prices could fall further if the market's fears are realised.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going through a worry phase where strong growth begets fears of higher inflation,&quot; said Mitchell Held, chief economist at Smith Barney Inc.</p>
<p>On Monday, the benchmark 30-year Treasury bond was up 2/32, or 62.5 cents on a $1,000 bond, lowering its yield to 6.63 percent from 6.64 percent Friday. Bond prices and yields move in opposite directions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
