<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="792284" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: DAIRY BRANDS WARNS OF MILK PRICE SQUEEZE.</title>
<headline>DAIRY BRANDS WARNS OF MILK PRICE SQUEEZE.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dairy Brands Limited warned on Monday it saw a negative impact on its current year's financial performance if milk prices are reduced as forecast and co-operative premiums remain at similar levels.</p>
<p>The largest cooperative player, the Dairy Board, has forecast a full-year milk price of between NZ$2.90 and $3.05 per kilogramme of milk solids.</p>
<p>Dairy Brands noted that this price represents a further reduction on that achieved in the 1996/97 season.  </p>
<p>&quot;Should the co-operative premium be maintained at similar levels, the resultant overall milk price will negatively impact Dairy Brands' performance in the current year,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Chairman Ruth Richardson noted in comments accompanying the firm's results for the first eight months of the year that the company wanted to see improved performance across the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;The dairy industry is a vital component in the New Zealand economy and the country can ill afford to have it performing at anything other than its optimal level.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is Dairy Brands' view that the current structure of the industry is constraining its ability to maximise its performance,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Dairy Brands said it believed the industry had a duty to expose its performance to competitive pressures.</p>
<p>Several ministers have commented lately on the need for reform at the Dairy Board, though no formal process has started yet.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 473-4746' Fax (64 4) 473 6212</p>
<p>e-mail wellington.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
