<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="792411" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: TOKYO NIKKEI SHEDS 500 POINTS ON YEN, WALL ST FALL.</title>
<headline>TOKYO NIKKEI SHEDS 500 POINTS ON YEN, WALL ST FALL.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Tokyo stock market's key index kept sliding on Monday, falling over 500 points in the Monday afternoon session, spooked by the weakness of the dollar against the yen as well as a Friday tumble on Wall Street, brokers said.  </p>
<p>As of 0547 GMT, the Nikkei average was down 715.77 points or 3.65 percent at 18,888.69. September Nikkei futures were down 780 points at 18,900.</p>
<p>&quot;Concern had been growing over the state of the economy in recent sessions due to a series of weak economic data and news of a feeble recovery in consumption,&quot; said Akihiro Naemura, Okasan Securities strategist.</p>
<p>&quot;A tumble in stocks on Wall Street on Friday and a weakening of the dollar against the yen added further pressure on the Nikkei average, inviting a sell-off in Nikkei futures,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Brokers added that summer holidays had thinned out the number of participants in the market and that the fall was exaggerated by the light volume.  </p>
<p>&quot;Trade was thin due to the summer holidays and the selling, which came from futures and also some index-linked sales, was exaggerated by that,&quot; Takada added.</p>
<p>Market participants who had not gone on holiday waited for public and pension funds to rescue the Nikkei average but such help was slow to come, leading the losses to snowball.</p>
<p>&quot;The supply/demand situation is not as healthy as it was,&quot; said Keiko Kondo, a Merrill Lynch strategist. &quot;It seems fund money allocations were concentrated at the beginning of the year and hopes of a cushion may not be realised and the market may take a while to recover.&quot;  </p>
<p>Brokers said the Nikkei average had crashed through various technical support levels on Monday and there were few factors on the horizon that would radically change its course.</p>
<p>They said the downside was being tentatively put at the lower end of 18,000.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is beginning to respond to the belief that Japan's economy is not going to be able to recuperate on its own and in the mid-term, an asset allocation in favour of bonds (over stocks) may be recommendable,&quot; said Deutsche Morgan Grenfell strategist Ryojji Musha.  </p>
<p>News that Japan and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) will provide a total of $4 billion each in loans to help ease Thailand's financial crisis had little direct impact on stocks.</p>
<p>But market sources said there was concern over Asian currencies and the possible knock-on effect on the dollar, and investors were watching for new developments.</p>
<p>&quot;Overseas demand had been sort of a lifeline for Tokyo stocks but with the dollar weak and possibilities of turmoil in Asian economies, the outlook could be bleak,&quot; Musha said.</p>
<p>Mining, fisheries, precision instruments, warehousing and transportation equipment headed the decliners.  </p>
<p>Sony Corp was down 500 yen at 11,400, while Fujitsu Ltd was down 70 yen at 1,580.</p>
<p>There were no gaining sectors, but Yamaichi Securities Co Ltd, the second &quot;Big Four&quot; brokerage to be involved in a racketeer payoff scandal which has put Nomura Securities Co Ltd on the sidelines as punishment, jumped.</p>
<p>Yamaichi gained 30 yen, or 13.10 percent, to 259 and was the largest percentage gainer on the Tokyo bourse's first section. Brokers said the gain was the result of relief that 11 top executives had resigned to take responsibility for involvement in the scandal.  </p>
<p>Brokers said there were hopes the new management would be able to help the brokerage recover from the scandal.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't expect the shares to fall sharply from this level, as there are hopes Yamaichi may tie up with a foreign brokerage,&quot; said a trader at a second-tier Japanese securities house.</p>
<p>The TOPIX fell 43.59 points, or 2.90 percent, to 1,459.68, while the Nikkei 300 slipped 9.05 points, or 3.07 percent, to 285.42. The second-section index lost 21.34 points, or 1.27 percent, to 1,660.86.</p>
<p>-- Masako Iijima, Tokyo Equities Desk (81) 3-3432-9052</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
