<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="792580" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Waigel ignites talk of reshuffle in Kohl's cabinet.</title>
<headline>Waigel ignites talk of reshuffle in Kohl's cabinet.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-08-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl should replace several ministers before launching the 1998 election campaign, Finance Minister Theo Waigel said in interviews on Sunday which quickly ignited speculation of a cabinet reshuffle.</p>
<p>With surprising candor, Waigel said in a series of interviews there were a number of ministers only trying to hang on to their jobs until the election and urged Kohl to jettison any who were tiring well before the 1998 campaign starts.</p>
<p>&quot;In the fall, if there are a number of ministers who no longer have the desire, then the chancellor should form a new team,&quot; Waigel told the Welt am Sonntag newspaper.</p>
<p>In another interview with Der Spiegel news weekly, Waigel was even blunter, saying there was no room in the cabinet for anyone who was merely marking time until the next election.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is a minister or two wanting to leave but eager to hang on until the election, one should tell him 'Comrade, it would be nice, but we have to form our new team now'.&quot;</p>
<p>The remarks from Waigel, a loyal ally of Kohl, came less than one month after Kohl abruptly stamped out speculation of a cabinet reshuffle by saying he saw no reason to make changes before the next election.</p>
<p>But with opinion polls showing the ruling Christian Democrats (CDU) slumping behind the opposition Social Democrats (SPD), Waigel's coordinated campaign had all the markings of an attack with at least the tacit endorsement of Kohl.</p>
<p>Guido Westerwelle, the general secretary of the junior coalition partners the Free Democrats (FDP), said he was also in favour of making changes before the election rather than after.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally have a lot of sympthy for Theo Waigel's view,&quot; Westerwelle told a rally in the eastern town of Doebeln. FDP chairman Wolfgang Gerhardt often speaks out against any changes, even though he is rumoured to be the next economics minister.</p>
<p>Occasional rumours of cabinet changes have whip-sawed through Bonn during the first three years of Kohl's fourth term, but were denied and quickly died. There have be no changes in Kohl's 17-member cabinet since it took office in November 1994.</p>
<p>Waigel declined to be any more specific about which ministers he was referring to, but the Christian Social Union (CSU) party chairman has reportedly long had his eyes on the foreign ministry, now held by Klaus Kinkel of the junior coalition partners, the Free Democrats (FDP).</p>
<p>Waigel fuelled that speculation further by telling the Leipziger Volkszeitung newspaper that if he were no longer finance minister he would like to work on the foreign affairs committee of the parliament.</p>
<p>The Bild am Sonntag identified Interior Minister Manfred Kanther (CDU) and Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt (FDP) as likely targets of his broadside.</p>
<p>Rexrodt, who is often called ineffective by politicians in the CDU as well as his own FDP, has staved off several ouster attempts in the last few years. The newspaper said CDU leaders believe Kanther has failed to take advantage of his office.</p>
<p>Labour Minister Norbert Bluem (CDU), who turns 63 in 1998, was also thought to be on the hit list, Bild am Sonntag said.</p>
<p>&quot;One year before the election the chancellor has to have the right to shape the cabinet so that those who stay and the new arrivals will be available to remain in the cabinet for a full four years after the elections,&quot; Waigel told the Leipziger Volkszeitung.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
