<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="792608" id="root" date="1997-08-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian pepper prices rally on U.S., European deman.</title>
<headline>Indian pepper prices rally on U.S., European deman.</headline>
<byline>Parakulam Sundar</byline>
<dateline>COONOOR, India 1997-08-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Surging demand for pepper from the United States and European countries, amid low global supplies, have forced buyers to turn to Indian pepper, boosting its price, traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The rally in Indian pepper prices is because of increased demand and low supplies,&quot; said A.S. Rajagopalan, a leading spices exporter in the southern town of Coonoor.</p>
<p>&quot;Although prices have marginally fallen to 190 rupees ($5.3) per kg at Kochi market (in southern Kerala state) after touching 200 rupees in end-July, they are still far ahead of the previous few weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said prices are expected to firm further.</p>
<p>They said Indian pepper was quoted in mid-July at 175 rupees per kg compared with 75 rupees per kg at the same time last year in the domestic market. It was quoted at 127.50 rupees in June and 115.50 in May.</p>
<p>India produces about one third of the world's annual pepper crop of 180,000 tonnes. The other major producers include Brazil, Indonesia, Malaysia and Vietnam.</p>
<p>India produced 62,000 tonnes of pepper in 1995/96 (November-October) against 55,000 tonnes in 1994/95. It has set a production target of 55,000 tonnes for the current year.</p>
<p>The country exported about 35,000 tonnes of pepper in the 1996/97 (April-March) financial year compared with 24,150 tonnes in the previous year, officials said.</p>
<p>Traders said the Indonesian crop was expected to be about 20 percent less than the 39,200 tonnes it produced in 1996.</p>
<p>They said October domestic pepper futures were quoted at 205 rupees per kg and December futures were quoted at 217.75 rupees per kg.</p>
<p>&quot;The differential between spot and futures on the local exchange keeps speculators active,&quot; said a report issued by the state-run Spices Board.</p>
<p>Traders said prices had also firmed in the domestic market as monsoon rains had slowed market arrivals.</p>
<p>&quot;With the monsoon being active in the pepper growing tracts of Kerala, the supplies to the market have come down,&quot; said G.A. Balakrishnan, a leading pepper exporter.</p>
<p>Traders said India exported 2,830 tonnes of pepper in June compared with 2,450 tonnes in June 1996.</p>
<p>A Spices Board official said that India exported 14,250 tonnes of pepper between April and June valued at 1.59 billion rupees compared with 10,405 tonnes worth 772.5 million rupees in the same period in 1996.</p>
<p>Traders said Indian exporters needed to look at exports of value-added products such as oleoresins, essential oils, pepper in brine, dehydrated pepper, pepper powder, dried and sterilised pepper, to increase its world market share rather than exports of bulk pepper.</p>
<p>Value-added products account for 20 percent of India's pepper exports.</p>
<p>($1=35.7 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COONOOR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
