<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="792803" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. blue chips stagger to lowest close in 3 weeks.</title>
<headline>U.S. blue chips stagger to lowest close in 3 weeks.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dow industrials staggered lower on Tuesday, ending below the 8,000 level for the first time in three weeks after new evidence that U.S. economic growth is accelerating from its tame second quarter pace.</p>
<p>The Dow tumbled 101 points to close unofficially at 7961, its lowest closing level since July 21, when the blue chip average finished at 7906.72, its last finish below 8,000.</p>
<p>Nearly all of the decline followed the afternoon release of the Redbook retail sales index, which showed seasonally adjusted retail sales rose 0.9 percent in the week ended August 9.  </p>
<p>&quot;If there's any sign the consumer is really starting to spend, that will push the whole inflation issue right back to the forefront,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Also due tomorrow are monthly producer price and weekly jobless claims figures, with consumer price data due Thursday. With stocks still richly-valued and investors on the defensive, analysts predicted more volatility for the near-term.</p>
<p>&quot;We're in a nervous environment and volatilty is a fact of life here,&quot; said James Crawford, senior vice president at Trevor Stewart Burton &amp; Jacobsen Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't be surprised by a period of consolidation here, and ultimately I think it's probably going to prove to be beneficial over the long-term,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The late-session decline pulled broader indexes lower. The Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index fell 10.47 points to 926.53 and the Nasdaq Composite skidded 10.50 points to 1576.24, its fourth straight losing session.</p>
<p>Among individual issues, Amgen Inc fell 6-15/16 to 50-3/16 after the biotechnology company warned of reduced earnings from its drug Epogen due to changes in Medicaid reimbursement policies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
