<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="792854" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ciatti's to report fiscal Q4, year losses.</title>
<headline>Ciatti's to report fiscal Q4, year losses.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ciatti's Inc said Tuesday it expects to report a loss of $663,889 or a loss of $0.89 a share for its fiscal fourth quarter ended June 29, 1997.</p>
<p>Also on an unaudited basis, the company expects to report a loss of $2,568,778 or $3.46 a share for the year ended June 29, 1997.</p>
<p>Revenues for the quarter for the restaurant operator were $4,597,887, while revenues for the year were $17,737,804, the company said in a news release.  </p>
<p>Ciatti's also said it intends to seek listing of its newly registered units and warrants on the Nasdaq SmallCap market under the symbols CIATU and CIATW, respectively.</p>
<p>However, Ciatti's said that as a result of its expected losses for the fiscal 1997 quarter and year, its shareholders' equity as of June 29, 1997 will be about $606,000, which is less than the minimum required for continued inclusion on the Nasdaq SmallCap Market.</p>
<p>The minimum proceeds from an offering of these units and warrants would allow the company to satisfy the SmallCap Market requirements. But if the company were unable to generate the minimum or could not get a temporary exemption for continued listing on the Nasdaq SmallCap Market pending completion of the offering, Ciatti's expects that its securities would trade in the over-the-counter market or through the Nasdaq Bulletin Board.</p>
<p>		((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
