<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="793150" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: CSFB DOWNGRADES EGIS' EPS, MAINTAINS BUY.</title>
<headline>CSFB DOWNGRADES EGIS' EPS, MAINTAINS BUY.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>CS First Boston said it downgraded its 1997 earnings per share forecast for Hungarian pharmaceuticals firm Egis but maintained its 'buy' rating after Egis's net income was below CSFB's expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;We have downgraded our full-year forecasts somewhat to reflect the sub-par performance during H1,&quot; analyst Spencer Jakab said in a company report, dated August 11.</p>
<p>Egis released its first half figures on Monday and its net income in the first half of 1997 of 3.03 billion forints was 8.5 percent down year-on-year.</p>
<p>&quot;Steep declines in key branded generics on the domestic market were only partially outweighed by rapid export growth to the CIS,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Jakab said Egis's operating margins contracted to 19 percent for the period from 24 percent in the same period of 1996, but margins should be only slightly weaker during the second half of 1997 as CIS sales volume reaches economies of scale.</p>
<p>&quot;For the full year, operating margins could decline to 18 percent but we feel that 1997 will be the low point,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking ahead to the next two years, we would expect operating margins to stabilise at 19 to 21 percent as licensed-in drugs begin to have a major impact on sales.</p>
<p>Jakab noted that Egis, Hungary's second largest pharmaceuticals company and the fourth largest in Central and Eastern Europe, is one of only two companies in the region which has an FDA-approved (Food and Drug Administration of the U.S.) facility for finished-form drugs.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
