<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="793360" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-AUSTRALIAN SPORTS NEWS - AUG 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-AUSTRALIAN SPORTS NEWS - AUG 13.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The good performances of the Australian swimming team at the Pan Pac championships in Japan has continued with 17-year-old Grant Hackett and 14-year-old Ian Thorpe taking the gold and silver medals in the 400-metres freestyle last night. Sprinter Michael Klim has become the seventh fastest man in history by swimming 49.15 seconds for the 100-metres in the freestyle relay. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australia's pace bowling stocks for the sixth and final cricket Test at The Oval have been severely hit through injuries to Jason Gillespie and Paul Reiffel. Their replacements are likely to be Michael Kasprowicz and Brendon Julian, who have played only a few games on tour. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian rugby union player David Wilson has been named as the new captain of the Wallaby side for the match this weekend against New Zealand. Wilson replaces injured skipper John Eales as his mixed season of fortune continues after he was dropped from the team earlier in the year. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Injuries to the Australian rugby union team have forced the inclusion of two new uncapped players for the Tri Nations Test against New Zealand. John Langford and Fili Finau are the newcomers, replacing injured team-mates John Eales and Matthew Cockbain. age 46.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Peace talks between the two warring rugby league competitions will continue tomorrow, with a merger likely to be announced without a clear understanding of the details for a new competition. Dividing issues of a new name for the competition and the ideal amount of teams will not delay the establishment of a new competition. Page 45.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian yachts are within sight of the lead in the marathon series Fastnet, the last race in the Admiral's Cup series. Ragamuffin is in fourth place, Sea in second place in its class and G-Net fourth in a separate division. Page 45.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Leading Australian swimmer Samantha Riley will swim for a world record in the 200-metres breaststroke tonight. Riley defeated long-time rival, South African Penny Heyns, to win the 100-metres title and is confident of breaking the record. Page B14.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian jockey Darren Beadman's commitment to a promise to ride sprinter Spartacus may see him without a ride at weekend meetings. Trainer Rick Hore-Lacy has not yet decided where the horse will run, leaving Beadman without a firm commitment for other races at the track. Page B14.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian soccer player Jason van Blerk, currently playing with Manchester City in the English first division, was likely to return home until he recently secured a work permit. Van Blerk has won the right to play after his transfer from a Dutch side was secured with the permit. Page B14.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Collingwood Australian Football League team president Kevin Rose has strongly criticised the club's management and says he will bring in new talent to assist coach Tony Shaw. Football director Graeme Allan will be replaced with former Richmond coach Robert Walls the likely newcomer. Page 72.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Leading Australian cyclist Brad McGee has withdrawn from this month's world championships claiming fatigue and a depleted immune system. McGee will have six months of complete rest before attempting a return. Page 65.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Carlton Australian Football Team player Matthew Allan is expected to sign a new contract with the club for a further three years today. The club's management and Allan have been involved in a long dispute over the upgraded contract. Page 70.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>North Queensland Cowboys Super League player Jason Death will give A$10,000 to charity to avoid being cut from the club. Death stripped naked during victory celebrations with the Australian cricket team and was sent home from the team's recent World Club Challenge mission in England. Page 69.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian tennis player Jason Stoltenberg has made it to the second round of the RCA championships by defeating South African Marcos Ondruska. Fellow Australians Michael Tebbutt and Luke Smith were defeated by seeded opponents in opening matches. Page 6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Two rugby union players will sign new deals with English clubs this week as the battle to retain second tier playing strength continues. Mark Giacheri is expected to sign with West Hartlepool and Simon Raiwalui will link with Sale. Page 64.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
