<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79383" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stride Rite says Keds line drag on sales.</title>
<headline>Stride Rite says Keds line drag on sales.</headline>
<dateline>LEXINGTON, Mass. 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stride Rite Corp Chairman and Chief Executive Robert Siegel said Thursday it does not expect a &quot;quick turnaround&quot; in the company's recent performance, citing an order backlog for Keds and efforts to streamline its operations.</p>
<p>Siegel said the company is investing in product development for its line of Keds and are trying to build the product line around the classic Champion silhouette style in order to appeal to Keds core customers, who are women between ages 25 and 44.  </p>
<p>&quot;As we approach fiscal 1997, we are working hard to improve our product lines and to strengthen our brands in order to return to sales and profitability growth,&quot; Siegel said.</p>
<p>For this year's third quarter, the company's net income dropped to $3.2 million, or $0.06 per share, from $3.5 million, or $0.07 per share, in the third quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>The company recorded sales of $123.5 million for this year's third quarter, a decline from $139.1 million in the third quarter of 1995.  </p>
<p>Third quarter sales for Keds, which represents half of the Stride Rite business, were down 29 percent below last year's level, the company said.</p>
<p>Although sales in other areas of the company are doing well, the low order backlog of Keds has proven to be a drag on the company, Stride Rite Vice President, Finance and Treasurer John Kelliher said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fourth quarter is a tough quarter for us anyway because we're known for canvas and white,&quot; Kelliher said. &quot;We'll lose money in the fourth quarter.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEXINGTON, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
