<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="793891" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: INDONESIAN RUPIAH REMAINS WEAK ON CONTAGION EFFECT.</title>
<headline>INDONESIAN RUPIAH REMAINS WEAK ON CONTAGION EFFECT.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah remained weak against the dollar in late trading on Tuesday on extended contagion effect, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said the weakness, triggered by falls in the Malaysian ringgit and the Singapore dollar, knocked the rupiah down to 2,655 against the dollar before it stabilised at 2,640.0/42.0 at 0915 GMT. Spot rupiah opened at 2,610/20. Tomorrow and today rupiah closed at 2,639.0/44.0 and 2,641.0/43.0, respectively.</p>
<p>The rupiah recovered briefly to a high of 2,638 but strong offshore pressure sent it back between a range of 2,640 and 2,650 for the rest of the day.  </p>
<p>The Singapore dollar fell through the psychological 1.50 to the U.S. dollar level to hit a new three-year low of 1.5085.</p>
<p>This followed comments by a Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS) official that the Singapore dollar's level was appropriate to what was happening in the market.</p>
<p>She said the U.S. dollar had been rising in currency markets and the Singapore dollar had depreciated by about five percent against the U.S. unit since the start of 1997.</p>
<p>Dealers said the drop in the sturdy Singapore dollar had set off selling of other Southeast Asian currencies as players increasingly grouped the region's economies together.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the central bank was not seen in the market although the rupiah fall off the range the central bank has said it was comfortable with, between 2,550 and 2,610.</p>
<p>One Japanese bank dealer said it was right that the central bank did not intervene because it need not have had the desired effect since the entire region's currencies remained volatile.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know what the equilibrium level is now although some suggest the rupiah is undervalued. We just go with the market and regional trends,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's dangerous to take on heavy positions. You don't know who is going to make the next comment,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Dealers said they were losing direction because the market had been moved by two comments made in two days. The rupiah was jolted on Monday when Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad made a comment on the ringgit and now again by the MAS.</p>
<p>But they said swap rates were up slightly following a sudden increase of overnight money. Overnight rates rose to 27 percent from 17 percent in the morning.</p>
<p>One local bank dealer said the increase was technical.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a delay of morning clearing results which prompted many operators to cover first,&quot; the dealer said.  </p>
<p>But another dealer said it could also be due to higher weekly tax payments at mid-month due Tuesday.</p>
<p>The central bank kept its rates of bilateral central bank certificates (SBIs) unchanged and continued to be absent from the short-term securities (SBPUs) market.</p>
<p>Dealers said artificially high central bank short-term rates were likely to continue as the foreign exchange market remained volatile.</p>
<p>One-month swap was at 21.5/25.0, two at 40.0/46.0, three at 60.0/66.0 and six at 124.0/134.0 points.</p>
<p>The central bank kept its intervention band at 2,378/2,682 but raised the conversion band to 2,616/2,664 on Tuesday from 2,588/2,636 on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom (6221) 384-6364; Fax (6221) 344-8404</p>
<p>-- Email: jakarta.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
