<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="793848" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Commonwealth to decide on 3 new members in October.</title>
<headline>Commonwealth to decide on 3 new members in October.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Commonwealth will decide in October whether to accept three new member countries, Commonwealth Secretary-General Emeka Anyaoku said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Anyaoku told a news conference Yemen, Rwanda and the Palestine National Authority had all made firm applications to join the association, which groups 53 mainly former British colonies around the world.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Heads of Government meeting in Edinburgh, Scotland, in October would make a final decision on the three applications, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment there are three firm applications,&quot; Anyaoku said. &quot;I can only say that they have submitted applications. I cannot begin to speculate on what the outcome of the applications will be.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;When the heads of government meet they will make the decision,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Anyaoku said the Palestinian National Authority led by Palestine Liberation Organisation chairman Yasser Arafat, which covers parts of territories formerly occupied by Israel, and Yemen had both previously been under temporary British control.</p>
<p>Rwanda had never been a British colony, but Anyaoku said this was not necessarily a reason to disallow its membership.</p>
<p>&quot;We already have some members who were never British. The latest to join was Mozambique,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But of course I do not want to prejudge what the outcome of the applications will be. I do not want to suggest that the applications will necessarily succeed or indeed fail. I don't know,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Anyoaku said other areas to be covered by the Edinburgh summit would include the promotion of trade, investment and development cooperation throughout the Commonwealth and the discussion of broader global trade issues.</p>
<p>The meeting would also discuss developments in Nigeria and Sierra Leone, both recently suspended for violating what Anyaoku said were the Commonwealth's fundamental values of &quot;democracy, good governance and human rights&quot;.</p>
<p>He said he believed the Commonwealth would emerge from the Edinburgh summit a stronger and better organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;The meeting will result in a reinforcement of the capacity of the Commonwealth both to serve as an instrument for promoting development and promoting trade and investment in its member countries and beyond and also as an instrument for promoting its fundamental political values,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COMWH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
