<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="793919" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: CP.INTELLIGENCE LOWERS RATINGS OF SKOREAN BANKS.</title>
<headline>CP.INTELLIGENCE LOWERS RATINGS OF SKOREAN BANKS.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cyprus-based Capital Intelligence on Tuesday lowered the ratings of five South Korean banks with high exposures to the troubled Kia Group.</p>
<p>The specialist bank rating agency lowered long-term ratings of Cho Hung Bank, Hanil Bank and Korea Exchange Bank to BBB+, while maintaining short-term outlooks of A-1 and negative outlooks until further notice.</p>
<p>Capital Intelligence said in a news release it was also reducing long term ratings of Korea First Bank and Seoulbank to BB. The short term rating for Korea First Bank has been lowered to A-3 from A-2.</p>
<p>A negative outlook is appended to these ratings until further notice, Capital Intelligence said, adding that it has also assigned a negative outlook to Commercial Bank of Korea.</p>
<p>&quot;The downgrades are a result of the bank's high exposures to Kia as well as their weakening financial conditions due to lost interest income and probable large provisioning requirements on other substantial doubtful debts,&quot; said Capital Intelligence.</p>
<p>Capital Intelligence said it expected banks to tighten their loan policies further, thereby increasing the potential for further near-failures which would probably then have to be supported by the banks.</p>
<p>&quot;Hence the string of corporate near-failures is expected to continue and the banks' financial strength is likely to weaken further,&quot; Capital Intelligence said.</p>
<p>It also lowered the ratings for Korea Development Bank, from AA long term and A-1+ short term to A+ and A-1, whilst maintaining a negative outlook.</p>
<p>As wholly owned by the governemnt, the bank's risk profile reflects Koreas state of financial affairs, Capital Intelligence said.</p>
<p>&quot;In this regard CI believes that the government's finances are presently being undermined by the potential costs arising from the restructuring of the country's finance and corporate sectors,&quot; Capital Intelligence said.</p>
<p>-- Nicosia newsroom 357 2 469625</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
