<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794082" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Study finds teaching hospitals have fewer deaths.</title>
<headline>Study finds teaching hospitals have fewer deaths.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hospitals which educate physicians as part of their business may achieve lower death rates among patients with major illnesses than those that do not, according to a report published on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The finding was based on a review of nearly 90,000 patients in the Cleveland area who were treated at various teaching and non-teaching hospitals for stroke, heart attack, pneumonia and other conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;We found that the risk of death was 19 percent lower in major teaching hospitals, compared with non-teaching hospitals, and that the length of stay was generally 10 percent lower,&quot; said the report published in this week's Journal of the American Medical Association.</p>
<p>Major teaching hospitals are considered to be more expensive -- and thus less attractive to insurance coverage in today's managed care environment -- because they sponsor research, offer a broad range of services and often treat large numbers of poor patients.</p>
<p>The study from Case Western Reserve University School of Medicine in Cleveland said the findings &quot;highlight the importance of such hospitals in individual care&quot; and the potential problems with &quot;purchasing decisions that shift hospital utilization patterns away from major teaching hospitals ...&quot;</p>
<p>Questions about the study were aired by Lisa Iezzoni of the Harvard Medical School, Boston, in an editorial in the same issue of the journal.</p>
<p>She said comparing death rates was a &quot;blunt instrument&quot; with which to make quality assessments and cited one study which indicated some patients near death may prefer nearby community (non-teaching) hospitals when desiring end-of-life comfort care.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, she said, society must continue to support major teaching hospitals &quot;for the greater good&quot; and find ways to make the facilities operate more efficiently.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
