<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794026" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LOCAL ECONOMY ROBUST IN EARLY Q3 -- RICHMOND FED.</title>
<headline>LOCAL ECONOMY ROBUST IN EARLY Q3 -- RICHMOND FED.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economic activity in the fifth U.S. district appears fairly robust in the early part of the third quarter, with broad-based underlying strength, said an official at the Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond.</p>
<p>&quot;As we are beginning the third quarter, at least in our district, we're looking at fairly robust activity. The quarter appears to be getting off on a pretty good foot,&quot; Raymond Owens, chief regional economist at the Richmond Fed, told Reuters Financial Television.  </p>
<p>Owens spoke to Reuters shortly after the release of the Richmond Fed's monthly manufacturing shipments index, which fell sharply to a negative 10 in July from 15 in June.</p>
<p>Although the headline numbers for the regional manufacturing survey suggested activity deceleration, the Richmond Fed economist said the drop was seasonal.</p>
<p>&quot;What we saw was a very strong rebound in retail. Retail sales ... indicate that there is strength across the board in our district,&quot; Owens said. &quot;The turndown in manufacturing is more a seasonal factor than any underlying phenomena.&quot;</p>
<p>Owens also said he saw some wage pressures in the region. But he added that upward pressures on prices remained modest.</p>
<p>The Richmond Fed survey cover industries located in the nation's fifth economic distric, which encompasses the District of Columbia, Maryland, North Carolina, South Carolina, Virginia and most of West Virginia.</p>
<p>(( -- Jose Paulo Vicente, 212-859-1676 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
