<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794110" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME FEEDER CATTLE END LIMIT DOWN ON CBOT CORN JUMP.</title>
<headline>CME FEEDER CATTLE END LIMIT DOWN ON CBOT CORN JUMP.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade corn futures surged up their daily 12-cent limit on a surprising USDA crop production report and knocked CME feeder cattle futures sharply lower to down the 1.500-cent- a-lb limit by the close, traders said.</p>
<p>September through January feeders closed limit down with other months down 1.450 to 1.025 cents. August was off 1.375 at 79.425 and September off limit at 78.975 cents, its lowst level since June 27.</p>
<p>Live cattle finished mostly lower, up 0.075 to off 0.300 cent with August up 0.075 at 65.725 cents a lb and October off most at 69.550 cents.</p>
<p>Active fund and speculative liquidation was evident from the start in feeder cattle and futures locked limit down when corn futures soared limit up following USDA's crop production estimates for corn. That report put corn production at 9.276 million bushels, less than market analysts had expected.</p>
<p>&quot;This is strictly a corn-driven break,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Higher feed costs will curtail demand for replacement feeders at feedlots. This follows recent good demand for feeders due to lower feed costs earlier in the year and reduced feeder cattle supplies, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
