<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794223" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Poor law enforcement in Latam worries White House. [CORRECTED 17:55 GMT]</title>
<headline>Poor law enforcement in Latam worries White House. [CORRECTED 17:55 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Anthony Boadle</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration is studying ways to get Latin American countries to crack down on corruption and crime as the hemisphere moves towards freer trade, U.S. officials say.</p>
<p>Drug trafficking and money laundering are uncontrolled, and corrupt courts are hazards for doing business in many of the region's countries, they say.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton is preparing to ask Congress for broad authority to negotiate the expansion of free trade before visiting South America in October.</p>
<p>And his top law enforcement officials are anxious to get across the message that there should be no safe haven for organised crime in the hemisphere.</p>
<p>Attorney General Janet Reno, FBI director Louis Freeh and the administration's drug policy czar Gen. Barry McCaffrey discussed the status of law enforcement in Latin America at a White House brainstorming meeting last week.</p>
<p>&quot;The message is that all countries need to agree that the hemisphere should not become a safe haven for criminals and organised crime,&quot; a White House official told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;And the way to do that is to provide training and technical assistance and agree on basic legal frameworks to attack criminals, including extradition,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Justice Department, Drug Enforcement Administration and FBI officials at the meeting chaired by Clinton's Latin American policy advisor, Thomas &quot;Mack&quot; McLarty, stressed the importance of having viable and trustworthy justice and penal systems in the region, the official said.</p>
<p>But political analysts said that pushing for judicial reforms could be seen as interference in Latin American nations' affairs and could stir up anti-U.S. sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;The Latin American judicial system is perhaps the most corrupt of any region in the world,&quot; said Larry Birns (corrects analyst's name), executive director of the Council on Hemispheric Affairs, an independent, non-partisan policy research organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;But the United States cannot take on a crusade to repair or improve an area that is so sensitive without getting some kind of concurrence from the societies you are dealing with,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a danger of getting on a high horse of moral rectitude that is going to lead to a lot of anti-U.S. feeling in Latin America,&quot; said Arturo Valenzuela, director of the Latin American Studies Centre at Georgetown University.</p>
<p>Administration officials believe that while Latin America is living in an unprecedented era of democracy, the region's democratic governments have failed to control crime, fight drug trafficking and stop the laundering of its profits.</p>
<p>Washington suspects President Ernesto Samper's government in Colombia is tainted by drug money, but hopes the world's largest cocaine producing country will restore extraditions that were banned in 1991 under pressure from drug lords.</p>
<p>In Congress there is concern that free trade with Mexico may have eased the flow of narcotics and drug money across the U.S. border. Scandals in Mexican law enforcement agencies have not helped this image.</p>
<p>&quot;Organized crime is the greatest threat to democracy in Latin America,&quot; the White House official said. She said the strengthening of democracy was intimately tied to the opening up of markets and improved justice.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are going to have a functioning democracy you have to have a law enforcement that you can trust. You have to have prosecutors that can prosecute. You have to have judges that will take objective decisions,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Some are sceptical as to what Washington can achieve.</p>
<p>&quot;The administration does not have the slightest idea of the magnitude of the problem it would have to confront in the region or how systemic the corruption is,&quot; Burns said.</p>
<p>Burns said the United States's method of weighing the degree of cooperation it gets from countries in fighting drug trafficking was itself &quot;politicized.&quot;</p>
<p>Colombia was decertified again this year even though its record was better than Mexico's, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Mexico was uncertifiable, but for political reasons the United States could not wreak damage on the Mexican peso by decertifying it,&quot; the Latin American affairs expert said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
