<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794282" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: J.C. PENNEY POSTS MODEST Q2 OPER SHR RISE.</title>
<headline>J.C. PENNEY POSTS MODEST Q2 OPER SHR RISE.</headline>
<dateline>PLANO, Texas 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>J.C. Penney Co Inc, which Monday offered voluntary early retirement to about 1,500 people, or five percent of its management staff, Tuesday reported a modest rise in second-quarter operating results.</p>
<p>The retail giant reported operating earnings for the quarter ended July 26, 1997, of $0.38 per share, up from the year ago's $0.37. Operating earnings exclude business acquisition and consolidation expenses.  </p>
<p>Including the effects of these expenses, which are primarily related to the Eckerd Drugstores acquisition, net income was $90 million, or $0.32 per share fully diluted. The First Call consensus was $0.37.</p>
<p>After the closing bell Monday, Penney said it was offering the buyout plan in a bid to cut costs to compensate for recent weak profits.</p>
<p>The company Tuesday reported operating profit for JCPenney Stores and Catalog totaled $156 million in the second quarter, an increase of $21 million, from a year ago. For the quarter, sales rose 3.5 percent. On a comparable store basis, sales rose 2.0 percent.</p>
<p>Operating profits for Eckerd totaled $89 million in the quarter, up 30 percent over pro forma results, assuming the drugstore acquisitions had occurred at the beginning of 1996. Eckerd Drugstores comparable store sales rose 7.8 percent in the second quarter from a year ago.</p>
<p>Commenting on the results, James E. Oesterreicher, chairman and chief executive officer, said, &quot;JCPenney is in position to take advantage of the positive economic and consumer environment. We have in place merchandising and marketing programs to generate profitable sales for the all important second half. Looking forward, we are committed to accelerating our ongoing expense reduction programs and lowering our expense to sales ratio, and improving our operating performance.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PLANO, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
