<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794295" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME HOGS SEEN STEADY TO OFF, PORK BELLIES LOWER.</title>
<headline>CME HOGS SEEN STEADY TO OFF, PORK BELLIES LOWER.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME lean hog futures were expected to open steady to 0.150 cent per lb lower while pork bellies were called 0.200 to 0.300 cent lower, livestock analysts said.</p>
<p>Mostly steady to lower cash hog indications and losses in pork cutout values were expected to weigh on hog futures early. Hog runs appear adequate to meet current packer demand, they said.</p>
<p>The market also appears technically weak after breaking through chart support at 72.100 cents, basis October, in Monday's trade, they said.  </p>
<p>The latest CME lean hog index fell $0.57 to $79.42 per cwt.</p>
<p>Pork belly futures were also seen showing carryover selling pressure following the continued weak tone to fresh cash bellies. Cash belly prices have fallen much further than expected without finding support, analysts said.</p>
<p>USDA reported 14-16 lb bellies selling as low as $78 per cwt after trading as high as $92 recently.</p>
<p>Estimates on Tuesday afternoon's CME out-of-town report ranged from out movement of 3.0 to 3.7 million lbs of pork bellies versus out movement of 3.416 million lbs last week and out 3.520 million lbs last year.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
