<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79438" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pinkerton upset by U.S. rock group's album name.</title>
<headline>Pinkerton upset by U.S. rock group's album name.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Pinkerton detective agency has turned its attention from tracking down villains to battling a popular rock band, which the company says is illegally using its name.</p>
<p>Pinkerton has obtained a temporary restraining order preventing Los Angeles-based band Weezer from selling its latest album, &quot;Pinkerton&quot;, which was released in the United States on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Encino, California-based company, founded in 1850 by theoriginal &quot;private eye&quot; Allan Pinkerton, says its name is a registered trademark. A spokesman told Reuters on Wednesday the company did not want to get caught up in controversy if people took exception to the album's lyrics and blamed Pinkerton.</p>
<p>The clean-cut band, whose lead singer is a student at Harvard University, had a big hit recently with the song &quot;Buddy Holly.&quot; The video spliced Weezer into Al's Diner scenes from the TV show &quot;Happy Days.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman at Geffen Records, which is releasing the album, said the title was inspired by the villainous lead character in the Puccini opera, &quot;Madame Butterfly&quot;. None of the album's songs refers to &quot;Pinkerton&quot;.</p>
<p>Geffen spokesman Dennis Dennehy said vocalist Rivers Cuomo was a big opera buff. &quot;It wasn't meant to be aimed at a corporate entity,&quot; Dennehy said.</p>
<p>The order prevents Geffen and Weezer advertising the record with the name &quot;Pinkerton&quot; associated with the album. However, stores are still selling the album.</p>
<p>Geffen, which is part of Seagram Co's MCA Inc media giant, will seek to dissolve the order at a court hearing on Thursday.</p>
<p>Pinkerton spokesman Dereck Andrade said the company did not want to stop the band from making money but had to ensure it was protecting the interests of its shareholders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
