<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79437" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Teamster chief Carey to sue rival Hoffa for libel.</title>
<headline>Teamster chief Carey to sue rival Hoffa for libel.</headline>
<byline>Peter Szekely</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Teamsters union President Ron Carey plans to file a $20 million libel suit charging rival Jim Hoffa Jr. with smearing his reputation by knowingly publishing lies about him, a Carey spokeswoman said Wednesday.</p>
<p>According to a complaint that was expected to be filed later this week, the suit will accuse Hoffa, son of the infamous Teamster leader who disappeared 21 years ago, and other Teamster leaders allied with him of waging a &quot;massive libel and slander campaign.&quot;</p>
<p>Carey, 60, and Hoffa, 55, are waging a bitter campaign against one another for the leadership of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, the country's second-largest union. A government-supervised mail ballot election open to all 1.4 million union members will determine a winner in December.</p>
<p>The complaint will charge the defendants with falsely publishing that Carey secretly owned $2 million of stock of United Parcel Service, a major Teamster employer; that he &quot;sold out&quot; UPS Teamster members in their 1993 contract to benefit his own financial interests, and that he used a UPS attorney to swindle an elderly woman into leaving him the bulk of her estate.</p>
<p>&quot;The defendants issued these statements knowing that they were false or with reckless disregard for their truth or falsity and did so out of ill-will and with the malicious intent of injuring plaintiff Carey and depriving him of his ability to earn a living,&quot; the documents said.</p>
<p>Hoffa campaign spokesman Richard Leebove denied the allegations against Hoffa and accused Carey of grandstanding.</p>
<p>&quot;Ron Carey doesn't have the guts to debate Jim Hoffa, so he's using the court system and the media as a gimmick to further his failing campaign,&quot; said Leebove, who, while not a defendant, is cited in the complaint as a member of a &quot;dirty tricks team&quot; for Hoffa and Teamster official Lawrence Brennan.</p>
<p>&quot;If this case is ever filed -- Carey has a pattern of filing libel suits and withdrawing them shortly thereafter -- we are going to move for an expedited deposition and have it videotaped so that the members can decide whether he's telling the truth,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Although the 18-page civil complaint was released to the press, it had not been filed in court because it is first being reviewed by the union's federal government overseers, Carey spokeswoman Renee Asher said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a step we had to do,&quot; said Asher, who is on the staff of Carey's reelection campaign.</p>
<p>Unless the overseers challenge the jurisdiction of the suit, it will be filed Friday in New York State Supreme Court for Queens County, Asher said. The overseers -- a U.S. Distict Court judge, three-person review board and elections officer -- were established as part of a 1989 settlement of a federal racketeering suit against the union.</p>
<p>Carey's complaint charges the defendants with publishing their allegedly false statements about him in their campaign literature and in &quot;The Teamster&quot; magazine.</p>
<p>In a statement, Carey said he will donate any court award for damages to benefit Teamster families.</p>
<p>As a public figure, however, Carey might likely have to make a much stronger case than a private citizen with a libel claim. To prevail, he might have to show that the defendants not only published falsehoods about him, but that they did so maliciously or with reckless disregard for the truth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
