<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794378" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FRENCH TRADERS SAY GOVT UNDERESTIMATES WHEAT CROP.</title>
<headline>FRENCH TRADERS SAY GOVT UNDERESTIMATES WHEAT CROP.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>French grain traders on Tuesday greeted as too conservative new official grain forecasts showing no revision in the previously estimated soft wheat crop.</p>
<p>The farm ministry earlier forecast 1997 soft wheat output of 33.2 million tonnes, unchanged from its July estimate and down from last year's record 34.7 million tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;It's fairly pessimistic, at the low end of the range,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's in the same direction as the drop we have seen in test weight results, but still an underestimate,&quot; another said.  </p>
<p>Traders said it was too late for wheat to get the astonishing late boost in productivity experienced when the harvest swung north of the river Seine last year, pushing output to an all-time high.</p>
<p>But one said this year's crop still had the potential to add 0.2 tonnes per hectare over and above the ministry's yield estimate during the last crucial days of harvesting.</p>
<p>The ministry bases its forecast on an area of 4.858 million hectares and an average yield of 6.84 tonnes per hectare.</p>
<p>If the area figure is left unchanged, adding 0.2 tonnes to the yield would imply output of some 34.2 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Some French grain officials have said they doubt, however, that this year's harvest will reach 34 million tonnes. Most put the realistic range between 33 and 34 million.</p>
<p>At 33.2 million tonnes, the crop forecast by the ministry is the second biggest for soft wheat after last year's record.</p>
<p>Most traders said they agreed with a ministry estimate of 7.128 million tonnes for the winter barley crop.</p>
<p>But some thought a spring barley yield estimate of 5.66 tonnes per hectare -- giving output of 2.871 million tonnes -- could eventually be revised up by another 0.1 to 0.2 tonnes.</p>
<p>The ministry forecast a total barley crop of 10 million tonnes for the first time since 1992.  </p>
<p>Traders were rather more cautious about the forecast for a 14.9 million tonne maize crop, France's second biggest and the largest since the 1992 reform of the Common Agricultural Policy.</p>
<p>The figure tallied with early forecasts by maize producers after weeks of ideal weather, but it was too early to issue firm predictions for the October crop, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Okay, we've had perfect weather until now but there is some time to go until the crop comes in,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Others said the real uncertainty was over the area planted to maize, which the ministry puts at 1.784 million hectares. That is a 50,000 hectare rise from last year, but French cereals office ONIC puts the area closer to 1.730 million hectares.</p>
<p>&quot;Farmers say they sowed the same area; ONIC says the area rose 10-15,000 hectares; the ministry says 50,000 -- these are large fluctuations,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The farm ministry is believed to include about 10,000 to 20,000 hectares of wet maize in its figure. This goes straight to feed instead of being marketed as grain.</p>
<p>-- Valerie Parent, Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
