<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79448" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: COUNCIL SET TO AGREE EU TELECOMS LICENSING REGIME.</title>
<headline>COUNCIL SET TO AGREE EU TELECOMS LICENSING REGIME.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Telecommunications Council has a good chance on Friday of reaching a political agreement on a regime for authorising and licensing telecoms operators in the post-liberalisation era, diplomats said.</p>
<p>Ministers are expected to endorse a draft directive that would require governments to set up open and nondiscriminatory procedures for authorising companies to offer telecoms services or infrastructure once state monopolies are abolished.</p>
<p>Most member states have accepted a compromise on the main conflicts -- when to require individual licenses as opposed to &quot;general authorisations&quot; -- and when governments can limit the number of those licenses, diplomats said.</p>
<p>The new text would allow member states to require individual licenses for all companies offering voice telephone services or public networks.</p>
<p>That goes beyond the Commission's proposal, which envisaged individual licenses only in certain cases, for example to allocate radio frequencies or numbers, grant access to land or impose public service obligations.</p>
<p>It wanted governments to rely mostly on &quot;general authorisation&quot; schemes allowing all companies that comply with certain rules to set up business.</p>
<p>But countries including France, Greece, Italy, Portugal and Spain fought to expand the use of individual licenses.</p>
<p>&quot;Not all the liberal countries are happy (with the compromise), but we think they will come around,&quot; one diplomat said.</p>
<p>The new text, however, rejected a bid by some countries to allow governments to limit the number of operators in a given sector because their markets are small.</p>
<p>The ministers look set to agree only to allow limits if needed to ensure the efficient use of radio frequencies or -- on a temporary basis -- because of a shortage of telephone numbers.</p>
<p>That responds to a request from Spain, which said it needed more time to reorganise its numbering system, diplomats said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
