<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794474" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish Match H1 profit jumps 33 pct.</title>
<headline>Swedish Match H1 profit jumps 33 pct.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish tobacco and lighter company Swedish Match said on Tuesday its profit after financial items rose 33 percent in the first half of 1997, despite a decline in the cigarette market.</p>
<p>The group posted a profit of 758 million crowns ($94.6 million) compared to 572 million a year ago and sales of 3.63 billion crowns versus 3.58 billion in the first half 1996.</p>
<p>Analysts expected the company to post a profit of 799 million crowns for the period. The share traded up 0.20 crown at 24.40 after the result.</p>
<p>Swedish Match said increased sales and higher prices of its moist snuff products helped compensate for a decline in cigarette sales. This division reported a 25 percent increase in operating profit at 232 million crowns compared to 186 million withg sales of 505 million crowns against 422 million.</p>
<p>Sales of cigarettes, of which its Blend brand has about a third of the Swedish market and its Prince brand another third, fell 15 percent to 779 million crowns. Operating profit slumped 28 percent to 238 million crowns.</p>
<p>Some eight percent of this decline was because of hoarding ahead of a tobacco tax increase on January 1, 1997, the company said.</p>
<p>An agreement which took effect on May 1 under which Swedish Match manufactures its Prince brand but House of Prince AB markets them explained the other part of the fall as well as a general market decline for cigarettes, the company said.</p>
<p>Swedish Match distributes virtually all cigarettes on the Swedish market.</p>
<p>-- Abigail Schmelz, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700-1003 ($ = 8.015 Swedish Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
