<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794586" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: ONLY DIV PAYING FIRMS SHOULD SEEK LISTING - SEBI.</title>
<headline>ONLY DIV PAYING FIRMS SHOULD SEEK LISTING - SEBI.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian market regulator Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) said on Tuesday it decided that only firms which paid dividends for three consecutive years will be allowed to seek listing on the country's bourses.</p>
<p>&quot;Presently, the entry barrier requirement for unlisted companies stipulates payment of dividend in at least three out of the preceding five years,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;This has been modified to require dividend payment in immediately preceding three years,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>It said a listed firm would be required to meet the entry norm only if the post-issue net worth becomes more than five times the pre-issue net worth.</p>
<p>Companies would be required to make their partly paid up shares fully paid up or forfeit the same before making a public or rights issue, SEBI said.</p>
<p>it said unlisted companies can freely price their securities provided they had shown net profit in the immediately preceding three years subject to fulfilment of the existing disclosure requirements.</p>
<p>At present, promoters' contribution for public issues by unlisted as well as listed firms is specified at 25 percent for issue size upto 1.0 billion rupees and 20 percent for issue size above 1.0 billion rupees.</p>
<p>The promoters' contribution has now been made uniform at 20 percent irrespective of the issue size, SEBI said.</p>
<p>&quot;Only such securities can be offered for promoters' contribution for which a specific written consent has been obtained from the shareholders for lock-in,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>SEBI said the appointment of registrar to an issue for rights issues has been made mandatory.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom (91)-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
