<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79450" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: S&amp;P SAYS HARD FOR FINNISH LOCAL GOVTS TO CUT STAFF.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P SAYS HARD FOR FINNISH LOCAL GOVTS TO CUT STAFF.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>It will probably become harder in the future for Finnish municipalities to trim costs through staff cuts than it was in the early 1990s, rating institute Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) said in a report received on Thursday.</p>
<p>Finland's local government sector had to face rapidly rising unemployment and reduced state transfers in the beginning of this decade, S&amp;P said in a report on Nordic municipalities in its CreditWeek newsletter dated September 18.</p>
<p>&quot;The sector was able to to meet these conditions through large staff cuts, tax increases, and a freeze on wages,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>&quot;Unemployment of about 18 percent still contributes to high social welfare costs that will have to be met by continued staff reductions and other measures of improved efficiency. This will most likely, prove to be more difficult than in previous years,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In the next few years, local governments in the Nordic countries will face major &quot;demographic changes&quot;, it said, referring to &quot;a growing proportion of elderly and school children&quot;, which S&amp;P said will &quot;require increased investments and put significant pressure on operating expenditures.&quot;</p>
<p>The ability to cope with these pressures differs by country, in part because of the respective central governments' financial positions, which affect transfers.</p>
<p>Finland saw some changes to its system already in 1993 and local governments have been affected by reduced transfer payments from the central government since, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Unlike most other OECD countries, Finland has only one level of sub-national government, the rating institute noted.</p>
<p>&quot;The broader service areas for Finnish local governments should not imply a lower credit quality than for its neighbouring countries,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Finnish municipalities have more flexible sources of revenue than local governments in other Nordic countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Finland exhibits the highest flexibility, with several sources of tax income and no central government restrictions,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Unfunded pension liabilities imply a burden on local government throughout the world, it said, adding, however, that the Finnish funding system was different.</p>
<p>&quot;Finland differs from other countries. Here a special fund covers the future pension peak expected in the beginning of the next decade. The fund will continue to be built up by 2009, whereafter it will start being used for pension payments,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Finland will hold local government elections on October 20.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom  +358 - 0 - 680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
