<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794576" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Former PM Khaleda wants early poll in Bangladesh.</title>
<headline>Former PM Khaleda wants early poll in Bangladesh.</headline>
<byline>Syed Ahmeduzzaman</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangladesh opposition leader Begum Khaleda Zia on Tuesday said she would launch a movement to agitate for mid-term polls to end what she called the current government's pattern of misrule.</p>
<p>&quot;The people no longer want the government to fulfil it's five year-term. It may be necessary to call mid-term elections,&quot; she told members of the Overseas Correspondent Association of Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Khaleda said the country's economic condition had worsened and law and order deteriorated under the government of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>
<p>Khaleda's Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) lost to Hasina's Awami League in June 1996 general elections supervised by a neutral caretaker government.</p>
<p>She said unemployment was rife, inflation soaring, exports were falling and capital markets in shambles.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks are faced with a chronic liquidity crisis. Domestic entrepreneurs are starving from a credit crunch,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The government has said it was determined to raise the country's economic growth to an average of seven percent annually over the next five years. A draft five-year government plan (1997-2002) aims to spur employment and reduce the number of Bangladeshis below the poverty line to 30 percent from 45 percent now.</p>
<p>&quot;We will force an early election through a movement. This government has failed to run the country,&quot; Khaleda said.</p>
<p>She said nearly 200 members of her party were killed by the &quot;goons of the ruling party&quot; and thousands more languished in prison on false charges. The government has denied such accusations.</p>
<p>&quot;We are discussing with other political parties for a united movement against the government,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Awami League has 178 of the parliament's 330 seats while the BNP holds 113. Former president Hossain Mohammad Ershad's Jatiya Party has 33, and the Islamic fundamentalist Jamaat-e-Islami occupies three.</p>
<p>Khaleda is seeking an alliance with Jamaat and other small Islamic and right-wing parties that split the remaining seats.</p>
<p>&quot;We wanted to cooperate with the government. But how could we do that? It (the government) is harassing our party workers. The government must correct itself immediately,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;(But) we are helping the government by not taking any harsh actions like frequent strikes as yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Khaleda also blasted the government's relations with neighbouring India, particularly India's desire for transit rights through Bangladesh to more easily reach its seven remote northeastern states.</p>
<p>&quot;This will have serious implications on our national security,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Bangladesh's opposition parties say India actually wants the ability to transport troops and arms to suppress the &quot;freedom struggle&quot; in those states, where a number of insurgent groups seek autonomy.</p>
<p>But she also accused India of &quot;sheltering Shanti Bahini insurgents that carry out barbarous attacks on our people from across the border,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The tribal rebels in Bangladesh's southeastern Chittagong Hill Tracts area, called Shanti Bahini (peace force), have been fighting a decades-old bush war for autonomy for their rugged 5,500 sq-mile (14,200 sq-km) region.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
