<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79468" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: P&amp;O up on buy notes, Belgian ferry firm demise.</title>
<headline>P&amp;O up on buy notes, Belgian ferry firm demise.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in British shipping group Peninsular &amp; Oriental Steam Navigation Co. Plc strengthened on Thursday, bolstered by the recent collapse of a Belgian ferry company and a buy note from BZW, dealers said.</p>
<p>P&amp;O shares set a year's high of 616p but slipped back to trade at 602-1/2p in mid-afternoon trade, up 7-1/2p on the day. The overall market was slightly lower.</p>
<p>&quot;The share has been squeezed today. There have been very good press comments on its container merger with Nedlloyd, a buy note from BZW, a buy note yesterday from Panmure and the Belgian ferry company story. It all helps,&quot; one marketmaker said.  </p>
<p>The Belgian government said last week it would wind up the operations of loss-making, state-owned Channel ferry operator RTM/RMT, a move analysts said was evidence of a hoped-for rationalisation in the industry.</p>
<p>Panmure Gordon issued a buy note on P&amp;O on Wednesday, citing hopes for the container business merger with Nedlloyd and the prospect of further streamlining in the ferry industry.</p>
<p>P&amp;O shares surged earlier this month after it announced the merger of its container business with Dutch partner Nedlloyd. Analysts said the merger would lift a heavy financial burden from P&amp;O's balance sheet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
