<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794976" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: N.Korea won't deal with Seoul til poll - US lawmaker.</title>
<headline>N.Korea won't deal with Seoul til poll - US lawmaker.</headline>
<byline>Paul Eckert</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Korea is unwilling to deal with South Korea until the latter elects a new president at the end of this year, members of a U.S. congressional delegation said on Tuesday after a visit to the isolated communist state.</p>
<p>&quot;They absolutely want nothing to do with the present leadership,&quot; said Porter Goss, chairman of the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not prepared to deal with South Korea until after elections (in December),&quot; Goss told a news conference in Tokyo.</p>
<p>He said Pyongyang's unwillingness to engage Seoul, which is a key goal of U.S. efforts to negotiate a formal peace treaty on the Korean peninsula, stems from its anger at South Korean President Kim Young-sam's refusal to mourn the death of North Korean strongman Kim Il-sung three years ago.</p>
<p>The South Korean president, whose five-year term ends in February and who is constitutionally barred from seeking a second term, has since been a daily target of abuse from North Korean official media and propaganda organs.</p>
<p>The seven members of the U.S. congressional intelligence committee said a three-day visit to Pyongyang left them disappointed at North Korea's unwillingness to let outsiders assess the depth of its food crisis or monitor distribution of food aid.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite repeated requests by congressional delegation members, the delegation was unable to travel to famine-stricken areas where it had hoped to determine the extent of the problem and investigate the system used for distributing food aid,&quot; the bipartisan delegation said in a statement.</p>
<p>North Korea's secretiveness, which food relief agencies have said is impeding fund-raising efforts, stems from intense shame in a proud country, committee member Nancy Pelosi said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very new stage for the North Korean government. This is a shame that the North Korean government cannot feed its people,&quot; Pelosi said.</p>
<p>North Korea's explanation for its plight -- floods, drought and U.S. trade sanctions -- sounded like &quot;excuses more than reasons&quot;, she added.</p>
<p>The hard-line Stalinist country is deeply suspicious of U.S. motives in extending food aid and stands firm in its refusal to abandon the highly centralised farm policies experts say have contributed to the famine, delegation members said.</p>
<p>&quot;They were adamant in representations to us that they are not going to retreat from what they call a 'cooperative system of agriculture',&quot; Goss said.</p>
<p>The delegation members underlined U.S. concerns on missile proliferation and nuclear issues during &quot;brutally frank&quot; talks with their North Korean hosts, headed by Foreign Ministry First Vice-Minister Kang Sok-ju, Goss said.</p>
<p>The delegation aimed to stress to North Koreans the bipartisan support in Congress for the U.S. policy of bringing Pyongyang to the negotiating table and would report to President Bill Clinton and key congressional leaders, he said.</p>
<p>Preparatory talks, intended to settle procedural issues for formal talks on a permanent peace arrangement to replace the fraying armistice that ended the 1950-53 Korean War, were held in New York last week but ended without final agreement.</p>
<p>The talks are to resume on September 15.</p>
<p>Pyongyang's negotiators have repeatedly raised the Stalinist regime's food needs during the preparatory discussions, which include the United States, China, North Korea and South Korea.</p>
<p>The United States has become a major donor to North Korea, providing $52 million in food aid through the World Food Programme so far in 1997 and a total of $60.4 million since 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
