<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794937" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Cambodia's exiled PM plans to return, says ally.</title>
<headline>Cambodia's exiled PM plans to return, says ally.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodia's ousted co-premier, Prince Norodom Ranariddh, plans to quit self-exile in Thailand and join his supporters in the jungles of northern Cambodia in his quest to regain power, a political ally said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Ranariddh's former finance minister, Sam Rainsy, said the deposed prince was negotiating with Thai authorities for safe passage across the border into opposition-controlled areas.</p>
<p>&quot;Immediately he is trying to go back to Cambodia in the regions not controlled by (co-premier) Hun Sen forces,&quot; Sam Rainsy, himself a self-exiled opposition leader, told Reuters in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as he can cross the border like other Cambodian leaders opposed to Hun Sen, there will be people inside Cambodia who will take care of those people,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Ranariddh fled Cambodia early last month just before he was ousted by Second Prime Minister Hun Sen in a bloody coup.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Ung Huot has since replaced Ranariddh as first prime minister. Ranariddh faces arrest if he returns home.</p>
<p>Sam Rainsy, who has now joined Ranariddh's royalist FUNCINPEC party in an anti-Hun Sen alliance, is in Australia to lobby Canberra to halt all government aid to his impoverished nation.</p>
<p>He is also meeting with expatriate Cambodians to lobby support for the Union of Cambodian Democrats, which includes FUNCINPEC and Sam Rainsy's own Khmer Nation Party.</p>
<p>&quot;I think any assistance provided to or through the Phnom Penh authorities must be suspended until the legal government is reinstated... and there are serious assurances that free and fair elections will be held as scheduled next May,&quot; Sam Rainsy said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a former finance minister, I can tell you how dependent any (Cambodian) administration is on international assistance, so Hun Sen cannot afford to avoid free and fair elections because this would mean suspension of all aid and he would just collapse,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Sam Rainsy is due to meet Australian Foreign Minister Alexander Downer and Immigration Minister Philip Ruddock in Canberra on Wednesday, the Cambodian politician's entourage said.</p>
<p>Sam Rainsy said that, like Ranariddh, he also might return soon to Cambodia's northern and western provinces, as a first step toward fighting a general election scheduled for May 1998.</p>
<p>But fresh polls could not be free and fair while Hun Sen remained in effective control, Sam Rainsy said, adding he was still hopeful the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) and Australia would work for a solution to the Cambodian crisis.</p>
<p>ASEAN appeared on Monday to back away from its support for Ranariddh, saying it had never called for his reinstatement. ASEAN has postponed Cambodia's entry as its 10th member.</p>
<p>Australia has cut military assistance, but not other aid.</p>
<p>Sam Rainsy said resistance to Hun Sen was strengthening and predicted turmoil if his rule continued. &quot;There are groups of opponents who are now getting themselves better organised all over the country,&quot; Sam Rainsy said.</p>
<p>Sam Rainsy served as Cambodian finance minister until 1995, when he quit FUNCINPEC and the government over his stand against official corruption. He has not returned to Cambodia since last March, citing fears for his safety.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
