<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="794930" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: NORWEST'S A$15 MLN FLOAT FOR TIMOR SEA EXPLORATION.</title>
<headline>NORWEST'S A$15 MLN FLOAT FOR TIMOR SEA EXPLORATION.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil and gas hopeful Norwest Energy NL launched a float on Tuesday to raise A$15 million to explore five prospects in the Timor Sea and Northern Territory.</p>
<p>Norwest said it would offer 75 million or 80 percent of its shares at 20 cents each and use the funds to spend A$13 million to drill five wells in its first two years and conduct a seismic survey.</p>
<p>Norwest chief executive Ivan Burgess told a media briefing that the offer was not underwritten, but that broker BZW Australia had offered to take up as much as A$7.5 million of the issue.  </p>
<p>Norwest is the operator and owns a third of the Timor Gap Zone of Cooperation (ZOCA) 96-16 production sharing contract, which is 25 km north-east of the huge Bayu-Undan gas condensate field and 10 km north-east of the Elang Kakatua and North Katatua oil fields.</p>
<p>&quot;At least 12 leads and prospects have been identified with at least one having potential to contain in excess of 100 million barrels of recoverable oil,&quot; it said in its prospectus.</p>
<p>Norwest also owns 10 percent of the nearby WA74-P permit, where drilling is due to start on the Schilling well in the Bonaparte Basin at the end of this month.  </p>
<p>Petroz NL is the operator and has half of the Schilling 1 well. The Schilling prospect has potential oil reserves of up to 50 million barrels of oil, Norwest said.</p>
<p>Norwest also has a 50 percent interest in the AC/P22 permit in the Ashmore Cartier region in the Timor Sea which contains the Puffin oil field.</p>
<p>The field, where a well has flowed 4,608 barrels per day on test, has potential to contain up to 50 million barrels of oil, it said.  </p>
<p>Norwest said it also had a 49 percent interest in the EP-75 area located onshore in the Northern Territory.</p>
<p>The Providence Hill prospect in the area has the potential to contain 80 million barrels of oil, it said.</p>
<p>The offer opens on August 14, closes on September 3 and is is expected to list soon after.</p>
<p>Chairman David Kennedy will retain a 20 percent shareholding in Norwest.</p>
<p>Burgess said a national broking firm had also offered to be the lead manager for the float.  </p>
<p>The prospectus has measured the net asset backing of the shares at 19 cents per share.</p>
<p>After adjusting for an independent valuation of the petroleum assets to be acquired, the net asset backing is seen in a range of 18 cents to 26 cents per share.</p>
<p>Any surplus cash generated by the company would applied to expanding Norwest's production base, rather than distributed as dividends.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim is to have production within the next two years to ensure the company keeps expanding,&quot; Burgess said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
