<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795055" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: INDONESIAN FIRM TO PUT UP 40 SATELLITE TV CHANNELS.</title>
<headline>INDONESIAN FIRM TO PUT UP 40 SATELLITE TV CHANNELS.</headline>
<byline>Raju Gopalakrishnan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's only pay television company is racing ahead with plans to put up its own satellite and will have 40 digital channels by the end of the year, officials said.</p>
<p>Peter Gontha, president director of PT Datakom Asia, told Reuters in an interview that the Indostar-1 satellite would be launched by Arianespace from Kourou, French Guiana, on October 10.</p>
<p>An earlier launch date of mid-August had to be postponed because of some minor technical problems but the satellite has now been shipped, he said.</p>
<p>By the end of the year, it would begin broadcasting 40 channels of Western and Indonesian movies, news, soaps and financial information, Gontha said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;All the channels will be digitally encrypted,&quot; he said, adding that the new satellite would be accessible to antenna dishes as little as one metre (3.3 feet) in diameter.</p>
<p>Currently, the skylines of Jakarta and other major Indonesian cities are crowded with huge dishes of at least 20 feet (3 metres) diameter to catch broadcasts from existing satellites.</p>
<p>Datakom's pay-TV platform, called Indovision, currently uses the Palapa-C1 satellite for its 19 channels, which include Turner Broadcasting's Cable News Network and TNT, five News Corp Ltd-owned STAR TV channels, British Broadcasting Corporation, Home Box Office, Discovery and ESPN.</p>
<p>By the end of August six Indonesian terrestrial channels would be added to the network, Gontha said.</p>
<p>All of these would shift to Indostar when it comes on line, and the additional channels would be filled by pay-per-view programmes, home shopping, financial news, educational programmes and his own music channel, he said.</p>
<p>Gontha, 49, is a jazz aficionado and runs his own jazz club in Jakarta.</p>
<p>Datakom is owned by some of Indonesia's most powerful businessmen -- President Suharto's second son Bambang Trihatmodjo controls one-third of its equity, Anthony Salim of the Salim Group controls 28.57 percent while Gontha owns 24.23 percent.</p>
<p>Other minority shareholders include Indonesian telecommunications firm PT Indonesian Satellite Corp (Indosat) with a five percent stake.</p>
<p>The company floated $260 million in guaranteed notes last month and the issue was oversubscribed, Gontha said. He said proceeds would be used to pay off existing loans, payments for the satellites and for working capital.</p>
<p>Datakom, he said, had been allotted slots to launch three more satellites by the year 2003. Gontha said he would order another satellite by the end of this year to be launched in 1999 with subsequent launches planned for 2001 and 2003.</p>
<p>He says Indovision could use up to 60 channels, and other space on the satellites could perhaps be leased.</p>
<p>Indovision's current subscriber base is only about 26,000 but Gontha said he expects demand to increase exponentially once the signals were accessible to low-cost small dishes.</p>
<p>&quot;Indonesia has 22 million TV homes now and a likely 38 million by the year 2000,&quot; he said. &quot;If we can get three percent of that market, I'll be happy.&quot;</p>
<p>Media analysts have said a listing of Datakom shares is being keenly anticipated by the market, but Gontha was coy on the subject.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously that's what we want to do,&quot; he said. &quot;We will do that once we fulfil all the requirements. Probably by late 1998.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
