<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795136" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASIAN EXOTICS - SING DOLLAR SLIDE SHAKES REGIONALS.</title>
<headline>ASIAN EXOTICS - SING DOLLAR SLIDE SHAKES REGIONALS.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southeast Asian currencies came under heavy pressure again on Tuesday as the Singapore dollar's sudden drop through a key support level triggered fresh buying of the U.S. dollar across the board, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Singapore dollar fell through the psychological 1.50 to the U.S. dollar level to hit a new three-year low of 1.5085 following comments by a Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS) official.</p>
<p>The official of the de facto central bank told reporters at an economic briefing that the Singapore dollar's level was appropriate to what was happening in the market.</p>
<p>She said the U.S. dollar had been rising in currency markets and the Singapore dollar had depreciated by about five percent against the U.S. unit since the start of 1997.</p>
<p>The Singapore dollar was quoted at 1.5070/90 to the U.S. dollar at 0415 GMT against 1.4850/70 before the comments.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/Sing is kind of stalling around 1.51 now. But if that goes, maybe we'll go to 1.53 eventually,&quot; a U.S. bank dealer said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the drop in the sturdy Singapore dollar had triggered selling of other Southeast Asian currencies as players increasingly grouped the region's economies together.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of it was due to the Singapore dollar. It's now all a knee-jerk reaction. The four major regional currencies are all moving in the same direction,&quot; the U.S. bank dealer said.</p>
<p>He said the market was still short of U.S. dollars and a lot of long-term players, portfolio managers and corporations were looking to hedge their exposure.</p>
<p>The lack of aggressive intervention by Southeast Asian central banks was also playing a part in keeping regional currencies depressed, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The central banks realise that intervening aggressively just gives the speculators a chance to buy cheap dollars. So they're letting demand and supply determine the correct levels,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Across the border, the Malaysian ringgit pulled back from an early 42-month low of 2.7930 to the dollar, but dealers said the currency remained vulnerable.</p>
<p>&quot;All the indicators are showing an overbought situation, but nobody is looking at the indicators. Everybody out there seems to be buying dollars,&quot; a European bank dealer in Singapore said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the dollar would face some resistance around 2.7950 but they did not rule out a rise above 2.80 for the first time since dollar/ringgit was officially floated in 1973.</p>
<p>&quot;We're staring at 2.80 now. And after that, I have no idea where it could go,&quot; the U.S. bank dealer said.</p>
<p>Spillover weakness from the ringgit and Singapore dollar pushed the Indonesian rupiah to an early low of 2,655, but it later recovered on dollar sales by Jakarta players.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the contagion effect again. The market is a bit nervous, with spreads tending to widen again. But volume was moderate,&quot; a foreign bank dealer in Jakarta said.</p>
<p>He said stop-loss limits were triggered after the rupiah fell through the 2,620 level.</p>
<p>The rupiah was at 2,638/43 at 0415 GMT against an opening of 2,610/20.</p>
<p>The Thai baht was also weak but activity was relatively subdued with the onshore market closed for a Thai holiday.</p>
<p>Singapore dealers said the baht was likely to trade between 31.10 and 31.75 to the dollar in offshore markets, with further weakness expected once Thai financial markets reopened on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that after the IMF (International Monetary Fund) package, the market is expecting the baht to depreciate to 35 eventually, because a weak Thai baht would be good for economic recovery,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>News that the IMF and other Asian donors had pledged to provide a $16 billion loan package to Thailand left the baht largely uninspired on Monday.</p>
<p>The Philippine peso weakened on heavy commercial demand for dollars, amid a shortage of the U.S. unit.</p>
<p>The peso was at 28.63/73 to the dollar at 0415 GMT against its previous close at 28.57. Manila traders said the central bank had offered to sell dollars at 28.65.</p>
<p>The Taiwan dollar recovered from its lows but remained weak at midday and dealers said it was soon likely to test the T$28.80 level, although the central bank was expected to moderate its decline.</p>
<p>They said the U.S. dollar's stronger stance against major currencies had triggered renewed buying of the U.S. unit from Taiwan importers.</p>
<p>-- Syed Azman in Kuala Lumpur (603-206 2323), Mantik Kusjanto in Jakarta (6221 384-6364), Lilian Karunungan in Manila (632-841-8937), Kevin Chen in Taipei (8862-508-0815) and Sonali Desai in Singapore (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
