<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795256" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Aug 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Aug 12.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-RAI</p>
<p>- Moslem Brotherhood says government asks for immediate talks without preconditions on Brotherhood's plans to boycott November parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>- Allenby Bridge opened for people entering and leaving West Bank, but not for those trying to get to Gaza.</p>
<p>AD-DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- Cabinet to discuss alterations to civil service regulations to extend periods of unpaid leave available to state employees.</p>
<p>- Hamas sounds warning of Palestinian infighting if Palestinian Authority cracks down on it.</p>
<p>- Shares on Amman stock exchange lost 67 million dinars ($94 million) in June.</p>
<p>AL-ARAB AL-YAWM</p>
<p>- Transport and Communications Minister Bassam al-Saket says state-owned Royal Jordanian airlines still has 41.4 million dinar deficit in 1997.</p>
<p>AL-ASWAQ</p>
<p>- Moslem Brotherhood members register to vote in parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>- Philadelphia Bank raises capital by 5.5 million dinars. Saudi Prince Waleed bin Talal takes one million shares worth 1.1 dinars each, Khalifah bin Abdul-Mohsen al-Seif takes another million.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- Japan's Grant Assistance for Grass Roots Projects has donated $2.1 million to Jordan in the past two years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
