<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795249" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan offers sale of electricity firm.</title>
<headline>Jordan offers sale of electricity firm.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan is offering foreign investors linked to a local partner up to 51 percent of Irbid Electricity Company (IDECO), the country's second largest electricity distribution firm, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The state-owned National Electric Power Company, which owns 55 percent of the publicly listed firm, has invited interested foreign and local investors to submit expressions of interest by September 15, 1997.</p>
<p>Officials at the National Electric Power Company, which is handling the transaction, said that they expected the sale to be completed by year-end. Financial proposals would be requested in October after shortlisting the firms, they said.</p>
<p>IDECO which has assets of 52 million dinars ($73 million) holds a concession to distribute electricity in nearly 30 percent of the country, covering Irbid, Ajloun, Jerash and Mefraq governates and an unutilised license to generate electricity.</p>
<p>The foreign investor must acquire the shares through a consortium with a local firm which would have a minimum 10 percent participation, they said.</p>
<p>IDECO's electricity supply rose 11.5 percent in 1996 to 642 kilowatts and sales turnover rose to $32 million from $26.8 million.</p>
<p>The firm has a private 11 percent private sector shareholding while 34 percent is owned by the municipalities</p>
<p>The government was looking primarily for a strategic partner in the power industry or a financial investor who could procure industry expertise, officials said.</p>
<p>-- Amman Newsroom 9626-623776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
