<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795202" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: SHENZHEN EXPRESS SEES GROWTH IN 2ND HALF.</title>
<headline>SHENZHEN EXPRESS SEES GROWTH IN 2ND HALF.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen Expressway Co Ltd said on Tuesday it expected an increase in operating income for the second half of the year in line with an expected growth in total highway traffic in Shenzhen.</p>
<p>&quot;The total highway traffic turnover in Shenzhen is expected to be 115 percent higher in the second half of the year than that of the first half,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Operating income of the company in the second half of the year is expected to increase along with the growth in traffic turnover,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Expressway also said it expected to obtain approval later in the year to increase toll rates on its highways.</p>
<p>The company, which operates three highways in Shenzhen, reported an interim profit of 86.69 million yuan on a turnover of 113.82 million yuan for six months to June 30.</p>
<p>The Chinese expressway developer and operator was listed in Hong Kong on March 12, 1997.</p>
<p>The company said traffic flow had grown on all three highways during the period under review.</p>
<p>It also said it had bought a 40 perncet stake in Wu Tung Ling Mountain Cable Way Co Ltd, which engages in the development and managment of the Wu Tung Ling Mountain Cable Way project whose income would derive from tourists.</p>
<p>The project is expected to start operation by June 1998 and will make a substantial contribution to the company, it said.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Expressway said it had negotiated for several potential highway projects in the east coastal region and would announce the purchase plans at an appropriate time.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
