<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795291" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: BUNDS CLIMB FURTHER AFTER REPO ANNOUNCEMENT.</title>
<headline>BUNDS CLIMB FURTHER AFTER REPO ANNOUNCEMENT.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bund futures added to Monday's solid gains in early trade as traders showed their relief that the Bundesbank had decided against signalling a change in monetary policy at the repo tender.</p>
<p>In a widely expected, but closely watched move, the central bank set a tender for 14-day repos at an unchanged fixed rate of 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>As of last week, speculation had been rife the Bundesbank might use the repo to tighten monetary policy. Such talk had died down by Monday, however, as the recently weak mark posted a comeback against the dollar.  </p>
<p>The Bundesbank move eased worries, at least for the moment, that interest rates are headed higher.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank will not start the rate hike process without broad-based support on the council. The dollar needs to climb over 1.90 marks to win over doves on the council,&quot; said Joerg Kraemer, economist at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>The dollar stood at 1.8621 in morning trade on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The DTB Bund future fluctuated after the announcement, but soon began to climb, trading up 26 basis points at 102.18 at 0819 GMT.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the market was further lifted by short-covering among speculators who had predicted a tightening of rates.</p>
<p>The gains, however, were most pronounced on the long-end of the curve with the short-end still seen burdened by worries that interest rates will climb in the not-too-distant future.</p>
<p>The spread between two- and 10-year maturities, for example, narrowed four basis points to 187 basis points.</p>
<p>Supporting the view the Bundesbank will keep a close eye on rates, the Federal Stastics office said inflation rose 1.9 percent year-on-year in July, its highest rate since June 1995.  </p>
<p>The month-on-month rise in the consumer price index was 0.5 percent, the highest since January 1997.</p>
<p>With the Bundesbank out of the way, the focus is clearly on the U.S. where a slew of data is due in the next few days which could cripple Treasuries.</p>
<p>U.S. unit labour costs and productivity data are due at 1400 GMT on Tuesday and retail sales and producer price data are due Wednesday at 1230 GMT on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The spread between Treasuries and Bunds stood at 78 basis points on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom + 49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
