<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795380" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada dollar opens flat on quiet overseas trading.</title>
<headline>Canada dollar opens flat on quiet overseas trading.</headline>
<text>
<p>FORECAST RANGE   1.3915/1.3950	   ASIAN CLOSE     1.3938</p>
<p>RESISTANCE 1.3855   SUPPORT 1.3405     HI 1.3945   LO  1.3922</p>
<p>CANADA OPEN  1.3925/30   HI 1.3945     EUROPE OPEN     1.3936</p>
<p>PREV CLOSE   1.3934/39   LO 1.3922     HI 1.3946   LO  1.3916</p>
<p>----------------------MARKET COMMENT-------------------------</p>
<p>* Canada's dollar opened flat at C$1.3925 (US$0.7181) in light trading on Wednesday after the currency was sidelined in overseas trading last night, traders said. * They said they expected the Canada unit to trade quietly in a range of C$1.3915 (US$0.7186) and C$1.3950 (US$0.7168) as it waits for direction from next week's economic data.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're stuck firmly in neutral right now. We might start moving if we get some more U.S. numbers,&quot; the trader added.</p>
<p>The U.S. reported that retail sales grew by 0.6 percent in July, matching market expectations of a 0.7 percent increase. U.S. producer prices, however, fell 0.1 percent in July, slightly below market expectations of a 0.1 percent rise.</p>
<p>Economists said the numbers should help to bolster the Canadian dollar. &quot;It takes some pressure away from the U.S. Federal Reserve to raise rates,&quot; so there's a little bit of selling pressure on the U.S. (dollar) and some buying of Canada (dollars),&quot; said Geoff Hall, economist with Tech Data.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is upward bias for the Canadian dollar today, so we're probably looking at something between C$1.3890 (US$0.7199) and C$1.3935 (US$0.7176),&quot; Hall said.</p>
<p>A stronger dollar would take some of the pressure of the Bank of Canada, which has resisted calls during the past month for another interest rate hike to bolster the flagging currency.</p>
<p>The bank last raised interest rates on June 26 in a fleeting effort to support the Canadian dollar.</p>
<p>In its Summer Review released on Tuesday, the bank said the currency could strengthen without a rate increase.  </p>
<p>&quot;Canada's strongly underlying economic fundamentals continue to support the currency market expectations that the Canadian dollar will appreciate over time,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>On the crosses, the Canada dollar climbed to 83.75 Japanese yen from 83.41 on Tuesday and dipped to 1.3293 marks from Tuesday's 1.3371 marks.</p>
<p>((Paul Simao, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8104)) (c) Reuters Limited 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
