<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795332" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Khatami submits cabinet list to Iran parliament.</title>
<headline>Khatami submits cabinet list to Iran parliament.</headline>
<byline>Steven Swindells</byline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's President Mohammad Khatami on Tuesday submitted his cabinet choices to the scrutiny of parliament in his first key test in office.</p>
<p>Parliamentary Speaker Ali Akbar Nateq-Nouri said the 270-member assembly would start debating Khatami's nominations -- read out in parliament -- next Tuesday.</p>
<p>Deputies will debate the proposed ministers' merits in three five-hour sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;As of next Tuesday morning the Majlis (parliament) will start discussing the cabinet,&quot; Nateq-Nouri told deputies. State radio broadcast the speech live from the national assembly.</p>
<p>Khatami's letter to parliament listed Kamal Kharrazi as his candidate for foreign affairs minister, navy chief Rear-Admiral Ali Shamkhani as defence minister, Qorbanali Dorri Najafabadi at intelligence, Abdollah Nouri at interior and Ataollah Mohajerani as minister of culture and Islamic guidance.</p>
<p>Hossein Namazi was chosen for the economy and finance portfolio and Bijan Namdar Zanganeh for the oil ministry, Khatami's letter said.</p>
<p>Three of the 22 ministers proposed retained portfolios they held under former president Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani. They are Issa Kalantari at agriculture, Hossein Kamali at labour and social affairs and Justice Minister Esmail Shoushtari.</p>
<p>Two ministers proposed in the new cabinet were also carried over from Rafsanjani's cabinet, but were given new portfolios -- new oil minister Zanganeh and Gholamreza Shafei, who switched to the industry portfolio from cooperatives.</p>
<p>Khatami's ability to put in place a cabinet of his own choosing is seen as vital to the reforming scope and tone of his four-year administration.</p>
<p>Analysts said the nomination of conservative cleric and parliament deputy Qorbanali Dorri Najafabadi to the key post of intelligence (internal security) minister was an important concession by the moderate president to his conservative opponents.</p>
<p>Kharrazi, formerly in charge of war propaganda during the 1980-88 Iran-Iraq War, is ambassador to the United Nations. If confirmed, he would replace veteran foreign minister Ali Akbar Velayati, voice of the Islamic republic in world capitals since December 1981.</p>
<p>Mohajerani, nominated as culture and Islamic guidance minister, is strongly opposed by conservatives. He has advocated more liberal cultural policies and stirred controversy in 1990 when he urged direct talks with the United States.</p>
<p>Khatami has already re-appointed Hassan Habibi as first vice-president. He is a non-controversial figure who held the same position under Rafsanjani.</p>
<p>Despite speculation after Khatami's landslide election victory in May, achieved in part through wide support from women, his cabinet list included no women.</p>
<p>There has been no confirmation of newspaper reports that Masoumeh Ebtekar, a 36-year-old U.S.-educated professor at Tehran university, would be appointed a vice-president.</p>
<p>She would be the first woman to achieve cabinet status since the 1979 revolution. Vice-presidential and advisory posts do not need to be endorsed by parliament.</p>
<p>Khatami was sworn in as president on August 4, sealing a huge political victory against Nateq-Nouri.</p>
<p>The 54-year-old moderate Shi'ite cleric was supported by the vast majority of Iran's young, women and middle class voters on a platform of more social and economic freedoms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
