<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795317" id="root" date="1997-08-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: ASSIDOMAN SAYS SEES STRONGER FORESTRY TRENDS '97.</title>
<headline>ASSIDOMAN SAYS SEES STRONGER FORESTRY TRENDS '97.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish forestry group AssiDoman on Tuesday said it expected a continued strengthening of trends in the forestry industry in 1997.</p>
<p>It posted a profit after financial items of 859 million crowns ($107.2 million) which was somewhat higher than market expectations of a profit of 819 million crowns.  </p>
<p>&quot;A continued weak improvement in the European economy, including some increase in order bookings for the manufacturing industry, provides scope for a continued strengthening of the business climate for the forest products industry in 1997,&quot; AssiDoman said in a statement.</p>
<p>However, it added that there was some uncertainty.</p>
<p>&quot;Activity in the European construction industry remained low, however, and this combined with weak consumer demand leads to a degree of uncertainty,&quot; AssiDoman said.</p>
<p>It said the positive market development for paper and cartonboard which started in the beginning of the year has continued, especially kraftliner and cartonboard.</p>
<p>Demand for corrugated board, packaging paper and barrier-coated paper, however, also continued to rise.</p>
<p>It said demand for sawn timber remained positive. There was a weak upturn for the pulp market.</p>
<p>&quot;The uncertainty in the pulp market continued to some extent although there are signs of a weak upward trend,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The group posted a four percent rise in sales to 10.14 billion crowns. For its packaging division, its largest business area, sales edged up five percent to 4.16 billion crowns but operating profit plummeted 47 percent to 209 million crowns.</p>
<p>It said demand for packaging continued to be favourable although price pressure continued.</p>
<p>For its forest and timber operations, turnover was largely flat at 2.99 billion crowns compared to 2.96 billion crowns while operating profit jumped 25 percent to 703 million crowns.</p>
<p>Increased prices, which were 21 percent up on those in the same 1996 period, were behind the increase although deliveries were flat but at high levels, AssiDoman said.</p>
<p>($ = 8.015 Swedish Crowns)</p>
<p>-- Abigail Schmelz, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
