<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79546" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Palestinians urge Arab states to isolate Israel.</title>
<headline>Palestinians urge Arab states to isolate Israel.</headline>
<byline>Mona Eltahawy</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Palestinian Authority said on Thursday that Israel had declared war on Palestinians after clashes broke out in Palestinian self-rule areas in the West Bank and Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>The Palestinian delegate to the Arab League warned of a cycle of violence if hardline Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netnayahu did not fulfil peace pledges between Israel and the Arabs.</p>
<p>&quot;Netanyahu and the Israeli government speak about peace while practicing a state of war. The situation is very dangerous,&quot; Mohamed Sobeih told a news conference after an Arab League meeting called to discuss Israel's decision to open a tunnel in Jerusalem close to the Aqsa mosque, Islam's third holiest site.</p>
<p>Clashes broke out on Wednesday in the West Bank and Gaza with Palestinian police and Israeli soldiers exchanging gunfire while Palestinians rained stones on the Israeli troops.</p>
<p>The death toll rose to 33 Palestinians killed by Israeli troops -- 28 shot on Thursday -- and five Israelis killed by Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;Not one Palestinian or Arab will accept a peace that is at the expense of Palestinian and Arab land or rights. Mr Netanyahu must abide by the letter and the spirit of all signed agreements and guarantees to Palestinians,&quot; Sobeih said.</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise Netanyahu will not succeed and will drag Israel into a whirlpool of violence and extremism. This Israeli terrorism will reflect badly all over the world,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Sobeih also said that the meeting &quot;saluted the martyrs of this new and blessed intifada in which all Palestinians and their leaders are participating.&quot;</p>
<p>Arab League Secretary General Esmat Abdel-Meguid said he would join U.N. General Assembly meetings on Monday to &quot;highlight the elements dangerous to the peace process&quot; and present the findings of the one-day meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The peace process is in more danger than you can imagine because of Israel's action, which is completely unacceptable,&quot; Abdel-Meguid said. &quot;We place responsibility for this on Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>Sobeih urged Arab states at the start of the meeting to turn their backs on Israel in retaliation for its conduct.</p>
<p>&quot;We implore you to provide help and work by every means to isolate Israel, punish it and show up its aggression until it refrains from this perverse aggressive behaviour,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Palestinian delegate said it was time for Arab states to carry out the threat they made at the June Arab summit to reconsider deals with Israel if Netanyahu refused to abide by peace deals signed by his predecessor. Netanyahu came to power on a platform opposed to giving back Arab land.</p>
<p>&quot;The time has come to put into effect the resolutions of the last Arab summit, to prove to Israel and the world that we are worthy to defend our national rights,&quot; Sobeih said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Palestinian people will continue to defend Jerusalem and our legitimate national rights, with everything they possess and whatever sacrifices it costs.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
