<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795541" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr ends lower in US on German rate, EMU jitters.</title>
<headline>Dlr ends lower in US on German rate, EMU jitters.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar closed sharply lower, hurt by expectations of higher German interest rates and a report suggesting Europe's single currency might be postponed, dealers said.</p>
<p>Welcome U.S. economic news, showing low inflation and tame retail sales, briefly provided support for the dollar. But after popping higher, the greenback continued its slide while U.S. stocks and bonds reversed early gains.</p>
<p>The dollar slump started overnight. The Bundesbank warned of rising consumer prices and said it would gear monetary policy towards keeping inflation under control.  </p>
<p>&quot;It seems the talk in Germany is the Bundesbank will raise rates, it's just a matter of timing,&quot; said Jeffrey Yu, a senior dealer at Sanwa Bank Ltd in New York.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at 1.8345/55 marks, down from 1.8440/50 at the open. A firm mark/yen slowed dollar/yen, which trailed dollar/mark lower, ending at 115.70/75, versus 116.18/23.</p>
<p>Sterling also fell sharply, dipping below 2.89 marks after Britain's Evening Standard Newspaper carried an editorial contending Germany and France may have offered to delay the euro's planned 1999 debut by one year if Britain would agree to participate.  </p>
<p>The U.K. government said it &quot;won't dignify&quot; the story with a quote. But the dollar eventually fell more than three pfennigs, dipping under 1.83 marks.</p>
<p>The Standard reinforced remarks by Edmund Stoiber, premier of the German state of Bavaria, who according to Dutch newspaper Algemeen Dagblad talked of a plan to delay European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) until 2001.</p>
<p>&quot;Now there is some noise coming out of the financial markets that a lot of Germans do oppose EMU and those forces are gaining some momenturm. A lot of politicians are backing down on the on-time EMU,&quot; Yu said.  </p>
<p>Both Germany and France are struggling with sluggish economies and high unemployment, making the tough budget cuts required to qualify for EMU politically unpopular.</p>
<p>The dollar came under renewed selling pressure after the U.S. data, setting session lows when U.S. assets reversed big early gains, starting a series of large swings in U.S. financial markets on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar actually looked like it was leading the stock and bond markets down,&quot; said Ben Strauss, a vice president at Bank Julius Baer and Co.  </p>
<p>The government reported that U.S. producer prices fell 0.1 percent in July, the seventh consecutive decline, and said July retail sales increased 0.6 percent. Both numbers were weaker than Wall Street forecasts.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials ended with a 33 loss, at 7928. The bond market reclaimed some lost ground but closed well below highs set during its early surge of more than one point.</p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar fell to 1.5110/20 Swiss francs, from 1.5170/80 and to Canadian $1.3921/26 from C$1.3925/30.</p>
<p>The pound rose to $1.5832/42 from $1.5745/55 and the Australian dollar rose to $0.7444/49 from $0.7425/30.</p>
<p>((--Alden Bentley, 212 859 1667))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
