<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795523" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. consumer group takes aim at check cards.</title>
<headline>U.S. consumer group takes aim at check cards.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Consumers Union, a non-profit group which publishes Consumer Reports, said Wednesday the Visa U.S.A. card group's newly-lowered limitation on liability for lost or stolen debit cards does not go far enough.</p>
<p>Earlier Wednesday, the card group Visa U.S.A. said holders of U.S. credit and check cards would be subject to zero liability if loss, theft or unauthorized use of cards was reported within two business days of discovery. After two days, consumers would have a maximum liability of $50.</p>
<p>On July 30, MasterCard International, a rival card group, said its U.S. member banks voted to cap liability for unauthorized use of U.S. debit cards at $50. A MasterCard spokesman said Wednesday liability for consumers is zero if loss or theft is reported in 24 hours of discovery. He said as a practical matter most card losses or theft are reported within 24 hours of discovery.</p>
<p>Consumers Union said in a statement responding to Visa's announcement that despite the lower maximum liabilities, consumers will face delays when trying to recover money.</p>
<p>&quot;Unlike a credit card, a loss with an unsecure debit card is instantly drained from your checking account,&quot; Gail Hillebrand, senior staff attorney for the Consumer Union's San Francisco office said in a statement. &quot;Consumers may find themselves without a penny in their account and may face enormous bounced-check penalties as a result of theft, fraud, or error.&quot;</p>
<p>Debit cards, also known as check cards, access funds in checking or other deposit account. Consumers Union said the core common credit card allows holders to review charges and withhold payments for disputed amounts.</p>
<p>Speaking in an earlier conference call with reporters, Carl Pascarella, president and chief executive of Visa U.S.A., said banks have been &quot;very very pro-active&quot; in trying to curb fraud. He said provisional lines of credit will be extended within five business days of notfication of lost funds due to unauthorized trnsactions, and many banks waive fees that result from theft. Overall, he said the level of fraud is &quot;minuscule,&quot; amounting to less than one tenth of one percent of card volume.</p>
<p>Consumers Union in its release suggested that bank customers using check cards request those with PIN number security protection.</p>
<p>The Visa card liability limiations apply to both check and credit cards and also to fraud involving use of credit cards in Internet transactions.</p>
<p>((--Cal Mankowski/New York Newsdesk/212 859 1732))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150108">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
