<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795759" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MIDCOM and Phoenix agree to merge.</title>
<headline>MIDCOM and Phoenix agree to merge.</headline>
<dateline>SOUTHFIELD, Mich. 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>MIDCOM Communications Inc and Phoenix Network Inc said Wednesday they have signed a definitive agreement to merge the two companies, combining MIDCOM's telecommunications services with Phoenix's long distance telephone services.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the proposed agreement, MIDCOM will acquire all outstanding shares of Phoenix common stock for 9.1 million shares of MIDCOM common stock. The merger requires approvals of the shareholders of both companies, government regulators and that MIDCOM raise at least $20.0 million in financing prior to closing.</p>
<p>The transaction is expected to close by year-end.  </p>
<p>&quot;We believe this merger will create a number of synergies which should result in significant savings and thereby enable us to reach profitability earlier than previously projected,&quot; said MIDCOM President William Oberlin.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect this merger to be accretive to earnings in both the short and long term. The addition of Phoenix Network's minutes will result in lower unit costs on our network and provide a broader base support for our overhead, as well as a larger pool of customers to cross-sell,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Phoenix Network currently has long distance switches located in Minneapolis, Colorado Springs and Phoenix. MIDCOM's current network includes local/long distance switching systems located in Seattle, Los Angeles, Dallas, Chicago, New York and Atlanta.</p>
<p>Separately, Phoenix also said Wednesday that it has agreed to purchase Trans National Communications (TNC), which provides long distance affinity marketing programs with $22.2 million in revenue for the six months ended June 30, 1997. The TNC acquisition is subject to MIDCOM's due diligence.</p>
<p>The merger agreement provides that, if the TNC acquisition is completed, MIDCOM will provide about 1.5 million additional shares of its common stock to Phoenix as well as assume about $15.7 million of debt.  In addition, Wallace Hammond and Phoenix board member, Charles McGettigan, will be appointed to MIDCOM's board of directors. Hammond will also join MIDCOM's management.</p>
<p>The merger of MIDCOM and Phoenix should be accounted for as a pooling of interests, while the Phoenix acquisition of TNC will be accounted for as a purchase.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOUTHFIELD, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
