<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795858" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: ATHLETICS-OTTEY BEATS WORLD CHAMPION JONES.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-OTTEY BEATS WORLD CHAMPION JONES.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marion Jones was warned that she has a tough fight on her hands to remain the new queen of sprinting when she was beaten by veteran Merlene Ottey over 100 metres at the Zurich grand prix on Wednesday, the richest meeting in athletics.</p>
<p>The American world champion failed to match Ottey's strong finish and had to settle for second, one hundreth of a second behind the 37-year-old Ottey who won in 10.96. Olympic champion Gail Devers took third in 11.06.</p>
<p>Former college basketball player Jones was heralded as the women's sprint star of the future after her victory in the 100 metres final at this month's world championships in Athens when Ottey finished seventh.</p>
<p>But the 21-year-old American will have to win races lsuch as this one before she can claim to dominate the world of women's sprinting.</p>
<p>The race was the highlight of the early part of the meeting which brought together 25 world champions from Athens.</p>
<p>Double Olympic champion Michael Johnson, who retained his 400 metres world title in Athens despite a season of injuries, had to work hard to win the 400 metres in 44.31.</p>
<p>After cruising through the first 200 metres, Johnson stepped up a gear in the final bend but was pushed all the way down the home straight by compatriot Tyree Washington and Uganda's Davis Kamoga.</p>
<p>Washington took second in 44.38 with Kamoga third in 44.43. Although the time was below his best for the season, the fans at the end of the straight greeted Johnson like a hero, chanting his name like a soccer crowd.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a close race and I'm happy I was able to win,&quot; Johnson said. &quot;My objective now is to win races. I was injured for a long time so I want to compete until the end of the season.&quot;</p>
<p>American world and Olympic champion Allen Johnson enhanced his position as the leading high hurdler in the world with victory in 13.13 seconds against a headwind.</p>
<p>American Mark Crear and Britain's Tony Jarrett took second and third in 13.14 and 13.21 respectively while Britain's world record holder Colin Jackson had to settle for fourth in 13.30.</p>
<p>Johnson still has the world record in his sights in the lucrative meetings around Europe in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't run as well as I could. I hit many hurdles,&quot; he said. &quot;But it's still a fast time. I have still got four races in Europe and I'm still motivated to break the world record.&quot;</p>
<p>In the women's 800 metres Mozambique's Maria Mutola gained some consolation for her defeat by Ana Fidelia Quirot at the world championships when she beat the Cuban in a close sprint finish.</p>
<p>Mutola, who finished third in Athens behind gold medallist Quirot, showed more power in the last 20 metres to win in one minute 56.36 seconds. Quirot was second in 1:56.47.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
