<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="795944" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - LATVIA - AUGUST 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - LATVIA - AUGUST 13.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Wednesday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- President Ulmanis opened the first meeting of the new cabinet which lasted 5 hours. Prime Minister Guntars Krasts said he hopes this government will be the last one before the next parliamentary election.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- Some 150 people protested near the building of the Riga city council against growing public utility tariffs.</p>
<p>- The cabinet's committee has decided to put off by one week the consideration of the  memorandum the Latvian government will send to the European Commission.</p>
<p>BIZNES &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- The Riga city council has decided to organise another auction to sell the asphalt plant bought by the previous council.</p>
<p>- A new exhibition hall will be opened in September in the premises of Alfa, a former electronics plant.</p>
<p>DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- The ministry of finance has announced that on August 14 and 15 it will pay back the 4 billion yen eurobond it issued in 1995.</p>
<p>- A record number of ships, 369, entered the Port of Riga in July. In May, 342 vessels visited the port.</p>
<p>-- Riga newsroom +371 721 52 40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
