<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796059" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICAN STOCK MARKET CLOSING REPORT.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICAN STOCK MARKET CLOSING REPORT.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African shares got a late boost from U.S. data that appeared to ease inflation fears across the Atlantic, but stocks still ended down as diamond giant De Beers took a hammering on reaction to its half-year results.</p>
<p>Local shares had traded under a cloud throughout the day as the market nervously eyed Wall Street to see if the current downwards trend in New York was set to continue.</p>
<p>But lower-than-expected growth in July retail sales and the seventh straight month of lower producer prices saw a U.S. stocks rally that carried into other financial markets.</p>
<p>&quot;We have really been riding on the back of Wall Street all day,&quot; said James Scott, equity marketing manager at Societe Generale Frankel Pollak.</p>
<p>South African shares usually trade on their own merits, but have followed new York closely all week in the absence of any significant local factors, despite the publication of favourable producer price inflation figures on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But dealers said, though the data boosted hopes for an interest rate cut, the move was already well-factored into the market and was providing support rather than any spur for major gains.</p>
<p>Instead, local sentiment took a knock from a hammering in bellwether share De Beers as traders bailed out of the diamond giant in the wake of disappointing half year results.</p>
<p>The share ended down 850 cents to 154.50 rand in trade worth 122 million rand and the fall-out knocked 350 cents off sister firm Anglo American which ended at 264.50 rand in business worth 28 million rand.</p>
<p>Overall dealers said the day was modestly busy as a hectic afternoon session followed on the back of a tepid morning's trade. The total value of shares traded hit 805 million rands and the day saw 163 counters rise as 210 fell.  </p>
<p>Elsewhere in the market a bookover deal involving 6.9 million shares by stockbrokers Martindale Stacey du Toit swelled volumes in stores firm Housewares Group Ltd to make it the busiest stock of the day.</p>
<p>Martindale Stacey said the deal was worth around seven million rand, but did not elaborate further. The firm ended up 14 cents at 106 cents.</p>
<p>In the gold sector shares rallied, but ended off their highs as the bullion prices zig-zagged on international markets between $326 and $328 dollars an ounce.</p>
<p>The golds index added 9.1 points to 1,026.1 as Vaal Reefs put on 175 cents to 236.75 rand and Kloof added 10 cents to 26.40 rand.</p>
<p>In the futures market early selling was replaced by a late rally and the contracts moved ahead. The September all-share contract was last at 6,660/68 from 6,759 as the industrials contract was at 8,630/40 from 8,696. The golds contract was at 745/53 from 726.</p>
<p>-- Paul Harris, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
<p>e-mail: johannesburg.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
