<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796354" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: INTERVIEW-BRAZIL CENBANK FACES RACE AGAINST CLOCK.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-BRAZIL CENBANK FACES RACE AGAINST CLOCK.</headline>
<byline>John Miller</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Central Bank chief Gustavo Franco has the tools to support Brazil's strong currency for now, but his bid to avoid a steep devaluation down the road is a race against time, a former finance minister said.</p>
<p>Strong dollar flows and record high hard currency reserves give Franco the ammunition to maintain a strong Brazilian real, a policy that has become his trademark, Mailson da Nobrega told Reuters in an interview Tuesday.</p>
<p>But Nobrega said that without reform of the state and a restructuring of the private sector -- both of which are out of Franco's hands -- the policy is unsustainable.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a bet on the process of reform and restructuring,&quot; said Nobrega, who served under former President Jose Sarney (1988-89).</p>
<p>&quot;The question is time. Do we have enough time to wait for the completion of the reform process? There is no clear answer to that question,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Franco, whose nomination as Central Bank president was approved on Tuesday, was expected to officially take over on August 20.</p>
<p>His biggest challenge, according to Nobrega, will be to maintain stability of the currency amid growing pressure to relax from Brazil's export community and some economists who say the real is overvalued by about 25 percent against the dollar.</p>
<p>Franco's success will largely depend on Congressional approval over the next few years of sweeping constitutional reforms and growing efficiency of Brazil's private sector, Nobrega said.</p>
<p>Social security and administrative reform are essential to cut the federal government's gaping budget deficit. A leaner, meaner private sector that can compete globally will also help turn around the nation's burgeoning trade deficit, he said.</p>
<p>The trade gap is the leading cause of Brazil's worrying current account balance of payments deficit, which is expected to hit about $35 billion, or 4.5 percent of gross domestic product in 1997.</p>
<p>Another challenge for Franco is to hold on to the autonomy the Central Bank gained under the leadership of outgoing President Gustavo Loyola.</p>
<p>Nobrega noted that among Loyola's achievements was his intervention in several large, ailing retail banks whose owners or shareholders had close ties to President Fernando Henrique Cardoso. In the past, Nobrega said, such ties could usually fend off Central Bank involvement no matter how poorly managed the bank was.</p>
<p>&quot;The Brazilian Central Bank has become a de facto independent Central Bank. They have enjoyed freedom to act as they want, although they have to consult with the president,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nobrega said Franco would inherit a great deal of independence and on matters of defending the currency, he would probably have the ultimate say over Finance Minister Pedro Malan.</p>
<p>((-- Sao Paulo newsroom, 5511-248-5414))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
