<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796380" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: INTERVIEW-REPSOL EXPANSION FOLLOWS HISTORY.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-REPSOL EXPANSION FOLLOWS HISTORY.</headline>
<byline>Tom Ashby</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-08-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Just as the conquistadors plundered the New World 400 years ago to fund expansion at home, so now are many Spanish companies returning to former colonies to kick-start their balance sheets pulled down by Europe's sluggish growth.</p>
<p>Repsol, the privatised Spanish oil company, is evolving into one of the biggest oil companies of the region, expanding aggressively into gas, electricity and all stages of the oil business, from exploration and production to refining and marketing.  </p>
<p>The company's expansion has coincided with a liberal economic wave sweeping the continent, offering up a multitude of investment opportunities.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not just a question of what we want to do, but what is possible to do,&quot; said Salvador Castella, Repsol's representative in Venezuela. &quot;If you look at the legal situation just two years ago, the change has been dramatic.&quot;</p>
<p>But for a company with weak growth in its home market and pitifully low oil reserves, its spending spree in the new world may be an unconventional bid for survival in a world of lean, mean multinationals.  </p>
<p>&quot;The reason Repsol has been so aggressive in Venezuela and other countries is precisely to balance out (the reserves deficit),&quot; Castella added</p>
<p>Since July 1996, the company has ploughed about $2 billion into the continent and is showing no signs of slowing the pace of investment.</p>
<p>Through acquisitions and direct participation, Repsol has bought oil refineries and marketing networks in Argentina and Peru, gas distribution chains in Argentina, Mexico, Colombia and Brazil and is building a liquified natural gas plant in Trinidad.  </p>
<p>It has also won concessions to explore for oil and gas in Peru, Venezuela, Trinidad, Colombia and Bolivia.</p>
<p>&quot;In the past year, Repsol has probably invested more (in Latin America) than any other company,&quot; Castella said.</p>
<p>Repsol bid nearly double its nearest rival to secure a 20- year contract to produce oil from Venezuela's Mene Grande field. Although the oil does not technically belong to Repsol, this contract alone represents a 12.5 percent increase in the company's 807 million barrels of proven oil reserves at the end of 1996.  </p>
<p>In Mexico last month, the company beat off stiff competition for the Toluca and Saltillo gas distribution concessions and is expected to run for the Nuevo Laredo and Mexico City contracts too.</p>
<p>Mexico was Repsol's third gas conquest in six weeks, having snapped up controlling stakes in two Rio de Janeiro gas distributors in July and a Bogota gas distributor in June.</p>
<p>In February, Repsol upped its stake to a controlling 47.5 percent in Astra, one of Argentina's largest energy companies with stakes in oil production, refining and marketing and electricity generation. It said last year it expects to spend $2 billion in Argentina by 2000.</p>
<p>In Trinidad, Repsol has a 20 percent stake in a billion- dollar liquid natural gas plant which is due to come on line in 1999 and shares exploration acreage with Amoco and Elf.</p>
<p>The company plans to spend $230 million in Peru by 2001, following its 1996 purchase of a controlling stake in the country's largest refinery at La Pampilla. It also has gas supply and oil and gas exploration concessions in the country.</p>
<p>Last year, Gas Natural Latinoamerica -- a Repsol joint venture with Spain's Gas Natural -- was set up to manage Repsol's gas assets in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;In line with its policy to expand into other countries in the region, Gas Natural Latinoamerica is studying projects in Mexico, Puerto Rico, Colombia, Argentina, Uruguay and Brazil,&quot; Repsol said in its 1996 annual report.</p>
<p>((-- Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2611))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
