<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796443" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: SHANGRI-LA OPTIMISTIC ABOUT SECOND-HALF.</title>
<headline>SHANGRI-LA OPTIMISTIC ABOUT SECOND-HALF.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shangri-La Asia Ltd said on Wednesday it was optimistic about its prospects for the second half of 1997 and was considering expansion outside East Asia after the acquisition of hotel manager SLIM International Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;We look forward to the next half year optimistically,&quot; managing director Paul Bush told a news conference.</p>
<p>Shangri-La Asia reported a 6.3 percent decline in net profit for the first six months of the year to HK$470.95 million.</p>
<p>The hotel company said demand for rooms in Hong Kong had softened from May to August, except for the period straddling Hong Kong's July 1 return to Chinese rule.</p>
<p>But Bush said he expected occupancy growth in the high season from September to November.</p>
<p>The hotel market had been flat in the Chinese capital, Beijing, hurting company profits in the first half, but other areas of China had shown growth in occupancy rates, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;China can turn around very quickly and we certainly are still optimistic,&quot; Bush said. &quot;We're still building hotels.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the acquisition of SLIM International, a company which manages hotels and resorts principally owned by Shangri-La Asia and other members of the Kuok Group, would enhance the company's earnings and valuation as well as provide opportunities for global expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;With the injection of the management company... the dimensions are immediately widened to a global basis and the group will be able to consider the possibility of managing hotels outside the East Asian area,&quot; Bush said.</p>
<p>The group had not previously expanded outside the East Asian region because of high capital and operating costs, he said.</p>
<p>Shangri-La has agreed to buy 100 percent of SLIM International from the Kuok Group, its parent, for HK$1.2 billion in shares.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
