<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796469" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan scraps offer in turbulent air talks with US.</title>
<headline>Japan scraps offer in turbulent air talks with US.</headline>
<byline>Edwina Gibbs</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan, angry at what it sees as a tough line taken by the United States in recent air talks, has withdrawn a proposal for a more deregulated aviation market, a official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposal is dead. It has been killed,&quot; the official said, blaming U.S. insistence on an &quot;open skies&quot; policy for the withdrawal of the proposal.</p>
<p>Transport Minister Makoto Koga wrote a letter to U.S. Transportation Secretary Rodney Slater last month warning that Japan's proposal would be withdrawn if Washington maintained a hardline stance seen in July talks, the official said.</p>
<p>He added that the proposal had been effectively dropped after talks in Tokyo earlier this month, although it could be revived if Washington stopped calling for Japan to agree to open skies, a U.S.-led policy of an unrestricted market for international air freight and travel.</p>
<p>The Japanese proposal called for unlimited access between the two countries for UAL Corp's United Airlines , Northwest Airlines Corp , Japan Airlines Co and All Nippon Airways Co .</p>
<p>It also included an increase in routes for three U.S. carriers: AMR Corp's American Airlines, Continental Airlines and Delta Air Lines Co .</p>
<p>United, Northwest and Japan Airlines already have wide rights under the existing treaty, while other carriers face substantial restrictions on routes.</p>
<p>The Transport Ministry official said talks planned for August 27 to 29 in Washington would proceed.</p>
<p>&quot;They will go ahead, but on the basis that Japan's previous flexible proposal is no longer on the table.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The two nations have been striving to forge an interim air deal, setting September 31 as their deadline.</p>
<p>Washington has said that a prerequisite to any deal would be an agreement by Tokyo to open skies after the interim period is complete.</p>
<p>But Tokyo, long smarting from what it considers an unfair bilateral treaty with the U.S., says it wants equal opportunities for its carriers and that open skies would only lead to alliances dominated by U.S. airlines.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
