<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796456" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX EUROYEN, JGBS TRADE LISTLESSLY, TONE FIRM.</title>
<headline>SIMEX EUROYEN, JGBS TRADE LISTLESSLY, TONE FIRM.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Euroyen and Japanese government bond (JGB) futures were confined to tight ranges in featureless trade on Wednesday but dealers said the market continued to show a firm bias.</p>
<p>The lead March Euroyen contract stood at 99.21 at 1115 GMT after hovering in a two-tick band against an IMM close at 99.22.</p>
<p>Dealers said the contract looked supported around 99.20 while the recent contract high of 99.25 continued to pose a barrier.</p>
<p>September JGBs ended at 126.51 against a previous 126.40.  </p>
<p>A senior dealer at a European futures house said JGBs were underpinned by talk of large-lot buying of cash JGBs by a major Japanese fund.</p>
<p>Eurodollar futures ended a touch easier ahead of the release of U.S. retail sales and wholesale inflation data at 1230 GMT.</p>
<p>Economists surveyed by Reuters expected retail sales data to show a rise of 0.7 percent in July after rising 0.5 percent in June.</p>
<p>Both the overall and core Producer Price Index were expected to have risen by 0.1 percent in July.  </p>
<p>December Eurodollars finished at 93.985 against their IMM close at 93.995. March were at 93.885 against 93.895.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65) 870-3090; Fax (65) 776-8112</p>
<p>-- Email: singapore.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
