<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796660" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gasoline soars on refinery shutdown, soybeans up.</title>
<headline>Gasoline soars on refinery shutdown, soybeans up.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gasoline prices soared on Wednesday after Exxon Corp shut down a key production unit at its Baytown, Texas, refinery, tightening supplies further as the summer vacation season continues.</p>
<p>In other markets, soybeans for August delivery soared on worries about dwindling supplies ahead of the fall harvest, and coffee prices fell for a second straight day as talk of stepped-up imports eased supply concerns.</p>
<p>Gasoline for September delivery at the New York Mercantile Exchange ended 2.37 cents a gallon higher at 66.08 cents.</p>
<p>The strength carried over to other petroleum markets, with September crude up 20 cents a barrel to close at $20.19 and September heating oil up 0.94 cent a gallon at 56.04 cents.</p>
<p>Triggering the rally was news that Exxon's Baytown refinery shut its 110,000 barrel per day catalytic cracker. The refinery, with a crude distillation capacity of around 411,000 barrels daily, has total cat cracking capability of around 190,000 bpd.</p>
<p>Cat crackers are units that produce gasoline and other light refined oil products from petroleum feedstock.</p>
<p>Exxon said the Baytown cat cracker was taken down due to operational problems and it did not estimate how long the production would be off-line.</p>
<p>&quot;They have been selling feedstock to make gasoline, so it seems like the cat cracker will be down for more than a day. Gasoline supply is already pretty tight in the (U.S.) Gulf and New York Harbor cash markets,&quot; said George Speicher, an energy trader with Fimat USA Futures in Houston.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the U.S. Department of Energy said that for the week ended August 8, U.S. gasoline stocks fell 1.5 million barrels. Traders noted that stocks of reformulated gasoline, the only grade deliverable against the NYMEX contract, fell 2.7 million barrels in the week.</p>
<p>The oil inventory data was not supportive for crude. The DOE said crude stocks rose a hefty 5.1 million barrels. Tuesday evening, the American Petroleum Institute said that for the same week crude stocks rose 2.7 million barrels.</p>
<p>Oil companies voluntarily report inventory data to the API, the oil industry's trade group, while they are required to report to the DOE.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade, the price of soybeans for August delivery soared on talk of export demand and on tight remaining supplies ahead of the fall harvest.</p>
<p>August soybeans closed 35-1/4 cents a bushel higher at $7.79.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we're finally reaching the bottom of the bin,&quot; said Daniel Basse, a grain analyst with AgResource in Chicago. &quot;We may not have (new crop) beans available until the first or second week in October.&quot;</p>
<p>There was talk that soybeans were needed to meet export commitments on the U.S. Great Lakes and the Gulf of Mexico but that supplies of old crop soybeans were not adequate.</p>
<p>One exporter in northern Ohio said 90,000 metric tons of soybeans would be needed to meet export commitments for the first half of September, but supplies remain scarce.</p>
<p>Bids for soybean barges at the U.S. Gulf for delivery during the first half of September rose 10 cents per bushel on Wednesday, cash market sources said.</p>
<p>Corn prices closed mixed, with December futures up 1-1/4 cents a bushel at $2.66-1/2.</p>
<p>Traders reported heavy sales of futures on Wednesday by commercial grain firms seeking to lock in high prices after the market surged the 12-cent a bushel daily trading limit Tuesday.</p>
<p>That rally followed a U.S. Agriculture Department estimate Tuesday of 1997 corn production at 9.276 billion bushels. The estimate, based on the first field surveys of corn this season, was down sharply from the department's July forecast of 9.7 billion bushels.</p>
<p>At the Coffee Sugar and Cocoa Exchange in New York, coffee prices closed mostly lower as speculators continued to exit the market in the belief that coffee imports from Africa and other origins have been flowing in to ease supply tightness.</p>
<p>September coffee closed at 183.10 cents a pound, down 5.10 cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
