<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796650" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fleet close to buying Columbia Management fund group.</title>
<headline>Fleet close to buying Columbia Management fund group.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the lastest sign of consolidation in the mutual fund industry, Fleet Financial Group Inc. is close to an agreement to buy Columbia Management for $400 million in cash plus incentives, a source close to the deal said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have an agreement at this point, but we are close to an agreement,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Columbia, which has $22 billion in assets under management, would be operated as an independent business unit under the Columbia name with the same management team, the source said.</p>
<p>The agreement calls for Fleet to make a five-year payment to keep the management of Portland, Ore.-based Columbia in place, as well as performance incentives, he said. The transaction should boost Fleet's earnings &quot;from day one,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>The acquisition, expected to be completed within days, would bolster Fleet's investment adviser division, which currently has $52 billion in assets under management. Fleet's goal is to double that amount, the source said.</p>
<p>Mutual fund analysts said Columbia has a good reputation as a small boutique of well-managed funds.</p>
<p>&quot;They are the kind of good, small fund family that is desirable today,&quot; Morningstar analyst Bill Rocco said in an interview.</p>
<p>Columbia runs 12 no-load, growth-oriented funds which total more than $5 billion in assets. The company also manages about $17 billion in private and institutional funds.</p>
<p>Fleet's shares rose 56 cents to $65.81 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>If the deal goes through, the Columbia acquisition would be the latest in a recent spate of bank takeovers of mutual fund companies.</p>
<p>In an effort to increase assets in a slow growth market, a wave of consolidations have swept the banking industry over the past five years. More recently, banks have been buying brokers and mutual fund companies to increase fee income and broaden product lines.</p>
<p>Last month, J.P. Morgan &amp; Co. Inc. agreed to pay $900 million for a 45 percent stake in Kansas City-based American Century Cos., the 10th largest fund company in the United States in terms of assets under management.</p>
<p>In June, Zurich Group announced it would buy a 69.5 percent stake in Scudder, Stevens &amp; Clark, based in New York, in a deal valued at more than $2 billion.</p>
<p>The stock of two other mutual fund companies rose Wednesday on speculation that they could be the next takeover targets.</p>
<p>Baltimore-based T. Rowe Price Associates Inc. rose $3.56 to close at $56.25 on Nasdaq. Officials at T. Rowe Price, which has about $79 billion under management in 72 mutual funds, have stated publicly that the company intends to remain independent.</p>
<p>Insurance broker Marsh &amp; McLennan Cos. Inc., which owns Putnam Investments, rose 87.5 cents to close at $74 on the New York Stock Exchange. Putnam has 100 mutual funds and total assets of $210 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
