<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796785" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: JUDGE ORDERS RELEASE OF MERRILL LYNCH FILES. [CORRECTED 22:06 GMT]</title>
<headline>JUDGE ORDERS RELEASE OF MERRILL LYNCH FILES. [CORRECTED 22:06 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ANA, Calif. 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A California judge Wednesday ordered the immediate release of grand jury transcripts about Merrill Lynch and Co's role in the Orange County bankruptcy.</p>
<p>&quot; ... This court orders the immediate release of the transcripts and documents of the criminal investigation of Merrill Lynch,&quot; Orange County Superior Court Judge David Carter said in a written ruling. &quot;There is a compelling and fundamental right on behalf of all citizens to have access to vital information relating to the loss of over $1.67 billion of the public's monies,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Wall Street was rocked in December 1994 when Orange County filed for bankruptcy after losing more than $1.6 billion on risky investments. The southern California county emerged from bankruptcy last year.</p>
<p>In June, Merrill Lynch settled with Orange County's district attorney for $30 million, ensuring that the brokerage giant and its employees would not face criminal charges. Transcripts of the grand jury probe of its role have so far remained sealed.</p>
<p>Lawyers for Orange County and news organizations asked Carter to give them access to the grand jury transcripts.  </p>
<p>County attorneys said the transcripts could bolster their $2 billion-plus lawsuit against Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>County prosecutors and Merrill Lynch had argued that the transcripts should remain sealed because no indictments were returned by the grand jury. But in a strongly-worded decision, Carter ruled that the public's right to know outweighed Merrill Lynch's concerns about disclosure.</p>
<p>&quot;The public, our state and federal elected officials and the financial community must be allowed access to information that allows them to examine the events that led to the largest municipal bankruptcy in our nation's history,&quot; Carter said.  </p>
<p>Having weighed the issues, &quot;the court concludes that secrecy must give way to openness,&quot; Carter said, ordering that the transcripts of all sessions of the 1996/97 Orange County grand jury be immediately unsealed by the district attorney.</p>
<p>Noting that the district attorney had agreed to release the transcripts to attorneys for former Orange County assistant treasurer Matthew Raabe, (corrects to insert sentences) Carter said it was &quot;ironic that a defendant in a criminal action knows more about the Orange County bankruptcy than the public ... Why should a defendant in a criminal action have greater access to this information than the public that was victimized?&quot; He said &quot;each and every citizen has an inalienable right to the disclosure of this information.&quot;  </p>
<p>Carter said the release of the transcripts &quot;may exonerate Merrill Lynch. Whether Merrill Lynch is culpable is not relevant to the issue of public access. Simply stated, the public has the right to make its own determination.&quot;</p>
<p>Noting that Merrill Lynch had paid $30 million under the settlement with Orange County's district attorney while denying any wrongdoing, Carter said: &quot;Legal scholars cannot recall any other case where a law enforcement agency agreed to accept a civil fine to terminate a criminal investigation of this magnitude.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ANA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
