<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796881" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany's Stoiber says no plan for EMU delay.</title>
<headline>Germany's Stoiber says no plan for EMU delay.</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bavarian premier Edmund Stoiber, one of Germany's leading Eurosceptics, denied on Wednesday suggestions he was the &quot;spiritual father&quot; of a plan to delay European economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>Stoiber, a member of Finance Minister Theo Waigel's Christian Social Union (CSU), was quoted by a Dutch newspaper as suggesting there should be a two-year delay to the creation of the common currency if countries fail to meet its entry terms.</p>
<p>&quot;Waigel knows our situation and anybody who can add up three and three knows that this (plan) is the only alternative for a further prudent development,&quot; the Algemeen Dagblad quoted Stoiber as saying.</p>
<p>But Stoiber's spokesman later said no such plan existed and the comments were simply &quot;hypothetical reflections&quot; on what should happen if countries failed to fulfil the entry criteria set by the Maastricht treaty.</p>
<p>Stoiber has won a reputation as an EMU hawk after wringing a concession from Chancellor Helmut Kohl that Germany would only join EMU in 1999 if it achieved the Maastricht budget deficit goal of three percent of GDP this year.</p>
<p>His spokesman said that if countries failed to stick to the EMU budget criteria this year, a decision on who could join should be made in the year 2000.</p>
<p>That would still leave time to make the final transition to issuing the notes and coins of the new euro currency as planned in 2002, he said. But he added that this position was not shared by Waigel.</p>
<p>A Finance Ministry spokeswoman said that there was no discussion being held in the German government over a possible EMU delay.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany and other countries are doing their best to meet the criteria -- and they will manage it,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Bonn also dismissed as &quot;pure speculation&quot; an article in the London Evening Standard suggesting that both Kohl and French President Jacques Chirac had offered to delay EMU for a year if Britain agreed to join the starting line-up.</p>
<p>A government spokesman said Germany's position remained unchanged, and both the timetable and the criteria must be met for the single currency to go ahead.</p>
<p>A British treasury spokesman also poured cold water on the article: &quot;We won't dignify this story with a quote,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Douglas Busvine, Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
