<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796812" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USW LOCAL LEADERS SEE NO VICTORY IN WHX PACT.</title>
<headline>USW LOCAL LEADERS SEE NO VICTORY IN WHX PACT.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Steelworkers who ratified a new contract with WHX Corp based their decision on dire financial need, not satisfaction with the pact, as their national leaders have claimed, local union officials said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, company officials said they would ramp up production over the next several weeks and had no plans to cut steel prices to win back customers.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a victory,&quot; said Mickey Forte, president of Local 1187 of the United Steelworkers union in Allenport, Pennsylvania. &quot;They (union leaders) can call it whatever they want...They don't have to live with it day in and day out.  </p>
<p>&quot;Look at what we had to give up. We're not happy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The union on Tuesday ratified a five-year contract with WHX by a vote of 3,105 to 817.</p>
<p>Some 4,500 workers had been on strike since last October, marking the longest strike ever against a major U.S. steelmaker. The strike idled plants in West Virginia, Pennsylvania and Ohio.  </p>
<p>Forte said he voted against the pact because it allows the company to change workplace rules by combining jobs, which will eventually eliminate some positions. It also enables WHX to cut 850 people from the workforce over the next 18 months.</p>
<p>&quot;These were all things we turned down (during negotiations,&quot;) he said. &quot;If it had been four months into the strike, this would've been voted down. But when people are starving, what are you going to do? These people are hurting.&quot;  </p>
<p>George Becker, the union's international president, and James Bowen, the union's chief negotiator with WHX, called the contract a victory because it gives workers a defined benefit pension plan, something the union had been demanding throughout the labor dispute.</p>
<p>That plan, which is the norm in the steel industry, guarantees a certain level of payments each month to a worker's pension. Throughout the strike, the company said such a plan would force it into bankruptcy and instead had offered to enhance its defined contribution plan.  </p>
<p>The contract becomes effective immediately. Besides the new pension, it includes wage increases of $1.50 an hour; a $2,000 signing bonus; a $2 million fund to reimburse workers for medical expenses incurred during the strike; and weekly payments of $200 plus health insurance pending a return to work.</p>
<p>The new pension pays $40 a month for each year of service. The multiplier increases to $44 a month on June 1, 2003. The pension also includes benefits for retirement at age 55 with 30 years of service and shutdown benefits to be paid in the event of a departmental or plant closing.  </p>
<p>Dennis O'Neil, a WHX spokesman, declined to comment on strike costs but said WHX did not plan to cut steel prices to win back customers as it re-enters the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Our intention is to not disrupt current market pricing and to come back in at market prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>WHX incurred heavy losses during the strike and it will take several weeks to bring production up to normal levels.</p>
<p>Wall Street's consensus is a loss of $1.30 per share in the third quarter and a loss of $0.70 for the fourth quarter. The estimate for the full year is a loss of $5.48 per share.</p>
<p>Analysts said the steel market, which is currently strong, should not be disrupted by WHX's re-entry.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see where a million and a half to 2 million tons of new supply could offset what is a very strong steel market,&quot; Aldo Mazzaferro at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell said. &quot;I don't see it as a negative at all.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
