<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79683" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Investigators pluck Dutch Dakota wreck from sea.</title>
<headline>Investigators pluck Dutch Dakota wreck from sea.</headline>
<byline>Jasper Juinen</byline>
<dateline>DEN HELDER, Neerlands 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crash investigators on Thursday raised the wreckage of a Dakota DC-3 aircraft which pitched into the North Sea off the coast of the Netherlands on Wednesday killing all 32 people on board.</p>
<p>The plane's ripped fuselage was hoisted by crane from the muddy waters of the Wadden Sea and placed on a floating pontoon for transport to the nearby Den Helder naval base. Experts will sift through the debris, seeking the cause of the crash.</p>
<p>The 55-year-old plane was not carrying a &quot;black box&quot; flight recorder, but the pilot radioed that he had engine trouble shortly before ditching into the shallow waters.</p>
<p>The vintage plane, owned by the Dutch Dakota Association (DDA), carrying 26 passengers and six crew, was returning a group of civil servants to Amsterdam's Schiphol airport after a day-trip to Texel, an island off the Dutch coast.</p>
<p>Within four hours emergency services had recovered the bodies of all those on board.</p>
<p>At the naval base's sports hall some 80 emergency staff were busy with the grim task of identifying the bodies, many of them mangled, plucked from the sandbanks where the Dakota came down.</p>
<p>One passenger initially survived the crash but later died in hospital in Den Helder.</p>
<p>A convoy of black hearses was parked at the base but relatives of the victims were sent home after being told the identification process could take up to two days to complete.</p>
<p>Fellow workers from the North Holland provincial government mourned the loss of life. &quot;We've lost nearly all our colleagues,&quot; said one. &quot;We're devastated,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>Three of the dead were employees of Dutch construction firm Ballast Nedam which sponsors the DDA.</p>
<p>Authorities said that death would have been instantaneous on impact with the shallow waters rather than by drowning.</p>
<p>The DDA said the aircraft was in perfect technical condition and had been checked by the national civil aviation authority.</p>
<p>The six crew members who died in the crash were named on Thursday. The pilot, 65-year-old Hans Buining, and his crew were volunteer enthusiasts belonging to the association.</p>
<p>Both Queen Beatrix and Prime Minister Wim Kok expressed deep shock at the tragedy, the second air disaster to hit The Netherlands within two months.</p>
<p>In July, over 30 young Dutch army bandsmen and women were killed when a Belgian C-130 Hercules transport plane crashed on approach to Eindhoven airport in the southern Netherlands.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DEN HELDER, Neerlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
