<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796951" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIA COALITION SAID POISED TO RAISE OIL PRICES.</title>
<headline>INDIA COALITION SAID POISED TO RAISE OIL PRICES.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's ruling coalition on Wednesday postponed a decision on whether to raise domestic petroleum prices but said it would soon have to increase prices despite stiff communist opposition.</p>
<p>The United Front's decision-making Steering Committee, deeply divided over how to control a mounting bill for oil subsidies, met for 30 minutes but for the fourth time in three months deferred the decision.</p>
<p>&quot;It has not been resolved,&quot; Information Minister Jaipal Reddy, who is coalition spokesman, told reporters after the meeting.</p>
<p>But a senior coalition official said the 15-party United Front could not put off the decision for much longer as the government owes oil companies billions of dollars.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no option but to increase prices which we would do shortly,&quot; the official, who asked not to be identified, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We will meet very soon to take a final view on oil prices,&quot; Reddy said. &quot;There was a feeling today that the decision on oil prices could not be put off for too long and we should meet very soon, though no date could be fixed.&quot;</p>
<p>At the end of March, the government owed $4.3 billion to state oil firms, which sell some oil products such as kerosene to consumers at prices below world levels.</p>
<p>The government eventually reimburses the firms, but the bill has kept rising because of the gap between Indian and international prices.</p>
<p>Communists in the 15-party coalition have strongly opposed proposals to raise the prices of some products, arguing that the move would hurt the poor.</p>
<p>But critics of the communists' plan, which would slash import duties on crude oil and raise taxes on luxury cars, say it would not curtail the cost of subsidies.</p>
<p>The centre-left coalition raised oil prices shortly after assuming power in June 1996, saying the previous government led by the Congress party had failed to tackle the growing oil subsidy bill.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
