<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796914" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: FOCUS-SAS beats H1 forecasts, shares jump.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-SAS beats H1 forecasts, shares jump.</headline>
<byline>Tanya Pang</byline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Scandinavian Airlines System (SAS) took off on Wednesday after the group posted first half results way above expectations.</p>
<p>SAS said increased volumes and subdued costs in the second quarter resulted in a 32 percent surge in operating profits before depreciation to 1.76 billion Swedish crowns ($219.3 million), versus 1.34 billion crowns a year ago.</p>
<p>Profits before tax amounted to 1.38 billion crowns against 867 million crowns in the 1996 period and more than double analysts' forecasts.</p>
<p>For the first half of the year, the company said revenues increased by nearly nine percent to 18.989 billion crowns, which when adjusted for currency effects of 504 million crowns, amounted to a rise of 1.04 billion crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;With the exception of domestic traffic in Sweden and Denmark, an increase of up to nine percent was noted on all route sectors,&quot; SAS said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Development was particularly favourable for Intra-Scandinavian and European traffic, which are the areas where competitive pressure increased most.&quot;</p>
<p>SAS said it was able to defend market share through new fare structures, new products and special offers.</p>
<p>SAS is jointly owned by the governments of Sweden, Denmark and Norway and by private investors. Each of the three countries has a locally-traded constituent SAS company.</p>
<p>In Oslo SAS shares rose 8.6 percent, or nine Norwegian crowns, to 114 crowns, while in Denmark the stock advanced nine Danish crowns to 114 crowns and in Sweden it closed at 124 Swedish crowns, a rise of 11 crowns.</p>
<p>But analysts were cautious about the result, which had been widely rumoured in Norwegian media.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very strong result and the share rose although these figures had been widely rumoured. The market must have been unsure of the rumours,&quot; said a Copenhagen-based analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock has gone up strongly over the last couple of months and I think it is fully priced now in general,&quot; he said, adding that he would slightly upgrade his recommendation to &quot;reduce&quot; from &quot;sell&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;In volume terms the second quarter, especially July, could have been influenced by the strike at British Airways and a lot of tourist class because of the summer holidays. Therefore it is difficult to see how SAS will perform in the second half.&quot;</p>
<p>SAS CEO Jan Stenberg said fewer labour disputes within the group had also contributed to the improved performance.</p>
<p>&quot;The management and personnel are communicating better and that may explain some of the progress. We know that conflicts influence the economy,&quot; he said, pointing to the fact that many passengers had switched to other carriers during the recent British Airway's strike.</p>
<p>The company said its hotel operations also showed positive developments, particularly in Britaand Scandinavia. Six-month operating revenues for SAS International Hotels amounted to 1.06 billion Swedish crowns against 836 million crowns a year earlier.</p>
<p>The group added that its earlier forecast for full-year earnings remained unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;This is based on an anticipated continued positive traffic trend in SAS's markets and a continued moderate increase in unit costs. Efforts to achieve structural cost reductions in operations continue and effects of this will appear during the second half and primarily in 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>--Tanya Pang, Oslo newsroom, +47 22 42 50 41 ($ = 8.024 Swedish Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
