<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="796959" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India meeting endorses international landmine ban.</title>
<headline>India meeting endorses international landmine ban.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Military and humanitarian experts from several countries on Wednesday endorsed a world ban on landmines and condemned the deaths and maiming caused among civilians by thousands of the devices each year.</p>
<p>&quot;Firstly, they do not discriminate the target and secondly, they continue to remain active long after the conflict has finished,&quot; said Major-General Dipankar Banerjee, director of the Institute for Peace and Conflict Studies.</p>
<p>Speakers at a meeting in the Indian capital noted that under the 1949 Geneva Convention all mines must be marked, recorded and removed after an armed conflict has ended.</p>
<p>The experts who endorsed an international ban were from India, Hong Kong, Ireland, Belgium, Norway, Canada and the International Committee of the Red Cross.</p>
<p>Banerjee said both sides in the three wars that India and Pakistan have fought since independence in 1947 had observed these rules.</p>
<p>He added that while the Convention has been followed by regular forces in conflicts across the world, the problem lay in the use of mines by guerrilla groups.</p>
<p>&quot;In Kashmir,&quot; he said, &quot;far more Indian soldiers and civilians have been maimed and killed than terrorists.&quot;</p>
<p>India and Pakistan have fought two of three wars over the disputed Himalayan territory of Kashmir.</p>
<p>A landmine explosion on Tuesday killed three Indian soldiers in Kashmir, and on Monday another blast killed two civilians and injured a police official.</p>
<p>International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) figures show that there are more than 119 million landmines scattered across 71 countries, with Afghanistan, Angola and Cambodia worst affected.</p>
<p>A spokesman from the ICRC estimated that landmines accounted for 24,000 casualties a year, a figure that translated to a death or maiming every 20 minutes.</p>
<p>An impressive list of states now back a total ban on landmine production and the movement to outlaw these weapons has gained considerable momentum over the past 12 months.</p>
<p>Last October, 50 states met in Ottawa and pledged to work together for a global ban on landmines and to increase resources available for mine clearance and assistance to victims who have lost limbs and livelihoods as a result.</p>
<p>In December 1996, 155 countries supported a United Nations General Assembly Resolution calling for a treaty to outlaw these weapons.</p>
<p>An international treaty banning the use of landmines is expected to be signed in Ottawa this December.</p>
<p>A total of 95 countries signed the so-called Brussels Declaration last June forming the basis for negotiations in Oslo, Norway in September on the exact wording of the Ottawa treaty.</p>
<p>An ICRC representative said that while the Ottawa meeting was an encouraging sign, there was an urgent need to increase funding for mine-clearing projects. &quot;Banning them is one thing, removing them is the next task&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
