<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797088" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: POLYSINDO ACQUIRES 11.6 PCT STAKE IN TEXFI.</title>
<headline>POLYSINDO ACQUIRES 11.6 PCT STAKE IN TEXFI.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polysindo Hong Kong Ltd, a Hong Kong-based polyester company, has acquired an 11.6 percent stake in Texfi Industries and is interested in owning a majority stake in the company, Polysindo said in a filing.</p>
<p>According to 13D filing at the Securities and Exchange Commission, Polysindo bought 1,024,928 shares of Texfi for $6.00 per share from 27 shareholders in private transactions.  </p>
<p>Polysindo, which owns a 23 percent stake in Dyersburg Corp and is an affiliate of P.T. Texmaco Jaya, said that its interest in buying more Texfi shares depends upon market and other considerations, including the price of Texfi shares.</p>
<p>Also, the company said in the August 11 filing that it may sometime dispose of all or part of its holdings in Texfi.  </p>
<p>Polysindo paid former president L. Terrell Sovey Jr. a finder's fee of $250,000 for assisting with the coordination of private purchases that were made on August 1, 1997.</p>
<p>Sovey has been out of the company since 1994 and has held more than five percent of the stock in Texfi, as of Texfi's January filing, Dane Vincent, Texfi's chief financial officer, said.</p>
<p>Vincent said Texfi will have its management and board meet next week to review Polysindo's plans.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have a lot of information to work with right now,&quot; Vincent said. &quot;We'll do what we think is best for the company. We're encouraged to see that they'd be willing to take such a position in the company.&quot;</p>
<p>Texfi shares gained 11/16 to trade at 5-1/16, topping the company's 52-week high of 4-3/4.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
