<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79720" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Fx forwards firm on funding of Greek FRNs, T-bills.</title>
<headline>Fx forwards firm on funding of Greek FRNs, T-bills.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forex forwards turned round in late trade to firm 20 basis points in short periods and 10 points in long tenors on funding for privately placed floaters and 12-month T-bills to be issued on September 30, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Forex forwards have risen 20 basis points in shorts and 10 basis points in long tenors reversing their early morning fall,&quot; said a money trader at a foreign bank. &quot;The rise is linked to funding for privately placed floaters and 12-month T-bills.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign players end up with a spread of 30 basis points over one-year $ Libor by borrowing one-year drachmas through swaps and buying into 12-month T-bills, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a good spread given the country's credit rating.&quot;</p>
<p>Greece has a BBB minus rating from S&amp;P.</p>
<p>The finance ministry said it would issue three-, six- and 12-month T-bills at unchanged yields of 11.90, 12.10 and 12.70 percent respectively on September 30.</p>
<p>Other bond traders said foreign players were interested in buying the seven-year floaters around 98.65 but local banks offered them at higher prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Only a few of the local banks that participated in the private placement have been quoting prices on the screens and there seems to be an implicit accord not to let bond prices fall below a particular level,&quot; said a bond dealer at a foreign bank.</p>
<p>But traders in two of the local banks that took part in the private placement denied the charge and pointed out that the prices included the regular commission of 110 basis points.</p>
<p>Some dealers said on Wednesday the state privately placed 7-year FRNs at par worth 830 billion drachmas carrying an annual coupon of 14.20 percent with some local state and private banks.</p>
<p>A five-year FRN carrying no spread over the 12-month T-bill benchmark issued by the treasury in 1991 is expiring on September 30.</p>
<p>The local banks, state National, Commercial, Ionian Bank and private Alpha Credit Bank and Ergo Bank held the expiring FRN issue, received a gross commission of 220 basis points, much higher than the normal 110 basis points, dealers said.</p>
<p>Some foreign banks took quotes for the seven-year FRNs off their screens in protest over the finance ministry's policy on the private placement issue.</p>
<p>&quot;I took quotes off my screen to protect myself,&quot; said a dealer at one of these foreign banks.</p>
<p>&quot;If the finance ministry wanted to subsidise a few banks for losses incurred in the past it should have done it in a straightforward way - give them cash - without hurting the secondary bond market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Traders at local banks taking part in the private placement dismissed the charge saying it was a compensation for past losses. These were incurred by holding state paper that was priced off market.</p>
<p>The mark was quoted at 157.75/85 drachmas from Thursday's 157.680 fix, the dollar at 239.96/06 drachmas from 237.970 and the Ecu at 301.25/33 from 301.300 drachmas.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Greece, the domestic money market's biggest player, quoted the following late rates:</p>
<p>** Overnight at 12.10-12.50</p>
<p>** T/N at 12.05-12.55</p>
<p>** S/N at 12.20-12.70</p>
<p>** One week at 12.20-12.70</p>
<p>** Two weeks at 12.25-12.75</p>
<p>** Three weeks at 12.30-12.80</p>
<p>** One month at 12.30-12.80</p>
<p>** Two months at 12.35-12.85</p>
<p>** Three months at 12.40-12.90</p>
<p>** Six months at 12.55-13.05</p>
<p>** Nine months at 12.70-13.20</p>
<p>** Twelve months at 12.85-13.35</p>
<p>--Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
