<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797319" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel tears down five illegally built Arab homes.</title>
<headline>Israel tears down five illegally built Arab homes.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Jerusalem municipality workers tore down five illegal Arab homes under construction in East Jerusalem on Wednesday, the municipality said.</p>
<p>&quot;This morning five structures were demolished. All five of them were foundations, they were all built without permits,&quot; a city spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;They were built on a valley that was not planned for housing units and will never be planned for housing,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said the unoccupied homes near the Arab village of Anata were built on public land and were only partially constructed. Witnesses said a few Arabs threw stones at Israeli soldiers and workers near the site.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said no Israeli construction was planned for the area.</p>
<p>Palestinians say they are forced to build illegally because the municipality will not give them permits. They accuse Israel of trying to drive them out of Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The municipality says Arabs have built more than 2,600 buildings without permits in the past two years. Jerusalem Mayor Ehud Olmert has called illegal Arab building a &quot;cancer&quot; that threatens Israel's sovereignty in the holy city.</p>
<p>The municipality says it has approved 75 percent of 504 applications to build in Arab neighborhoods in the past two years. It says it has approved 90 percent of 2,893 applications to build in Jewish neighborhoods.</p>
<p>This year, the municipality has issued 17 orders to destroy homes in East Jerusalem and has carried out nine of them. The city said it had torn down parts of seven Jewish homes that were built without permits.</p>
<p>Israel captured East Jerusalem from Jordan in the 1967 Middle East war and later annexed it in a move that failed to win international recognition.</p>
<p>Palestinians want East Jerusalem for the capital of a future state. They say Israeli demolitions and construction of Jewish homes in East Jerusalem are aimed at preempting future &quot;final status&quot; peace talks on the city's fate slated to end in 1999.</p>
<p>Israel says it will never cede any part of Jerusalem and has the right to do as it pleases in the city it claims as its &quot;eternal capital&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
