<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79740" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Survey finds decision makers at odds with public on EU.</title>
<headline>Survey finds decision makers at odds with public on EU.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union decision makers are at odds with ordinary citizens over the worth, role and future of the 15-nation bloc, a survey revealed on Thursday.</p>
<p>A poll by Eurobarometer* showed 94 percent of &quot;decision makers&quot; in the European Union thought EU membership a good thing, compared to just 48 percent of ordinary people.</p>
<p>Decision makers were said by Eurobarometer to be elected politicians, senior civil servants, business or labour group leaders, media chiefs and leading academic or cultural figures.</p>
<p>The survey questioned nearly 4,000 decision makers across the EU and the results were compared with a similar poll of ordinary people released last month.</p>
<p>Some 63 percent of decision makers thought the EU did not play a big enough role in world affairs while 29 percent felt it had the right amount of influence.</p>
<p>Ninety percent of decision makers thought their country had benefitted from EU membership compared to just 45 percent of ordinary people.</p>
<p>Decision makers were more closely allied to popular opinion on the priorities facing the EU over the next decade with maintaining peace, fighting unemployment and combatting terrorism and drugs ranking high in both groups.</p>
<p>But support for a single European currency varied significantly with 85 percent of decision makers either &quot;for&quot; or &quot;somewhat for&quot; the idea, compared to 54 percent of the public.</p>
<p>Opinion varied greatly among member states on the worth of a single currency. Only 30 percent of decision makers from Britain -- which has an opt out of the scheme -- were &quot;very much for&quot; participation, although another 30 percent were &quot;somewhat for&quot;.</p>
<p>In contrast, some 93 percent of Luxembourg's decision makers were in favour of a single currency.</p>
<p>The survey also revealed strong support by decision makers for a more important role for the European Parliament in the EU's decision making, although there was no comparison for ordinary citizens.</p>
<p>Some 83 percent felt the European Commission -- the EU's executive -- should resign without the majority support of the parliament, while 65 percent backed the idea of a European government responsible to parliament. (*Eurobarometer, &quot;Top Decision Makers Survey&quot;, Summary Report, Directorate-General X)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
