<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797521" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. state of Missouri executes killer of four men.</title>
<headline>U.S. state of Missouri executes killer of four men.</headline>
<dateline>POTOSI, Mo. 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Donald Reese, who killed four men in a 1986 robbery, was executed by lethal injection early on Wednesday, a spokesman for Missouri's department of corrections said.</p>
<p>Reese, 54, was arrested June 15, 1986 -- one week after the bodies of James Watson, Christopher Griffith, John Burford and his brother-in-law, Don Vanderlinden, were found at a rifle range in central Missouri. Reese later confessed to the killings and to having taken wallets from three of the men.</p>
<p>He was sentenced to death for murdering Watson and was given life without parole for killing Griffith.</p>
<p>Reese's last meal consisted of six fried shrimp, french fries, ice cream and a large soft drink, according to Tim Kniest, a spokesman for the Missouri Department of Corrections.</p>
<p>&quot;I love everybody,&quot; Reese said in a brief final statement.</p>
<p>Kniest said 27 demonstrators gathered outside the correctional centre before the execution. Most of the demonstrators were opposed to capital punishment.</p>
<p>About 25 opponents of capital punishment also staged a silent protest on Tuesday evening at a busy traffic intersection in Kansas City, Mo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="POTOSI, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
