<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797672" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germans lose confidence in Kohl economic policies.</title>
<headline>Germans lose confidence in Kohl economic policies.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germans are losing confidence in Chancellor Helmut Kohl's ability to resolve the most urgent economic problems such as unemployment, a survey published on Wednesday by Wirtschaftswoche magazine found.</p>
<p>The survey by the Emnid Institute found that only one in five Germans had confidence that Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) could solve problems such as joblessness and for the first time voters no longer viewed the CDU as the most competent party on economic issues.</p>
<p>Only 21 percent said the CDU was the most competent on economic issues, the same number that viewed the opposition SPD as most capable of resolving the troubles.</p>
<p>&quot;The confidence in Chancellor Kohl has declined most dramatically,&quot; Wirtschaftswoche wrote in an advance text. &quot;Only nine percent view his engagement in fighting unemployment as good while 38 percent said it is deficient.&quot;</p>
<p>The magazine said Kohl's ratings were generally poor and well below those of his possible SPD challenger, Lower Saxony premier Gerhard Schroeder.</p>
<p>-- Erik Kirschbaum, Bonn newsroom, 49 228 260 97160 rtr egk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
