<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79763" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: MEPs say Council wrecked health monitoring scheme.</title>
<headline>MEPs say Council wrecked health monitoring scheme.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Parliament is expected next month to attack EU health ministers, saying they have practically sabotaged plans for an EU system to monitor the spread of cancer, AIDS and other major illnesses, parliamentary sources said.</p>
<p>When MEPs give the plans a second reading on October 22 they are expected to accuse the member states of reneging on their EU treaty commitment to ensure &quot;a high level of human health protection&quot; by coordinating their efforts to prevent disease and improve health information.</p>
<p>The European Commission has proposed a five-year EU action programme for monitoring health indicators -- COM(96)222 -- but the Council's common position on the text empties it of substance, complains a report from the parliament's environment committee.</p>
<p>The committee is furious that ministers have axed the programme's budget, refused to harmonise national health indicators or set up a permanent, central health monitoring structure and given the programme a costly, bureaucratic administrative structure.</p>
<p>&quot;The governments of the member states are guilty of alarming shortsightedness,&quot; and are preventing the development of an EU policy on public health, says the report, drafted by Italian Christian Democrat Danilo Pogglioni.</p>
<p>Pogglioni's report reinstates amendments to the draft decision which MEPs made at first reading on April 17 but which health ministers threw out when they adopted their common position on May 14.</p>
<p>At first reading, parliament reduced its original demand for a budget of 35 million Ecus for the programme to 20 million Ecus. MEPs are refusing to compromise further and will insist the 20 million figure is retained.</p>
<p>The Council's decision to offer the programme 13 million Ecus amounts to &quot;insulting&quot; penny-pinching and makes little sense since an efficient and cost-effective EU disease prevention mechanism would help governments reduce their astronomical health budgets, the report argues.</p>
<p>Parliament will also insist on the need for the member states to use the same technical language.</p>
<p>In a situation in which even the definition &quot;hospital bed&quot; means different things in different countries, it is currently impossible to compare national health indicators, the report says.</p>
<p>The Council rejected this idea on the grounds that the EU treaty chapter on public health policy (Title X) explicitly excludes &quot;any harmonisation of the laws and regulations of the member states&quot;.</p>
<p>But Pogglioni points out he is only suggesting a harmonisation of technical, medical and sanitary definitions.</p>
<p>&quot;How can the EU ensure a high level of public health protection if we can't even carry out a coherent analysis of national health data?&quot; an assistant to the MEP said to Reuters.</p>
<p>Parliament will also reintroduce a request, refused by Council, for a study to examine the feasibility of setting up a permanent European health observatory which would collect and analyse national health indicators.</p>
<p>&quot;It's strategic. If we can understand the development of illnesses we can prevent them happening and save money in the long term,&quot; the assistant explained.</p>
<p>EU action on health could be made even more efficient, parliament will say, if the committee set up to help the Commission run the monitoring programme is made up of one expert from each of the 15 member states.</p>
<p>Ministers said there should be two representatives per country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
