<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797784" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: All MPC members voted for July UK rate rise.</title>
<headline>All MPC members voted for July UK rate rise.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>All members of the Bank of England's Monetary Policy Committee voted for an immediate increase of 1/4 percentage point in interest rates at the committee's July 9-10 meeting, minutes from the meeting showed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The committee discussed the relative merits of a rise in interest rates of a quarter point or a half point.</p>
<p>It said said there was a risk that an increase of a half point would lead to an upward revision of the expected level at which interest rates would peak and would cause the exchange rate to appreciate unnecessarily.  </p>
<p>&quot;It was not clear how large an increase in interest rates would be needed either to achieve the inflation target,&quot; the minutes said.</p>
<p>The members agreed it was clear domestic demand was growing significantly faster than any plausible measure of potential output and that a further tightening of monetary policy was needed.</p>
<p>&quot;The main issues were the revisions to the national accounts data, windfall gains from demutualisations and their effect on consumer spending, the behaviour of the exchange rate and its effect on the economy, the budget and the behaviour of the labour market,&quot; the minutes said.  </p>
<p>The MPC estimated that the real contractionary effect of the July 2 budget, in terms of both spending and tax measures, probably lay between 0.5 percent and 1.0 percent of gross domestic product (GDP).</p>
<p>&quot;The budget seemed likely to have its full effect on the economy only after some delay,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The committee agreed that the economic effect of the budget would need to be further examined in the August inflation report.</p>
<p>The committee reviewed the latest credit and money supply data, which appeared stronger than a month earlier when there had been an indication of possible deceleration.</p>
<p>Personal money and credit growth had picked up this year at a time of strong consumer confidence.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, monetary growth continued to be a source of considerable concern,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The committee discussed the labour market and said that &quot;it appeared possible that the rate of unemployment compatible with a stable rate of inflation was lower than had earlier been thought.&quot;</p>
<p>The committee noted residual appreciation of the exchange rate seemed likely to reflect in part EMU related influences.</p>
<p>&quot;A higher proportion of the latest month's exchange rate appreciation could be related to changes in relative yield curves,&quot; the minutes said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
