<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79776" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Paribas can go it alone - chairman.</title>
<headline>Paribas can go it alone - chairman.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>French financial holding company Paribas can forge on alone and has &quot;does not need to look for a mega-merger&quot;, chairman Andre Levy-Lang said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are convinced, and I think our results in the first half prove it, that Paribas can succeed on its own. We have the means to succeed alone,&quot; Levy-Lang told a news conference.</p>
<p>Earlier the company announced a first-half net attributable profit of 4.042 billion francs, versus 609 million francs last time round.</p>
<p>Banque Paribas produced a net attributable profit of 1.274 billion francs, versus 124 million last time, and the group's results were also bolstered by capital gains of 2.958 billion francs, versus 358 million, from Paribas Affaires Industrielles.</p>
<p>Other positive factors were a return to profit for Credit du Nord, the sorting out of the Navigation Mixte dossier and the fact that property investment problems were coming to a close.</p>
<p>On property, Levy-Lang said, &quot;since the start of the year we have noted that the provisions made are sufficient&quot;.</p>
<p>Involvement in property when the bottom fell out of the market in the early 1990s will have cost the group a net total of 10 billion francs over a period of five years.</p>
<p>Levy-Lang said everything that had been done since the start of the year had given Paribas group a &quot;margin of tactical and financial manoeuvre&quot; in its markets, at world, European and local level.</p>
<p>&quot;Paribas is more than ever a banking group active in two main fields, international banking on one hand with Banque Paribas, and financial and retail services on the other,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Concerning the second area, he declined comment on recent press speculation of a looming sell-off of Credit de Nord.</p>
<p>Questioned by reporters on the possibility of a tie-up with Societe Generale or state bank Credit Lyonnais -- a subject of market talk in recent months -- Levy-Lang said Paribas could go on alone.</p>
<p>&quot;Firstly because we are already at a good size...and secondly our results are based on a result which is not the result of a 'monoproduct' or a 'monomarket'. All that means we do not need to get into a mega-merger.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
