<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797834" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - 20 years on, Britain still all shook up over Elvis.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - 20 years on, Britain still all shook up over Elvis.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The King is Dead. Long live the King -- even if he did only touch down in Britain for an hour.</p>
<p>All across the country, 200 impersonators will be squeezing into their rhinestone-studded jumpsuits, slicking back their sideburns and fixing up their bouffant hairstyles for the big memorial night.</p>
<p>Britain is still &quot;All Shook Up&quot; about Elvis Presley, the king of rock 'n roll who died in his Graceland Mansion on August 16, 1977.</p>
<p>Sid Shaw does a roaring trade in &quot;Are you lonesome tonight&quot; knickers and &quot;Jailhouse Rock&quot; ties at his Elvisly Yours memorabilia shop in London.</p>
<p>Paul &quot;Elvis&quot; Chan wows customers at his Chinese restaurant with a karaoke version of &quot;Heartbreak Hotel&quot; in between the noodles and the sweet and sour pork.</p>
<p>At least Scottish fans can cherish two tenuous links with their great idol.</p>
<p>Elvis touched down for an hour at Prestwick Airport in Scotland in March 1960 on his way back from doing military service in Germany. A plaque now marks the spot.</p>
<p>Researchers caused great excitement by tracking down Elvis' great-great-great-great-great grandfather back to the village of Paisley.</p>
<p>Author Bill Burk believes the great pelvic thruster is descended from a blacksmith, Andrew Presley, who emigrated to America in 1745.</p>
<p>The Scottish National Party proudly celebrated the link with their homeland.</p>
<p>&quot;Since Scots appear to have invented everything from tarmacadam to the telephone, it is no surprise to discover that someone of Scottish ancestry was one of the pioneers of rock 'n roll,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Elvis impersonator Abie Lane was even more enthusiastic. &quot; It's no surprise to find that the greatest singer in the world was Scottish. There must be quite a few people in Scotland who share the same genes. Maybe we will see another King.&quot;</p>
<p>UNSTOPPABLE ELVIS BANDWAGON</p>
<p>One British television channel is staging an Elvis theme night on August 16. Barbie Doll's boyfriend Ken is being issued with a special edition Elvis wardrobe. A summer holiday camp is planning a mass lookalike competition.</p>
<p>&quot;Twent years on, Elvis' hearse cruises on unstoppably,&quot; said the Sunday Telegraph, reflecting on the enduring legend.</p>
<p>Sid Shaw had a 14-year battle with the Presley estate over his memorabilia.</p>
<p>Judge Hugh Laddie, ruling in Shaw's favour in March, said: &quot;Presley did not own his appearance. During his life he could not prevent a fan from having a tattoo put on his chest or a drawing on his car which looked like the musician simply on the basis that it was his appearance which was depicted.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if Elvis Presley was still alive, he would not be entitled to stop a fan from naming his son, his dog or goldfish, his car or his house Elvis.&quot;</p>
<p>Paul Elvis Chan, who firmly believes that Elvis songs do mix with Chinese food, recalls his adoration in awed tones.</p>
<p>&quot;I am born in Hong Kong. That is where it begins. It is 1956 I think and I'm hearing 'Teddy Bear.' This voice is soft, so very much beautiful. I believe -- Here is the King of Kings,&quot; he told the Guardian in a frank appraisal of his obsession.</p>
<p>&quot;Same as Elvis, I did alright. I only small, he so big but not all different inside. We make it fine, but everything is not alright. In our heart, we both lonesome tonight.&quot;</p>
<p>The appetite for Elvis memorabilia never seems to wane with the musical on his life -- starring three Elvises at each stage of his career -- now running in London's West End.</p>
<p>But The Guardian did wonder why fans dwelt so much on Elvis' later, sadder years of junk food binges.</p>
<p>&quot;Elvis was a man remembered by virtually everyone he met in his early days as the most handsome man on the planet. He was responsible for half a dozen of the finest songs ever recorded.</p>
<p>&quot;He was the man who, more than any other, changed the direction of modern culture. Yet now, 20 years after his death, he is forever cast in the public mind as Burger Beast.&quot;</p>
<p>Fans should spare a thought for Elvis impersonator Leyton Sommors who did such a good job that he has turned into a virtual recluse.</p>
<p>Sick of the constant jibes, he rarely ventures out.</p>
<p>&quot;I went to a curry house in Manchester with friends. I was wearing ordinary casual clothes, no make-up or costume. In fact I had done eveything not to look like him,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But as soon as I walked in the door, eight blokes started singing 'One for the money, two for the show ..' I couldn't stay because it would spoil things for my friends.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
