<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797884" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: INL QUASHES TALK OF NEWSPAPER PRICE HIKES.</title>
<headline>INL QUASHES TALK OF NEWSPAPER PRICE HIKES.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Brockett</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>INL managing director Mike Robson on Wednesday quashed speculation the publisher was about to raise cover prices on its New Zealand newspapers.</p>
<p>INL recently raised cover prices on a number of its Saturday and weekend publications, including the Saturday edition of The Christchurch Press to 90 NZ cents from 70 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;But beyond that we don't have any plans,&quot; Robson told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Analysts expected INL, which also publishes Wellington's Evening Post and The Dominion, to raise cover prices on at least the Saturday editions of its other major papers.</p>
<p>They said the increased cover price of Auckland's New Zealand Herald, published by INL competitor Wilson and Horton, left the door open for INL to hike its Wellington newspaper prices.</p>
<p>The daily price of the Herald rose to 90 cents from 70 cents on June 3.  </p>
<p>&quot;It would be a fair assumption to say that INL has a little bit of a cover price rise up its sleeve,&quot; one analyst said, adding that a cover price rise would help INL to offset poor advertising volumes in the slow New Zealand economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy has turned down for them very badly in the last quarter and advertising is poor, so if it was just that you'd have to say the company had a nasty outlook for the next half year. But they've got a cover price rise up their sleeve and they've just put in some ad rate increases,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>INL, 49.5 percent owned by Rupert Murdoch's News Corp, is due to report its results for the 1996/97 year on Friday and analysts expect a bottom line profit of about $50 million, up from $47.2 million last year.</p>
<p>This figure includes abnormal costs in the region of $4 to $5 million, and the losses sustained by CD Rom publishing house Terabyte, which could be as much as $4 million.</p>
<p>Analysts said while ad volumes were suffering in the depressed economic environment, lower newsprint costs would bolster second half earnings, as would a sharp turnaround the company's magazine distributor Gordon and Gotch.  </p>
<p>&quot;You'll find a very stunning second half turnaround in Gotch. That's part of the abnormals -- they lopped off 100 people at the start of the year, reorganised their warehousing, just got focused on what they needed to produce out of the business, and it's working,&quot; said another analyst.</p>
<p>He said INL was likely to sell its U.S. operations, which include newspapers in Houston and in California, after it has concluded ongoing negotiations to purchase a 51 percent stake in Sky Network Television from U.S. consortium HKP Partners.  </p>
<p>&quot;They're going to sell them. Once the Sky deal is through they'll flog off the U.S. stuff.&quot; He said the combined U.S. assets could probably be sold for around NZ$40 million.</p>
<p>Robson said INL hoped to complete its negotiations for Sky in the next couple of weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I would hope so...but I think beyond expressing the opinion that they are proceeding in a satisfactory manner, I don't really want to go beyond that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom +64 4 4714 272</p>
<p>e-mail wellington.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
