<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797892" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: ST LUKES SEEN POSTING SOLID YR PROFIT GAIN.</title>
<headline>ST LUKES SEEN POSTING SOLID YR PROFIT GAIN.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shopping mall owner St Lukes Group, under new management, is expected to post a solid gain in earnings when it reports its annual result on Thursday.</p>
<p>Analysts told Reuters they expected a profit, before interest on convertible notes, of between NZ$29-31 million for the June year, up from $28.69 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>The consensus was for a profit of around NZ$29.9 million.</p>
<p>Little change was likely in the immediate future until Westfield Holdings, which took over management in April, completed its strategic review, analysts said.  </p>
<p>Contrary to media reports, St Lukes is not expected to go to the market for expansion funds in the short term, they added.</p>
<p>Analysts forecast the result on a pre-convertible note interest payment basis because the notes are reqarded as quasi equity. The notes are mandatory, so interest payments are seen in a similar light to dividends.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment I think they're going to say it's business as usual,&quot; said one Wellington analyst.</p>
<p>Future refurbishment was likely but the timing and size of such a programme would remain an unknown for the time being.  </p>
<p>&quot;Clearly the input of Westfield as manager is going to be pretty beneficial to the company,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Local retailers are treating Westfield, which has a reputation in Australia as an uncompromising landlord, with some trepidation.</p>
<p>Jeweller Michael Mill International said on Tuesday it was to soon meet with St Lukes' new managers.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe their rent demands are unreasonable and we understand, in Australia, their modus,&quot; MHI's New Zealand managing director Howard Bretherton said. &quot;We will argue every case as well as we can,&quot; he told a results briefing.  </p>
<p>One Auckland analyst said he expected an outcome of around NZ$31 million but again, nothing out of the ordinary.</p>
<p>The slump in retail sales would have no impact on St Lukes, because their rents are reviewed every two years in arrears.</p>
<p>&quot;They are currently getting rental growth from two years ago's retail sales growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The proportion of St Lukes' earnings linked to its tenants' sales was also small, he said.</p>
<p>-- James Gray, Auckland newsroom +64 9 302 1253</p>
<p>e-mail wellington.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500029">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
