<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797867" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: AUSTRALIAN DOLLAR STAGES AN UNEXPECTED RALLY.</title>
<headline>AUSTRALIAN DOLLAR STAGES AN UNEXPECTED RALLY.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar managed a substantial rally through a number of key resistance levels on Wednesday, defying expectations that it would remain rangebound with a bias to the downside in the near term.</p>
<p>The dollar put on half a cent in local trading after one U.S. player bought the unit solidly, in effect ignoring a speech by Reserve Bank Governor Ian Macfarlane that was interpreted by many as leaving the door open for a sixth interest rate cut.</p>
<p>By 4.45 p.m. (0645 GMT) the dollar had risen to US$0.7453/58, over half a cent up on its early US$0.7401/06 and Tuesday's closing US$0.7391/96.  </p>
<p>On its rise to a two week high of US$0.7458, the local dollar broke through resistance at US$0.7420 in the morning and US$0.7450 later in the afternoon.</p>
<p>Wednesday's local close was the highest since July 30, and meant the dollar had put on over one and a half cents since hitting a two-year low last Friday of US$0.7295.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was very confused this morning, it wasn't really sure which way to take it,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>While Macfarlane's speech had seen the dollar fall overnight, traders said a Sydney-based U.S institution bought the dollar in significant volume from the local open.  </p>
<p>Traders estimated the amount involved at over half a billion U.S. dollars. The initial buying triggered stop loss orders above US$0.7420, and saw other buyers enter the market.</p>
<p>Given the driving force was the one major buyer, traders were cautious as to whether the dollar will continue its rally or even hold all its gains in the face of profit-taking.</p>
<p>Macfarlane was not as hawkish in his speech as many had expected.</p>
<p>While bullish on the growth outlook, saying growth above 4.5 percent was possible in the next few years, Macfarlane said it was the inflation outlook that determined rate changes.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have an inflation target, appropriately and flexibly defined, which tells us to tighten when our forecast of inflation has it exceeding the target for any sustained period of time, and to ease when the forecast has inflation sustainably below target,&quot; Macfarlane said.</p>
<p>Nomura economist Andrew Pease thought cash rates would remain at 5.0 percent, &quot;but (the) speech suggests a further easing is a bigger risk than previously thought.&quot;</p>
<p>Helping talk of further rate cuts was data released on Wednesday showing only a 0.2 percent rise in Westpac Bank consumer sentiment index for August.  </p>
<p>&quot;This represents a very disappointing response for consumer sentiment to the 0.5 percent reduction in official interest rates and mortgage rates which occurred about a week before the survey,&quot; said Westpac's economics manager, Bill Evans.</p>
<p>The dollar's gains were not limitedollar, as it rose strongly on the cross rates. The dollar closed at 58.7 in trade weighted terms, up from Tuesday's close of 58.1. Since Monday, the TWI has risen by 1.1 points, or 1.9 percent.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at 86.69/79 yen and 1.3820/37, having risen from an early 86.12/22 and 1.3799/3812 and a Tuesday close of 85.81/91 and 1.3777/90.  </p>
<p>On Thursday, final May quarter average weekly ordinary time earnings data will be released. Preliminary data released last month showed a 0.5 percent quarterly rise, seeing the annual rate moderate to 3.7 percent, well below the level considered to be the RBA's line in the sand on wages growth, 4.5 percent.</p>
<p>The final data also provides a split between the pace of private and public sectors wages growth. The controlled pace of private sector wages over the past year has been on of the factors that gave the RBA room to ease, and economists expect annual growth to remain below 4.0 percent.</p>
<p>-- John Mair 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
