<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="797943" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: PRESS DIGEST - MALAYSIA - AUG 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - MALAYSIA - AUG 13.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in today's Malaysian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NEW STRAITS TIMES</p>
<p>-- A group of 12 companies, including a listed one, have formed a consortium to spearhead Malaysia's efforts at rebuilding Bosnia-Herzegovina.</p>
<p>-- Malaysian firms Bina Puri Holdings Bhd and KTA Tenaga have won a contract to build, operate and manage a 122-million ringgit hydroelectric dam in China's Yunnan region.</p>
<p>-- Malaysia will abide by the decision of the International Telecommunications Union's decision to slash the cost of international telephone calls, but not if it is only by the U.S.</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>-- Malaysia's Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim said drastic steps, including cutting down on infrastructure projects, will be taken to reduce the country's current account deficit and strengthen the ringgit.</p>
<p>BUSINESS TIMES</p>
<p>-- Malaysia, which has pledged $1.0 billion in the International Monetary Fund's rescue package for Thailand, will also benefit the donor. Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim said Thailand's economic woes had had a domino effect on all countries of the region.</p>
<p>-- The new Kuala Lumpur International Airport will be ready for operation by January 1, 1998, but commercial operations will only begin in the first quarter, Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim said.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom 603-201 4813; Fax - 603-232 6752</p>
<p>-- E-mail: kuala.lumpur.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
