<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798059" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASIA PRODUCT SWAPS - FUEL OIL UP ON FRESH SUPPORT.</title>
<headline>ASIA PRODUCT SWAPS - FUEL OIL UP ON FRESH SUPPORT.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore fuel oil swaps rose at midday on Wednesday amid firmer overnight crude values and fresh buying interest in the physical market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Fuel is going up because supplies are tight in Singapore and there are signs that China is coming back to buy,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>September fuel oil was last quoted at $104.25/$105.00 per tonne, up from Tuesday's $103.50/$104.50, brokers said. It traded late Tuesday to a high of $103.75, they said.</p>
<p>September has gained about $1.50 per tonne since Monday.  </p>
<p>The firmer prices were partly due to support in the physical market from more than one player.</p>
<p>In the physical market, trading broke clear of the previous range of between $102.00 and $103.00 per tonne after a 20,000-tonne cargo traded at $103.50 on a free-on-board Singapore basis, up $1.00 from Friday's traded level.</p>
<p>A Singapore trader bought the September 7-11 lifting cargo from a European major. Another buyer was seen for a end August cargo at $102.50 per tonne.  </p>
<p>Also the emergence of Chinese traders on the swaps market picking up several September and October lots has led to speculation that China will re-enter the market to buy physical cargoes.</p>
<p>The gas oil was edged up slightly in line with the firmer crude and was last quoted up 10 cents at $23.40/$23.50 per barrel with no deals seen, brokers said.</p>
<p>The jet fuel/gas oil spread or regrade is coming under pressure due to forced sales of physical jet fuel by traders who do not have enough storage space.  </p>
<p>Traders said the sales on Tuesday of two 100,000 barrel cargoes at $22.80 per barrel was in part due to this.</p>
<p>Sellers are increasingly being forced to turnover their cargoes in Singapore tanks as new supplies arrive from the Middle East.</p>
<p>The September regrade is valued steady at $1.00 but the prompt August regrade is valued at about 40 cents from $1.20 a week ago, brokers said.</p>
<p>-- R.Rajendran, (65) 870-3093; Fax (65) 776-8112</p>
<p>-- Email: singapore.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
