<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798065" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Indonesian rupiah under siege, central bank acts.</title>
<headline>Indonesian rupiah under siege, central bank acts.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Desai</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah fell prey to the malaise afflicting Southeast Asia's currencies on Wednesday, tumbling to a historic low before the central bank provided some support by raising rates.</p>
<p>The rupiah was quoted at 2,665/75 at 0420 GMT after plunging to a low of 2,679 in morning trade against an opening 2,674/76. The rupiah's previous low was 2,665 on July 21.</p>
<p>Dealers attributed the slide to lingering spillover weakness from other regional currencies and to a local newspaper report quoting an economist as saying Bank Indonesia should allow the rupiah to find its own level.</p>
<p>Sjahrir, an economist and brokerage firm owner, was quoted in the Kompas daily as saying the market would ultimately decide a fair value for the rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;According to me, just let the rupiah fall to 2,700 or 2,800. The central bank does not have to do anything. Once they (speculators) realise the central bank hasn't done anything, the dollar is already overvalued,&quot; Sjahrir was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Singapore dealers said there were market rumours Bank Indonesia might widen or remove its intervention band for the rupiah.</p>
<p>The rupiah received a brief lift after the central bank raised interest rates for central bank certificates (SBIs) of all maturities by 100 basis points.</p>
<p>Analysts said the move, which followed a 50-basis-point cut in SBI rates for paper above one week last Friday, was inevitable in the face of the rupiah's slide and could be a prelude to the removal of the intervention band.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the Singapore dollar remained under pressure but recouped some of its losses on talk of possible central bank intervention near its low of 1.5175 to the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>The domestic unit was quoted at 1.5127/37 at 0420 GMT and dealers said the U.S. dollar continued to draw strong bids near the low end of 1.5100.</p>
<p>They said local banks were seen selling the U.S. dollar near its highs earlier, often an indication of the central bank's presence, but no confirmation was available.</p>
<p>&quot;The market still seems to be quite biddish on the U.S. dollar,&quot; a U.S. bank dealer said.</p>
<p>A European bank dealer said the U.S. dollar would be bought on any dips to 1.5100 or 1.5050 for an eventual move up to 1.53.</p>
<p>The Malaysian ringgit moved narrowly but showed persistent signs of weakness and dealers said the market was likely to take a crack at the 2.80 level, a low not seen since the ringgit was officially floated in 1973.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/ringgit could still reach 2.80 and probably go above that level,&quot; said a Malaysian bank dealer. &quot;But I'm expecting some resistance at 2.7850.&quot;</p>
<p>The ringgit was quoted at 2.7720/50 to the dollar at 0420 GMT against 2.7645/75 at the close of Kuala Lumpur trade on Tuesday. It hit a new 42-month low of 2.7930 earlier on Tuesday. The Thai baht opened weaker in domestic markets as players returned from a one-day holiday and bought the dollar on concern about weakness in regional markets.</p>
<p>The baht was quoted at 31.59/64 to the dollar in onshore markets and at 31.10/20 in offshore markets.</p>
<p>Dealers said there were some sales of dollars offshore ahead of the expected mid-August maturity of short baht positions, established when the Thai currency came under speculative attack three months ago.</p>
<p>The Philippine peso remained weak as banks bought up the dollar in volatile regional currency markets. Corporate demand for the dollar also weighed on the peso, which was at 28.925/29.050 against its previous close at 28.66.</p>
<p>The Taiwan dollar was weak but its decline was expected to be slowed by fears of central bank intervention and tight liquidity in domestic money markets.</p>
<p>It was at T$28.723/726 against Tuesday's T$28.718 close.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
