<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798078" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: USDA REPORT TO SPOOK SE ASIAN CORN BUYERS - TRADE.</title>
<headline>USDA REPORT TO SPOOK SE ASIAN CORN BUYERS - TRADE.</headline>
<byline>Rene Pastor</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian and Indonesian buyers will probably jump into the market after the overnight release of a bullish U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) report which sent corn futures prices soaring, dealers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The USDA estimated on Tuesday that U.S. 1997 corn production would be around 9.276 billion bushels, sharply below its forecast of 9.7 billion in July.</p>
<p>The September corn futures contract on the Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) closed the 12-cent limit up, ending at US$2.61-3/4 a bushel. December was also up 12 cents at $2.65-1/4 a bushel.  </p>
<p>&quot;I was very surprised by the numbers. It's already spooked buyers here,&quot; a dealer for a U.S. commodity house told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody was surprised. I don't think people can hold back on buying too long. We're a long way from the next crop report and we're coming into September when they have to make decisions on their last quarter needs,&quot; anther dealer said.</p>
<p>Prices of U.S. corn coming into Southeast Asia rose sharply and were seen by the trade at around $145-$150 a tonne C&amp;F on a Panamax for October-December shipment against a quote last week of $138-$142 a tonne C&amp;F.  </p>
<p>One analyst was a bit more cautious about buyers chasing corn supplies, saying they would probably come in if prices dipped.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think consumers are going to run and go crazy. I would be surprised to see people chasing corn,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But most of the trade believes otherwise.</p>
<p>&quot;This thing will scare people. It will definitely spook the buyers,&quot; one said.  </p>
<p>Traders said Indonesia, which recently bought around 150,000 tonnes of corn mostly from China for September delivery, may need to buy another 250,000 tonnes because of a drought which appears to have blighted the crop on Java.</p>
<p>The crop has taken a pounding from dry conditions believed precipitated by the El Nino weather phenomenon.</p>
<p>&quot;The Indonesians are already looking at new crop corn. If they start buying, that would be the number they're looking at -- 200,000 to 250,000 tonnes,&quot; one dealer said.  </p>
<p>Malaysian feedmills will also be looking to pick up an estimated 100,000 tonnes of corn for September-November delivery and a further 150,000 tonnes for December.</p>
<p>&quot;The 100,000 tonnes for September to November is the minimum the Malaysians will need. I think it will be more than that,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Malaysians are not going to be happy about this. They should be buying soon,&quot; a trader added.</p>
<p>Thailand, on the other hand, is believed to be close to securing most of the 150,000 tonnes of duty-free corn the government has allowed into the country.  </p>
<p>&quot;Their corn harvest is coming in so they will not probably need any new shipments immediately,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>One grains analyst said buyers in Malaysia and Indonesia would try to get Chinese corn, although supplies from there are seen drying up towards the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;For November-December, they will have to look at U.S. corn,&quot; a dealer said. A drought in China would also curb its corn exports going into next year, he added.</p>
<p>In the oilseeds business, bearish USDA numbers and expectations of a bumper soybean harvest in the U.S. drove buyers to the sidelines.  </p>
<p>The USDA forecast a record soybean crop of 2.744 billion bushels, up from from trade expectations of 2.607-2.731 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm pretty comfortable with the bean number. The rain is there, the plants are fine. I think it's (the soybean crop) going to be bigger,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The buyers will say the USDA figures is bearish and ask for really low prices,&quot; another trader said. &quot;They can sit back and wait for prices to come closer to their level.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65) 870-3080; Fax (65) 776-8112</p>
<p>-- Email: singapore.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
