<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798067" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: LONDON ROBUSTAS SEEN DOWN, ASIAN TRADE IN DOLDRUMS.</title>
<headline>LONDON ROBUSTAS SEEN DOWN, ASIAN TRADE IN DOLDRUMS.</headline>
<byline>Rene Pastor</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>London robusta futures are likely to open lower on Wednesday after the sharp fall in New York arabicas, regional coffee dealers said.</p>
<p>They said London should be US$10-$100 lower and prices were likely to fall even further.</p>
<p>The September robusta contract in London slid $110 to end at $1,520 a tonne. September arabicas tumbled 11.15 cents to end at 188.20 U.S. cents a lb after heavy speculative and trade selling.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think you can look at London coming down another $100 easily, especially after New York has done so badly,&quot; a coffee dealer in Singapore said. &quot;I think it will drop down some more.&quot;</p>
<p>Other traders were more cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;By the numbers, it should only be $30 lower. I'm calling it $10 lower,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The Asian coffee trade, however, was very quiet although some Vietnamese exporters were said to have started making offers of a few hundred tonnes for their new crop Grade 2 coffee, 8.0 percent black and broken, dealers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's very, very, very quiet. We're in between seasons. The Indonesian harvest is almost over while people are now just waiting for the Vietnamese crop in November,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think anybody is doing any kind of business at the moment. There's not much happening. The physical side is very quiet,&quot; another said.</p>
<p>Roasters are not expected to make their winter purchases until the end of the month, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The roasters won't come in now. Their people are on holiday,&quot; one said.  </p>
<p>Indonesian exporters may decide to unload some of their beans ahead of the Vietnamese harvest in November in fear that coffee prices may ease further.</p>
<p>&quot;Before the Vietnamese come out, some of the Indonesians will probably sell by then,&quot; one coffee house dealer said.</p>
<p>Other Indonesian coffee farmers waiting for higher prices may be forced to hold onto their beans until next year if futures prices do not firm up soon.</p>
<p>&quot;Those farmers who want to hang onto the beans will probably wait until March next year,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;They don't want to take the loss.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders said offers were beginning to come in from Vietnam.</p>
<p>&quot;The Vietnamese are starting to offer some shipments of a few hundred tonnes,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Another dealer said the Vietnamese want &quot;to test the market to see what kind of prices are there for new crop beans&quot;.</p>
<p>Many traders said they expected a bumper Vietnamese crop with no reports of disease or bad weather so far.</p>
<p>Dealers expected Vietnam to export a record 300,000-320,000 tonnes of robusta beans in the November/February (1997/98) season, up around 10 percent from the previous season.  </p>
<p>&quot;Vietnam's crop is going great. It should easily be up by 10 percent from last year,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65) 870-3305; Fax (65) 776-8112</p>
<p>-- Email: singapore.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
