<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798199" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Aug 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Aug 13.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>HAARETZ</p>
<p>- Assad to Israeli-Arab delegation: I am committed to peace.</p>
<p>- Dennis Ross delays his departure: &quot;Much work remains&quot;.</p>
<p>- Military court issues indictment against Hebron shooter Noam Friedman.</p>
<p>JERUSALEM POST</p>
<p>- Arafat agrees to full security cooperation.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu to meet Hussein in Jordan.</p>
<p>- Assad tells Israeli Arabs all options are open, says Netanyahu is enemy of peace.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister fires Suissa, signs on Reform religious council appointment.</p>
<p>MAARIV</p>
<p>- Assad to Israeli Arabs: &quot;Netanyahu is a strange man; Barak remains committed to peace&quot;.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu's adviser participated in an official lunch on Tisha B'Av Jewish fast day.</p>
<p>- According to new study unattached Israelis have sex less than once a month.</p>
<p>YEDIOTH AHRONOTH</p>
<p>- Netanyahu in secret message to Assad: &quot;The depth of the security arrangements will be matched by the depth of Israel's concessions on the Golan.&quot;</p>
<p>GLOBES</p>
<p>- Police recommend indictments against five key suspects in Paz affair.</p>
<p>- Defence Minister Mordechai wants to raise 1998 deficit target to 2.8 percent.</p>
<p>- Heinekin of Holland froze contacts for joint venture with Tempo until political situation in the Middle East clears up.</p>
<p>- Offers to buy Bank Hapoalim to be made on September 4.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
