<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798202" id="root" date="1997-08-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: OPINION-GERMAN BUILDING SECTOR CRISIS BY S MUETZE.</title>
<headline>OPINION-GERMAN BUILDING SECTOR CRISIS BY S MUETZE.</headline>
<byline>Stefan Muetze</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Construction sector analyst at Landesbank Hesse-Thuringia, Frankfurt</p>
<p>The German construction industry is currently in a crisis -- since the beginning of 1995, both new orders and production have shown a downward trend.</p>
<p>Thus, an upswing that lasted nearly 10 years and whose origins were the favourable economic developments during the second half of the eighties, the clear increase in the population since 1980 and primarily the enormous expansion of demand in the course of German unification, has come to an end.</p>
<p>In 1997, overall building investments are expected to decline by roughly 1.25 percent. This decline is affecting all three sectors of the construction industry. A stabilisation of construction activity is not to be expected before 1998.</p>
<p>Investments in residential construction are expected to decline by only 0.5 percent in 1998, after a likely decline of roughly one percent in the current year.</p>
<p>Currently, only the construction of single-family homes is providing impetus to residential construction.</p>
<p>This will presumably continue to benefit from the improved measures to promote residential property (e.g. building allowance, higher children's allowance for families willing to acquire residential property, improved measures to promote building saving).</p>
<p>The situation in the more important construction ot rental housing is less favourable. Nevertheless, the decline is likely to slow down in 1998. Completions are expected to number about 540,000 in 1997, roughly 60,000 units less than in 1995, the peak of residential construction activity.</p>
<p>After a decline of roughly one percent in the current year, commercial construction is expected to grow at the same rate in 1998. The reason of the again more positive development is above all the gradual increase in investment activities in the corporate sector.</p>
<p>Public construction continues to suffer from spending cuts on the part of the central, regional and local authorities which, as experience has shown, affect building investments in particular.</p>
<p>However, during the second half of 1997, initial impetus is likely to be provided to public construction from the DM 25 billion spending programme decided upon by the Federal Government to boost economic activity.</p>
<p>Thus, public infrastructure measures for an amount of DM 5 billion are intended to be financed by private investors. In addition, there will be interest-subsidised loans by the development agencies Kreditanstalt fuer Wiederaufbau (KfW) and Deutsche Ausgleichsbank (DtA), which are intended to stimulate public construction and residential construction in particular.</p>
<p>Assuming that the interest subsidies are only a minor investment incentive for public-sector principals due to their precarious financial situation, only the privately financed measures are likely to be realised.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the decline in public-sector building investments at two percent and one percent in 1997 and 1998, respectively, is expected to be less pronounced than it would have been without the programme.</p>
<p>Despite the normalisation of construction activity after the unification-induced boom, the need for further construction measures, whose realisation is mostly thwarted due to financial bottlenecks, is still noticeable in Germany.</p>
<p>Thus, several years of restrictive budgetary policies pursued by the central, regional and local authorities have led to accumulating demand for infrastructure investments.</p>
<p>This does not only apply to public buildings, such as schools and universities, but also to sewerage systems as well as to the removal of contaminated soils and environmental damages.</p>
<p>Demand also remains in residential construction, in particular for housing in the lower to medium price range. In eastern Germany, considerable redevelopment measures continue to be necessary.</p>
<p>Over the next few years, much will depend on the possibility to transform the existing need for new construction into effective demand.</p>
<p>In public-sector construction, financing models which include private investors, should be seriously considered. A change in the strained financial situation of the central, regional and local authorities is not likely in the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>Within the framework of build-operate-transfer models, infrastructure projects are completely planned, constructed and operated by private investors. The projects are funded by tolls.</p>
<p>This type of financing however makes sense only for a few large projects, such as important tunnels or bridges. In addition, a partial financing by the government would be conceivable, in order to limit the amount of the toll.</p>
<p>Other financing possibilities are offered by the various leasing models or private investors as dormant partners in public projects, which does not adversely affect the independence of local authorities.</p>
<p>The financing of public tasks is facilitated by these instruments. They are a significant complement to the traditional forms of financing of public-sector investments.</p>
<p>In the residential construction sector, lower construction costs and prices for land are indeed possible; they however require efforts by all those involved - the construction company and service providers, principals, municipalities, the legislature.</p>
<p>The consistent use of prefabricated parts, more efficient planning of construction work and perhaps the assumption of some part of the work by the principal make it possible to lower construction costs considerably.</p>
<p>If land is offered at favourable prices - e.g. by resurrecting the &quot;Erbbaurecht&quot; (a type of building lease) with the option to purchase the land at a later time - this should promote residential construction.</p>
<p>The crisis in the construction industry has already caused some manufacturers of prefabricated houses to offer cheap homes at prices starting at DM 125,000; building leases are sometimes offered.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, there is still pent-up demand in Germany in the field of low-price construction.&quot;</p>
<p>(NOTE: The opinions in this column represent those of the author only. They should not be seen as representing the views of Reuters.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
