<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798500" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: October IPE Brent sags at close with US gasoline.</title>
<headline>October IPE Brent sags at close with US gasoline.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE October Brent shed gains in a late sell-off to finish in negative territory after market leader U.S. gasoline lost impetus.</p>
<p>October Brent ended down eight cents at $19.08 a barrel after hitting an afternoon peak of $19.40.</p>
<p>The expiring September Brent contract finished 20 cents higher on the day at $19.19 a barrel.</p>
<p>Dealers said prices had scaled back after a cent a gallon gain on the leading U.S. unleaded gasoline contract disappeared.</p>
<p>&quot;Gasoline is still the leader but the bulls didn't quite have the taste for it again today,&quot; said a broker.</p>
<p>&quot;There's some concern that gasoline might be due for a correction (lower),&quot; said another.</p>
<p>An outage of Exxon's Baytown, Texas gasoline-making catalytic cracking unit had helped lend support to U.S. gasoline on Wednesdayu and encouraged speculative buying.</p>
<p>Weekly oil inventory data released on Tuesday by the American Petroleum Institute for the week ended August 8 showed U.S. gasoline stocks near historical lows for the time of year.</p>
<p>But an open arbitrage from Europe is starting to attract cross Atlantic gasoline sales, traders said.</p>
<p>Dealers noted that other oil contracts already were becoming increasingly reluctant to follow prompt NYMEX gasoline's premium over the rest of the market.</p>
<p>They said that from a technical standpoint, measuring RSIs and stochastics, IPE oil futures remained neutral to positive.</p>
<p>Earlier IPE gas oil for September ended up $3.75 near the day's high and at a steady $4.09 premium over Brent.</p>
<p>Gas oil traders said plentiful supplies in European storage prevented any early possibility of a run-up in gas oil premiums over crude.</p>
<p>--Richard Mably, London newsroom +44 171 542 6280</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
