<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798550" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - Aug 15.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - Aug 15.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Australian Cricket pace bowler Brendon Julian is unlikely to play in the last Test at The Oval next Thursday, due to a cracked bone in his left wrist. Julian suffered the injury during practice more than a week ago, before the fifth Test at Trent Bridge. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The National Basketball League has announced that draftee C.J. Bruton won't be able to play for the Brisbane Bullets until the player is granted clearance for the release from his former contract with the Perth Wildcats. Bruton was rendered ineligible to be registered as the NBL will not grant clearances to unrestricted players after week ten of the competition. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Sydney Swans Australian Football League captain Tony Lockett will retire from the game at the end of the 1998 season, according to the player's manager Robert Hessian. Swans coach Rodney Eade however, disagrees, and expects Lockett to play for a couple more years. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD Soccer Australia chairman David Hill's handling of an inquiry into Sydney United's involvement in a post-match brawl raised concerns of 'bias' and 'prejudice' according to Justice John Bryson at a New South Wales Supreme Court. Page 44.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Adelaide Thunderbirds netball team's coach Margaret Angrove says the team needs to win tonight's preliminary final against the Sydney Swifts in order to reach next week's grand final against the Melbourne Phoenix's. Page 43</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian racehorse All Our Mob will make a comeback at Rosehill tomorrow quelling fears that the horse would never ride again after his second bout of brain surgery in July 1996. The racehorse has been retired, after suffering travel sickness.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Geelong Australian Football League player Leigh Colbert has been ruled out of this weekend's match after a shoulder injury. The absence of Colbert has raised considerable concern for Geelong after his significant role in beating Carlton in round five. Pag D3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian Football League team Carlton's Greg Williams may play again next season after it was revealed that Williams had a contract with the Blues for 1998. Williams has not yet publicly declared his position with the team due to a continuing legal batte over a nine match suspension with the AFL. Page D3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>National Basketball League North Melbourne player Paul Rees will tonight play in the Giant's clash with the Melbourne Tigers, returning for the first time since surgery to his left knee in March. Rees' return is a surprise, as it was he was not expected to play until next week at the earliest. Page D12.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Australian cricketer Paul Reiffel will miss the final Test against England as he returned home to join his pregnant wife. Despite Reiffel joining the Ashes tour late, and finishing early, he affirmed his position as a superb bowler with 11 wickets at an average of 26.64 and strengthened his all-rounder status by averaging 59.67 batting at No.9. Page 100.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Football League is expected to make a decision within the next couple of days as to whether its television rights will go to Channel Nine or Seven. Network executives met with the AFL yesterday to discuss the rights, which will become free in 2001. Page 110.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Football League has increased the cost of its family membership ticket for 1998, and reduced the number of children it admits. AFL operations manager Ian Collins says survey research indicated that most families have two children and not four, and that the tickets were being wasted. Page 110.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>Queensland Golfer Peter Senior has been withdrawn from the 79th United States PGA Championships at Winged foot after a communications mix-up. Unaware he had received a start in the tournament, Senior was withdrawn when officials learned he was not in New York, but at another event in Asia. Page 122.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian Rugby Super-League chief Ian Frykberg believes that the Australian Rugby League will need the consent of Optus Communications to merge with Super-League in a unified national premiership next year. After talks with ARL chiefs in Sydney, Frykbeg says Optus' A$200 million commitment to the ARL means it will need approval by Optus for the proposed merger. Page 126.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian swimmer Kieren Perkins says he will not consider fellow swimmer Grant Hackett as a serious competitor until Hackett breaks the 15-minute barrier for the 1500 metre freestyle. Page 126.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
