<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798581" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Six Kenya police, 7 civilians killed in Mombasa.</title>
<headline>Six Kenya police, 7 civilians killed in Mombasa.</headline>
<byline>Edmund Kwena</byline>
<dateline>MOMBASA, Kenya 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya police said on Thursday six officers and seven civilians were killed when assailants burned down a police station at the port city of Mombasa, releasing prisoners and stealing firearms.</p>
<p>Residents said dozens of men, working in groups and mostly armed with machetes, attacked two police stations at Likoni on Wednesday night, blocking the ferry to Mombasa until dawn to prevent police sending reinforcements.</p>
<p>The motive for the stunning attack, close to Kenya's favourite tourist beaches on the Indian Ocean, was unclear. Some witnesses said they were local people taking reprisals against Likoni police for alleged brutality.</p>
<p>It was too early to rule out a political or ethnic motive and witnesses said the attackers seemed to be well-organised.</p>
<p>Witnesses said several hundred Kenyans from other parts of the country, mainly Luhya and Luo tribesmen, were leaving the area and heading south.</p>
<p>State television quoted a statement from Minister of State in the Presidency, Jackson Kalweo, as saying the government had launched speedy investigations into the attack and vowed to get to the bottom of the matter.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything possible is being done to get to the root of the attack. The government is determined to arrest those behind this senseless act of violence,&quot; said Kalweo.</p>
<p>A witness told Reuters that there appeared to have been at least five groups behind the Wednesday attack.</p>
<p>&quot;There appeared to have been at least five groups operating simultaneously.</p>
<p>&quot;While four of them engaged the police in a fire-fight, one went on the rampage attacking civilians,&quot; the witness, a medical worker who declined to be quoted by name, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Kenya's police commissioner, Duncan Wachira, was accompanied by top military and security officials when he flew to Mombasa from the capital Nairobi early on Thursday to head inquiries.</p>
<p>A police statement in Mombasa said six officers and two of the arsonists were killed. It said several civilians were seriously hurt and police firearms were stolen.</p>
<p>&quot;A major security operation was immediately launched to net the culprits,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Police sources in Mombasa said they were holding four men suspected of being among the attackers.</p>
<p>Later Kenya's police spokesman, Peter Kimanthi, told reporters in Mombasa the death toll had risen to 13 but the number of dead police officers remained at six.</p>
<p>A Reuters correspondent in Mombasa who visited the morgue at Coast general hospital on Thursday counted the bodies of 10 victims of the violence. At least two were burned policemen.</p>
<p>Several civilians suffered machete wounds but there were no reports of casualties among thousands of foreign tourists in the Mombasa area.</p>
<p>A group of German tourists, heading for a disco by bus, did a fast U-turn at Likoni on Wednesday when they nearly drove into a fusillade, witnesses said.</p>
<p>There was no immediate evidence of any political motive for the attacks. Pre-election tension is high in the East African country and two policemen died in political violence in and near the capital on August 8.</p>
<p>Foreign and Kenyan human rights groups have this year denounced the police as brutal and corrupt. Low pay is one of the reasons with junior officers saying they take home as little as 2,000 shillings ($28) a month for their dangerous work.</p>
<p>Wednesday night's attacks began at about 8.30 p.m.  (1730 GMT) when the assailants struck the tourist police post at Likoni, killing two policemen. The post is at the landing point of the ferry from Mombasa Island, separated from Likoni by a narrow sea channel.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the mob then moved on to the Likoni police station about 300 metres (yards) from the ferry. They set the station on fire, killing at least one policeman, after releasing prisoners held there and stealing weapons.</p>
<p>For several hours they prevented the ferry from Mombasa Island docking at Likoni, blocking police reinforcements.</p>
<p>A petrol station attendant told Reuters three armed men in a Mercedes drove up after the attacks, ordered him to fill up the tank and two jerry-cans and then sped off south towards Tanzania.</p>
<p>The last time the area was hit by serious violence was in December 1992 when the local Digo people attacked settlers from other tribes in a row over a Likoni quarry.</p>
<p>The conflict was linked to tension ahead of the 1992 polls.</p>
<p>Mombasa lies on the Indian Ocean and is about 500 km (310 miles) southeast of Nairobi.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOMBASA, Kenya"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
