<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798642" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Aug 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Aug 14.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Nigerian press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- The Nigerian government is to build airstrips for the 15 new states which have been created since 1991. Official sources put the cost of each airstrip at 20 million naira.</p>
<p>- The Petroleum Trust Fund has called for a list of all the equipment that is needed to make teaching hospitals across the country function properly. So far the fund has already spent five billion naira on the hospitals.</p>
<p>- Large scale redundancies are in the offing at the National Electric Power Authority following allegations of inefficiency and corruption.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>- Charges of incompetence are being made against government-appointed pre-shipment inspectors. Importers say their sloppy handling of inspections is delaying goods and encouraging businesses to use ports in neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>- Ernest Shonekan, chairman of Vision 2010 economic thinktank, says Nigeria needs stable government, reduced corruption, maintenance of law and order and sustainable economic growth if it is to emerge from the woods.</p>
<p>- Economists and bankers say the late release of this year's capital spending grants was untimely and unlikely to resuscitate the economy.</p>
<p>THISDAY</p>
<p>- Son of dead Afrobeat superstar Fela Anikulapo-Kuti says he does not want his father's name to be used to campaign against the spread of AIDS -- the disease from which the popular musician died.</p>
<p>- National Electoral Commission rules out any reduction in the size of the national assembly, which is proposed under the military government's plan to restore civilian rule next year.</p>
<p>- Salary increases for textile workers may threaten the financial position of some firms. The textile workers' union last month forced companies to pay salary increases of 45 percent.</p>
<p>VANGUARD</p>
<p>- Head of State General Sani Abacha has not given anyone the mandate to canvass for his continued stay in office after the planned return to elected government next year, says one of his close aides.</p>
<p>($1=83 naira)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
