<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="79861" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: UK takeover panel says EU plan useless, dangerous.</title>
<headline>UK takeover panel says EU plan useless, dangerous.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British Takeover Panel, which polices mergers and acquisitions, has launched a fierce campaign against plans to impose EU-wide rules on takeover bids, saying they are unnecessary and dangerous.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters this week the panel's director-general Alistair Defriez stressed the fear that a European Commission draft directive on the issue would provide for &quot;tactical litigation&quot; by disgruntled parties.</p>
<p>Defriez advocated, instead, lighter, non-binding, rules such as a recommendation.</p>
<p>&quot;We are worried that parties may be using the oportunity that will be created by the directive to pursue their disputes in takeover bids outside the takeover panel&quot; Defriez said.</p>
<p>He said there was a real danger this would become a defensive tactic to obtain an injunction and delay a bid. Defriez was afraid not only of the British courts -- which have so far discouraged such tactical moves -- but also the European court in Luxembourg which would almost certainly be called to give a final ruling.</p>
<p>The Commission proposed in February a much watered down version of a 10-year attempt to impose common rules on takeover bids. The new draft sets general principles such as equal treatment of all shareholders and the obligation for the board of the target company to abstain from any action that is not in the interest of the company's owners.</p>
<p>Defriez said such principles were already safeguarded in the British non-statutory system and in most other EU states.</p>
<p>Britain is one of the EU's most active countries in the field of mergers and acquisitions. According to Commission figures, British companies are among the most targeted and certainly the most agressive when it comes to bidding for foreign firms.</p>
<p>In what was seen as an attempt to accomodate the British system, the Commission said in the draft directive that national governments were free to implement the directive other than by legislative means.</p>
<p>But Defriez thought governments would transpose it into national laws if adopted to avoid legal interpretation challenges.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be ironic indeed if the directive which is modelled on the takeover code in the UK were introduced and seriously damaged that system,&quot; Defriez said.</p>
<p>The European Parliament legal affairs committee is expected to draft a report on the proposed directive in October to allow for the house to give its first reading at its December session. It is only then that EU ministers are expected to discuss the plan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
