<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="798949" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: INSTANT VIEW - Mexico June IP seen boosting GDP.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Mexico June IP seen boosting GDP.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A higher-than-expected 9.9 percent rise in industrial production in June sparked a rally in the Mexican stock market and suggests strong second quarter gross domestic product (GDP) data next Tuesday, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like GDP will be somewhere between 7 and 8 (percent) given this industrial production figure,&quot; said Rogelio Ramirez de la O, head of Ecanal consultants.</p>
<p>A Reuters survey of 13 economists before the industrial production data saw GDP at 5.92 percent.  </p>
<p>He added that the difference between GDP and IP should not be very large because the services sector has begun to recover and its recovery was accelerating. That will help boost Q2 GDP, he said. &quot;Everyone will be revising up their forecasts.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders in the stock market took the June data positively.</p>
<p>&quot;The market took the industrial production data very well, as soon as it came out there was a lot of buying,&quot; one trader said. The IPC index was up 21.68 points, or 0.43 percent, at 5,038.31.</p>
<p>Graciela Avila, economic advisor at Banamex-Accival financial group, also believed GDP forecasts would be raised because of the industrial performance.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of the (industrial activity) rise can be explained by stronger than expected export figures last week, as exports account for about 35 pct of industrial output. The rest seems to have come from a stronger domestic sector and confirms a recovery on the macroeconomic front,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures suggest that GDP data next week could also be stronger than expected.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9560))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
