<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="799284" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dollar's further rise seen limited in Asia.</title>
<headline>Dollar's further rise seen limited in Asia.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Any further advance by the dollar against the yen is expected to be limited in Asia on Friday after it rose sharply overnight, triggered by strong short-covering of the mark versus the yen, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar/yen was largely driven by technical factors overnight, and at the same time there were no incentives to buy yen,&quot; a Japanese city bank dealer said. &quot;But I think the dollar isn't expected to jump sharply from this level.&quot;</p>
<p>Activity is expected to be thin today with the dollar unlikely to find a clear direction in dollar/yen trade as many Tokyo operators are on their &quot;Obon&quot; summer holidays.  </p>
<p>Dealers said strong technical resistance seen lined up around 118 yen area, while the greenback is expected to be supported around 117.30 yen after rising decisively overnight.</p>
<p>Dealers said that the dollar's rallies against the yen overnight were also exaggerated as many Japanese exporters and other Japanese operators were out on vacation.</p>
<p>Concern that a Southeast Asian currency crisis may hurt Japan's fragile economy depressed the yen overnight.</p>
<p>A broad yen slump commenced after Indonesia announced a de facto float of its currency on Thursday, following similar action by neighbouring countries in recent weeks.  </p>
<p>Bundesbank vice president Johann Wilhelm Gaddum, in an interview with the German newspaper Handelsblatt, said the German central bank was concerned about inflation and wanted the freedom to act.</p>
<p>Gaddum also reiterated that Bundesbank policy is not driven by foreign exchange developments, but added they were keeping a close eye for any &quot;exaggerated&quot; moves.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market should be a bit cautious about selling the mark aggressively after the comments by Gaddum and the Bundesbank's monthly report on Wednesday which warned that the pace of inflation has picked up.  </p>
<p>Dealers said that the dollar was expected to be under downward pressure should it climb above 1.8450 marks.</p>
<p>The mark advanced sharply overnight on heavy short-covering and stop-loss buying. A clear break above 63.50 yen also intensified the German currency's upward trend, dealers said.</p>
<p>However, Japanese exporters may show some selling interest in the mark above 64.00 yen. In the short term, the mark is expected to trade in a range of 63.80 to 64.30 yen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
