<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="799324" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Investors see Ka Wah as new red chip conglomerate.</title>
<headline>Investors see Ka Wah as new red chip conglomerate.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ka Wah Bank Ltd took centre stage in the Hong Kong stock market on Thursday, with its shares surging to records as investors speculated that the bank could become a new diversified flagship of China parent CITIC.</p>
<p>Ka Wah Bank, 61.25 percent owned by China International Trust and Investment Corp (CITIC), said it was considering a proposal which would make it a wholly-owned subsidiary of a new holding company to be incorporated in Bermuda.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be easier for the holding company, based in Bermuda, to take any other assets,&quot; said Alan Hutcheson, a banking analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;Ka Wah, under the banking ordinance, could be restricted in what it buys,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Ka Wah Bank shares rose HK$2.25, or 20.64 percent, to close at HK$13.15 just a touch lower than their intra-day record of HK$13.20 hit earlier.</p>
<p>The stock topped the most actives list with 87.93 million shares traded, worth HK$1.08 billion.</p>
<p>Buying was mainly fuelled by market talk that CITIC was ready to inject assets into the new holding company and expand the new company, said Stanley Ng, research manager at Mansion House Research.</p>
<p>&quot;People think it will become a new flagship for CITIC,&quot; added another analyst.</p>
<p>Ka Wah's business was not particularly exciting, since the bank was involved in a lot of syndication business in China, and what was driving the stock was restructuring hopes rather than fundamentals, the analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is trading at 30 times consensus earnings and it is no longer within the realm of regular banking,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>CITIC, which is under the direct supervision of China's State Council, lowered its stake in CITIC Pacific Ltd to 26.45 percent from 41.92 percent in early 1997 following a management buyout.</p>
<p>Ben Kwong, director of research at Dharmala Securities, said investors were hoping Ka Wah Bank would become more diversified, &quot;something like building up a new CITIC Pacific&quot;.</p>
<p>CITIC Pacific is a blue chip conglomerate with a market capitalisation of HK$110 billion.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
