<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="799412" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Nurses' Saudi lawyer sees court news within week.</title>
<headline>Nurses' Saudi lawyer sees court news within week.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Drees</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The lawyer for two British nurses on trial for the murder of an Australian colleague in Saudi Arabia said on Thursday he expected news from the court within a week but doubted it would be a verdict.</p>
<p>Sources close to the case had said a ruling in the murder trial of Deborah Parry, 38, and Lucille McLauchlan, 31, could be issued as soon as Sunday. The court adjourned on August 10, and lawyers representing the victim's family said the judges were deliberating on the verdict.</p>
<p>&quot;We are expecting news from the court within the next week,&quot; Saudi lawyer Salah al-Hejailan told Reuters by telephone from the United States, where he is on a business trip.</p>
<p>&quot;In theory it could be a verdict. What is more likely is that the court will make a ruling on the confessions or simply pass the case on to a higher court,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Parry and McLauchlan say they are innocent and have withdrawn confessions they said were made under duress.</p>
<p>The women were arrested on charges of murder after the body of Yvonne Gilford, 55, was discovered in her room at the King Fahd medical complex in the eastern Saudi city of Dhahran in December. She had been stabbed, bludgeoned and suffocated.</p>
<p>If the court finds them guilty of any charge, the case would go through an elaborate appeals system in the kingdom, which applies strict Islamic laws including beheading by the sword for murderers, drug smugglers and rapists.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think they (the court) will say anything about a death penalty or anything of that nature,&quot; Hejailan said. &quot;They will just refer the case to a higher court.&quot;</p>
<p>Lawyers for the victim's family were not available for comment.</p>
<p>According to Saudi law, the victim's immediate family -- her mother Muriel and brother Frank -- have authority to demand an execution if the defendants are found guilty and the court rules the death penalty is appropriate.</p>
<p>Frank Gilford has repeatedly said he prefers the maximum punishment, though an Australian court last week temporarily barred him from calling for the death penalty.</p>
<p>Defence lawyers said they had given the court a copy of a medical report showing Gilford's mother was not mentally competent, making her unable to agree with her son's call for an execution.</p>
<p>Legal experts in Saudi Arabia say an Australian court would have to appoint Muriel a guardian -- other than Frank -- to act on her behalf.</p>
<p>Hejailan said a demand for the death penalty had to be unanimous.</p>
<p>The U.S.-educated lawyer said he was taking steps in Australia to prevent Frank from demanding capital punishment.</p>
<p>&quot;I am suing him in a new case, which was filed yesterday (Wednesday) to prevent him from asking for the death penalty in Saudi Arabia because it is against the public law in Australia,&quot; Hejailan said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
