<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="799430" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UPS chief indicates new flexibility in strike.</title>
<headline>UPS chief indicates new flexibility in strike.</headline>
<byline>David Lawsky</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Parcel Service and Teamsters officials met Thursday to try to settle the nation's biggest strike in 27 years as UPS Chairman James Kelly said his company might soften its previous unbending stance.</p>
<p>Kelly had declared the dispute at an impasse Wednesday but in an interview Thursday he struck a more conciliatory tone on pensions and whether UPS's &quot;final&quot; offer was negotiable.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the pension issue is very important for both our people and the future of our company, but as I said there is no one or two single issues that will determine whether we're able to reach agreement,&quot; he told wire service reporters in a telephone interview from Atlanta.</p>
<p>Kelly also said that if progress came out of Thursday's talks, which were billed as informal, that may lead UPS eventually to drop what it has called its &quot;last, best and final&quot; offer.</p>
<p>&quot;If those informal discussions lead us to believe that the negotiations could be concluded at some point in time, then the last, best and final offer would cease to exist,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In addition to a dispute over adding more full-time jobs, UPS has insisted on establishing a new pension fund covering only UPS workers to replace the existing fund covering Teamster workers at dozens of firms, mostly trucking lines.</p>
<p>The strike has crippled UPS, the nation's largest package delivery company, and sent thousands of businesses scrambling to ship their goods.</p>
<p>Kelly's comments may open the way for a pact to end the strike by 185,000 sorters, loaders and drivers, now in its 11th day, which UPS says is costing it $300 million a week. The company is shipping about 10 percent of its normal 12 million packages a day.</p>
<p>While Kelly was talking with reporters, federal mediator John Calhoun Wells was meeting in a Washington hotel with Teamster President Ron Carey and UPS negotiator Dave Murray, who met face to face for the first time since Saturday.</p>
<p>Labor Secretary Alexis Herman was nearby in case her help was needed, a Labor Department spokesman said. But Herman -- who persuaded the parties to return to the table -- did not directly involve herself in the talks.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton has decided not to intervene in the strike, the largest since the postal workers' strike of 1970, but the administration is closely watching its effects.</p>
<p>Carey said Wednesday he doubted Thursday's meeting would end the strike. &quot;While there is no reason for optimism at this point, we will be there, ready to negotiate a reasonable agreement that provides the good jobs that American families need,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The two sides had hardened their positions Tuesday, when the AFL-CIO labor group said it would provide loans to cover the $10 million in weekly pay for striking workers while UPS warned it would cut 15,000 jobs due to lost business.</p>
<p>In another potential problem for UPS, the head of the union representing the company's pilots said they might strike near Christmas in an unrelated pay dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;A strike could potentially occur close to Christmas,&quot; Independent Pilots Association President Robert Miller told a news conference. IPA members are already refusing to cross Teamsters picket lines, grounding UPS planes.</p>
<p>About 2,000 IPA members normally fly UPS' fleet of 500 planes. They had been working without a contract since December 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
