<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="799599" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MGE spring wheat end lower on commercial selling.</title>
<headline>MGE spring wheat end lower on commercial selling.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>MGE spring wheat futures closed lower, weakened by commercial selling as harvesting in North Dakota slowly began to gather pace, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the selling was partly pre-hedging with commercials selling futures in the expectation of buying newly harvested spring wheat in the cash market.</p>
<p>The North Dakota Agricultural Statistics Service earlier this week reported the state's hard red spring wheat harvest was five percent complete as of Sunday, in line with both last year's pace and the five-year average.</p>
<p>They noted some support from news that U.S. weekly net export sales were estimated by USDA at 641,700 tonnes, slightly stronger than expected and talk that U.S. supplies remain very competitively priced.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got the most (wheat) so we should be the cheapest and should do the business,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>They noted featured sellers included of September included Prudential Securities and Benson Quinn.</p>
<p>September closed off 3-1/4 cents a bushel at $3.88. Other months were down four to six cents.</p>
<p>Volume on spring wheat totalled 18.6 million bushels, down from 24.4 million on Wednesday.</p>
<p>((-Nigel Hunt 312-408 8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
