<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="799727" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CIA slayings suspect eyes Pakistan for defense.</title>
<headline>CIA slayings suspect eyes Pakistan for defense.</headline>
<byline>Jim Wolf</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two months after being snatched back from Pakistan, the lone suspect in a 1993 shooting spree outside CIA headquarters is reaching back to his homeland to build his defense.</p>
<p>The court-appointed lawyer for Mir Aimal Kansi, the 33-year-old suspect from Quetta, Pakistan, said in court papers filed this week that Pakistan was the site of &quot;virtually all mitigation evidence.&quot;</p>
<p>The defense attorney, Richard Goemann, has asked the judge for funds to send a lawyer and an investigator to Pakistan ahead of the capital murder trial due to start Nov. 3.</p>
<p>Judge J. Howe Brown of the Fairfax County Circuit court has scheduled a pre-trial hearing Monday to consider this and other defense requests, including one for more time to prepare.</p>
<p>The prosecution has not yet spelled out Kansi's alleged motives for the Jan. 25, 1993, rampage. But some U.S. officials have suggested he bore an old grudge against the CIA for some unspecified injury to his family, one of Quetta's wealthiest clans.</p>
<p>In the 1980s, as the Soviet Union battled to control neighboring Afghanistan, Quetta was a city of spies and intrigue. The CIA worked through Pakistani military officers, some based in Quetta, to pump millions of dollars of weapons to anti-Soviet guerrillas.</p>
<p>Kansi is accused of firing an AK-47-type assault rifle at drivers waiting to turn into the spy agency's main gate in Langley, Virginia, before returning to Pakistan as a fugitive. Two CIA employees were shot to death; three commuters were wounded.</p>
<p>The prosecutor in the case, Fairfax County Commonwealth Attorney Robert Horan, has said he will seek the death penalty.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Horan has been caught up in pre-trial maneuvering over a comment he made that prompted anti-American demonstrations in Pakistan. Discussing the prosecution in a television interview, he referred to the $2 million U.S. reward that may have led to Kansi's capture in June.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure there are people over there who would turn in their mother for $20,000, let alone $2 million,&quot; he had said, according to a transcript of the interview.</p>
<p>Seizing on the scattered anti-American demonstrations prompted by the remark in Quetta and Karachi, the defense now claims that one of the reasons it needs more time is that anti-American sentiment in Pakistan has made it too dangerous for a defense team to travel there.</p>
<p>&quot;Defense counsel should not be placed in the position of having to choose between effectively representing Kansi by sending representatives to Pakistan and putting employees of the Public Defender Office in the path of unnecessary danger,&quot; Goeman argued in court papers.</p>
<p>The defense's proposed trip to Pakistan could be to gather evidence to substantiate any future insanity plea among other possible defenses, said Gerald Lefcourt of New York, president of the National Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers.</p>
<p>The defense may also be reaching back to Kansi's home in preparation for persuading a jury against imposing the death penalty in the event of conviction.</p>
<p>&quot;You must always remain conscious of the sentencing phase,&quot; said Drew Findling, an Atlanta lawyer and co-chairman of the forensic evidence committee of the criminal lawyers' group.</p>
<p>While the prosecution had to prove any aggravating factors that might lead the jury to sentence a defendant to death, the defense must try to show &quot;reasons why the client should be spared from the ultimate penalty,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;So they're going to need access to Pakistan so they can review his entire history from birth,&quot; Findling added. He said that a review of any possible Kansi clan ties to the CIA might also be relevant.</p>
<p>&quot;To the extent that any of that would contribute to any conceivable defense -- whether it be a mental health defense or whether it be some other type of defense -- they'll clearly need access to Pakistan to bring life to any claim like that,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
