<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="799777" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Global Marine says not agreed to lower rates.</title>
<headline>Global Marine says not agreed to lower rates.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global Marine Inc said that it had not agreed to lower dayrates for two jackup rigs under contract to Unocal Corp.</p>
<p>Shares in Global and other offshore drilling concerns declined earlier Thursday amid speculation that some exploration and production companies were balking at higher charges for rigs, especially shallow-water jackup rigs.</p>
<p>However, David Herasimchuk vice president in charge of marketing at Global, said over the telephone: &quot;In neither case have we agreed lower dayrates. Global shares were down 1-5/8 to 26-1/4 in early afternoon, after falling as low as 25-5/8.  </p>
<p>Of the two rigs, one would have a gap of 30 to 60 days between contracts, and the other was looking for a new contract, although both will be drilling to the end of this month, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We may have news on a contract for the second rig as early as tomorrow,&quot; Herasimchuk said.</p>
<p>He said talk of lower dayrates often hits the sector ahead of a Texas lease sale -- and one is approaching -- as companies prepare to bid on new leases.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think that this has nothing to do with project economics.... What is happening is operators are getting prepared for the Texas sale,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The drop by drilling stocks was not confined to the jackup sector, but also hit those companies that concentrate on the deepwater.</p>
<p>&quot;The story on jackups has been developing for a while and we have been cautious on that sector for some time, but all companies are being tarred with the same brush,&quot; Iain Smith of Eastgate Management said.</p>
<p>Among deepwater drillers, Diamond Offshore Drilling Inc was down 1-7/8 at 86-1/8, Atwood Oceanics Inc was off 2-15/16 at 82-1/2, having traded as low at 81-15/16, and Transocean Offshore was down 7/16 at 81-5/8, having traded as low as 79-1/8.</p>
<p>Among the jackup operators, Marine Drilling Cos Inc fell 1-1/15 at 20-13/16.</p>
<p>((David Chance New York Newsroom 212 859 1902))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
