<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="799955" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIAN RUPEE ENDS UP VS DLR IN SPOT, QUIET IN FWD.</title>
<headline>INDIAN RUPEE ENDS UP VS DLR IN SPOT, QUIET IN FWD.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian rupee ended Thursday stronger at 35.7125/7175 per dollar against opening quotes of 35.725/730 in two-way trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said the rupee initially weakened on corporate demand but dollar sales by exporters helped it rally.</p>
<p>The rupee traded at a high of 35.7175 and a low of 35.73 per dollar on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;There was some demand from Bombay-based foreign banks and this pushed the rupee down initially,&quot; said a dealer at a state-run bank.</p>
<p>&quot;State Bank of India was also bidding. But later on there were good dollar sales from exporters which helped the rupee end stronger than opening quotes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The dealer said Thursday's fluctuations in the exchange rate were on expected lines.</p>
<p>&quot;We knew there would be some demand ahead of the extended weekend and also that exporters will sell at higher levels,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The forex market is closed on Friday as banks are shut for the Independence Day holiday. The market reopens on Monday.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rupee was little changed against the forward dollar in quiet, range-bound trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Rates went up marginally on tighter domestic liquidity,&quot; said a dealer at a state-run bank.</p>
<p>The annualised premium on six-month dollars ended at 4.59 percent against its previous close of 4.53 percent.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom (91) 22-265 9000;Fax (91) 22 264 1699</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
