<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800263" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: What breaking FTSE 5,000 may mean for UK brokers.</title>
<headline>What breaking FTSE 5,000 may mean for UK brokers.</headline>
<byline>John Hanley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bigger bonuses and more job offers.</p>
<p>That's what British stockbrokers, traders and sales people can hope for this year as they enjoy summer vacations with the London FTSE 100 share index rocketing to all-time highs, industry sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>However, as the 10-year anniversary of the global stock market crash looms in October, the mood is more tempered and geared to deferred compensation, in hopes of avoiding the &quot;hire-and-fire&quot; churning seen in the &quot;yuppie&quot; 1980s.</p>
<p>The blue-chip FTSE index has surged 24 percent so far this year to a record 5,095.3, touched last week. At 1413 GMT, it was trading at 4,997.9.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't noticed a surge in hiring because the FTSE has gone through 5,000, but admittedly there is a lot more confidence and I've noticed people are more confident to call and say they are looking for a job,&quot; said Justin McLennan, senior consultant at headhunters Jonathon Wren Search and Selection.</p>
<p>&quot;Salaries have been going up anyway over the last couple of years and I would expect that because of the market, that will continue. But I don't expect a dramatic rise in salaries...People are a lot more cautious now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>By the estimates of one remuneration consultant in the City, London's financial district, pay packages should be at least similar to a year ago, assuming the stock market does not spin lower the next few months.</p>
<p>In 1996, the head of trading or sales at a European firm made about 100,000-120,000 pounds ($190,000) in base salary, and the equity division head 150,000 to 200,000 pounds, this consultant said. The bonus would equal one to two times that salary, he said.</p>
<p>At a U.S. investment house in London, a trading or sales head earned on average 80,000 pounds, with the annual bonus equal to four or five times that, he said.</p>
<p>Deferred compensation, such as options, could equal another 100 percent of base pay, he estimated.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly the bull market is having an effect on remuneration levels, primarily through bonus payments,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Staff movement is expected to pick up as analysts and sales traders look for the highest bidder, sources said.</p>
<p>Indeed, on Thursday, BZW, the investment banking arm of Barclays Plc, said it had hired three analysts, one from Natwest Securities and another from Cridit Lyonnais Securities.</p>
<p>Roger Monson, chief equity strategist at Daiwa, who has been covering the Western European markets since 1986, said the atmosphere in the City could heat up to that of 10 years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of movement and I think bonuses have been noticeably larger than a year ago and a lot larger than two years ago,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The business of the City is making money and individuals take that on board personally.&quot;</p>
<p>Bonuses are normally paid after the end of the fiscal year.</p>
<p>Monson added, &quot;I would say the appointment pages in the financial newspapers are a little fatter than I would have thought a year ago, both the number of ads and the numbers quoted in the ads.&quot;</p>
<p>A survey by the Confederation of British Industry and accountants Coopers &amp; Lybrand, in July, said jobs in Britain's financial services sector would likely grow by six percent in the three months ended in September.</p>
<p>Securities traders and fund managers in the previous three months reported the sector's largest rises in employment, it showed.</p>
<p>The healthy City comes against the backdrop of the lowest jobless rate in Britain in 17 years.</p>
<p>The Office for National Statistics said on Wednesday that the unemployment rate in July fell to 5.5 percent from 5.7 percent.</p>
<p>Notwithstanding pay in financial services, the growth in average earnings, an important barometer of future inflationary trends, remained steady in June at 4.25 percent.</p>
<p>The remuneration consultant, ironically, called for a sharper focus on &quot;softer issues&quot;, such as working environment and management styles.</p>
<p>&quot;I just question how much longer you can carry on focusing purely and simply on how much you're paying people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 4366 ($ = 0.630 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
