<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800239" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: THE PROTEUS COLUMN - LIBERALISATION.</title>
<headline>THE PROTEUS COLUMN - LIBERALISATION.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN</p>
<p>Insurance liberalisation has always been something of a high wire act, but with a cautious step and the right balance a good landing has always seemed certain.</p>
<p>Recent political, economic and competitive developments in Asia though seem to be combining to make the wire walk tougher.</p>
<p>Last week India's parliament rejected legislation that would have paved the way for the break up of its state monopolies.</p>
<p>After years of waiting for a breakthrough in India, the abandonment of the Insurance Regulatory Authority Bill means would-be entrants will have to wait longer.</p>
<p>Thailand, meanwhile, has been hit by a financial crisis so great that potential market entrants have started to run for cover.</p>
<p>A run on the baht and a crisis in the financial sector has put the plans of most of the 28 new insurance license holders revealed in March on hold.</p>
<p>And, in Japan, a row is brewing over plans by one domestic firm to enter the lucrative, foreign-dominated niche product sector by acquiring a foreign insurer's life unit.</p>
<p>The positive news is that while the height of the wire has been raised significantly, the safety net has not yet been taken away.</p>
<p>In India, insurers are hopeful the draft insurance law can be revived by the year end, or by the 1998 budget -- although entrance permits remain further off than that.</p>
<p>Pressure is mounting on the Indian government to increase inward investment. Insurance will be needed to cover the resulting exposures. The logic cannot be ignored forever.</p>
<p>And, while the Thai crisis might have rocked some of the potential entrants, for the 60 plus players already in the market the near economic collapse of the country is serving to sort the wheat from the chaff.</p>
<p>Those who are not serious about being in the insurance business for the long term are going to get out and those who thought about getting in for short term gain will find it difficult to raise the capital to do so.</p>
<p>The net effect will be to lend some strength to the real players and help them harden rates which is much needed in Bangkok.</p>
<p>As for Japan, the players most upset by the Yasuda takeover of Cigna's INA Himawari Life are its non-life sector competitors who didn't think of it first.</p>
<p>The foreigners will tolerate a Japanese entrant in their niche because the level of premiums they expect to tap when the rest of the market opens far outweighs the three percent of total market volume they can now access.</p>
<p>Liberalisation might be something of a circus at the moment, but if the ringmasters of reform can keep their act together, there is every chance that Asia's great insurance liberalisation show will go on.</p>
<p>			    --OO0OO--</p>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN is an insight piece produced by Reuters journalists based on their own research and interpretations. While it aims to be as accurate and incisive as possible, it does not necessarily reflect the views of Reuters.</p>
<p>	   **************************************</p>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN appears in the GLOBAL INSURANCE NEWS SUMMARY every weekday on Reuters Insurance Briefing. For enquiries, contact -</p>
<p>Gordon Mackenzie, Editor, London</p>
<p>Tel: 44 171 542 2770</p>
<p>Fax 44 171 542 2583</p>
<p>e-mail gordon.mackenzie@reuters.com</p>
<p>John Sanders, News Editor, London</p>
<p>Tel: 44 171 542 2769</p>
<p>e-mail john.sanders@reuters.com</p>
<p>		****************************************</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
