<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800230" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FINNISH INDUSTRY OUTPUT GROWTH BRISK TO END-97 - TT.</title>
<headline>FINNISH INDUSTRY OUTPUT GROWTH BRISK TO END-97 - TT.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish industrial production growth is expected to remain brisk until the end of this year and profitability to improve in the year ahead, a big industrial lobby said in a quarterly survey on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Output and exports in manufacturing industry and construction will continue to grow briskly in the coming months,&quot; the Confederation of Finnish Industry and Employers (TT) said.</p>
<p>&quot;The most positive business cycle expectations are in the basic metal industry and the electronics and electrical industries,&quot; TT said.</p>
<p>But the mechanical forest industry's outlook was clouded by expectations of a weakening business cycle, the lobby said.</p>
<p>&quot;Growth has been considerable in the electronics and electrical industry, the base metal industry and in construction. Recent months have seen no further increase in production in the mechanical forest products industry,&quot; TT said.</p>
<p>The chemical industry, on the other hand, expected accelerating output growth in the remaining months of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The two last quarters have shown an improvement in the profitability of industrial companies,&quot; TT said, referring to Q1 and Q2 this year.</p>
<p>In general, industrial companies saw profitability improving, although in mid-July, at the time of the survey, profitability was still weaker than a year earlier in some sectors, including the base metal industry, mechanical engineering and the paper industry.</p>
<p>&quot;It is reckoned that in a year's time, profitability will be higher than at present except in the mechanical forest products industry,&quot; TT said.</p>
<p>An 18-month fall in sales prices seemed to have come to an end although prices had continued to fall in the paper, electronics and electrical industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices are expected to show a moderate increase in industry in the near future,&quot; TT said, adding expectations in this respect were greatest in construction and the paper industry.</p>
<p>Costs were expected to rise in step with sales prices, TT said.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +358-9-6805 0248, news@Reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
