<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800452" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks jump on more good news about inflation.</title>
<headline>Stocks jump on more good news about inflation.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stock prices soared in early trading Thursday on more good news about inflation, this time at the consumer level.</p>
<p>Shortly after 10 a.m. EDT, the Dow Jones industrial average was up 18.12 points at 7,946.44, after earlier climbing more than 60 points.</p>
<p>The government reported that consumer prices posted a modest increase last month, continuing a pattern of subdued price increases.</p>
<p>The Consumer Price Index edged up 0.2 percent in July after rising 0.1 percent in June. The so-called &quot;core&quot; rate of inflation, which leaves out the often-erratic food and energy measures, also rose 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>The increase matched Wall Street expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;The number is just as expected -- it's good news for the markets,&quot; said Sherry Cooper, chief economist, Nesbitt Burns. &quot;At least we didn't get a nasty shock, and on the heels of yesterday's PPI decline, this should cause the markets to breathe a sigh of relief.&quot;</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the government said the Producer Price Index for July fell 0.1 percent, following an identical drop in June. Without the volatile food and energy components, wholesale prices also fell by 0.1 percent. It was the seventh straight month of declines in wholesale prices.</p>
<p>The inflation-sensitive bond market also rose, with the benchmark 30-year Treasury bond up 16/32, which lowered its yield to 6.59 percent from Wednesday's close of 6.63 percent. Bond prices and yields move in opposite directions.</p>
<p>The inflation numbers come just days before the Federal Reserve's policy-setting Federal Open Market Committee meets next Tuesday.</p>
<p>Wall Street is betting that the absence of inflationary pressures should help convince the Fed to keep interest rates steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
