<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800613" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SAFETY BOARD TO WEIGH VALUJET REPORT NEXT WEEK.</title>
<headline>SAFETY BOARD TO WEIGH VALUJET REPORT NEXT WEEK.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A final report on the crash of a ValuJet plane that killed 110 people last year will be considered by the National Transportation Safety Board next Tuesday, a board spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The DC-9 plunged into the Florida Everglades on May 11, 1996, killing all 110 people on board.</p>
<p>NTSB staff have prepared a draft report on the facts and probable cause of the incident.</p>
<p>Preliminary reports have indicated the crash was caused by a fierce fire in the cargo hold fueled by oxygen-generating canisters that were improperly handled and labeled.</p>
<p>The Federal Aviation Administration was sharply criticized after the crash for its lax oversight of the budget carrier.</p>
<p>In its final report, the NTSB is also expected to be critical of Valujet and SabreTech Corp., the contractor that handled the oxygen generators.</p>
<p>The accident led to changes at the FAA, including closer scrutiny of new, rapidly expanding carriers.</p>
<p>Bulk transport of oxygen generators, which are considered relatively safe when located above passengers for emergency oxygen, was restricted to all-cargo flights.</p>
<p>New regulations requiring the fitting of smoke alarms and fire suppression systems in cargo holds also got a push from the crash.</p>
<p>Aviation safety sources believe the fire may have started before the ValuJet plane even took off and a smoke alarm could have warned the crew.</p>
<p>New FAA administrator, Jane Garvey, has asked for a progress report on the implementation of recommendations that flowed from a special 90-day safety review last year.</p>
<p>Areas slated for re-examination include the oversight of new airlines and increasing the number of safety inspectors at critical locations.</p>
<p>ValuJet is to merge shortly with AirWays Corp and will be renamed AirTran Airlines.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
