<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800790" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: New euro may be sound swap for weak mark - analysts.</title>
<headline>New euro may be sound swap for weak mark - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Kate Kelland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>With the deutschemark spiralling lower against the dollar, German promises that the euro single currency will be &quot;as strong as the mark&quot; are beginning to look odd.</p>
<p>Yet many traders and analysts have blamed the recent acceleration in the mark's decline partly on growing speculation that the euro will in fact be a soft currency.</p>
<p>But some economists are beginning to baulk at the 'broad EMU equals soft euro' equation, arguing that the euro will be more sturdy than the deutschemark has been for some time.</p>
<p>&quot;Telling people that the new European currency is going to be as strong as the weakest major currency on earth is not going to reassure anybody,&quot; said Chris Golden, head of fixed income research at Nomura in London.</p>
<p>Indeed, there is far more effective ammunition to fire at the 'soft euro' camp.</p>
<p>&quot;Cyclical conditions will dominate,&quot; said Darren Williams, economist at UBS in London. While current European growth rates are nothing spectacular, he said, by late 1998 certain potential euro economies will be ticking along nicely with the need for inflation-fighting monetary tightening much greater.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we are pretty sceptical about German rates going higher in the short term, clearly over the next 18 months they are going to head up, and that is more true for the other countries likely to be invloved in the euro.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The pressure on interest rates in the second half of next year and through to 1999 will be quite strongly upwards -- that will favour a strong euro in the early phase of its existence.&quot;</p>
<p>One of the most significant shifts to a 'soft euro' expectation came as the German government made a bid to revalue Bundesbank gold reserves and take a one-off profit to help meet the Maastricht Treaty's demand for a three percent budget deficit to gross domestic product ratio.</p>
<p>The attempt failed. But along with concern about a fiscally-lax left-wing French government and doubts about a number of one-off steps by European governments to cut deficit, markets took Germany's apparent shift to a softer EMU line as another signal that a broad group of untrustworthy economies would form the new single currency.</p>
<p>Markets saw the prospect of a large group of EMU starters -- perhaps including Spain, Portugal, Italy -- as a sign that the euro, due for launch on January 1, 1999, would be less stable and weaker than if the starting group comprised a more exclusive group of traditionally stable currencies.</p>
<p>The 'hard euro' camp, however, say it is wrong to assume that the new currency will be no more than the sum of its old parts.</p>
<p>&quot;This is something very new, and very different,&quot; said Alison Cottrell, chief international economist at PaineWebber.</p>
<p>The strength and the stability of any currency depends largely on the ability of its central bank to foster the confidence of financial markets by controlling inflation without hampering growth.</p>
<p>Granted, the future European Central Bank, which will take over monetary control in January 1999, has no track record.</p>
<p>But there is little evidence to suggest the ECB will conduct an easier monetary policy if, for instance, the EMU starting group includes 12 countries, than it would if only six countries were in the first round.</p>
<p>&quot;People have tended to think that with a narrow EMU, the ECB would be very hawkish, but with the traditionally weaker currencies added, it would take a more dovish stance,&quot; said Williams. &quot;In fact...the affect will be exactly the opposite.&quot;</p>
<p>Cottrell pointed to 'newly' independent central banks -- such as the Bank of England -- who tend to err to a tight monetary stance when credibility needs to be established. The BoE has raised rates at every opportunity since it won control of interest rates in May, and sterling has rocketed.</p>
<p>&quot;When a central bank has to get off from a standing start on the credibility stakes, it does not make mistakes in a relaxed direction, it would only make mistakes in a tighter direction,&quot; Cottrell said.</p>
<p>&quot;The ECB will inherit a period of very low interest rates which have been that way for a very long time. Everyone will be watching the ECB, so it almost has to make gesture, and it cannot afford to look softer than the Bundesbank might have looked in that position.&quot;</p>
<p>Nomura's Golden said the onus was on those who argue that a broad EMU will give birth to a weak euro to explain their case.</p>
<p>&quot;The euro is a very much more attractive investment currency than the mark, purely in terms of its liquidity, and will be a seriously more attractive invoicing currency for world trade.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Those two factors alone are enough to generate a vast amount of floating demand for the euro.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
