<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800970" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: L.LEASE SAYS PROFITS UP IN ALL UNITS.</title>
<headline>L.LEASE SAYS PROFITS UP IN ALL UNITS.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Property and financial services group Lend Lease Corp Ltd said on Thursday all of its units had profit rises in the year to June 30. The group reported a 15 percent rise in net profit to A$322 million in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Lend Lease said its funds management and life insurance operations contributed a profit of A$168 million in 1996/97, compared with A$152 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>It said significant progress had been made toward achieving the 40 percent unit cost reduction goal over the three years to June 1999. Expenses to funds under management in 1997 were 1.6 percent compared with 2.0 percent in 1996.  </p>
<p>Investment performance was strong due to the strength of investment markets, especially the equities market, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;These results clearly indicate a successful year for this division and the level of profitability is expected to continue,&quot; Lend Lease said. It said the financial services division had established a business development office in Singapore to investigate business opportunities in the region.</p>
<p>The company's joint venture with Sinar Mas's unit PT Bank Internasional Indonesia was now Indonesia's largest funds manager, it said. Funds under management grew to A$600 million from A$310 million since December 1996.  </p>
<p>Lend Lease said its real estate investment services division's contribution to group's profit after tax totalled A$21 million in 1996/97 compared with A$18 million a year earlier. It said the property services, project management and development contributed A$26 million to the 1996/97 net profit, compared with A$24 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>The group said profits from its equity investments totalled A$105 million in 1996/97 compared with A$74 million a year ago.</p>
<p>It said these profits included dividends received from Mirvac Ltd, IBM Global Services Australia Ltd, Westpac Banking Corp and Hoyts Cinemas Ltd.  </p>
<p>Lend Lease said it received A$2 million in dividend payments from Mirvac, A$4 million from IBM Global, its joint venture with International Business Machines Inc and Telstra Corp, and A$57 million from Westpac.</p>
<p>The result also included profits from the sale of 15 million Westpac shares at A$7.00 per share and 10.5 million Hoyts shares at A$2.00 per share.</p>
<p>At 11.40 a.m. (0140 GMT), Lend Lease shares were 39 cents up at A$29.15.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
