<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800983" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan bankruptcies up despite recovery assurances.</title>
<headline>Japan bankruptcies up despite recovery assurances.</headline>
<byline>Ayumi Moriyama</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of Japanese firms going bankrupt continued to rise in July despite government assurances of economic recovery, a research firm said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The situation could worsen in coming months with further insolvencies in the troubled construction sector, Tokyo Shoko Research said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;Nearly 60 percent of insolvencies in July were recession-related, despite the government's announcement that the economy was gradually recovering,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The total number of companies that went under rose five percent from a year earlier to 1,301, topping the 1,300 level for a fifth consecutive month, the report said.</p>
<p>It said debt held by bankrupt firms soared 158 percent from July 1996 to 1.13 trillion yen ($9.8 billion), the highest ever for the month.</p>
<p>The figure was pushed up by insolvencies at two medium-sized general contractors.</p>
<p>Tokai Kogyo Co Ltd failed with debts of 511 billion yen ($4.44 billion) followed by Tada Corp, with debts 171.4 billion yen ($1.49 billion).</p>
<p>It was the first time in 26 years that two companies listed on the first section of the Tokyo Stock Exchange failed in a single month, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Conditions in the construction market are worsening and builders are delaying settling problems from the 'bubble' era. That has led to the plunge in share prices of general contractors below 100 yen, one after another,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;This has led to concerns that some large bankruptcies in this sector are yet to come,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>A total of 390 bankruptcies took place in the sector in July, exceeding 300 for the 18th month in a row, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Since insolvencies in large construction firms lead to chain-reaction bankruptcies, it is important to keep a close watch,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Japan's Mitsui group announced a bailout for debt-ridden member firm Mitsui Construction Co after the latter presented group firms with a three-year restructuring programme.</p>
<p>The Tokyo Shoko report said large businesses are recovering from the effects of the bursting of the late-1980s economic &quot;bubble&quot; of inflated asset prices, but many smaller firms are still in a fragile state and posting losses.</p>
<p>&quot;Bankruptcies caused by lack of business funds rose 10.5 percent in July. This trend may continue as smaller companies find it difficult to borrow money (from financial firms),&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Bankruptcies at larger firms started a chain reaction that led to failures at affiliated firms, it said.</p>
<p>While the actual number of companies that went bankrupt was down slightly from June, the amount they owed soared. In June, 1,336 firms folded with 384.4 billion yen ($3.34 billion) in debt.</p>
<p>The highest number of bankruptcies for a single month was the 1,965 cases in May 1984, while the largest amount of debt was the 2.62 trillion yen ($22.7 billion) in April 1997. ($1=115 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
