<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="800999" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: PRESS DIGEST - INDONESIAN NEWSPAPERS - AUGUST 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - INDONESIAN NEWSPAPERS - AUGUST 14.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following are the leading stories in the Indonesian press on August 14. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>Telephone: (6221) 384-6364. Fax: (6221) 344-8404.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA POST</p>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah reached a record low on Wednesday but later recovered after Bank Indonesia intervened in the market. Spot rupiah, which opened at 2,645/2,651 against the U.S. dollar, nosedived to 2,680 by midday - just two points away from its lowest permitted limit of 2,682.</p>
<p>President Suharto has told Information Minister Hartono to play an active role in the Association of Indonesian Moslem Intellectuals (ICMI). Hartono expressed his intention last month to join the influential organisation chaired by Research and Technology Minister Jusuf Habibie.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>INDONESIAN OBSERVER</p>
<p>Indonesia has sent an official letter of protest to the European Commission for reopening inquiries into alleged dumping of gray cotton fabric by Indonesia. The European Community last week decided to reopen investigations into the alleged dumping of gray cotton fabric by China, Egypt, India, Indonesia, Pakistan and Turkey after a complaint by EuroCoton, the Committee of the Cotton and allied Textile Industries of the European Union.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>INDONESIA TIMES</p>
<p>Environment Minister Sarwono Kusumaatmadja said the clearing of land to build large plantations has caused thick smoke and haze on Sumatra and Kalimantan islands. Smoke and haze, which started to occur in May, has disrupted air and sea traffic in Indonesia as well as affected neighbouring Malaysia and Singapore.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
<p>-- email: jakarta.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
