<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801012" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: HSBC SAYS PLEASED WITH CHINA BUSINESS.</title>
<headline>HSBC SAYS PLEASED WITH CHINA BUSINESS.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>HSBC Holdings Plc's Hongkong Bank has made good progress in developing Chinese yuan business at its Shanghai branch, bank general manager Chris Langley said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Despite restrictions on the range of domestic currency business Hongkong Bank could conduct from the branch in Shanghai's Pudong district, its staff had already identified a large number of business opportunities, Langley told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We have only been doing that business since March this year, but I can say we are very pleased with the progress that we have made,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Langley, who was in Beijing to mark the opening of new branch premises in the Chinese capital, declined to give any details of the amount of yuan business being done by the bank but said overall it was outstripping foreign rivals.</p>
<p>&quot;We can say quite confidently that we do more business in China than any other foreign bank,&quot; he said but did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Hongkong Bank is one of a handful of foreign banks given licences to do Chinese yuan business since late last year that also includes Japan's Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi Ltd and Citibank of the United States.</p>
<p>The approved banks are subject to a 30 million yuan ($3.6 million) cap on interbank transactions, may only deal with foreign firms based in Shanghai and cannot trade on the first tier of the interbank market.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Beijing Newsroom (86) 10-6532-1921; Fax (86) 10-6532-4978</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
