<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801086" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBS END HIGHER IN TOKYO ON LATE TECHNICAL BUYING.</title>
<headline>JGBS END HIGHER IN TOKYO ON LATE TECHNICAL BUYING.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key September 10-year Japanese government bond (JGB) futures contract closed higher and at its session peak on Thursday, lifted by late stop-loss buying after a break above the recent high of 126.91.</p>
<p>Traders attributed the late buying mainly to technical short-covering by dealers ahead of a shift in the benchmark to the December contract later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;Large-lot buying from a city bank around 126.70 triggered the late rally,&quot; said a dealer at a long-term credit bank. September JGBs closed up 0.49 at 126.97, the highest closing since April 23.  </p>
<p>Turnover was 30,084 contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;The September contract has been mostly in an uptrend since it started trading. Therefore, bears have been the losers,&quot; said a dealer at a city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>JGBs rose in the morning due to a rise in U.S. Treasury bonds overnight, and extended gains later in the day. Scattered buying of cash JGBs was supportive, traders said.</p>
<p>Option-related cash bond buying was detected in the morning. Buying, albeit in small lots, from banks and pension funds was also seen at the long end of the JGB yield curve in the afternoon, they said.  </p>
<p>The yield of key 182nd 10-year JGB stood at 2.080 percent at 0657 GMT, down 0.045 from Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>The all-time low for any benchmark 10-year JGB yield was 2.070 percent, recorded on August 4.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who bought cash bonds today are likely to be quick to take profits. They may sell ahead of the end-September book closings for the fiscal half-year,&quot; said a senior dealer at another city bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>An International Monetary Fund (IMF) report saying it would probably be desirable for Japan to begin raising interest rates later in the year had little impact on JGBs, traders said.  </p>
<p>The outlook for the Japanese economy is still too weak to warrant a rise in interest rates, traders said.</p>
<p>The IMF said in Wednesday's report: &quot;Directors believed that the current easy stance of (Japan's) monetary policy should be maintained for the time being, but that it would likely be desirable to begin tightening later in the year.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said September JGBs seemed to be trending upward toward a record high for any benchmark contract of 127.34.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd like to see if investor buying continues when the contract is above 127.00,&quot; said a dealer at a domestic brokerage. --Risa Maeda, Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-33432-8570</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
