<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801199" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: CHINA CENTRAL BANKER RULES OUT INTEREST RATE CUT.</title>
<headline>CHINA CENTRAL BANKER RULES OUT INTEREST RATE CUT.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's central bank governor Dai Xianglong said on Thursday that current interest rate levels were appropriate and he saw no need for a change at present.</p>
<p>&quot;Taking into consideration the interest of depositors... we believe the current rate is still appropriate,&quot; Dai, head of the People's Bank of China, told a news conference.  </p>
<p>Current actual interest rates after taking account for inflation were about 4.0 percent, Dai said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is about same or equal to Western countries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The central bank felt the current levels should be maintained, Dai said.</p>
<p>China's two interest rate cuts last year brought rates down by 2.48 percentage points on average, with the rate for one-year bank deposits now at 7.47 percent from 9.15 percent in May 1996.</p>
<p>Bank interest rates were now the lowest since 1990, analysts have said.</p>
<p>China's benchmark retail price inflation for January-July was 1.6 percent while consumer price inflation was 3.9 percent for the period.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
