<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801372" id="root" date="1997-08-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: FEATURE - Floating tunnels in Norway - a bridge too far?.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Floating tunnels in Norway - a bridge too far?.</headline>
<byline>Tanya Pang</byline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-08-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian engineering has proved to be among the world's most innovative, driven by the special geographical needs of the vast, rugged country and development of its enormous offshore oil and gas resources.</p>
<p>Now engineers are looking to achieve a new milestone -- the world's first submerged floating tunnel (SFT).</p>
<p>The Norwegian Public Roads Administration plans to build a 1.4 km (0.89 miles) SFT across the Hoegsfjord near the oil city of Stavanger in the western county of Rogaland.</p>
<p>Unlike more usual submerged tunnels, which either sit on the sea or river bed or are embedded into the earth's surface, an SFT is suspended below the water surface and anchored in its submerged position.</p>
<p>&quot;People might be afraid to drive in such a structure because they think it will sink,&quot; Haavard Oestlid, project manager told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;But remember Archimedes' principle: the tunnel tube is so light it wants to float up just like a cork and that's the whole point.</p>
<p>&quot;It has a buoyancy which gives carrying capacity. You don't need to support the structure on the sea floor, but rather the opposite. You have to anchor it down because it actually wants to float to the surface.&quot;</p>
<p>The concept is not new.</p>
<p>Sir Edward James Reed, a British civil engineer and member of parliament, patented an SFT system for linking railways across bodies of water as early as 1887. Similar patents were awarded to Norwegian engineers in the 1920s.</p>
<p>NORWAY'S GEOGRAPHY HAS LED TO VAST EXPERIENCE</p>
<p>Norway has amassed vast experience of building bridges and tunnels able to cope with rough environments of high winds, stormy seas, and extremely low temperatures. Until the end of 1995 there were 15,700 bridges and 814 tunnels dotted across the country's 386,958 square kilometres (149,404 square miles).</p>
<p>These structures have been essential in linking many small, isolated communities separated by mountains or lakes or the tapestry of fjords and bays running along the coastline.</p>
<p>Town planners have started using this knowledge to take an environmental approach to designing city centres.</p>
<p>In Oslo and Tromsoe, for example, vehicles are diverted through labyrinths of underground tunnels, leaving the city centre as a mainly pedestrian area while traffic is free to flow at a reasonable pace.</p>
<p>Not only does this cut down the long queues, but also significantly reduces car fumes and noise on the streets.</p>
<p>The Hoegsfjord project has been on the planning board for more than a decade.</p>
<p>The one billion crown ($136 million) structure will make it possible for 13,000 people to travel to Stavanger and other parts of the country without using ferries with an estimated 2,500 vehicles expected to use the toll tunnel daily.</p>
<p>The authorities oppose a spanning bridge because of the width of the fjord -- 1.4 km (0.87 miles) -- and because of the area's outstanding natural beauty. The water depth at 155 metres (510 feet) is a drawback to a conventional embedded tunnel.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the problems with a tunnel that goes below the bottom of the fjord is that it has to be very steep and go very deep before coming up again on the other side,&quot; Oestlid said.</p>
<p>&quot;The traffic has to go 200 to 400 metres (658-1,312 feet) below the level that it would normally be at, which means a lot of extra energy in the form of fuel and therefore more pollution. If we can keep things as horizontal as possible, it means less energy and less pollution.&quot;</p>
<p>The Hoegsfjord SFT would have an inner diameter of 9.5 metres (31 feet), with a tunnel wall of 0.8-1.3 metres (2.5-4.3 feet). It would be suspended 25 metres (82 feet) below the water surface, allowing boats to sail above it.</p>
<p>HOEGFJORD IDEAL FOR PROTOTYPE SFT</p>
<p>Oestlid said the fjord, with its relatively calm conditions -- average currents of 0.6 metres per second (two feet per second) and wave heights of 1.5 metres (five feet) -- was ideal for a prototype SFT.</p>
<p>Four contractors have put forward preliminary design ideas for the structure, many of which have drawn on expertise from the oil sector.</p>
<p>&quot;This is definitely a development of North Sea technology. Offshore engineers have had an infectious effect. I don't think people generally, worldwide, are aware of the achievements made in the North Sea,&quot; Oestlid said.</p>
<p>Offshore concrete specialists Aker Maritime ASA , under its former subsidiary Norwegian Contractors, have designed a concrete tunnel structure anchored to the sea floor by groups of steel vertical tension legs.</p>
<p>The Anglo-Norwegian construction and engineering group Kvaerner, also a world leader in the offshore sector, has proposed a steel tunnel with cigar-shaped pontoons, or huge floats, on the water surface fixed to the tunnel via steel tubular piles.</p>
<p>Selmer ASA and Eeg-Henriksen have both suggested using concrete tunnels attached to pontoons via concrete towers. The pontoons and towers are so heavy they hold the tunnel tube in position in the water.</p>
<p>One advantage of a pontoon solution is that pontoons are independent of depth. Fjords can run down to 1,200 metres (3,940 feet), although 300 to 400 metres (984-1,312 feet) is more normal.</p>
<p>FINAL DECISION ON CONTRACTOR EXPECTED 1999</p>
<p>Contracts for detailed design will be awarded to the companies next year and a final decision is expected in 1999. Oestlid said construction could begin as early as 2000 once plans have been approved by parliament.</p>
<p>Norway, however, is not the only country considering SFTs. Research groups in Japan have studied the feasibility of a link across Funka Bay, connecting Hokkaido with Honshu islands, a road/rail crossing across Uchiura Bay on Hokkaido island and a connection between Kansai and Kobe airports across Osaka Bay.</p>
<p>In Italy, an SFT is one proposal to bridge the Messina Strait between the mainland and Sicily. A solution for that crossing has been under study for more than 25 years.</p>
<p>Oestlid said he expected the SFT concept to catch on fast once it had been tried and tested especially in areas of high tourism such as Lakes Lugano, Garda, Constance and Lucerne in Europe and the great lakes in the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>Tolls could help fund the SFTs and, in the case of pontoon solutions, the huge floats could be used for tourism -- restaurants, hotels, floating gardens, or as marine research stations.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the concept will become very popular once planners and the public become aware of the possibilities,&quot; Oestlid said.</p>
<p>&quot;It means we can cross lakes invisibly, no sound or visual pollution, the end of traffic problems and soon I think we will have systems to treat tunnel air to get rid of the worst pollutants and fumes.&quot;</p>
<p>($ = 7.350 Norwegian Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
