<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801435" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CYCLING-SORENSEN DETERMINED TO HANG ON TO WORLD CUP LEAD.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-SORENSEN DETERMINED TO HANG ON TO WORLD CUP LEAD.</headline>
<byline>Mike Price</byline>
<dateline>ROCHESTER, England 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rolf Sorensen, who has twice finished third in the World Cup, is determined to hang on to his lead this time as he prepares for the British round of the 10-race series.</p>
<p>Sunday's Rochester Classic is the second of three British races.</p>
<p>&quot;I am going flat out in the August Cup races with our team's best riders in support. Then I will have a better idea of my Cup chances,&quot; the Dane said.</p>
<p>In 1991 Sorensen was unable to defend his Cup lead after fracturing his collarbone in the Tour de France where he crashed wearing the yellow jersey of Tour leader.</p>
<p>Last Sunday he snatched the series lead back in the San Sebastian Classic as Italian Michele Bartoli, who had deposed him in April, failed to score.</p>
<p>Sorensen picked up 16 points to maintain his record of scoring in each of the previous rounds, notably April's Tour of Flanders classic where he took a maximum 100 points.</p>
<p>&quot;I am in good shape after the Tour de France, and that is important if I am to maintain my challenge,&quot; said the Olympic road race silver medallist.</p>
<p>He fought out the Atlanta finish with eventual winner Pascal Richard of Switzerland and Derby-born Max Sciandri, the Italian who races for Britain.</p>
<p>Of those two Sciandri could be the bigger threat on Sunday, but last year he was surprisingly outflanked by Italian Andrea Ferrigato in a duel to the finish at Leeds where Sciandri had won the previous year.</p>
<p>The Paris-Roubaix and San Sebastian rounds this season fell to his team mates Frederic Guesdon and Davide Rebellin, and Sciandri wants to be the third.</p>
<p>The tendinitis which plagued him during the Tour has cleared, and Sciandri said: &quot;My form should be good for the weekend&quot;.</p>
<p>Sunday's 242.3 kilometres does not offer the climbing challenge of past British rounds. Italians have won this round six times in eight years, but on more testing courses mainly through the Pennines.</p>
<p>The race takes in roads used for the 1995 visit of the Tour, but it may not be hard enough to help Bartoli regain the overall lead.</p>
<p>However, three laps of a finishing circuit of nearly eight kilometres is tough enough to sap legs that will have been pedalling through Kent for nearly six hours.</p>
<p>Switzerland's Beat Zberg who is third in the standings misses Rochester because his Italian team have another engagement.</p>
<p>A likely challenger in a record line-up of 152 could be Sorensen's compatriot Bjarne Riis. The 1995 Tour winner won the Dutch round, and is eighth overall.</p>
<p>In 1996 Johan Museeuw won the world road race championship in Lugano and the Cup series for a second year. This season the Belgian has scored in only two rounds and badly needs a victory to lift him from 11th in the standings.</p>
<p>After nine years Britain is losing its Cup place to a German race in 1998. The chance of bowing out with a home win rests with Sciandri and Chris Boardman who is keen to test his form after a neck injury forced him to quit the Tour.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
