<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801496" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: BOXING-DOMINGUEZ MEETS TAFER AGAIN TWO YEARS ON.</title>
<headline>BOXING-DOMINGUEZ MEETS TAFER AGAIN TWO YEARS ON.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine Marcelo Dominguez defends his WBC cruiserweight title for the fifth time on Saturday when he faces Akim Tafer the Frenchman he knocked out to take the vacant crown two years ago.</p>
<p>Dominguez and Tafer, making his third bid for the title, meet at Le Cannet outside Cannes. They last clashed at St Jean de Luz on the Atlantic coast in July 1995, the Frenchman going down in the ninth round.</p>
<p>The Argentine has not fought since December when he beat Brazilian Arimatea da Silva in Buenos Aires. Frenchman Fabrice Tiozzo pulled out of their scheduled title bout two months ago.</p>
<p>Buenos Aires-born Dominguez said: &quot;I've been ready to fight for two months. Of course, we had to make some adjustments in preparation when the rival changed. But physically I'm at 10 points.&quot;</p>
<p>Dominguez, who has been on the Cote d'Azur since the beginning of August, said in an interview with an Argentine newspaper that he was just doing the bare minimum to keep fit in intensely hot summer weather.</p>
<p>&quot;I boxed three times last week, but not any more. I don't want to take any unnecessary risks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dominguez, the smaller of the two with less reach but great courage, said his main concern was Tafer's height. The Frenchman is 12 centimetres taller.</p>
<p>&quot;All fights are different. In the last we were both looking for the vacant title, but now I'm going to defend my crown. I'm not going to speculate, it's not my style,&quot; Dominguez said.</p>
<p>&quot;What could make things difficult for me is Tafer's height, but I'll try to leave him short of breath and mobility with blows to the body.</p>
<p>&quot;He's well prepared but that's only 50 percent because you have to add fighting spirit and courage in the ring and in this I have a lot of faith in myself.&quot;</p>
<p>The Argentine's only defeat in 23 bouts was against another Frenchman, Anaclet Wamba in late 1994, his first title fight.</p>
<p>Grenoble-born Tafer, who has a 23-6 record, also lost to Wamba in 1993 in his first bid for the crown.</p>
<p>His chances against Dominguez may have been setback with his separation from manager Dominique Ramirez two weeks ago.</p>
<p>But Ramirez said: &quot;Akim is ready, he's like a bomb. That's maybe why he no longer needed me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
