<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801552" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: REVIEW-ESTONIAN SHARES COOL, LITHUANIA GAINS STEADILY.</title>
<headline>REVIEW-ESTONIAN SHARES COOL, LITHUANIA GAINS STEADILY.</headline>
<byline>Ed Stoddard</byline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Estonian shares caught their breath over the last week as investors reaped profits gained from a recent record-breaking surge while foreign buyers boosted Lithuania's struggling market.</p>
<p>Latvian shares posted more modest gains led by market leader Unibanka.</p>
<p>Analysts say that Estonia should pick up steam again as its gains were backed by better than expected first-half results and raised 1997 profit forecasts.</p>
<p>Lithuania's market remains relatively illiquid but bargain prices, solid results and a good variety of companies have lured foreign investment funds and kindled hopes that a long and brutal correction is over.</p>
<p>ESTONIA</p>
<p>Profit-taking halted Estonia's dizzying bull run in its tracks but dealers dismissed the possibility of bears looming on the horizon.</p>
<p>However, the market's immediate direction was unclear.</p>
<p>&quot;Volumes are down as investors wait for a clear trend, with many waiting for a rise to start,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>The Talsi index fell to 403.55 on Thursday from 413.20 the previous Thursday. It had climbed to a record 422.27 on Friday before easing on Monday.</p>
<p>Estonia's market remains by far the most liquid and profitable in the region.</p>
<p>Analysts say its performance reflects the radical economic reforms Estonia has pursued since quitting the Soviet Union in 1991.</p>
<p>LATVIA</p>
<p>Latvian shares crept up slightly amid low liquidity and volumes.</p>
<p>The bourse index rose to 388.15 on Thursday compared to 383.74 the previous week.</p>
<p>Market leader Unibanka dominated trade as usual as it gained to 3.40 lats from 3.31 lats over the week.</p>
<p>Dealers said that the bank's results and expectations that it will maintain a solid performance should translate into further gains, which they hope will pull up the rest of the fledging market.</p>
<p>The bourse has been hard hit by summer and competition from the local debt market, which is where much of the portolio investment in the country goes.</p>
<p>LITHUANIA</p>
<p>Low prices and a relatively wide selection of corporates inticed foreign buyers to Lithuania's market, which dealers said seems to be finally pulling out of a painful correction that set in after shares soared to new highs last January.</p>
<p>That correction has made local investors wary and dealers have pinned their hopes on growing foreign interest to revive the market.</p>
<p>The official list index, which tracks the top five stocks, rose to 1142.23 over the week while the broader group A index climbed to 1977.38 from 1843.41.</p>
<p>&quot;Lately we have noticed bigger foreign buyers coming to the bourse and they tend to invest in official list shares, which pushes the rest of the market up,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Pharmaceutical producer Sanitas grabbed the limelight on Thursday as 50 percent of its shares were sold to foreign investors at 96 litas a piece in a deal worth 33.5 million litas.</p>
<p>&quot;Eight foreign funds and persons bought the shares,&quot; Arvydas Jacikevichius, a dealer with Suprema brokerage, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said that Suprema registered the deal but declined to say which funds or persons were involved.</p>
<p>-- Riga newsroom +371 721 52 40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
