<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80161" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks end higher, chip share rally continues.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks end higher, chip share rally continues.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo stocks closed higher on Thursday, marking the third straight day of gains on the back of rising high-tech shares. Brokers said the stock average was likely to keep its firm tone at least until the end of September, but the 22,000 level would be temporary resistance.</p>
<p>The key Nikkei 225 average was up 110.70 points or 0.52 percent to end at 21,461.37. Its December futures gained 180 points to 21,550. &quot;Blue-chips, especially semiconductor shares, remained bullish, and trading volume was heavier today, indicating the market had regained its energy,&quot; said Kaoru Ichikawa, a senior trader at Kokusai Securities Co Ltd.  </p>
<p>Fujitsu Ltd was up 30 yen to end at 1,060 yen in the third heaviest trading volume. Hitachi Ltd rose 10 yen to end at 1,070.</p>
<p>Shares of microchip-related equipment makers, such as Tokyo Electron Ltd and Advantest Corp, also rose.</p>
<p>Tokyo Electron, which produces semiconductor manufacturing equipment, was up 70 yen to close at 3,140. Advantest, a manufacturer of semiconductor testing devices, was up 70 yen to finish at 4,270.</p>
<p>A stronger dollar against the yen prompted buying in automobile shares, brokers also said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
