<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801636" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada bonds close weaker but pare earlier losses.</title>
<headline>Canada bonds close weaker but pare earlier losses.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed weaker in moderate trade on Friday, but pared some of their early losses after the release of tame U.S. economic data, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;That weaker-than-expected (U.S.) data did give us some support from about ten o'clock onwards. We saw some improvement in the U.S. and we picked up on that, but basically bonds are still mired in a negative tone going into the weekend,&quot; said Andrew Pyle, head of fixed-income research with ABN AMRO Bank Canada.</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year benchmark bond fell C$0.61 to C$118.98 to yield 6.543 percent.  </p>
<p>The U.S. 30-year bond traded unchanged to yield 6.55 percent. The negative spread between the bonds narrowed to one basis point from six basis points on Thursday's close.</p>
<p>Canadian bonds initially opened much weaker with U.S. Treasuries, which softened in early trade in tandem with the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>However, Canadian bonds pared some losses along with the U.S. market after a report that the University of Michigan's preliminary index of consumer sentiment for August fell to 102.8 against a 107.1 reading in July.  </p>
<p>&quot;As far as the long end is concerned it was U.S. driven. The short end of the curve continues to be a Canadian story with the squeezing of the two year bond,&quot; said Pyle. &quot;This was a very interesting and I guess spectacular week from the perspective of short Canadian bonds which had nothing to do with the U.S.&quot;</p>
<p>A &quot;short squeeze&quot; in the two year area came to light in trading on Thurday. The Government of Canada 4.0 percent bond due March 15, 1999 closed up C$0.03 to C$99.79 to yield 4.139 percent.  </p>
<p>In other prices, Canada's 10-year benchmark bond fell C$0.22 to C$109.35 to yield 5.972 percent.</p>
<p>The U.S. 10-year bond rose 4/32 to yield 6.24 percent.</p>
<p>The negative spread between the bonds narrowed to 27 basis points from 32 basis points at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>The 10-year Canadian government bond futures contract trading on the Montreal Exchange closed down 0.29 to 119.85 with 3029 contracts changing hands, down from 3909 on Thursday.</p>
<p>((Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
