<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80160" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan to dissolve parliament, prepare for election.</title>
<headline>Japan to dissolve parliament, prepare for election.</headline>
<byline>Tsukasa Maekawa</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto told his partners in Japan's ruling coalition on Thursday that he will dissolve parliament's Lower House on Friday, paving the way for elections widely expected to be held on October 20.</p>
<p>Shoichi Ide, president of Sakigake, one of the three coalition parties, disclosed the prime minister's comment to reporters after a meeting of coalition leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister told us that there was no other time when parliament could be dissolved than the opening of its special session on Friday,&quot; Ide told reporters.</p>
<p>He did not provide a date for the general election, but government officials have said openly that an October 20 vote is expected. October 20 is a Sunday, the day Japanese elections are traditionally held, and the polls must be called within 40 days of a dissolution of parliament.</p>
<p>Polls are not mandated until July 1997, but Hashimoto's Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) -- the biggest partner in the coalition -- favours going before voters as early as possible before April, when a rise in an unpopular national sales tax will take effect. The consumption tax is to be raised to five percent from three percent.</p>
<p>The smaller coalition parties had wanted more time, as they are locked in a bitter row over how to regroup for the polls, which will be held under a revised electoral system expected to benefit larger parties.</p>
<p>Although the LDP is expected to get the most votes, no single party is likely to capture a majority in the 500-seat Lower House.</p>
<p>This means the LDP could be forced to form a another coalition with one or more of its political rivals.</p>
<p>The main opposition Shinshinto (New Frontier Party) is projected to finish second with around 200 Lower House seats.</p>
<p>Except for the planned rise in the sales tax, there are few major policy issues facing the country.</p>
<p>Japan's economy is recovering from a slump that followed the bursting of an asset &quot;bubble&quot; -- the end of an era of soaring real estate and stock prices -- in the early 1990s. But analysts and government experts agree it remains fragile and could be seriously set back by a rise in the sales tax.</p>
<p>Hashimoto is Japan's fourth prime minister since the last general election in 1993, when the pro-business LDP lost its grip on power for the first time in 38 years.</p>
<p>The polls will be the first under a system designed to make campaigning less costly and reduce graft. In place of a multi-seat system, 300 seats will be decided on a first-past-the-post basis and the other 200 by proportional representation.</p>
<p>Members of the less-powerful Upper House are elected on a fixed schedule unrelated to the terms of the Lower House.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
