<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="801746" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: FEATURE - Zimbabwe battles &quot;alarming&quot; rise in rape.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Zimbabwe battles &quot;alarming&quot; rise in rape.</headline>
<byline>Stella Mapenzauswa</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nyasha Moyo felt an overwhelming sense of relief when the doctor told her the baby she was carrying was a boy.</p>
<p>&quot;I normally wouldn't mind either way, but this is no longer a safe country for little girls,&quot; Moyo said.</p>
<p>She pointed to a dramatic rise in the number of Zimbabwe's rape and sexual abuse victims, including babies just a few months old, which has prompted some Zimbabweans to call for offenders to be castrated.</p>
<p>In March, deputy police commissioner David Blake praised Zimbabwe's local media for highlighting cases of rape and child abuse, which he said had reached alarming proportions.</p>
<p>Some local social scientists attribute the increase to spirit mediums and traditional healers who allegedly prescribe rape or incest as a good luck charm or cure for the deadly disease AIDS, which kills an average 500 people a week in Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>Gordon Chavunduka, president of Zimbabwe's main traditional healers association, denies his members are to blame.</p>
<p>&quot;These rape and child abuse cases have reached wholly unacceptable levels. In some cases, children as young as three months have been abused,&quot; Blake said.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like to congratulate the media for highlighting this scourge and we consider it everyone's moral and legal duty to expose these abusers whoever and wherever they may be.&quot;</p>
<p>Zimbabwean police say more than 1,460 cases nationwide were reported in the first five months of 1997. A total of 3,010 cases were recorded for the whole of last year.</p>
<p>Most disturbing is the fact that 52 percent of last year's cases involved assaults on children aged under 16, says deputy commissioner Godwin Matanga, in charge of administration.</p>
<p>&quot;Viewed in the light of the raging AIDS pandemic, it is shattering to imagine what devastation this is having on our adults of tomorrow,&quot; Matanga said.</p>
<p>MOST CASES UNREPORTED</p>
<p>Also disturbing, he said, was that only a small proportion of rape cases came to the attention of the police, with hundreds of others going unreported partly because attackers threatened further acts of violence unless victims kept quiet.</p>
<p>There was also the fear of social stigma attached to being publicly known to have been sexually abused.</p>
<p>In some cases, children fall victim to close relatives like their fathers. Such incidents are usually swept under the carpet to preserve the family honour.</p>
<p>Mothers have been known to protect their husbands from possible jail sentences by concealing the fact that they have sexually abused their daughters.</p>
<p>At a recent commemoration of the Day of the African Child, Zimbabwe's President Robert Mugabe added his voice to those expressing concern at the rising level of child abuse in the southern African country, saying he was particularly disturbed by incestuous rape.</p>
<p>&quot;When a father rapes his own two- or three-year-girl child, one begins to wonder what is becoming of our society,&quot; Mugabe said. &quot;We need to make society feel it has a duty to ensure that no child is abused.&quot;</p>
<p>CALL FOR HARSHER PENALTIES</p>
<p>Zimbabweans have debated at length how rapists should be dealt with.</p>
<p>Some say they are psychologically disturbed and need society's help rather than its condemnation, and that imprisoning them is not a deterrent but makes them into hardened criminals.</p>
<p>Many disagree. Turning down a lawyers' plea for clemency on behalf of a convicted 17-year-old rapist recently, Supreme Court judge Justice Korsah said:</p>
<p>&quot;I do not consider a fine a serious enough punishment for rape because it reduces the victim to the level of a prostitute whose favours are willingly granted for a fee.</p>
<p>&quot;I, likewise, regard community service as an inappropriate punishment for rape because it does not protect society at large from the caprices of the culprit.&quot;</p>
<p>Many Zimbabweans, including the police, feel the penalties meted out to convicted rapists are too light to deter and have called on Mugabe's government to sanction more severe sentences, especially where the victims are children.</p>
<p>Most rape cases are tried in a magistrates court, where the maximum penalty is 10 years in prison.</p>
<p>&quot;Life sentences and related harsh sentences rather than the current mandatory terms may also help in the fight against such people,&quot; says provincial assistant commissioner Adam Ndlovu.</p>
<p>&quot;The society at large, through their parliamentarians, should...help the police in lobbying for stiffer sentences against those convicted of rape.&quot;</p>
<p>Michael Mawema, a former leading Zimbabwean politician, wants rapists to be castrated. So far, though, that proposal has received little support.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
