<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80175" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: FORECAST - Japan Aug output seen down month-on-month.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Japan Aug output seen down month-on-month.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's industrial production data for August is expected to show a slight fall from the previous month, reflecting weakish consumer demand for goods, analysts say.</p>
<p>In a Reuters poll, analysts forecast it would show a month-on-month decline of between 1.4 percent and 2.4 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;In recent months, output data has tended to be below initial forecasts. With recent key figures such as large-lot electricity demand and car output data staying below their year-ago levels, I think weak output numbers will come out,&quot; said Tetsuro Sawano, an economist at Nikko Research Center.  </p>
<p>In July, industrial output rose a revised 4.9 percent from the previous month, compared with a preliminary estimate of a 4.1 percent rise. It rose a revised 6.0 percent from a year earlier, against a preliminary estimate of a 5.3 percent rise.</p>
<p>The Trade Ministry announced late last month that manufacturers' output, a major component of overall output, was forecast to fall 1.2 percent in August from the previous month.</p>
<p>Analysts said overall output in August would likely show a larger month-on-month drop than initially thought following the upward revision in July's figure. The preliminary production data for August is due at 3.30 p.m. (0630 GMT) on Monday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Steel and other basic material companies are currently in the final stage of cutting excess inventories, but not much progress has been made so far in the machinery industry, which accounts for about 40 percent of overall production,&quot; said Shuji Shirota, an economist at Yamaichi Research Institute.</p>
<p>Shirota sees large-lot electricity demand as a clue to gauging overall output trends. He said electricity demand was sluggish in the electric machinery industry. Analysts said high inventories in the chip industry, hit by sagging prices, may be a drag on recovery in overall production, despite falling inventories in the pulp/paper and steel industries.  </p>
<p>&quot;The actual amount of semiconductor output is not large, but it has a major spillover impact on other products such as personal computers, home electronic goods and car navigation systems, which for a time served as a locomotive behind the recent recovery in overall output,&quot; said Shirota.</p>
<p>Nikko's Sawano said there were growing fears that both the economy and production may later lose steam, but added that there are some better signs. He said car production may recover later this year, lending support to overall output.</p>
<p>But other analysts said consumer demand still lacked strength even after carmakers introduced new models.  </p>
<p>Analysts agreed that uncertainty prevails over the strength of consumers' appetite for goods.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumption has not regained its full strength, so what companies can do now is just to trim excess inventories and wait for any upturn in demand,&quot; said Yamaichi's Shirota.</p>
<p>But many analysts played down the risk of any rapid decline in output. They said a planned rise in the sales tax rate to five percent from three percent would lead to a temporary rally in consumption, supporting production for the rest of this fiscal year. But the same factor would likely later hurt output once the tax rise actually takes effect in April 1997.  </p>
<p>The following is a breakdown of forecasts of changes, the first column for a month ago, seasonally adjusted, and the second column for a year ago, unadjusted:</p>
<p> Salomon Brothers Asia	  -1.4 pct   +2.8 pct</p>
<p> Nikko Research Center	  -1.6 pct   +2.5 pct</p>
<p> Deutsche Morgan Grenfell     -1.9 pct   +2.3 pct</p>
<p> Merrill Lynch		    -1.9 pct    --</p>
<p> Schroders Japan		  -2.0 pct    --</p>
<p> BZW				  -2.0 pct   +2.1 pct</p>
<p> Yamaichi Research Institute  -2.4 pct   +1.7 pct</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
