<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802061" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo spring sown crops in good condition -analyst.</title>
<headline>Yugo spring sown crops in good condition -analyst.</headline>
<byline>Amra Kevic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia's spring crop outlook is promising, especially for maize, soybeans and sunflower, but final yields will depend on the weather over the next two months, the Yugoslav Chamber of Commerce said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;All sown crops are in exceptional condition but..it is difficult to give firm forecasts now,&quot; Milan Prostran, secretary of the Chamber's Association for Agriculture, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Heavy rains in late June and early July boosted maize, soybeans, sunflower and sugar beet, although they slowed wheat harvesting and reduced yields slightly.</p>
<p>&quot;But more rain would not be good for these crops as they enter ripening stages,&quot; said Prostran.</p>
<p>According to the Chamber's data, maize was sown on nearly 1.5 million hectares with average yields expected at around 5.0 tonnes per ha, which would give around 6.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>If sunny weather holds, the crop could exceed 7.0 million tonnes as most of the maize area is under late hybrids which give higher average yields, Prostran said.</p>
<p>That could create a substantial maize export surplus, but it was risky to make forecasts and more specific information on the crop would be available in September, Prostran said.</p>
<p>Maize is a major export product for Yugoslavia but is also vital for the revival of the country's livestock sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Depending on how meat exports to the European Union go, more maize could be used for fodder...If not, there will be more for export,&quot; Prostran said.</p>
<p>The EU has granted a 10,000 tonne meat export quota to Yugoslavia but exports have not yet begun pending permits from the EU's commission.</p>
<p>The most pronounced shortfall in spring sowing was in sugar beet, which is now ripening on some 56,000 ha, around 40 percent belanned area.</p>
<p>Some 20,000 ha had to be resown after cold weather destroyed sprouting crops.</p>
<p>Around 2.0 million tonnes of beet is expected to be harvested, which will be enough to produce some 220,000 tonnes of sugar, Prostran said.</p>
<p>&quot;Together with reserves from 1996 and last year's imports of brown sugar, we will have enough for domestic needs which are around 285,000 tonnes per year.&quot;</p>
<p>According to official statistics, last year's sugar beet area of some 70,000 ha yielded 2.391 million tonnes of beet and sugar production of around 270,000 tonnes. Around 180,000 tonnes of refined and brown sugar were imported in 1996.</p>
<p>The beet crop is in excellent condition but more will be known after beet tests in the second half of August, Prostran said.</p>
<p>According to Prostran, there would probably be no sugar surplus for export.</p>
<p>Sunflower was planted on some 176,000 ha, below the planned area of 200,000 ha. Forecasts are for an average yield of 2.0 tonnes and a crop of 350,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Soybean crops were also progressing well, with some 70,000 ha expected to yield 140,000 tonnes of beans.</p>
<p>&quot;If good and sunny weather continues to the end of ripening, we could have some 25,000-30,000 tonnes of cooking oil for export,&quot; Prostran said.</p>
<p>--Amra Kevic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 311 4305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
