<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802013" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: PRESS DIGEST - SLOVAKIA - AUG 15.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SLOVAKIA - AUG 15.</headline>
<text>
<p>SME - Hungarian Prime Minister Gyula Horn will not accept an appendix to the Slovak-Hungarian treaty at Friday's summit in Gyor with Premier Vladimir Meciar. The two are also expected to discuss the problem of Slovakia's Hungarian minority.</p>
<p>- Trade unions claim the government is not solving the causes of the country's unfavourable macro-economic development.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Preliminary estimates of damage caused by flooding last month in Slovakia total 2.3 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- Milk and dairy product consumption in Slovakia has dropped over the past few years from 253 kilogrammes per capita in 1989 to some 150 kg, compared to a worldwide average of between 290 to 300 kg per head.</p>
<p>- Representatives of the chambers of commerce from Slovakia, Germany, Hungary and the Czech Republic will meet in Lucenec, central Slovakia on September 3-4 to review four years of cooperation and to discuss the latest Slovak legal and other measures concerning investment, exports and imports.</p>
<p>- Planned government austerity measures could cause a drop in real monthly income of up to 1,500 crowns.</p>
<p>SLOVENSKA REPUBLIKA - Interior Minister Gustav Krajci made use of his right not to give evidence when questioned by the state prosecutor on his involvement in a thwarted refererendum last May on Slovak entry to NATO and direct presidential elections.</p>
<p>- Republican U.S. congressman John Mica, who is of SLovak origin, will visit Slovakia on August 17-28 and will be received by Foreign Minister Zdenka Kramplova.</p>
<p>NARODNA OBRODA - The Centre for Economic Development (CPHR) says that creditors can solve the problems of debt-ridden enterprises better than the 10-member revitalisation committee.</p>
<p>- The employers' union has proposed that the government postpone measures to freeze wages until next January.</p>
<p>- The parliamentary committee for economics, privatisation and business is to discuss last year's privatisation of gas storage company Nafta Gbely at its meeting in September.</p>
<p>PRAVDA - Thefts of copper coils for lift brake magnets are increasing in Bratislava and so far caused the immobilisation of up to 250 lifts in the capital, including many high rise buildings. Repair firms are having difficulties in finding spare parts.</p>
<p>- It is assumed that the aims of the state budget will be fulfilled after recent government measures to regulate expenditure, Finance Minister Sergej Kozlik said.</p>
<p>- Employees of the Svidnik public transport company are threatening to strike to support their wage demands.</p>
<p>PRACA - Opposition leader Jan Langos claims that there exists in Russia a database with confidential information on many leading Slovak personalities. He warned that many former members of the former Czechoslovak StB secret police could be working with the Russian or other secret services.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom 421-7-521-8402</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
