<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802006" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Two Bosnian Moslems shot dead, federation says.</title>
<headline>Two Bosnian Moslems shot dead, federation says.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Bosnian Moslems were killed and another was wounded by automatic gunfire in eastern Bosnia on Friday, Moslem-Croat federation authorities said.</p>
<p>The shooting took place near a former front line in a village inhabited by Serbs before the 1992-95 Bosnian war, the federation said.</p>
<p>The NATO-led peacekeeping force said it was investigating the report.</p>
<p>The federation interior ministry said the Moslems were &quot;ambushed&quot; by unidentified gunmen at about 9 a.m. (0700 GMT) as they rode on a tractor on their way to cut firewood in the eastern Sapna region.</p>
<p>Four Bosnians who were travelling along the same road earlier had gone missing, it said.</p>
<p>The ministry said the NATO-led Stabilisation Force (SFOR) must &quot;undertake urgent and energetic measures&quot; to protect the eastern village of Laze, near the boundary between Bosnia's Moslem-Croat federation and Serb entity.</p>
<p>NATO peackeeeping troops patrol a zone of separation between the two territories and all weapons are supposed to be banned from the zone.</p>
<p>Violence erupted along the boundary line in eastern Bosnia last year when Serb authorities tried to block the return of Moslem refugees to their pre-war homes in Serb-controlled territory.</p>
<p>Some Moslems, prevented from going to their homes in Serb territory, have moved into damaged houses in the zone of separation along the former front line.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
