<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802290" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Naphtha/Mogas - Supplies bear down on naphtha.</title>
<headline>Asia Naphtha/Mogas - Supplies bear down on naphtha.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ample supplies of naphtha and high stocks depressed prices while gasoline remained steady in a balanced market, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>Naphtha September swaps fell by 30 cents per barrel to $21.15/$21.20.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese have increased their domestic production of naphtha and have no need to import,&quot; said a Japanese trader. &quot;In fact some are trying to defer their term liftings from the Middle East.&quot;  </p>
<p>Thai buying which caused a bull-run in July was also absent from the market as the mercury removing unit at Aromatic Thailand's plant came back onstream on August 12, a source said.</p>
<p>The company needs to import around one cargo per month but had already covered its September requirements.</p>
<p>Only Taiwan's state-owned Chinese Petroleum Corp (CPC) was an active buyer, seeking 30,000 tonnes of full range naphtha for delivery between October 1-31 in a tender which closes August 20 and is valid for two days.  </p>
<p>CPC's last full range naphtha tender, for September 1-10 delivery was awarded to South Korean refiner Yukong Ltd at $203 per tonne on a cost-and-freight (c-and-f) basis, industry sources said.</p>
<p>In the absence of buyers, Singapore refiners were not actively offering September cargoes, although some lifting schedules would only be confirmed next week.</p>
<p>Traders assessed premiums at flat to a &quot;small premium' after one major sold a full cargo earlier this month at par to Singapore spot quotes.</p>
<p>&quot;If you can get flat, you are lucky,&quot; said one U.S. major.  </p>
<p>Indonesia was adding to the already oversupplied market with a very prompt August 18-22 lifting 200,000-barrel full range cargo heard being offered from Dumai.</p>
<p>Gasoline in comparison, looked healthier after Taiwan's tender this week removed 750,000 barrels out of September.</p>
<p>A European major sold 50,000-barrels of unleaded 97-octane gasoline lifting Septmber 1-5 to a Dutch trader at $24.55 per barrel fob Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;The levels are steady and look okay because naphtha is coming down and the spread is widening,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>The spread between gasoline and naphtha, the reforming margin has been under pressure with a surplus of gasoline since last year, forcing cuts in reformer output.</p>
<p>The cuts have in turn tightened supplies of the high octane creating a two-tiered market between high and low octane material.</p>
<p>Traders assessed the spread between naphtha and the 97-octane at $3.70, while it was only $2.20 lower than the 95-octane.</p>
<p>China was offering the 92 and 97-octane material while India cancelled its buy tender for 87.15 octane.  </p>
<p>(Prices are in dollars per barrel)</p>
<p> MTH  FOB SIN		    BUY/SELL     PREV BUY/SELL</p>
<p> SEP  NAPHTHA		  21.15/21.20	21.40/21.55</p>
<p> SEP  NAPHTHA SWAPS	  21.15/21.20	21.40/21.55</p>
<p> OCT  NAPHTHA SWAPS	  21.10/21.20	21.40/21.55</p>
<p> SEP  GASOLINE 95 UNL	23.20/23.50	23.20/23.50</p>
<p> SEP  GASOLINE SWAPS	 - - -/- - -	- - -/- - -</p>
<p>-- M. Choy, (65) 870-3086; Fax (65) 776-8112</p>
<p>-- Email: singapore.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
