<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802247" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian forex markets end week of carnage.</title>
<headline>Asian forex markets end week of carnage.</headline>
<byline>Phil Smith</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian foreign exchange markets ended the week on a decidedly sour note with regional currencies tumbling to new lows as already poor sentiment turned even worse.</p>
<p>Analysts said the market was no longer looking at economic or political fundamentals of Asia and was instead simply taking a dim view of nearly the whole region.</p>
<p>&quot;Confidence is the key to restoring faith in Asian currencies, but unfortunately it seems that the key has broken in the lock,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>The Malaysian ringgit slumped to 2.8210 per dollar, its lowest level since it was officially floated in 1973, while the Singapore dollar slid to 1.5240, its weakest level in three years.</p>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah, which was floated on Thursday, tumbled to another all-time low of 2,960.00 before recovering to 2,880/10 later in the afternoon.</p>
<p>In all cases there was no detectable central bank intervention.</p>
<p>Towards the end of the Asian session there was some profit taking on the higher dollar and in London traders said some investors had also decided to scalp some profits off the Asian dollar gain.</p>
<p>But the outlook is bleak with figures like 3,000 being talked about for dollar/rupiah, 3.00 for dollar/ringgit and 1.55 for dollar/Sing.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's gone beyond the point of being fundamental because countries like Hong Kong are being dragged in, the issues which started the thing in the first place are not protecting the countries where those issues don't exist,&quot; said Tim Fox, international economist at Standard Chartered Bank in London.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong dollar sagged in late business but it was in the forward market where the pressure was greatest as continued hedging by nervous fund managers took its toll.</p>
<p>Traders say the market is focusing closely on the Hong Kong dollar, despite the fact that the territory has sound economic fundamentals and huge reserves, as it is the last major pegged currency in the region.</p>
<p>Even the mighty yen succumbed to the regional depression and the scramble to buy U.S. dollars. With interest rates at 0.5 percent in Japan and the fact that the economy is likely to be hurt by the Asian turmoil, investors are simply looking to buy dollars.</p>
<p>The Thai baht, which kicked off the whole Asian debacle in May, held reasonably steady.</p>
<p>Analysts said this is because of all the currencies the baht is the one which has gone through the greatest adjustment. The market seems to be drawing others down to try and match the baht depreciation, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;People now are just lumping Asia together and almost seeing it as one country, it doesn't make too much sense but that is certainly what is happening,&quot; said one Singapore based trader.</p>
<p>The baht is down 18 percent since July 1 while the ringgit is down nine percent, the rupiah 15 percent and the Singapore dollar nearly six percent.</p>
<p>While the baht is holding steady for now the focus could shift back to Thailand amid much speculation that capital controls will be lifted soon.</p>
<p>Three-month forward positions which were taken out during the baht crisis in May have now matured and this was seen as the only bar to the lifting of controls.</p>
<p>Capital controls were slapped on in May to prevent overseas speculators getting hold of baht to sell but some traders thought there could be an announcement on the capital controls as early as this weekend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
