<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802369" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk Islamists fight secularist schooling plan.</title>
<headline>Turk Islamists fight secularist schooling plan.</headline>
<byline>Daren Butler</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish government and opposition deputies clashed in parliament on Friday over a bill to limit religious education that sparked fresh street battles between Islamists and police.</p>
<p>In the second day of stormy debate, deputies from the former ruling Islamist Welfare Party condemned secularist schooling plans at the heart of a military-led campaign against religious activism in the secular republic.</p>
<p>&quot;This mistake will bury you in the depths of history and on your gravestones ... it will be written that you are traitors,&quot; Welfare deputy Mikail Korkmaz said in a heated assembly address.</p>
<p>The expected passage of the bill fuelled Islamist anger across the country, sparking protests after Friday prayers which led to the arrest of more than one hundred demonstrators.</p>
<p>In Istanbul, police fired water cannon and used batons to break up a crowd of about 2,000 Islamists protesting after Friday midday prayers against the draft law.</p>
<p>The secularist coalition under Prime Minister Mesut Yilmaz, who replaced Turkey's first Islamist leader in June, has drawn the wrath of devout Moslems by giving top priority to a law which they see as a threat to religious schools.</p>
<p>The 550-seat parliament worked laboriously through each article of the law on Friday in the second day of a debate which assembly sources said may drag on until late into the night.</p>
<p>Under the bill, compulsory state schooling would be extended to eight years from five, effectively bringing an end to the primary section of Islamic Imam Hatip schools.</p>
<p>The schools were originally created to train Imams, or prayer leaders, for state-run mosques, but they now produce more graduates than even the vast religious establishment can absorb.</p>
<p>Government MPs tout the bill as a reaffirmation of Turkey's secularist foundations set out by, Mustafa Kemal Ataturk.</p>
<p>The armed forces, self-appointed guardians of the state's secularism, demanded introduction of the bill in February as part of an offensive against the Islamist-led government under Welfare leader Necmettin Erbakan.</p>
<p>Rallying behind the military, secularist politicians regard Imam Hatips as a breeding ground for radical Moslem activists.</p>
<p>Many Islamists took to the streets across Turkey on Friday to protest at the plans.</p>
<p>&quot;Imam Hatips cannot be closed,&quot; protesters chanted as they left a mosque in the historic heart of Istanbul.</p>
<p>Anatolian news agency said sixty-people were arrested in the Istanbul clashes which broke out as police blocked the path of protesters trying to march and deliver a statement to a nearby local education directorate.</p>
<p>Several of the protesters were dragged bleeding away from the scene and at least one policeman was injured.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, 37 people were detained in the southeast town of Sanliurfa, 13 people were arrested in the western city of Bursa and 10 in southeastern Bingol. Police also dispersed protests in Konya and Ankara, the agency said.</p>
<p>Police had refused permission for such protests which they saw as a security threat on Friday's thirteenth anniversary of the start of an armed Kurdish insurgency in southeast Turkey which has claimed the lives of more than 26,000 people.</p>
<p>In the southern province of Antalya, armed assailants held up a group of 40 Italian and Belgian tourists in a roadblock which prompted local officials to point the finger at Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) guerrillas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
