<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802312" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai govt to cut 57 bln baht off 1997/98 budget.</title>
<headline>Thai govt to cut 57 bln baht off 1997/98 budget.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Thai government said on Friday it will cut its 1997/98 (October-September) budget by 57 billion baht ($1.84 billion) to 925 billion baht.</p>
<p>Deputy Finance Minister Chaturon Chaisaeng said the cut would trim the budget for the 1997/98 financial year from 982 billion baht. The new figure is the same level as the budget for the current 1996/97 fiscal year.  </p>
<p>He said although the government expected to collect a projected 907 billion baht revenue next year, it would balance the 1997/1998 budget by using part of an estimated 66 billion baht increase in value added tax (VAT) levies after the sales tax is raised from Saturday.</p>
<p>Thailand is required by the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to cut government spending as part of tough austerity measures in return for a $17 billion international bailout package to help the country ride out its economic turmoil.</p>
<p>The opposition has called on the government to slash its 1997/1998 budget by at least 100 billion baht, a level which it said would make it necessary for the country to raise the VAT to 10 percent from seven. Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh said his cabinet would finalise details of the ministerial budget cuts next Tuesday.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Chaiyawat Wibulswasdi said on Thursday the Thai economy will likely grow 2.5-3.0 percent this year, expand four percent in 1998 and five-six percent in 1999. The expected 1997 growth will be the slowest since at least the early 1960s.</p>
<p>($1 = 31 baht)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662)-6520642</p>
<p>	 email:bangkok.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
