<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802372" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. announces largest hamburger recall in history.</title>
<headline>U.S. announces largest hamburger recall in history.</headline>
<byline>Doug Palmer</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Agriculture Department on Friday announced the largest recall of U.S. ground beef products in history, giving consumers one more reason to look twice at their burgers before taking a bite.</p>
<p>Hudson Foods Inc., an Arkansas-based meat processor, is voluntarily recalling at least 1.2 million pounds (544,000 kg) of frozen hamburger nationwide due to possible contamination with a deadly strain of the E. coli bacteria.</p>
<p>The amount is far beyond any previous ground beef recall and 60 times the 20,000 pounds (9,000 kg) that USDA initially said Hudson Foods was recalling. The size of the recall could continue to mount as USDA investigates the matter.</p>
<p>&quot;It's enough to make somebody a vegetarian,&quot; said Michael Jacobson, executive director of the Center for Science in the Public Interest. &quot;Clearly, the company has not been as careful as it should,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hudson Foods, which is primarily a poultry processor, began the recall this week after ground beef product from its Columbus, Nebraska plant was tied to 16 cases of E. coli contanimation in Colorado in July.</p>
<p>Five people were hospitalized for treatment, according to Colorado health officials. The strain of E. coli suspected of contaminating the beef can cause bloody diarrhea and dehydration, and in some, life-threatening kidney failure.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, these microorganisms are all around us,&quot; USDA Undersecretary for Food Safety Catherine Woteki told CNN. &quot;They occur naturally in cattle and at times during slaughter and processing there is some contamination that occurs.&quot;</p>
<p>At this point, consumers should do two things to protect themselves, Woteki said.</p>
<p>They should check to see if they have any of the potentially contaminated product. They should also, as a general rule, cook all ground beef to least 160 degrees Farenheit to kill any bacteria that is present, she said.</p>
<p>As part of its investigation, USDA also wants to know why it took Hudson Foods so long to provide full production reports for the days when the contamination occured.</p>
<p>The at least 1.2 million pounds of hamburger so far involved in the recall were processed at the firm's Columbus, Nebraska, facility on June 4, 5 and 9, the department said.</p>
<p>Consumers who have bought Hudson Farms frozen ground beef patties since June 4 to return any unused portion to where it was purchased, the department said.</p>
<p>The frozen patties were distributed nationwide in retail groery stores, wholesale stores and in fast food restaurants.</p>
<p>Sara Lilygren, spokeswoman for the American Meat Institute, said consumers should keep the recall in perspective.</p>
<p>&quot;A product recall is a sign that the system is working&quot; to keep unsafe food out of the mouths of consumers, Lilygren said. &quot;The U.S. meat supply is among the safest in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>But Jacobson of CPSI said meat and poultry should always be treated with caution, due to the potential health risk.</p>
<p>&quot;I think consumers should assume that meat and poultry is contaminated and treat it as such,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>That means cooking it to the proper temperture and washing up to avoid spreading potentially deadly bacteria, he said.</p>
<p>Bob Hahn, a food safety expert at Public Voice, a consumer advocacy group, agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;The message consumers have to take home is that they have to take some action to protect themselves,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Even with continuing improvement in meat inspection, &quot;noboby can give you a guarantee that any particular piece of meat is safe,&quot; Hahn said. The specific Hudson Food products so far subject to the recall are the following:</p>
<p>-- All 3-pound packages of &quot;Hudson Beef Burgers, Individually Quick Frozen,&quot; containing 12 quarter-pound frozen patties, with the code 1567A on the botton of the bag.</p>
<p>-- All 3-pound packages of &quot;Hudson 100 Percent Pure Beef Patties, Individually Quick Frozen,&quot; containing 12 quarter-pound frozen patties, with the code 156B7.</p>
<p>-- All 15-pound boxes of &quot;Hudson 60 quarter-pound Beef Patties, Uncooked Individually Quick Frozen,&quot; containing 60 quarter-pound frozen patties, with the code 155A7, 155B7, 160A7 or 160B7 on the bar code of the side panel of the box.</p>
<p>	  ((Washington newsroom, 202 898-8341))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
