<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802435" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New &quot;shoot-the-carjacker&quot; law fails Louisiana teens.</title>
<headline>New &quot;shoot-the-carjacker&quot; law fails Louisiana teens.</headline>
<byline>Jua Nyla Hutcheson</byline>
<dateline>BATON ROUGE, La. 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Just hours after a  Louisiana law that allows drivers to shoot would-be carjackers took effect on Friday, one teenager was killed and another wounded by two men who stole their car.</p>
<p>St. Martin Parish Sheriff's Office Capt. Newman Braud said two Abbeville, La., teenagers were shoved from their car and shot by two men they had picked up earlier.</p>
<p>Damian Durke, 19, died at the scene, he said. Kelso Montgomery, 18, managed to walk to a nearby home to summon police after the two carjackers drove off.</p>
<p>&quot;That's about all we're going to say right now,&quot; Braud said.</p>
<p>The law, which took effect at 12:01 a.m. Friday permits intended carjacking victims to shoot to kill when they believed themselves threatened by an assailant, armed or not.</p>
<p>The law, approved by the state legislature earlier this summer, is a companion to the 1993 &quot;shoot the burglar&quot; law that allowed residents to open fire when they believe themselves to be in danger from an intruder.</p>
<p>Louisiana law already permitted handguns to be carried in vehicles without permits.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the state, police reported no incidents. &quot;We haven't killed any up here today,&quot; Monroe, La., Police Lt. Mike Walker said. &quot;I figured we'd have all out war, but it hasn't happened.</p>
<p>&quot;Those shootings in St. Martinville are really ironic,&quot; a New Orleans police department spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;I mean, that's what the law was supposed to prevent. Now you can't help but worry that the next person's going to overreact when somebody walks up to his car for directions,&quot; she said.&quot;</p>
<p>The new law's supporters intended the measure to serve as a deterrent, but detractors said it was unnecessary and potentially dangerous. &quot;Self-defense has always been a valid defense,&quot; one law enforcement official said. &quot;You just have to use it when necessary.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BATON ROUGE, La."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
