<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802408" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks tumble with bonds, dollar, Gillette warning.</title>
<headline>Stocks tumble with bonds, dollar, Gillette warning.</headline>
<byline>Huw Jones</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks remained sharply lower Friday, dragged down by a weak bond market, the ailing dollar and an earnings warning by Gillette Co.</p>
<p>Shortly after 1 p.m. EDT (1700 GMT), the Dow Jones industrial average was off 124.27 points, or 1.56 percent, at 7,817.76, after falling as much as 130 points. After the Dow fell 50 points, the New York Stock Exchange imposed the first tier of limits on program trades.</p>
<p>Curbs were also placed on the Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks after the market fell 12 points. The S&amp;P index was down 11.88 points at 912.89 in early afternoon trading.</p>
<p>In the broader market, declining issues outpaced advancers by a margin of 18-7 on volume of 293 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now we are just hanging sideways, licking our wounds,&quot; said Doug Myers, vice-president of equity trading at Interstate/Johnson Lane.</p>
<p>A sharp rise in bond interest rates sparked a wave of selling in stocks Friday morning. The market recouped some of the lost ground in late morning, but the downtrend resumed by early afternoon.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond was down 13/32, or $4.06 on a $1,000 bond, boosting its yield to 6.58 from Thursday's close of 6.55 percent.</p>
<p>Adding to the day's volatility was the &quot;double-witching&quot; expiration of both stock and index options.</p>
<p>News that Gillette Co., the maker of razors and other personal care products, had told analysts to lower their earnings estimates for the year triggered a sell-off on the company's stock that spilled into the broader market, analysts said. Gillette's stock tumbled to a low of 85-3/8 before recovering slightly to 85-7/8, off 4-4/16.</p>
<p>The warning by Gillette echoed an announcement made last week by Coca-Cola Co. that its third-quarter earnings may come in lower than expected.</p>
<p>A slide in the dollar vs. the German mark amid fears the Bundesbank may raise interest rates also weighed on stocks. The dollar traded at 1.8215 marks, up from 1.8155 early in the day but off Thursday's close of 1.8395 marks.</p>
<p>A poll tracking consumer sentiment released at midmorning helped stem the market's losses, analysts said.</p>
<p>Preliminary figures from the University of Michigan showed consumer sentiment in August fell to 102.8 points from the final July reading of 107.1. The index, which gauges optimisim among consumers, helped to ease fears about a resurgence of inflation.</p>
<p>Among individual issues, Pep Boys tumbled 6-13/16 to 26-1/4 after Merrill Lynch cut its rating on the stock.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite index was down 12.62 points at 1,574.07. The American Stock Exchange index fell 3.27 points to 637.12.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
