<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802569" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs close limit down, pork bellies follow.</title>
<headline>CME hogs close limit down, pork bellies follow.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME lean hog futures tumbled for limit losses of 2.000 cents per lb late and held there at the close after concerns over cash markets pressured futures into sell stops. Pork bellies followed with next-year contracts down the 3.000 cent limit, traders said.</p>
<p>Hog futures ended 2.000 cent per lb lower to 0.075 higher with October and December down limit and October at 71.025 and December at 67.700 cents. Pork bellies were 3.000 to 1.600 lower with February down limit at 71.625 cents.</p>
<p>Hog futures turned down as cash concerns grew and sell stops took the market down limit, they said.</p>
<p>Cash hog indications turned lower for Monday and talk circulated that cash pork products would also be pressured, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;They (private sources) expected the loin market to be stronger for next week and now they are telling me loins are going to be dumped next week and probably lose 10 or 15 cents which they think will weigh heavily on the cash hog market next week,&quot; said Chuck Levitt, senior livestock analyst for Alaron Trading Corp.</p>
<p>Some of the anticipated pressure in pork is coming from less than expected demand from Japan, they added.  </p>
<p>Japan has been showing only light demand for pork from other countries despite low storage stocks. They also are taking in more beef, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;Our beef exports to Japan are up so they got it switched away from pork to maybe beef,&quot; said Dave Maher, analyst for Securities Corp of Iowa.</p>
<p>Rand Financial, Rosental Collins and RBH sold on the early setback while selling was general late into the stops, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Pork belly futures followed with sell stops taking February and March limit down. Futures broke through early technical support, they said.</p>
<p>Although August deliverable stocks may be in strong hands, that market is holding a premium to cash when futures usually are at a discount this time of year. Cash belly prices may have topped after moving up to as much as $82 per cwt this week from $78, traders added.</p>
<p>Refco and Iowa Grain notably sold February on the early setback, pit sources said.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
