<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802582" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Nu-Kote's, Epson's legal battle continues. [CORRECTED 19:24 GMT]</title>
<headline>Nu-Kote's, Epson's legal battle continues. [CORRECTED 19:24 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>TORRANCE, Calif. 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The legal battle between Epson America Inc and Nu-Kote Holdings over the latter's ink jet cartridges took a new twist Friday, as a federal judge held Nu-Kote in contempt and ordered it to recall its cartridges, but at the same time stayed his decision.</p>
<p>Epson said the U.S. District Court in Los Angeles Thursday held Nu-Kote Holdings Inc in contempt for selling cartridges for Epson ink jet printers in violation of an 1995 injunction and ordered a recall of all cartridges sold by Nu-Kote that violate Epson's 401 utility patent.  </p>
<p>The judge, however, stayed both the recall and sanction payments pending an expected appeal to the Federal Circuit Court of Appeals.</p>
<p>Epson, an affiliate of Seiko Corp, said the ruling applies to cartridges sold by Nu-Kote from March 10 through August 6.</p>
<p>No-Kote's outside counsel (corrects from general counsel) Ronald Katz said in an interview the ruling was &quot;actually better than we expected.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;With respect to anything that's on the shelves right now, that will be sold before the stay is lifted,&quot; Katz said, adding &quot;it's probably going to take a year&quot; for the appelate court to review the case.&quot;</p>
<p>The judge's order followed an August 11 ruling that required Nu-Kote to pay Epson $1 million for selling cartridges before March 10 in violation of the injunction.</p>
<p>Nu-Kote's Katz said Thursday in an interview that Nu-Kote redesigned its Epson-compatible cartridges to avoid the injunction. A Nu-Kote spokesman added Friday the company has offered to exchange all its older cartridges with the newly designed ones.</p>
<p>But Epson's assistant general counsel (corrects from general counsel) Alf Andersen said Thursday in an interview Epson believes its 401 patent covers all Epson-compatible cartridges made by Nu-Kote, including the newly-designed ones.</p>
<p>The August 11 ruling specifically named Nu-Kote's RF60, RF61 and RF62 cartridges in violation of Epson's patent. A Nu-Kote spokesman said the company no longer ships these cartridges but added retailers may still sell the RF60 and RF62.</p>
<p>Epson's Andersen said the company will probably file a motion asking the court to specifically order an injunction against Nu-Kote's newly designed cartridges for violating Epson's patent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORRANCE, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
