<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802601" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gillette stock cheap after fall - analysts.</title>
<headline>Gillette stock cheap after fall - analysts.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gillette Co's drop in stock price following a warning it expected lower than anticipated growth at one of its units presents a buying opportunity, analysts said.</p>
<p>Gillette told analysts late Thursday that its Braun unit, which makes electric shavers, kitchen appliances and other electric products, has been impacted by weakness in Japan and Germany. Gillette guided analysts to the lower end of an earlier range of $2.55 to $2.60 per share for 1997 earnings.</p>
<p>Brenda Landry, an analyst with Morgan Stanley, said she cut her earnings forecast on Gillette but still recommends a buy on the stock.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are buyers with the stock down like this,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Maureen Carini, an analyst with S&amp;P Equity Group, said that the entire consumer products group has been hit recently because of their high valuations.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, she said with the recent weakness in Gillette's stock price, which hit a high of over 106 in late July, was at a good price at 86 on Friday, down 4-3/16 on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's kind of overblown,&quot; she said.  &quot;And the market in general is down. I have an accumulate on right now and I plan to keep that.&quot;</p>
<p>Joseph Jordan, an analyst with PNC Institutional, said Gillette has several products in its pipeline, including a new shaving system, which will help fuel future growth.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not concerned about Gillette,&quot; he said.  &quot;This is just a little hiccup.&quot;</p>
<p>((Michael Ellis, Boston bureau, (617) 367-4176))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
