<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802690" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Publishing Co says growing directory revs.</title>
<headline>Publishing Co says growing directory revs.</headline>
<dateline>LAKE HELEN, Fla. 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Publishing Co of North America Inc said Friday the growth in its directory publishing revenues reflects its plan to be an integrated full service provider of specialty publishing for bar associations, colleges and universities, and other organizations.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement it published 21 directories during the 1997 second quarter, mostly for smaller bar associations.</p>
<p>It said it received average net advertising revenues of $77,041 per directory, compared to $64,805 per directory in the similar period a year ago.</p>
<p>In addition, the company said it is continuing with its program of investments in sales and operations, and with the upgrading of its production infrastructure to accommodate its planned growth in 1997 and beyond.</p>
<p>The company reported net income for the second quarter of $0.01 per share compared to nil in the same period a year earlier.</p>
<p>The company said nearly all its college directory publishing's annual revenue and all of its profits occur in the second half of the fiscal year, with operating losses incurred on minimal revenues during the first six months of the year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAKE HELEN, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
