<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802700" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>Italy: Last six abducted Italians freed in Yemen.</title>
<headline>Last six abducted Italians freed in Yemen.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The last six of 10 Italians who were kidnapped in separate incidents in Yemen this week were set free on Friday, the Italian Foreign Ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said the six Neapolitans, who included children aged nine and 10, were taken to a hotel near the Gulf of Aden coast, not far from the site of their abduction on Wednesday while on their way to Al Mukallaa.</p>
<p>The brother of Adolfo Ferraro, who was one of the six, was quoted as telling ANSA news agency that his brother had called him saying the group had been treated well and were considering continuing their holidays in Yemen.</p>
<p>Their release came after a group of four other Italians from the northern town of Cuneo were set free earlier on Friday after their abduction on Thursday near Khamir, some 100 km (60 miles) north of the capital Sanaa.</p>
<p>The four were taken to the Italian embassy in Sanaa, the foreign ministry said.</p>
<p>ANSA quoted relatives of the four tourists, who were in their late 20s and early 30s, as saying their kidnappers had treated them well, giving them whisky and pastries.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm calm now it seems everything has turned out all right,&quot; Liliana Radonia, whose son Franco was among the four, told ANSA.</p>
<p>&quot;My husband had told them that Yemen could be dangerous, but they went ahead and left anyway,&quot; she said. &quot;Now they will have some adventures to talk about.&quot;</p>
<p>The abduction of the two Italian groups was the latest in a series of kidnappings carried out by Yemeni tribesmen in one of the Arab world's poorest countries.</p>
<p>The tribesmen have tried to use hostages -- who have included French and U.S. diplomats and a Saudi ambassador -- as bargaining chips in land and water disputes with the government and foreign oil firms.</p>
<p>An Italian kidnapped earlier this month was released last Sunday and two others who were abducted in late July were freed after one day. In March, 11 Germans including seven motorcycle tourists were abducted and later freed.</p>
<p>All hostages have so far been released unharmed. Giorgio Gonanomi, the Italian released last Sunday, said he had been fed exotic fruits and treated wonderfully during his five days in captivity.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
