<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="802832" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bankruptcy filings up 24 percent in April-June period.</title>
<headline>Bankruptcy filings up 24 percent in April-June period.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite a buoyant economy, bankruptcy filings in U.S. federal courts rose 24 percent in the April-June period compared with the same three months a year earlier, the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts said Friday.</p>
<p>Filings also rose 10 percent from the first three months of the year, the seventh consecutive quarterly increase.</p>
<p>The court agency reported 367,168 businesses and individuals filed for protection from creditors during the April-June period, compared with 335,073 in the previous three months and 297,162 in the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>For the 12-month period ended June 30, a record 1.3 million bankruptcy cases were filed, the agency said. Courts in California, New Jersey and parts of Georgia and Florida reported the most filings over that period.</p>
<p>With the economy growing and unemployment low, economists have struggled to explain the continued rise in bankruptcy filings. Some blame the unprecedented rise in consumer debt, mostly from credit cards, while others say current laws make bankruptcy filing too easy.</p>
<p>A federal commission is reviewing the current system and is expected to send Congress recommendations for reform in October.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
