<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803052" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Currency/data supports quiet Euro veg oil market.</title>
<headline>Currency/data supports quiet Euro veg oil market.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tumbling Asian currencies and data from PORLA and the USDA supported prices on a holiday hit European vegetable oil market on Friday.</p>
<p>New lows against the dollar by the Malaysian ringgit and Indonesian rupiah coupled with friendly data from the Malaysian Palm Oil Registration and Licensing Authority (PORLA) supported palm oil prices.</p>
<p>But the full impact is not likely to hit prices in Europe until Monday owing to the Assumption Day holiday in many European countries.</p>
<p>PORLA pegged Malaysian palm oil output at 833,159 tonnes during July against 791,426 in June, a rise of 5.27 percent.</p>
<p>Exports were 715,906 tonnes against 622,210 tonnes in June, while stocks fell from 789,806 tonnes at end-June to 769,275 tonnes at end-July, a fall of 2.6 percent.</p>
<p>The Malaysian Oil Palm Growers' Council released data before PORLA and put output at 828,000 tonnes in July, 5.1 percent from June.</p>
<p>In its estimate for the first 15 days of August cargo surveyor SGS put local palm oil exports at 312,757 tonnes against 307,536 during the same period in June.</p>
<p>&quot;To say today's figures have been friendly is an understatement, but a lot of the increases we have seen this morning are due to currency,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The lauric oil sector took its lead from palm oil despite the good supply situation.</p>
<p>In the soft oil sector firm Chicago soy oil futures on the back of good export numbers from the USDA underpinned the market, but buyers were showing little interest.</p>
<p>&quot;People start to be tried of Chicago at this time of year and as far as most people are concern the weather market has been relegated to side-show status until the harvest, but these export figures have made some people sit-up and take notice,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>On Thursday the USDA said U.S. net export sales of soyoil during the week ended August 7 total 30,800 tonnes, against trade expectations of 5,000 to 10,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>At midday Dutch soy oil was one to two guilders up while rape oil was 1.25 to two guilders higher.</p>
<p>Palm oil was $2.50 higher across the board with no further business reported since the opening.</p>
<p>Coconut oil sellers were $5 to $10 up while palmkernel oil was $2.50 higher.</p>
<p>--Jim Ballantyne, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8062</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
