<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803056" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK defence project costs jump again, says report.</title>
<headline>UK defence project costs jump again, says report.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's defence ministry suffered a further rise last year in the cost overruns and delays which have dogged its major procurement projects, a parliamentary watchdog said on Friday.</p>
<p>The National Audit Office (NAO) said in its annual review of major military equipment projects that the Ministry of Defence (MOD) was likely to spend 1.375 billion pounds more than it originally estimated on 23 major projects, not including the two biggest projects -- the Eurofighter combat aircraft and Trident nuclear submarines.</p>
<p>In addition, it said that on average most projects were running 40 months behind schedule, an increase of five months on last year's level, mainly due to spending constraints and technical difficulties.</p>
<p>The office said the total cost of all 25 projects, which include new tanks, naval helicopters, assault ships and submarines, was more than 33 billion pounds.</p>
<p>The rising price of Eurofighter, which was highlighted in last year's report, was put at 1.36 billion pounds, while exceptionally, Trident is set to cost 3.429 billion pounds less than estimated. In last year's report the NAO had put the cost overrun on the 23 projects at 695 million pounds.</p>
<p>The MOD said in response that many of the overruns were accumulated over the many years of developing projects and it was now improving its budgeting and procurement processes.</p>
<p>&quot;The picture represents increases and delays accumulated over a number of years and action has been taken in all these cases,&quot; said a ministry official.</p>
<p>&quot;But nevertheless we recognise there is more work to be done,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last month, Britain's defence minister George Robertson said there would be a &quot;ruthless examination&quot; of how to improve procurement methods as part of the new Labour government's current review of national defence policy.</p>
<p>The NAO noted that the MOD was now working to improve project budgeting by taking a &quot;three-point&quot; range of scenarios in future cost estimates, and was also changing some procurement processes.</p>
<p>But there were pitfalls, it said. Tougher price negotiating methods had led to a reduction of 160 million pounds in the price for two new assault landing ships but the NAO said the negotiations delayed the project by a further 12 months.</p>
<p>-- Greg Mahlich, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
