<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803129" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: U.S. at odds with Israel on Palestinian money.</title>
<headline>U.S. at odds with Israel on Palestinian money.</headline>
<byline>Howard Goller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel said on Friday its ally the United States disagreed with it for freezing the handover of Palestinian tax money and customs duties following a Jerusalem suicide attack.</p>
<p>Danny Naveh, senior adviser to Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, insisted both countries made their positions clear during a four-day troubleshooting mission this week by U.S. envoy Dennis Ross.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States sees one matter differently and that's the decision by Israel to hold up the transfer of money to the Palestinian Authority,&quot; Naveh, the Israeli cabinet secretary, told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>Netanyahu sealed off the West Bank and Gaza and stopped financial transfers after the July 30 market attack which killed 16 people, including two bombers.</p>
<p>The attackers have yet to be identified. Israeli and Palestinian officials doubt the authenticity of a claim of responsibility in the name of the Islamic militant group Hamas.</p>
<p>Washington, chief sponsor of Middle East peace moves, sent Ross to the region to get Israel and the Palestinians to revive security coordination.</p>
<p>&quot;We must still wait and see what the results are...We aren't ready to return to business as usual...We have only one interest and that is that the Palestinian Authority fight terrorism,&quot; Naveh said.</p>
<p>A Gallup Poll of 510 adults published on Friday showed most Israeli Jews are satisfied with Netanyahu's steps following the attack. The poll for the daily Maariv showed 57 percent backed his handling of the situation.</p>
<p>Israel has partly eased the &quot;internal closure&quot; between Palestinian towns inside the West Bank, but retained a bar on entry to Israel that has kept tens of thousands Palestinians workers from getting to their jobs in the Jewish state.</p>
<p>At a Jerusalem magistrate court on Friday, two Israeli paramilitary border policemen were ordered held until Monday on suspicion they brutally assaulted two Palestinians who entered Israel without permits.</p>
<p>The two border policemen, aged 20 and 22, are suspected -- along with two others yet to be located -- of beating the workers, threatening them with a rifle and dragging one of them along the ground tied to a jeep.</p>
<p>Both workers had to receive hospital treatment. In a similar case on Thursday, a court gave eight-month jail sentences to two border policemen filmed brutalising Palestinians in a videotaped incident broadcast on television worldwide in October.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat's wife Suha said in an interview published on Friday that Netanyahu did not like Palestinians nor peace deals with them.</p>
<p>The Israeli daily Yedioth Ahronoth quoted her as saying her people were suffering under Israeli sanctions but that she would not &quot;beg&quot; the Netanyahu family for aid.</p>
<p>In Tel Aviv, an Israeli Arab delegation returned from a rare trip to Damascus saying they carried a message of peace from Syrian President Hafez al-Assad.</p>
<p>But opposition politicians in the group said Syria saw little chance of reaching a peace accord with Netanyahu's right-wing government.</p>
<p>&quot;The main message is that the Syrian leadership headed by President Assad wants real peace. He said clearly that 'With Bibi (Netanyahu), it will be hard for us to make peace'&quot;, member of parliament Saleh Tarif said on his return.</p>
<p>The 44 Israeli Arabs -- only the second such delegation to visit Damascus in 50 years -- spent a week in Syria at Assad's invitation.</p>
<p>No Syrian-Israeli peace talks have occurred since the May 1996 election of Netanyahu, who rejects Syrian demands for the return of the Golan Heights that Israel captured in 1967.</p>
<p>Former Labour governments of Shimon Peres and Yitzhak Rabin had been willing to cede at least part of the strategic plateau.</p>
<p>Israeli troops on Friday freed a Palestinian policeman they seized in the Gaza Strip on suspicion he was shooting at them on Thursday. An army statement said it turned out the policeman was firing at a fleeing suspect.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
