<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80320" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR: World market for September 25, 1996</p>
<p>London's nearby white sugar futures edged up slightly in reaction to a firmer New York market. December added $0.90 to close at $328.50 while March ended $1.60 lower at $325.60. In New York raw sugar futures ended lower across the board, pressured by fund liquidation, which drove March futures below the psychologically key 11.00 cents/lb-mark. While October added 4 points to close at 11.21 cents/lb, March gave up 12 points to close at 10.92 cents/lb. The back months lost between 4 and 12 points.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>SERBIA - According to official sources, sugar production in Serbia in 1996/97 is expected to reach 270,000 tonnes, white value, up from 155,200 tonnes produced in 1995/96. It is even not excluded that production could be as high as 280,000 tonnes. Producers are demanding protection from cheaper imports, which totaled about 100,000 tonnes of raw sugar and 40,000 tonnes of white sugar during January/August 1996. It was added that the most efficient protection would be introducing import quotas. The government plans to raise the area sown to sugar beet by 30,000 ha in 1997, taking it to 110,000 ha. It was added that the state's aim was to boost sugar production to 700,000 tonnes in 1997/98, equivalent to the factories' capacity. However, that figure seems to be totally unrealistic.</p>
<p>UNITED KINGDOM - The latest beet test results of September 23 show satisfactory increases in both, root weight and sugar content. Root weight now is 632 grams, up 24 grams from the previous test against 573 grams in 1995 and the five- year average of 634 grams. Sugar content is developing favourably and hit a high of 17.84 per cent on September 23, up from 15.80 per cent in 1995 and the five-year average of 17.22 per cent. This resulted in a theoretical sugar weight per root of 112.7 grams, 24.5 per cent up on the previous year's disappointing result of 90.5 grams and also above the five-year average of 109.2 grams.</p>
<p>SWITZERLAND - The latest beet test results show an above average increase in sugar content while beet yield increased only slightly. Beet yield on September 24 amounted to 91.5 tonnes, sharply up on last year's 61.4 tonnes and above the average of 74.6 tonnes. Sugar content reached the record high of 18.2 per cent against 16.7 per cent in 1995 and 16.1 per cent in 1991/95. This resulted in a theoretical sugar weight of 16.65 tonnes, white value, almost 40 per cent up on last year's 11.92 tonnes and significantly above the average of 11.99 tonnes. Given these excellent results and a higher area sown to beet, Switzerland will have a greatly improved crop in 1996.</p>
<p>DENMARK - The latest beet test results of September 23 show an above average increase in sugar content while root weight continued to develop sluggishly. Root weight amounted to 45.9 tonnes per ha, down from last year's 51.4 tonnes and also below the five-year average (1991/95) of 52.3 tonnes. Sugar content reached a high of 18.0 per cent against 15.5 per cent in 1995 and the average of 16.1 per cent. This resulted in a theoretical sugar weight of 8.26 tonnes, white value, per ha, up 4 per cent on the 1995 result of 7.94 tonnes but roughly 2 per cent below the average. Sugar industry representatives are still confident that an average crop will be reached.</p>
<p>SWEDEN - The latest Swedish beet test results of September 23 show an above average increase in sugar content, while the growth of beet weight remained disappointing. Beet weight reached 44.1 tonnes per ha, down from last year's 51.0 tonnes and also below the five-year average (1991/95) of 50.0 tonnes. At 18.1 per cent, sugar content was sharply up on last year (15.9 per cent) and also significantly higher than the five-year average of 6.3 per cent. This resulted in a theoretical sugar weight of 7.99 tonnes, down from last year's 8.10 tonnes and the five-year average of 8.17 tonnes.</p>
<p>TENDERS</p>
<p>The European Union awarded 79,500 tonnes of white sugar at a maximum refund of ECU 44.709 per 100 kg at its weekly tender on September 25. Cumulative awards so far made under the 1996/97 series of tenders for the period up to September 25 reached 392 750 tonnes, which compares to 663 525 tonnes last year. Following heavy rains, which affected the 1996/97 crop, Ethiopia is holding a buying tender for 25,000 tonnes of white sugar for delivery at the neighbouring Eritrean port of Asab or the Red Sea State of Djibouti. Offers will be reviewed on October 25.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
