<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803342" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Santander's Geral to buy 50 pct Brazil's Noroeste.</title>
<headline>Santander's Geral to buy 50 pct Brazil's Noroeste.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's leading bank Santander said on Friday its Brazilian unit Banco de Geral would buy a 50 percent controlling stake of another private Brazilian bank, Noroeste, for an estimated $500 million.</p>
<p>This operation will broadly complete Santander's investment programme in Latin America, where it has already invested or agreed to invest more than $1.5 billion this year, Santander said.</p>
<p>&quot;Geral will take control of Banco Noroeste through the acquisition of approximately 50 percent of Noroeste's total share capital,&quot; the bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Banco Geral's estimated investment in Noroeste will be a maximum of $500 million, which includes all related transaction costs and fees,&quot; the bank added.</p>
<p>Santander's 51-percent owned Banco de Geral is carrying out the operation using its own capital.</p>
<p>&quot;Taking into account Banco Geral's balance sheet strength, and in the light of preliminary due diligence, Banco Geral does not expect to require additional capital from Banco Santander to complete the acquisition,&quot; Santander said.</p>
<p>Santander agreed in March to purchase Geral for $220 million to be paid over three years, but is not yet consolidating its accounts into the group. Santander will begin to consolidate accounts when it makes its initial payments for Geral.</p>
<p>&quot;Santander will maintain its initial overall level of investment in Brazil and does not expect these transactions to have any significant dilutive effect,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>Santander chairman Emilio Botin said Noroeste's solid capital base, commercial branch network and client base complemented that of Banco Geral and enabled the bank to consolidate its initial plans for Brazil.</p>
<p>&quot;With this operation...Santander's programme of investments in Latin America is broadly complete,&quot; Botin said in a statement. &quot;The Brazilian market is fundamental to any strategy of building a full banking service franchise in the continent.&quot;</p>
<p>The sum of the two holdings will make Santander the seventh largest private bank in Brazil. The acquisition is subject to approval by the Brazilian and Spanish authorities.</p>
<p>Noroeste, owned by the Cochrane and Simonsen families who are selling their shares to Geral, is a medium-sized bank with 93 branches and assets of 6.5 billion reais ($6 billion). ($ = 1.085 Brazilian Reais)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
