<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803393" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal pilots call off strike, talks to continue.</title>
<headline>Portugal pilots call off strike, talks to continue.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pilots at Portugal's loss-making state airline TAP-Air Portugal called off a partial strike on Friday after an all-night negotiating session with the government.</p>
<p>The threatened strike over working hours, which had been expected to cause widespread disruption during the Assumption Day weekend, one of the busiest of the year, ended with an agreement between the pilots' union and TAP management to hold more talks on working conditions.</p>
<p>The government also agreed to suspend the application of special powers forcing pilots to fly.</p>
<p>&quot;From now on we have a guarantee that pilots will always be able to negotiate their rest periods. This is fundamental for us,&quot; the deputy leader of the Civil Aviation Pilots' Union (SPAC), Angelo Felgueiras, told TSF radio.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now in a position to negotiate measures that will guarantee (passenger) safety while enabling the summer timetable to operate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>TAP, which wants to reform schedules it says leave pilots flying fewer hours than those at rival carriers, had asked the country's civil aviation authority to decree an emergency increase in flying hours to cover the peak summer period.</p>
<p>SPAC warned that the company's actions would put passenger safety at risk because of the strain on crews.</p>
<p>On Thursday pilots queued up for special medical tests to ensure that they were psychologically fit to fly.</p>
<p>The selective strike and the unusually high number of pilots off sick led to numerous cancellations and delays over the last fortnight but a spokeswoman at Lisbon airport said the flight schedule was back to normal on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
