<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803605" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai copper futures end down on LME losses.</title>
<headline>Shanghai copper futures end down on LME losses.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai copper futures ended down on Friday on overnight losses on the London Metal Exchange (LME), with long liquidation controlling the market rhythm, traders said.</p>
<p>LME copper prices sagged on commission house selling on the kerb, but managed to stay within the market's current technical range. Last trade was at $2,271, down $16 from Thursday.</p>
<p>A downside chart and a stock rise of 4,575 tonnes was likely to prompt a test of $2,250 on Friday, London analysts said.</p>
<p>In Shanghai, the most actively traded December 1997 contract ended at 21,030 yuan ($2,537) per tonne, losing 220 yuan.  </p>
<p>It opened at 21,060 yuan, hitting an intraday high of 21,150 and a low of 20,960 yuan per tonne.</p>
<p>August fell 70 yuan to 20,720, September 80 yuan to 20,820, October 210 to 20,970, November 230 to 21,020, the January 1997 contract 190 to 21,060, and February 430 to 21,150 yuan per tonne.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 48,020 tonnes from 12,090 tonnes.</p>
<p>Copper opened lower and moved at low levels for most of the session.</p>
<p>Traders said the LME losses had hurt the confidence of long position holders in Shanghai and triggered long liquidation.  </p>
<p>In Shanghai, physical copper prices were around 20,750 yuan, down from 20,800 at in the early Friday session due to losses on the futures market, traders said.</p>
<p>Despite the LME losses, stop-loss orders were limited on Friday, showing investors were not altogether pessimistic, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Many investors are wary and will not sell their positions unless there is major negative news,&quot; a second trader said.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected copper to move around the 21,000-yuan level early next week.  </p>
<p>Aluminium ended mostly down.</p>
<p>August fell 50 to 14,550 yuan per tonne, September 100 to 14,650, October 100 to 14,900, November, the only rising contract, put on 60 to 15,040 and December dropped 100 to 14,950 yuan per tonne.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 3,810 tonnes from 3,090 tonnes.</p>
<p>($1=8.2889 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Shanghai Newsroom (86) 21-6279 7004 Fax: 6279-7174</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
