<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803803" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs erase gains after cash bond yield sets record.</title>
<headline>JGBs erase gains after cash bond yield sets record.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-08-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese government bonds (JGBs) erased their gains by midday on Friday in the face of pre-weekend book-squaring sales despite strong sentiment that earlier pushed yield on the benchmark 182nd 10-year cash bond to a record low and sent the key September futures contract above 127.00, traders said.</p>
<p>But any setbacks are likely to be temporary, with a further rise above the 127.00 level possible in afternoon trade.</p>
<p>Yield on the key 10-year cash bond touched 2.065 percent, a record low for any key contract, in mid-morning trade, partly on short covering in futures, traders said.  </p>
<p>This short-covering, which dealers said was linked to a shift in the futures benchmark to December later this month, took key September to 127.08, its highest level since late April, before selling emerged.</p>
<p>September ended the morning at 126.92, down 0.05 from Thursday's Tokyo close, with volume of 17,501 contracts. Yield on the 182nd bond was at 2.080 percent as of 0221 GMT against 2.075 percent at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>A lack of follow-through buying also undercut gains, traders said. Although investor buying had been widely expected, little sign of such activity was detected by midday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
