<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="803950" id="root" date="1997-08-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Worldwide Advertising &amp; Media Digest - August 15.</title>
<headline>Worldwide Advertising &amp; Media Digest - August 15.</headline>
<text>
<p>------------------------- WAM -----------------------</p>
<p>....REUTERS WORLDWIDE ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST.....</p>
<p>----------------- August 15, 1997 ------------------</p>
<p>Reuters news from around the world on Advertising, Marketing, Media, the Internet, Brand-name Products and Consumer Trends</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>NEW YORK - The Interpublic Group of Companies Inc says it has agreed to acquire the marketing service businesses of Marketing Corp of America, which it says has capitalized billings of almost $300 million.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - British advertising firm WPP Group Plc says it has agreed to form joint ventures in China and Hong Kong with South China Marketing Research. WPP's information and consultancy unit, RI, will have a 49 percent stake in each firm, investing 490,000 renminbi ($59,100) in the Chinese company and HK$14.0 ($1.8) million in the Hong Kong venture.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>WIESBADEN, Germany - OWM, the association of German advertisers, attacks television channels for hiking advertising rates during tough economic times. &quot;Ad price increases threaten to throw the advertising business out of balance,&quot; the OWM says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - Marsteller Advertising, the business-to-business advertising arm of public relations firm Burson-Marsteller, says it sees 1997 revenues reaching about $75 to $85 million, as the market for corporate advertising continues to grow.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - The highly fragmented nature of the advertising industry and the globalisation of brands and businesses will create growth opportunities for WPP Group Plc's two leading advertising agencies, J.Walter Thompson and Ogilvy &amp; Mather, says chief executive Martin Sorrell.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SCHAUMBURG, Illinois - Motorola Inc says it has chosen McCann-Erickson Worldwide for global advertising of its consumer products, including its cellular telephones and pagers. Motorola says its 1997 spending on consumer advertising will exceed $100 million.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - The Advertising Standards Authority, a British advertising watchdog, says it has been prevented by a court injunction from publishing a report mentioning a complaint about advertising by Direct Line, an insurance group.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - America West Airlines says it has retained Achenbaum Bogda Associates, a marketing management consulting firm, to advise the airline in its advertising account review.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - A new dimension of virtual imagery which can make adverts appear floating over a playing field during a high-profile sports event is set to revolutionise television advertising at major world sports and cultural events, proponents of the technology say.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - BMP interAction, the new media division of advertising agency BMP DDB, has made three new appointments, signalling a major investment in new media, it says.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>MEDIA &amp; THE INTERNET:</p>
<p>LONDON - Pay television operator British Sky Broadcasting Group Plc says it is on course to launch its digital satellite service in the UK in spring 1998. BSkyB says trading in the first six weeks of its 1997/98 financial year was in line with the year-ago period.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>PLEASANTVILLE, New York - Days after its chief executive quit, beleaguered publishing giant Reader's Digest Association Inc. says it lost nearly $23 million in the fourth quarter as it struggled to revamp its businesses.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>WELLINGTON - New Zealand publisher Independent Newspapers Ltd, controlled by media baron Rupert Murdoch, expects to raise its net profit in 1997/98 despite plans to purchase a stake in loss-making Sky Network Television, managing director Mike Robson says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - British media and leisure group Pearson Plc says it has sold its Churchill Livingstone medical publisher to Harcourt General Inc of the U.S. for $92.5 million.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - The European Commission warns Spanish telecommunications giant Telefonica de Espana against going ahead with its purchase of a stake in television channel Antena 3 without EU approval.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SYDNEY - Telstra Corp Ltd says it plans to trial technology which will allow customers with one telephone line to receive and make calls on their personal computer while they are using the Internet.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - Britain's Commercial Radio Companies Association says it has appointed National Economic Research Associates to study the best ways to develop UK commercial radio and identify the best overall circumstances for the UK commercial radio sector's audience and revenue growth.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>NEW YORK - ABC Inc has slashed about 200 jobs at the television network in a cost-cutting move as it prepares its annual budget for parent Walt Disney Co, say executives at the network.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>SAN FRANCISCO - Gap Inc, the casual clothing chain, says it is well positioned for the back-to-school season and the third quarter. Gap chief executive officer Millard Drexler said the chain will continue to build its brands, stepping up investment in advertising and marketing. Gap reported net sales grew 20 percent to $1.345 billion in the second quarter ended August 2.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>ZURICH - Latest Swiss watch export figures confirm a trend towards pricier, more durable models, including timepieces made of steel, and away from plastic watches. The industry also appears to be doing better overall according to data published by the Federation of the Swiss Watch Industry.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>STOCKHOLM - The state monopoly on alcohol sales could be overturned in a ruling challenging the legality of the unpopular system, under which alcohol can be sold only by state-owned stores called Systembolagets. A ruling is expected in the next two months.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Germany's motor vehicle output rose 20 percent in July on a year-on-year basis, rising to 434,000 units, the VDA German vehicle association says. Vehicle output in the first seven months of 1997 was up five percent at 3.03 million units, the VDA says.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>GOLDEN, Colorado - Lee Iacocca, former Chrysler Corp. chairman, plans to create a new industry -- electric bicycles and scooters. He has formed Los Angeles-based EV Global Motors to develop and market light electric transportation.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BUDAPEST - Hungarian food retailer chain Csemege-Julius Meinl Rt says it plans to further boost its Hungarian market share by opening new retail outlets and restructuring its product range according to demand.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>CONSUMER TRENDS:</p>
<p>NEW DELHI - Indian businessmen are offering 50 percent discounts to customers to mark the 50th anniversary of independence from Britain. Jaypee Hotels is cutting prices on its rooms at Hotel Siddarth, New Delhi. Mobile phone firm Escotel is lowering tariffs in Harayana state. Retailer Inter Craft Ltdis is offering discounts at its Inter Shoppe outlets, and Banaras House is selling silk sarees at half the usual price.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>LONDON - Digital Audio Broadcasting is about to catapult radio into a new era of CD-quality sound and extra programme choice. A dozen manufacturers are developing digital radio receivers for the consumer market and believe the devices will be popular in Britain, where 12 million radio receivers are sold each year.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SOFIA - Despite political upheaval and economic crisis, Bulgaria's opera singers have kept their place as one of the Balkan country's most enduring exports. Singers like the late Boris Christoff and soprano Raina Kabaivanska are winning acclaim in opera houses around the world and tickets for performances at Sofia's ornate opera house sell out despite the economic hardship affecting many people.</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>SHANGHAI - Shanghai's makers of mooncakes, the sticky, sweet cakes Chinese eat at Mid-Autumn Festival, have been forced into a price war, Business News says. Despite price increases for ingredients, most mooncake makers will charge the same as last year,as the growing number of laid-off workers has eaten into residents' disposable income.</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>See full stories on Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. And why not visit our Internet site at http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com?</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>($ = 8.289 Chinese Renminbi)</p>
<p>($ = 7.749 Hong Kong Dollars)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
