<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80415" id="root" date="1996-09-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Waterloo - A song, a train station or a battle?.</title>
<headline>Waterloo - A song, a train station or a battle?.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>WATERLOO, Belgium 1996-09-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>To many it is a song by Abba. To Londoners it is a railway station.</p>
<p>But to millions with a feeling for history it was the scene of the battle that broke France's military dominance of Europe -- although not all could say just where it is.</p>
<p>Given that there are some 75 Waterloos scattered around the globe, that is hardly surprising .</p>
<p>Researchers have identified 35 Waterloos in the United States, three in Canada, 15 in Britain, eight in Australia, five in Jamaica and others in the Caribbean, Sierra Leone, Germany, Ireland and even one in France -- although the name is understandably not terribly popular in that country.</p>
<p>But the original Waterloo is in Belgium, 20 km (12 miles) south of the capital Brussels, and it is celebrating this month its 200th anniversary as a self-governing commune.</p>
<p>&quot;Ours is the real Waterloo...but many of the others have outgrown the parent,&quot; said Yves Vander Cruysen, the town's alderman for culture and tourism.</p>
<p>Indeed, it was only the occupation of the area by the French Revolutionary forces in 1796 that finally allowed Waterloo to break free of its domination by neighbouring Braine-l'Alleud -- although it took 30 years more of wrangling to set the borders.</p>
<p>Many of the other Waterloos around the world were actually founded by soldiers who took part in the epic battle in June 1815, when an allied army led by Britain's Duke of Wellington and helped by a Prussian force led by Marshal Bluecher trounced the French army led by Napoleon Bonaparte.</p>
<p>An estimated 40,000 soldiers -- one-in-five of those who fought in the battle -- were killed. But the battle put the town on the map.</p>
<p>&quot;Waterloo is known throughout the world for the battle. But we wanted to show everyone there is much more to the place than that,&quot; Vander Cruysen said.</p>
<p>Nowadays Waterloo, a solely French-speaking commune in this bilingual country, is a somewhat calmer place with a highly cosmopolitan character.</p>
<p>As part of its bicentennial celebrations, Waterloo has invited the civic heads from all of its namesakes to join in the party. Most have had to decline but 10 will be there at the end of September to wave the flag.</p>
<p>The celebrations kick off on Thursday September 26 when the 10 will meet their Belgian counterpart and open an exhibition on the history of Waterloo from its rural start, through the battle and on to its present international status.</p>
<p>But the high points will be on Friday, Saturday and Sunday with a bicentennial banquet, an international fair and a vintage and veteran car rally respectively.</p>
<p>For 1,796 francs ($58) -- symbolic of the year in which Waterloo won its freedom -- diners will be able to feast on local cheeses, fresh and smoked salmon, roast scampi with shallots and tomatoes, roast lamb with maize crepes, cake, coffee and a selection of wines and -- of course -- water.</p>
<p>But of the set-piece events, the most eclectic is likely to be the international fair, including samples of many of the different cultures represented among Waterloo's 28,000 inhabitants.</p>
<p>Vander Cruysen said that with 96 different nationalities listed among Waterloo's inhabitants, it could justifiably claim to be about the most cosmopolitan commune in Belgium.</p>
<p>Americans, English, Koreans, Finns, French, Greeks, Indians, Irish, Japanese, Norwegians and Swedes are just some of the nationalities to be found in the town -- making it easy to understand why it is as normal to hear English as French on the streets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WATERLOO, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
