<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80420" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: REUTER EUROPEAN COURT OF JUSTICE DIARY FOR TUESDAY, OCTOBER 1 - THURSDAY, OCTOBER 10.</title>
<headline>REUTER EUROPEAN COURT OF JUSTICE DIARY FOR TUESDAY, OCTOBER 1 - THURSDAY, OCTOBER 10.</headline>
<text>
<p>(All venues Luxembourg, Plateau de Kirchberg)</p>
<p>TUESDAY, OCTOBER 1</p>
<p>THIRD CHAMBER (1530/1330 GMT) - Oral procedure C-10/96 Ligue royale belge pour la protection des oiseaux ASBL and others v/ Region wallonne: environment and consumers. Request for preliminary ruling. Interpretation of articles 5, 9 and 18 of Council directive 79/409/EEC of April 2, 1979 on the conservation of wild birds. National law allowing the continuous capture of wild birds for recreational purposes, so as not to force enthusiasts to modify their facilities and break with certain traditions. National law permitting the capture of wild birds to mitigate the ill effects of inbreeding in domestically reared recreational birds.</p>
<p>SIXTH CHAMBER (0930/0730 GMT) - Oral procedure C-80/95 Harnas &amp; Helm CV v/ Staatssecretaris van Financien: taxation. Interpretation of articles 4, paragraph 2, 13b(d), points 1 and 5, and 17(c), paragraph 3 of Council directive 77/388/EEC. Sixth Council VAT directive of May 17, 1977, on the harmonisation of member states' legislation on turnover tax. Common VAT system: uniform basis of assessment. Acquisition and holding of bonds bearing no relation to the activity of a company. Exemption of said activity insofar as the bonds are issued by a person residing outside the EU.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, OCTOBER 3</p>
<p>FOURTH CHAMBER (1530/1330 GMT) - Oral procedure C-105/95 Paul Daut GmbH &amp; Co. KG v/ Oberkreisdirektor des Kreises Guetersloh: free movement of goods. Request for preliminary ruling. Interpretation of EC treaty articles 30 and 36. Interpretation of Council directive 64/433/EEC of June 26, 1964, on health problems affecting intra-Community trade in fresh meat as amended and codified by Council directive 91/497/EEC. Interpretation of Council directive 77/99/EEC of December 21, 1976 on health problems affecting intra-Community trade of meat-based products as amended and codified by directive 92/5 - restriction on intra-Community trade in mechanically separated meats that have not been heat treated. Health conditions in respect of production and marketing.</p>
<p>FIFTH CHAMBER (0930/0730 GMT) - Opinion C-131/95 P.J. Huijbrechts v/ Commissie veer de behandeling van administratieve geschillen ingevolge artikel 41 des ABV in de provincie Noord-Brabant: free movement of persons. Interpretation of article 67 of Council regulation 1408/71 of June 14, 1971, on social security schemes for employed persons and their families moving within the EU as amended and updated by Council regulation 2001/83 of June 2, 1983. National law under which payments following the receipt of unemployment benefits are reserved for former beneficiaries of the unemployment benefit as applied under national law. - Oral procedure joined cases C-94/95 and C-95/95 Danila Bonifaci and others v/ Istituto nazionale per la previdenza sociale (INPS): social policy. Request for preliminary ruling. Interpretation and validity of article 4, paragraph 2 of Council directive 80/987/EEC of October 20, 1980, on the harmonisation of member states' laws on the protection of salaried workers in cases of employer bankruptcy. Financial guarantee institutions' obligation to pay. Member state's right to fix limits. Breach by a member state of obligation to transpose a directive. Obligation to pay damages to individuals affected. - Oral procedure C-261/95 Rosalba Palmisani v/ Istituto nazionale per la previdenza sociale (INPS): principles of Community law. Interpretation of EC treaty article 5. National law regulating deadlines for the introduction of a suit for damages resulting from rights conferred upon individuals caused by delays in the transposition of a directive. Less favourable deadlines than those imposed on an analogous measure by internal law. - Oral procedure C-373/95 Federica Maso and others v/ Istituto nazionale per la previdenza sociale (INPS) and others: social policy. Request for preliminary ruling. Interpretation of Council directive 80/987/EEC of October 20, 1980, on the harmonisation of member states' laws on the protection of salaried workers in cases of employer bankruptcy. Compensation measures for damages to individuals affected due to the non-transposition of a directive. System fixing the ceiling on the amount of compensation.</p>
<p>SIXTH CHAMBER (0930/0730 GMT) - Judgment C-41/94 Germany v/ Commission: agriculture. Annulment of Commission decision 93/659/EEC of November 25, 1993, on the clearance of the accounts presented by member states in respect of expenditure for 1990 of the EAGGF, Guarantee Section. Special primium granted to bovine meat producers under article 4A of regulation 805/68 as modified by regulation 571/89. - Judgment C-126/95 A. Hallouzi-Choho v/ Bestuur van de Sociale Verzekeringsbank: external relations. Request for preliminary ruling. Interpretation of article 41, paragraph 1 of the EEC/Morocco accord. Particular application measures in Dutch law on general old-age insurance. Refusal to take periods into consideration for the calculation of the pension rights of a member of a Moroccan worker's family. Discrimination on grounds of nationality. - Judgment C-380/95 Commission v/ Greece: approximation of legislation. Non-respect. Failure to have transposed within the prescribed period Council directive 91/414/EEC of July 15, 1991, on the marketing of phytopharmaceutical products. - Opinion C-29/95 Eckehard Pastoors and others v/ Belgian state: principles of Community law. Request for preliminary ruling. Interpretation of EC treaty article 6 and Council regulations 3820/85 of December 20, 1985, on the harmonisation of certain social security provvisions in the road haulage sector and 3821/85 of December 20, 1985, on recording equipment in road transport. Sanctions in cases of infringement. National rules requiring, in cases when they are challenged, the provision of a guarantee solely by foreign offenders, including EU citizens. - Opinion C-181/95 Biogen Inc. v/ Smithkline Beecham Biologicals SA: approximation of legislation. Request for preliminary ruling. Interpretation of articles 6 and 8, paragraph 1(b) of Council regulation 1768/92 of June 18, 1992, on the creation of a supplementary certificate for medicinal products. Rights of the patent holder vis-a-vis the holder of the marketing authorisation. - (1130/0930 GMT) Oral procedure C-285/94 Italy v/ Commission: agriculture. Non-respect. Failure to have transposed within the prescribed period Council directive 93/85/EEC of October 4, 1993, on the control of potato ring rot, 93/61/EEC of July 2, 1993, setting out the schedules indicating the conditions to be met by vegetable propagating and planting material other than seed pursuant to Council directive 92/33/EEC, 93/49/EEC of June 23, 1993, setting out the schedule indicating the conditions to be met by ornamental plant propagating material and ornamental plants pursuant to Council directive 91/682, 93/48/EEC, setting out the schedule indicating the conditions to be met by fruit plant propagating material and fruit plants intended for fruit production pursuant to Council directive 94/34/EEC, 93/52/EEC of June 24, 1993, amending Council directive 89/566/EEC on animal health conditions governing intra-Community trade in and imports from third countries of embryos of domestic animals of the bovine species. - Opinion joined cases C-94/96 Commission v/ Greece: agriculture. Non-respect. Failure to have transposed within the prescribed period Council directive 92/116/EEC of December 17, 1992, amending and updating Council directive 71/118/EEC on health problems in intra-Community trade in fresh meat and poultry. - Oral procedure C-171/95 Recep Tetik v/ Land Berlin: external relations. Request for preliminary ruling. Interpretation of article 6, paragraph 1 of Council decision 1/80 of the EEC/Turkey association Council. Worker in the regular employment market of a member state. Turkish citizen having boarded a ship sailing under a member state flag and subject to the laws of said state regarding his work, social security and income tax arrangements. Consequences for an eventual right of stay - voluntary abandonment of employment. - Oral procedure C-285/94 Italy v/ Commission: agriculture. Annulment of Commission regulation 1840/94 of July 27, 1994, laying down olive and oil yields for the 1993/1994 campaign. Adjustments in relation to data furnished by Italy.</p>
<p>PROVISIONAL AGENDA FOR TUESDAY-THURSDAY, OCTOBER 8-10</p>
<p>TUESDAY, OCTOBER 8</p>
<p>COURT OF JUSTICE, PLENARY COURT (0930/0830 GMT) - Judgment joined cases C-178/94, C-179/94, C-188/94, C-189/94 and C-190/94 Dillenkofer: institutional law. - Oral procedure C-357/95-P ENU v/ Commission: contracts. - (1000/0800 GMT) Oral procedure joined cases C-65/95 and C-111/95 Shingara: free movement of persons.</p>
<p>SECOND CHAMBER (0930/0730 GMT) - Opinion C-109/95 Astir: agriculture. - Opinion C-152/95 Macon: agriculture.</p>
<p>COURT OF FIRST INSTANCE, THIRD CHAMBER (enlarged) (1400/1200 GMT) - Judgment T-24/93 Compagnie Maritime Belge v/ Commission: competition. - Judgment T-25/93 Dafra-Lines v/ Commission: competition. - Judgment T-26/93 Deutsche Afrika-Linien v/ Commission: competition. - Judgment T-28/93 Nedlloyd Lijnen v/ Commission: competition. - Oral procedure T-106/95 FFSA v/ Commission: state aid.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, OCTOBER 10</p>
<p>COURT OF JUSTICE, FIFTH CHAMBER (0930/0830 GMT) - Judgment joined cases C-245/94 and C-312/94 Hoever: free movement of persons. - Judgment C-78/95 Magenta Druck and Verlag: judicial competence convention/execution of decisions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
