<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804380" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TENNIS-SELES BEATS HUBER TO WIN CANADIAN OPEN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SELES BEATS HUBER TO WIN CANADIAN OPEN.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-08-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top-seeded Monica Seles won her third Canadian Open in a row on Sunday with a 6-2 6-4 victory over eighth-seeded Anke Huber of Germany.</p>
<p>Seles earned the first prize of $150,000 in extending the string of Canadian Open titles she began two years ago when she made a triumphant return to tennis after her April 1993 stabbing in Hamburg, Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;That was the first tournament when I came back after the stabbing,&quot; Seles answered when asked to compare her victory this year with 1995. &quot;I remember everything like where my family was sitting in the stands. It's hard to have that same kind of nervousness and excitement again because I've been back on the tour for two years now.&quot;</p>
<p>This year, her mother is at home in Sarasota, Florida, with her father, who is battling cancer.</p>
<p>The victory was her eighth in a row over the eighth-ranked Huber -- all without losing a set -- and it moved the 23-year-old Seles from third to second in the rankings behind top-ranked Martina Hingis of Switzerland.</p>
<p>Under scattered clouds at Canada's National Tennis Centre, Seles lost the opening game of the match as she looked a little slow afoot. But she quickly picked up her game and won the set by simply outhitting an erratic Huber.</p>
<p>She led 3-1 in the second set but then appeared to tire as Huber rallied. At 3-all, Seles won the first point and then lost six in a row with a string of uncharacteristic unforced errors.</p>
<p>But Huber in turn, leading 4-3, 30-love, made five consecutive unforced errors to allow Seles back into the set. Seles capitalized on the chance and ended up winning the 75-minute match when Huber hit her fifth double fault at match point.</p>
<p>&quot;She's always there and she doesn't miss, especially on the important points,&quot; the 22-year-old Huber said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard if you've never beaten someone,&quot; Huber added, &quot;because it's always in the back of your head, even if you don't want to think about it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't play the big points very well, I tried to overpower the ball too much.&quot;</p>
<p>Commenting on Huber's second-set comeback, Seles said: &quot;I got a little tired and a step or two short but she also started playing better.&quot;</p>
<p>Though Huber led 4-3, 30-love on her serve, Seles said she wasn't overly concerned. &quot;I'd made two unforced errors so I just tried to stay calm and take it point by point,&quot; she said. &quot;Even if I'd gone down 3-5, it's no big deal.&quot;</p>
<p>Seles will play in at the WTA Tour event in Atlanta this week, her fifth tournament in as many weeks, and then move on to the U.S. Open which begins August 25. &quot;It's always a gruelling two weeks,&quot; she said about the U.S. Open. &quot;I'd probably like to serve a little better and be more consistent.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Monica is mentally stronger than she was two months ago,&quot; said Huber, who will play doubles with Seles at Flushing Meadows. &quot;She'll be tough to beat at the U.S. Open.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
