<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804453" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Golf-Love wins PGA by five shots over Leonard.</title>
<headline>Golf-Love wins PGA by five shots over Leonard.</headline>
<byline>Larry Fine</byline>
<dateline>MAMARONECK, New York 1997-08-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Davis Love outdueled British Open champion Justin Leonard on Sunday to win the PGA Championship by five strokes and claim his first major championship crown.</p>
<p>Love began the day tied with Leonard at seven under, a massive seven shots better than the rest of the field, and was near flawless as he posted five birdies and just one bogey in the pressure-packed showdown.  </p>
<p>The 33-year-old Love finished the final round with a four-under-par 66, his third 66 of the tournament, for an 11-under total of 269 as he shed the dreaded label of one of the best players in the world not to win a major.</p>
<p>As Love walked up the 18th fairway to the cheers of the gallery, a stunning rainbow graced the sky as the sun came out after a sudden downpour had drenched the course over the last few holes.  </p>
<p>After rolling in a birdie putt to punctuate his triumph, Love hugged his caddie, his brother Mark, his wife and his mother in a tearful celebration at the home hole. Love's father, famed teaching pro Davis Love Jr, was killed in a plane crash in 1988.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a long time coming,&quot; an emotional Love said after hoisting the silver Wanamaker Trophy. &quot;I've been close a few times, as we all know. I was finding it hard to get through the last three holes without breaking down.&quot;  </p>
<p>Love's maiden major fittingly came at the PGA, which has seen nine of its last 10 champions posting their first major championship triumph.</p>
<p>Victory brought Love a first-prize check for $470,000.</p>
<p>Leonard, whose sensational putting touch deserted him after three impeccable rounds on Winged Foot's greens, made four birdies of his own but suffered five bogeys as well as he put himself in trouble with errant drives throughout the day.</p>
<p>Leonard, who set a course record with his five-under 65 on Saturday, posted a 71 to finish at six-under-par 274.  </p>
<p>Jeff Maggert won his fight for a berth on the U.S. Ryder Cup team by firing a 65 of his own to finish third with a four-under 276 total.</p>
<p>Maggert made six birdies against one bogey to jump past Tommy Tolles into the 10th spot in the Ryder team standings. Tolles closed with a 66 for 284.</p>
<p>The only other player to finish the tournament under par was Lee Janzen. The 1993 U.S. Open champion, who led after two rounds, birdied the last hole for a one-under 69 and a one-under-par 279 total.  </p>
<p>Alone in fifth place was U.S. Ryder Cup captain Tom Kite, who shot 70 for even-par 280.</p>
<p>Tiger Woods and Phil Mickelson, playing in one of the day's glamor pairings, both finished with 75s for 286, six over par.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAMARONECK, New York"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
