<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804405" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-MADDUX WINS NINTH STRAIGHT AS BRAVES RALLY PAST CARDS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-MADDUX WINS NINTH STRAIGHT AS BRAVES RALLY PAST CARDS.</headline>
<dateline>ST LOUIS 1997-08-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greg Maddux fell behind early but battled on in the wilting heat to win his ninth straight decision as the Atlanta Braves rallied to a 5-3 victory over the St Louis Cardinals Saturday.</p>
<p>Maddux (16-3), who has not lost since June 13, gave up three runs and seven hits with no walks and two strikeouts in six innings. The right-hander, who had no-decisions in his prior three starts, has walked just three batters in his last six outings, spanning 42 innings.</p>
<p>&quot;They got me early, I got ambushed,&quot; said Maddux. &quot;They moved up on the plate and were hacking. Being three runs down, I can't give up more. My intensity has to pick up.</p>
<p>&quot;Mentally, every inning after that turns into the ninth. The mental part and the heat just wore me down.&quot;</p>
<p>Mike Bielecki and Mike Cather each pitched a hitless inning before Mark Wohlers worked the ninth for his 29th save in 33 chances. Atlanta avoided matching its season-high four-game losing streak.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Maddux) wasn't exactly sharp, but he shut them down,&quot; said Braves manager Bobby Cox. &quot;It was tough out there today.&quot;</p>
<p>The Cardinals, who have lost 10 of their last 13 games, took a 3-0 lead in the first on Ray Lankford's 24th home run. But the Braves chipped away and took the lead for good on Fred McGriff's two-run homer in the sixth that made it 4-3.</p>
<p>St. Louis starter Matt Morris (8-8) allowed five runs, eight hits and one walk with seven strikeouts in seven-plus innings.</p>
<p>&quot;It was hot out there, you need to focus every pitch against the Braves,&quot; said Morris. &quot;It was tough going against Maddux. The heat seems to get to you. I threw a lot of pitches, plus I got on base and had to run.</p>
<p>&quot;I think our team got content thinking, 'Wow, we got three runs off Maddux.' We need to keep plugging away and give it our best shot.&quot;</p>
<p>In Los Angeles, Roger Cedeno and Mike Piazza hit back-to-back homers to cap a five-run third inning, propelling the Dodgers to a 5-3 victory over the Cincinnati Reds.</p>
<p>Kent Mercker (8-9) took the loss but Richie Lewis, who relieved him, committed a three-base error that allowed two runs to score and then yielded the back-to-back homers.</p>
<p>Chan Ho Park (12-6) allowed three runs and six hits over six innings, striking out eight without a walk to win for the seventh time in his last eight decisions. After two scoreless innings from Antonio Osuna, Todd Worrell got the last three outs for his 29th save.</p>
<p>Los Angeles has won three of its last four games and moved within 1 1/2 games of first-place San Francisco in the National League West.</p>
<p>Eddie Perez hit a three-run homer for the Reds.</p>
<p>In Miami, Jose Guillen homered and drove in a career-high five runs and Francisco Cordova won his first outing since his ejection for throwing at a Florida batter nine days ago as the Pittsburgh Pirates routed the Marlins 10-5.</p>
<p>Kevin Polcovich homered back-to-back with Guillen.</p>
<p>Cordova (9-6) allowed three runs and six hits over 5 2/3 innings to win his third straight decision.</p>
<p>Bobby Bonilla homered for Florida, which dropped 4 1/2 games behind first-place Atlanta in the N.L. East.</p>
<p>In San Francisco, Mike Lansing stroked three hits and drove in three runs as the Montreal Expos ended a four-game losing streak with an 8-5 victory over the Giants.</p>
<p>Dustin Hermanson (8-5) allowed two runs over seven innings for his fourth straight victory. Steve Kline, Dave Veres and Ugueth Urbina finished up, Urbina for his 19th save in 23 chances. David Segui homered for Montreal in the sixth.</p>
<p>Pat Rapp (5-8) surrendered five runs and five hits over 6 2/3 innings. Barry Bonds hit his 30th homer for the Giants.</p>
<p>In Denver, Larry Walker regained his hitting stroke with a single, double and triple, two runs scored and an RBI to lead the Colorado Rockies past the New York Mets 7-5.</p>
<p>Walker, who homered to stop an 0-for-16 slump Friday, went 3-for-3 to raise his average to .380.</p>
<p>Darren Holmes (5-2) got the win.</p>
<p>Reliever Greg McMichael (7-10) allowed two runs in two innings and Mel Rojas yielded run in one inning of work.</p>
<p>In Houston, Gregg Jefferies belted a two-run homer in the top of the ninth to give the Philadelphia Phillies their season-high sixth straight win, 5-3 over the Astros.</p>
<p>The red-hot Phillies -- who still have baseball's worst record -- scored all of their runs over the final four innings. They have won 14 of their last 17 games.</p>
<p>Astros closer Billy Wagner (7-5) relieved Darryl Kile in the eighth with a 3-2 lead but yielded Kevin Jordan's game-tying single and then in the ninth the game-winner.</p>
<p>Jerry Spradlin (2-6), who had lost his last five decisions, pitched the eighth for the win. Ricky Bottalico fanned two in the ninth to earn his 23rd save in 28 chances.</p>
<p>In San Diego, Steve Finley's single scored Quilvio Veras with one out in the bottom of the 10th as the Padres remained perfect in extra-inning games at home with a 4-3 win over the Chicago Cubs.</p>
<p>The Padres are 9-0 in extra innings at Qualcomm Park.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
