<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804471" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO: Sporadic shell fire in Republic of Congo capital.</title>
<headline>Sporadic shell fire in Republic of Congo capital.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-08-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Political factions in the Republic of Congo capital Brazzaville traded shell fire on Saturday night and occasional bursts were heard on Sunday across the Congo River in Kinshasa, residents said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been the odd bit of firing, but only from time to time,&quot; an official with the World Health Organisation in Brazzaville said.</p>
<p>Further exchanges were heard by people in Kinshasa, capital of the neighbouring Democratic Republic of the Congo (formerly Zaire), just after noon on Sunday although the firing was again described as only sporadic.</p>
<p>Last week, battles between forces loyal to Congolese President Pascal Lissouba and his predecessor Denis Sassou Nguesso forced thousands more people to flee Brazzaville.</p>
<p>Peace talks in Libreville, capital of Gabon, have reached an impasse but were expected to resume on Monday, diplomats said.</p>
<p>The Congolese delegations are back in Gabon after several days of consultations with their leaders in Brazzaville. The two sides cannot agree on who should be named interim prime minister and what his powers should be.</p>
<p>The caretaker would take the country up to rescheduled presidential elections. Voting should have taken place in July but the poll was cancelled due to the fighting, which began in June when Lissouba started a crackdown on private militia.</p>
<p>Lissouba went to Kinshasa on Saturday to see President Laurent Kabila of the Democratic Republic of the Congo, days after an exchange of shell fire between their two capitals. Lissouba has blamed Sassou for the shelling that set it off.</p>
<p>He appealed for a regional solution.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Kabila) is going to get involved. He will not be alone. We would like to see all of Central Africa get involved, because this problem is African, and African problems should preferably be resolved by Africans,&quot; he said on state television.</p>
<p>Kabila said an African peacekeeping force should be set up to stop the conflict. &quot;We think that we must have an African peacekeeping force so that normal life can resume, constitutional life,&quot; he said without elaborating.</p>
<p>The United Nations backs the idea of an African peacekeeping force but wants a real end to hostilities before it is sent in.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
