<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804472" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Six killed in continuing violence in Kenya.</title>
<headline>Six killed in continuing violence in Kenya.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>MOMBASA 1997-08-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Five people were killed and dozens wounded in a night attack by unidentified assailants on the outskirts of Kenya's Indian Ocean port of Mombasa, residents said on Sunday.</p>
<p>A sixth person was shot by police and his body burned by angry villagers on Sunday after survivors of the first attack raided a neighbouring slum area, accusing the people there of attacking them.</p>
<p>Sunday's shooting at Bombolulu village and the Saturday night attack on the Shauri Yako slum area, eight km (five miles) north of Mombasa town, brought the death toll in a series of attacks since Wednesday to 31.</p>
<p>About 40 homesteads in the slum area were burned down by attackers armed with knives, machetes, clubs and other weapons.</p>
<p>Residents said the identity and the motive of the raiders were unknown. But they said leaflets found in the area had warned Kenyans from other areas to leave the Indian Ocean coast.</p>
<p>Those killed in the latest attack -- four men and a woman -- all came from western Kenya.</p>
<p>Non-coastal Kenyans were similarly targetted in the earlier raids.</p>
<p>Resident George Rakwar told Reuters: &quot;The police were told about the leaflets but did not take them seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;When the attacks began people ran to tell the nearest police station, but they were turned away. We have been left to die.&quot;</p>
<p>The leaflets, hand-written in Swahili, said: &quot;The time has come for us original inhabitants of the coast to claim what is rightly ours. We must remove these invaders from our land.&quot;</p>
<p>Police opened fire on Sunday to disperse an angry crowd which moved from Shauri Yako to the neighbouring village of Bombolulu, calling for revenge and accusing the people there of attacking them.</p>
<p>When one man was shot, villagers attacked his body with machetes and set it alight.</p>
<p>In Shauri Yako, pools of blood mingled with mud patches on village paths. Bodies of the dead lay where they had fallen -- one, covered with blood, lay on the doorstep of a burnt-out house.</p>
<p>The wife of one victim told reporters her husband was slashed to death when he called for help. He appeared to have recognised his attackers.</p>
<p>Resident Steve Migiro said: &quot;Perhaps everyone should now arm themselves because the government cannot protect us. The police have told us everyone should fight for themselves.&quot;</p>
<p>Fire engines were unable to negotiate muddy tracks to reach burning houses in Shauri Yako.</p>
<p>In another incident at Ukunda, south of Mombasa, a local restaurant was burned down on Saturday night, area residents reported.</p>
<p>Kenyan police mobilised reinforcements and called in the army and the navy to help in a massive security operation last week after a gang reported to number over 100 burned down a police station and killed seven policemen at Likoni, which is linked to Mombasa by a busy ferry.</p>
<p>The army and navy were stood down on Saturday, but the police operation continued. Police officers said a search had been mounted in an attempt to round up the group who stole 30 guns and a large quantity of ammunition from the Likoni police station.</p>
<p>Police said they had killed seven of the attackers and recovered two of the stolen guns and made 40 arrests. They denied earlier reports that three policewomen were missing, believed abducted by the attackers.</p>
<p>The Sunday Times, owned by the ruling Kenya African National Union (KANU) party, said there had been an &quot;orgy of violence and sporadic murders&quot; in the Mombasa area.</p>
<p>Several thousand foreign tourists in hotels along the coast north and south of Mombasa have been advised to stay in their hotels. No tourists have been involved in the violence , officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOMBASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
