<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80458" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: East European bourses drift lower in quiet trading.</title>
<headline>East European bourses drift lower in quiet trading.</headline>
<byline>Luli Popescu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The major East European stock exchanges drifted lower this week, when Prague reacted to a banking crisis, Warsaw dipped and Budapest shares weakened on international news.</p>
<p>Only Croatian and Sovenian stocks rose, while Bratislava shares eased, Bucharest and Tirana had no trades and investors focused on foreign currency and treasury papers in Bulgaria.</p>
<p>WARSAW</p>
<p>Polish shares eased this week and analysts said the market could be entering sideways trend, starting a typical consolidation period after rising for much of September.</p>
<p>The WIG index closed at 14,454.0 points, down 50.1 or 0.3 percent from last Friday's close.</p>
<p>Analysts said the next significant signal should be Friday's food-price figure for September's second 10 days.</p>
<p>They said investors would be watching if September inflation fell below 2.5 percent, putting it at less than 20 percent year-on-year and creating grounds for a rate cut.</p>
<p>BUDAPEST</p>
<p>Budapest bourse prices were driven by international developments, primarily news about Russian President Boris Yeltsin's health and by expectations of a U.S. rate hike.</p>
<p>With U.S. Fed rates unchanged, the BUX index began to rise after two losing sessions, but could not make up for Tuesday's fall of more than 89 points. It closed at 3,471.25 points on Thursday, down 78.95 from last Friday.</p>
<p>PRAGUE</p>
<p>Czech shares continued to suffer from the fallout of a recent banking crisis for most of the week, though a blue chip surge on Thursday brought with it hopes for the beginning of a market turnaround.</p>
<p>The PX50 index fell 16.9 points on the week to close on Thursday at 548.9.</p>
<p>The PSE had lost just over five percent after Kreditni Banka's failure led to the fifth biggest Czech bank, Agrobanka, being put under forced administration last week.</p>
<p>BRATISLAVA</p>
<p>The Bratislava exchange saw a week of listless trading, with significantly smaller volumes of shares generally traded in the Slovak blue chips.</p>
<p>The 12-share SAX index dipped during the week, from Monday's open at 208.68 points to Thursday's close at 207.22 points.</p>
<p>Market analysts did not expect the market to recover from its current apathy over the next few weeks.</p>
<p>BULGARIA</p>
<p>Only one corporate issue traded on the Bulgarian stock market this week as investors sought more liquid investments, including foreign currency and treasury paper.</p>
<p>Razvitie Investment Fund (RIF) sold 350 third issue shares at 32 levs, down 5.88 percent from last week's close. The 13-share Reuter All Bulgaria Stock Index (RABSI) ended at 41.02 points, down 0.12 from last Thursday under RIF's fall.</p>
<p>LJUBLJANA</p>
<p>Slovenian shares rose 4.8 percent, fuelled by a strong performance of drug company Lek's A issue which has soared 37.3 percent since it was listed two weeks ago.</p>
<p>The SBI index firmed 43.98 points to 962.84, while total turnover reached 1.1 billion tolars.</p>
<p>ZAGREB</p>
<p>Croatian stocks continued to rally amid new gains in leading issues with slight corrections, while market participants said the current bull run would last for a while.</p>
<p>The biggest gainer confectioner Kras jumped 60.50 kuna to 530.50. Fully-listed Zagrebacka Banka rose 100 kuna to a new high of 1,000, continuing a steady climb.</p>
<p>BUCHAREST</p>
<p>The Bucharest stock exchange was closed this week as it started to install new software to improve trading and settlement. It is due resume trading on October 1.</p>
<p>TIRANA</p>
<p>No treasury bills or state bonds changed hands in Tirana during its weekly sessions on Monday and Thursday.</p>
<p>		   SEPT 26  WEEK'S  CHANGE    1996 HIGH    1996 LOW</p>
<p>		   CLOSE     pts     pct</p>
<p>   CESI	 1,465.80  -39.29   -2.62     1,544.70	959.24</p>
<p>   WIG	 14,454.0   -50.1    -0.3     14,832.7     7,725.2</p>
<p>   BUX	  3,471.25  -78.95   -2.23     3,574.65    1,557.91</p>
<p>   PX50	   548.9   -16.9    -2.99	 582.0	 425.9</p>
<p>   SAX	    207.22   -1.46   -0.69	 226.34	150.4</p>
<p>   RABSI	   41.02   -0.12   -0.29	  55.48	 40.61</p>
<p>   SBI	    962.84  +43.98   +4.8	1,589.18	891.93</p>
<p>All-time high: WIG 20,760.3 (March 8/1994); BUX 3,574.65 (Sept 2/1996); RABSI 112.2 (April 27/1994); PX50 1,002.4 (April 7/1994); SAX 402.3 (Feb/1994); SBI 1,598.02 (June 28/1994). -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
