<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80459" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish Pioneer boosts share of stocks in its funds.</title>
<headline>Polish Pioneer boosts share of stocks in its funds.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's Pioneer mutual fund company raised the share of stocks in its balanced fund's portfolio to 40.8 percent in the first half of 1996 from 37.7 percent in the same period in 1995, Pioneer said.</p>
<p>First Polish Trust Fund Co., a fully-owned subsidiary of the U.S.-based Pioneer Group Inc, said in its interim report that the share of bonds in the balanced fund rose to 11.6 percent from 8.87 percent.</p>
<p>The proportion of T-bills in the fund's assets fell to 44.5 percent from 52.1 percent.</p>
<p>Pioneer said the balance was held in other securities and assets.</p>
<p>It said the largest stakes in its portfolio were Bank Slaski (4.0 pct), Elektrim (3.9 pct) and BPH (3.8 pct).</p>
<p>Listed stocks had a 66.7-percent share in Pioneer's Aggressive Investment Trust Fund. It said 27.9 percent of the fund's assets were held in T-bills and 5.4 percent in other assets. The fund started operating in December last year.</p>
<p>The report said Bank Slaski and BPH had the highest share in the aggressive fund's portfolio with 4.9 percent each.</p>
<p>Pioneer also said the share of government bonds in its debt instruments fund rose to 39.5 percent from 18.3 percent in December last year, while the share of T-bills fell to 55.8 percent from the earlier 77.1 percent.</p>
<p>It said the balanced fund generated an operating profit of 237.7 million zlotys in the first half of 1996, up from 119.7 million in the same period last year.</p>
<p>The aggressive fund had an operating profit of 25.0 million zlotys of while the debt fund's was at 2.1 million zlotys.</p>
<p>-- Malgorzata Rzepka +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
