<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804544" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian wool expected to stay stable this week.</title>
<headline>Australian wool expected to stay stable this week.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian wool market was expected to continue to be relatively steady at this week's sales in Sydney and Melbourne, with the possibility of downside, Wesfarmers Dalgety Ltd said.</p>
<p>The recent increase in Chinese activity and new business did not continue to the same extent last week, largely due to the nearly two cent increase in the Australian dollar since August 8 to a peak of 74.82 US cents on August 14, it said.</p>
<p>Combined with this, European activity was traditionally quiet during its summer holiday period.  </p>
<p>&quot;These slightly weaker demand factors suggest any potential upside in (this) week's market is unlikely and that new business needs to be stimulated in order for this to happen,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>However, this week's offering was smaller than in recent weeks. Smaller offerings would apply for the rest of August and this would provide the market with some support, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, little volatility is expected, a situation which is likely to remain for a couple of weeks,&quot; Wesfarmers said.</p>
<p>A total of 79,445 bales are rostered for sale this week.</p>
<p>The eastern market indicator firmed by seven cents to 703 cents a kg clean last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
