<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804527" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - Aug 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - Aug 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Bank of Australia has revealed it will cost the organisation more than A$100 million to fix the year 2000 &quot;millennium bug&quot; on its computer systems, while Telstra estimates a similar cost and Woolworths has allowed A$45 million. UK adviserPeter de Jager has warned the. Federal Government it must take emergency action to convert its computers. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Victorian Premier Jeff Kennett is seeking strong personal involvement with Prime Minister John Howard to assist in tax reform, and promote an interventionist agenda where tax directly encourages investment, which is at odds with the Federal Government's aproach to industry policy and tax. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The New South Wales Industrial Relations Commission last week delivered a decision on Friday to give workers under the State's awards a A$10-a-week pay rise, in line with the Federal &quot;living wage&quot; increase, rejecting the minimum wage concept of the Austraian Industrial Relations Commission but adopting an &quot;award review classification rate&quot;. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard and Industry Minister John Moore will attend a function at Melbourne's Crown Casino this morning where Toyota Motor Corporation president Hiroshi Okuda will announce plans to start the Australian manufacture of a full-sized car o compete with the Commodore and Falcon, involving millions of dollars in investment at the Altona plant. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Federal Health Minister Michael Wooldridge will announce a plan tomorrow which will see private hospital patients receiving a quote for their surgery and out-of-pocket expenses in an effort to limit the gap in medical fees, which has been identified as a main reason people drop private health cover. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The positions on the Reserve Bank board left vacant by retailer Solomon Lew and businesswoman Janet Holmes a Court, whose terms expire today, have not been filled by the Federal Government, which could force the board to meet as scheduled on 2 September wthout a full contingency of members. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Bureaucrats will soon warn the Federal Government that some initiatives announced in the recent Mortimer and Metal Trades Industry Association reports on industry policy could be in contravention of world trade rules and could see Australia's free-trade cedentials undermined if adopted. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Brisbane police said yesterday a Federal Member of Parliament caught leaving a brothel would not be charged because he had paid for the services of a prostitute who worked in the same building but separately to the brothel. Queensland's prostitution laws allow patronage of a prostitute who works alone but not of those working in groups. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>The vice-chancellors of Australia's eight wealthiest universities, known as the Group of Eight, agreed on the weekend to launch an Asia-Pacific campaign to counter the negative publicity generated by Independent MP Pauline Hanson, and improve the standingof the nation's higher education system. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Federal Health Minister Michael Wooldridge will advise Federal Cabinet against making the legal changes that are required for the Australian Capital Territory's proposed heroin trial to proceed, due to the bitter public debate over the issue and the questionable scientific merit of the trial, despite his support for the idea at a Health Ministers' meeting last month. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Law Reform Commission released a report today claiming Australian judges are not properly trained, don't have experience across the range of cases they have to deal with, that there are no formal educational qualifications required for appontment to the Bench, and judges are likely to resist training from outside the legal profession. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The alcoholic drinks industry and the medical profession have launched a joint campaign to ensure people are aware of what constitutes a standard drink, following an Australian Medical Association survey last month which showed only 20 per cent of people new men could safely consume only four standard drinks a day. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The Real Estate Institute of Australia yesterday released figures showing lower interest rates had lifted housing prices in Melbourne, Sydney and Adelaide, with the median price of houses sold in Melbourne increasing 11 per cent or A$17,000 in the June qurter to A$170,000. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Victorian Association of Secondary School Principals will release a report today, &quot;Improving the School Performance of Boys&quot;, showing a decline in the academic achievement of boys, and will argue that early intervention and a change in teaching stylesmay be needed. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Western Bulldogs 43-point victory over Adelaide in their Australian Football League clash at Football Park yesterday means they are almost certain to make the finals, and are in the running for a top-four finish, after finishing 15th last year and being dismissed by most commentators earlier this year after losing four successive matches. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>South Australian Premier John Olsen last week cancelled the proposed multi-function polis, planned to be a futuristic science city, with nothing to show for the A$150 million spent on it over the past 10 years. The move defuses a potentially central issue of the State's upcoming electoral campaign. Page A1.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
