<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80468" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Korea, Taiwan hit by falling electronics demand.</title>
<headline>Korea, Taiwan hit by falling electronics demand.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Davison</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea and Taiwan are among Asian nations most damaged by a downturn in U.S. demand for electronics, but experts say their outlooks differ sharply.</p>
<p>&quot;They were both affected badly by the slowdown in global demand for electronic products, particularly from the United States,&quot; said Kevin Chan, economist at Salomon Brothers in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Electronics account for the majority of exports from both nations, but Korea had been particularly vulnerable to sinking Dynamic Random Access Memory (DRAM) prices and this would hinder near-term recovery, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;In Korea's case, (the trouble) is just starting,&quot; Graham Courtenay, an economist with SBC Warburg, said.</p>
<p>Semiconductors and other electronic components account for at least 35 percent of Korea's exports, which crashed in response to slowing global demand, ING Barings said.</p>
<p>Currency fluctuations worsened the situation, making Korean exports more expensive than competing Japanese products.</p>
<p>The won has depreciated by only seven percent against the dollar in the last year, compared to a 30 percent decline in the Japanese yen.</p>
<p>Courtenay said there had been plenty of warning signals to the DRAM price decline, but Korea failed to respond and cut back production.</p>
<p>&quot;The price plummeted essentially because Korea was making too many,&quot; he said. &quot;Korea has more or less destroyed the price... We all knew the price of DRAMs remained much higher than a normal cycle would suggest but Korea continued to expand capacity like no tomorrow, and all of a sudden tomorrow came.&quot;</p>
<p>But growth in Korean exports, which are restricted to relatively few products -- electronics, machinery, automobiles and steel -- fell across the board, worsening a trade deficit to an estimated US$14.2 billion this year from US$4.7 billion last year.</p>
<p>ING Barings estimates Korea's exports growth at 7.5 percent this year from a stellar 30.3 percent last year. Sluggish recovery to 9.0 percent is forecast next year.</p>
<p>Taiwan, by comparison, is already showing signs of recovery, with Salomon Brothers noting a 37.4 percent rise in computer orders in the first half this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The total exports decline appears to have bottomed,&quot; Salomon said in a recent report. &quot;Export orders received by Taiwanese companies up to the first seven months this year were growing by an average of 7.3 percent, while total exports grew by 4.3 percent over the same period.&quot;</p>
<p>Even so, declining demand is expected to push Taiwan's export growth down to five percent this year from 21 percent last year. Recovery is forecast next year to about 11 percent.</p>
<p>Falling semiconductor prices actually buffered Taiwan from some of the damage this year, ING Barings said. Cheaper components fuelled demand for personal computers and notebooks, which make up most of Taiwan's electronics exports.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
