<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804688" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. sends &quot;SWAT team&quot; to Midwest hamburger plant. [CORRECTED 23:11 GMT]</title>
<headline>U.S. sends &quot;SWAT team&quot; to Midwest hamburger plant. [CORRECTED 23:11 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Julie Vorman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A special &quot;SWAT team&quot; of government investigators is going to the plant that produced 1.2 million pounds of frozen hamburger patties recalled last (corrects from this) week, U.S. Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman said on Sunday.</p>
<p>A dozen inspectors from the Agriculture Department's food safety division and inspector general's office are on their way to the Columbus, Nebraska, plant of Hudson Foods Inc. to examine plant records and meat processing procedures, Glickman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome that because we're not afraid of what they will find,&quot; James Hudson, chairman and founder of the beef and poultry processing company, told reporters.</p>
<p>The department on Friday announced the largest recall of U.S. ground beef products in history, citing possible contamination with a deadly strain of the E. coli bacterium. Health officials blamed the beef and the microbe for 16 cases of illness in Colorado in July.</p>
<p>&quot;I've sent the SWAT team out to this particular plant because I want to send a signal throughout the industry that we will not tolerate practices which are ... incompatible with public health,&quot; Glickman told CNN's &quot;Late Edition&quot; program.</p>
<p>&quot;We got to find out why it happened and put a stop to it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The strain of E. coli suspected of contaminating the beef can cause bloody diarrhea, dehydration and, in some, life-threatening kidney failure. The same kind of bacterium was found responsible for a fatal outbreak of disease in the Pacific Northwest two years ago.</p>
<p>Hudson Foods was responsible in 1995 for the United States' biggest previous meat recall. That involved bits of turkey bone in packaged meat.</p>
<p>And the company was fined more than $300,000 last month by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration for repeated violations of federal worker safety rules, the Washington Post reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>Soon after Glickman's televised appearance, Hudson held a telephone news conference and said the company was cooperating fully with the Agriculture Department.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still baffled as to where it came from,&quot; Hudson said of the contamination, adding that it might have occurred before the meat arrived at the plant.</p>
<p>Hudson said the company had purchased foreign beef in the past, including beef from Australia, but all beef produced at the plant on the June recall dates had been domestic beef.</p>
<p>In recent months, Hudson Foods has conducted 57 tests on its beef patties to detect E. coli, he said.</p>
<p>The amount of meat being recalled is far bigger than in any previous ground beef recall and 60 times the 20,000 pounds the Agriculture Department initially said Hudson Foods was taking back. Hudson said he did not believe the quantity would grow again.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm concerned that the thing grew so rapidly, and that also happened a few years ago,&quot; Glickman said.</p>
<p>Asked why the company was still operating after two large recalls, Glickman said: &quot;I'm not in a position to judge the company right now. ... We have to conduct an investigation to determine if there is a pattern or not.&quot;</p>
<p>New federal meat safety rules are being implemented at processing plants around the country, Glickman said.</p>
<p>The plant in question was new and medium-sized, which meant it did not yet have to implement all the new federal rules, which are being phased in over two to three years.</p>
<p>Glickman said his department needed more inspectors and better tools -- such as the ability to impose civil penalties -- to improve its enforcement of the new meat safety rules.</p>
<p>But he said consumers also had a role to by learning to handle meat safely and to cook it at high enough temperatures.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the department said the stepped-up investigation of the Hudson Foods plant did not involve possible criminal charges. Investigators are trying to determine why Hudson initially estimated the amount of potentially tainted beef at just 20,000 pounds instead of the 1.2 million pounds eventually determined by the government.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to review their reporting process. We're going to try to figure out why there was such a gap,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
