<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80463" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Osprey Maritime confident of good 1996 results.</title>
<headline>Osprey Maritime confident of good 1996 results.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil tanker charter company Osprey Maritime is confident it will have a good full-year result for calendar 1996, Chairman Tim Cottew said on Friday.</p>
<p>Cottew told Reuters in an interview, the company, which currently has a fleet of 23 crude oil, product and chemical carriers, mostly operating under charter to oil companies, had grown substantially so far this year.</p>
<p>It had acquired eight new oil product tankers through its decision to purchase the Petrobulk Group earlier this year and also had four newly built ships coming on stream.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident we are going to have a fairly good year this year,&quot; Cottew said just after the release of the company's first-half 1996 financial results.</p>
<p>Osprey Maritime posted an eight percent rise in net profit for the six months to June 30, 1996, to US$7.61 million from US$7.03 million in the same period the year before.</p>
<p>Total revenue rose 14 percent in the period to US$33.40 million from US$29.37 million.</p>
<p>Of the total revenue, 69 percent came from operations in Indonesia, Cottew said.</p>
<p>Osprey Maritime, which is 48 percent owned by Bambang Trihatmodjo, son of Indonesian President Suharto, has substantial Indonesian business connections and several of the ships in its fleet are on charter to Indonesian state oil company Pertamina.</p>
<p>But Cottew said he did not believe the company was too concentrated on Indonesia: &quot;We were very concentrated on Indonesia. Today we aren't. We have a fairly good balance.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Indonesia is a very, very important market for us. It is a big market. It's a big population and demand is going up. Frankly, for any company looking at shipping in the region, Indonesia is a very good market to be in,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cottew said Osprey Maritime had almost overcome the difficulties it had had with a newly purchased vessel, the 268,000-dwt turbine Osprey Promise, which was acquired in June of this year for a total cost of US$17.5 million.</p>
<p>The ship developed boiler problems soon after acquisition and had to be taken out of service for maintenance work, he said.</p>
<p>Cottew said the total net cost of the problem was US$600,000 and the vessel would be ready to go back in service on October 6 or 7 and would load her next cargo soon afterwards.</p>
<p>Asked if Osprey could match the 120 percent rise in year-on-year profits it reported for 1995, Cottew said the rise had been exaggerated by the company's poor result in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to look at the 120 percent in the light of the 1994 figures...in which we had a one-time yen hit in profits.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think this year, barring unforeseen circumstances, we will meet the business plan we laid down for ourselves last year...The plan is not an ultra conservative plan,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But I'd rather have conservative steady growth rather than an enormous leap and then a problem later on. So good steady growth is what we are looking for.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if he was confident over prospects for the full year, Cottew replied:</p>
<p>&quot;Yes we are. We have had acquisitions, we have had new vessels coming in. He have been hit obviously by the problems to a certain extent. But with an expanded fleet you expect to get some technical problems. But the rest of the fleet so far, knock wood, we haven't seen difficulties there.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
