<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804788" id="root" date="1997-08-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran oil minister candidate maintains policy.</title>
<headline>Iran oil minister candidate maintains policy.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-08-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's oil minister designate Bijan Namdar Zanganeh signalled he would not carry out any immediate changes to the country's oil policy, the official news agency IRNA said on Sunday.</p>
<p>In his first interview since being nominated by President Mohammad Khatami, Zanganeh stressed policies already put in place by outgoing minister Gholamreza Aghazadeh.</p>
<p>&quot;Reducing the country's reliance on oil revenues and expanding petrochemical industry, increasing utilisation of domestic natural gas resources and upgrading domestic technology would be among the priorities,&quot; Zanganeh told the official Iranian news agency IRNA.</p>
<p>Boosting local gas production to feed an expanded petrochemical sector and domestic supply network would also be a priority, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Iran (has) the second largest gas reserves in the world and therefore it was necessary to accelerate exploitation of gas fields shared by Iran and other countries,&quot; IRNA quoted Zanganeh as saying.</p>
<p>Zanganeh stated Iran's oil policy was to strengthen the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), Iran's role in the 11-member group and encourage producer-consumer dialogue aimed at stabilising world markets.</p>
<p>Iran is OPEC's second largest producer with a supply quota of 3.6 million barrels per day (bpd). It is the world's third largest exporter behind Saudi Arabia and Norway.</p>
<p>&quot;Among his other programmes are well-calculated exploitation of oil and gas reserves and increasing the production capacity of the oil and gas fields,&quot; IRNA reported.</p>
<p>National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC) officials state that Iran's upstream production capacity stands at 4.2 million bpd, but industry analysts say that NIOC cannot sustain an output rate of more than four million bpd.</p>
<p>Zanganeh, who was energy minister in the cabinet of former president Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani, made no mention of U.S. sanctions targeting the Iranian oil and gas sector.</p>
<p>The IRNA interview did not touch on his views on international oil prices, the return of Iraqi oil to the market or what actions OPEC should carry out to support world prices.</p>
<p>Iran's Majlis, or parliament, begins scrutinising President Mohammad Khatami's proposed 22 cabinet ministers on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Khatami was sworn into office on August 4 after winning a landslide election victory in May.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
