<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="804890" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: PRESS DIGEST - RUSSIA - AUG 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - RUSSIA - AUG 18.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Aug 19 editions of Russian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>IZVESTIA</p>
<p>- Moscow has proposed giving separatist Chechnya wide autonomous rights similar to those obtained by Tatarstan.</p>
<p>- Six years after the attempted August 1991 coup which brought down the Soviet Union, Russians seem to have lost their post-Soviet romantism to a pragmatism which they had to learn the hard way.</p>
<p>- Russian cosmonauts aboard the Mir space station are limbering up for the hard task of repairing the crippled craft while on earth experts are working out who to blame for a series of glitches which put the Russian space mission on the verge of collapse.</p>
<p>- Organisers of the MAKS-97 airshow near Moscow are hoping new technologies will pave Russia's way to world markets.</p>
<p>- Russia is in for an upsurge in road accidents, says the head of the Traffic Police in an interview.</p>
<p>ROSSISKIYE VESTI</p>
<p>- Russian President Boris Yeltsin after a meeting with separatist Chechen leader Aslan Maskhadov in Moscow said he hoped Russia and Chechnya would stay together.</p>
<p>- The memoirs of former President Yeltsin's bodyguard Alexander Korzhakov are, in fact, not as interesting to normal people as they are to journalists who seem to thrive on the smell of dirty linen, says the official paper.</p>
<p>MOSKOVSKY KOMSOMOLETS</p>
<p>- Moscow, like before, continues to send huge sums of money towards Chechnya and then be surprised at the news it has disapeared into thin air.</p>
<p>- Russia is slowly turning from 'semi-bandit capitalism' towards a game played with rules, says First Deputy Prime Minister Boris Nemtsov in an interview.</p>
<p>--Andrei Shukshin, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
