<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805125" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya shilling ends slightly higher, remains weak.</title>
<headline>Kenya shilling ends slightly higher, remains weak.</headline>
<byline>Wambui Chege</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya's shilling slid to a new official low against the dollar on Monday as political an economic instability continued to weigh on sentiment.</p>
<p>The beleaguered Kenyan currency ended the day marginally higher as dealers took profits but the shilling's near-term prospects remain bleak, dealers said.</p>
<p>Commercial bank dealers said the shilling edged up 0.97 percent to close at 69.99 versus the dollar after touching a new official low of 70.68 earlier in the session.</p>
<p>The shilling has dropped 17.63 percent against the U.S. currency since the International Monetary Fund (IMF), citing corruption, cancelled a key aid package on July 31.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot of speculative funds being held by investors and they rushed immediately to cash in,&quot; a dealer told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;They're waiting for the next peak (low),&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Other dealers said the day's trade saw renewed dollar in-flows from Kenyan exporters who had been holding back their funds in order to sell dollars at levels above 70 shillings.</p>
<p>The shilling, which took a severe beating after the IMF's row with the Kenyan government on graft and governance, suffered another early blow on Monday, after violence flared its second city, Mombasa.</p>
<p>Market analysts said the violence in Kenya's largest tourist centre undermined the shilling's recovery chances, especially as tourism was Kenya's biggest source of hard currency, earning $465 million in 1996.</p>
<p>Tour operators said they had received some cancellations and Italy and Germany warned their tourists to take precautions in the coast region, where at least 35 people have been killed since Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The image of Kenya is dented. Cancellations will be there because people are worried,&quot; said Najib Balala, chairman of Mombasa and Coast Tourist Association.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to affect the way they (investors) leave the market. Right now it looks like they just want to get out,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Some foreign investors pulled out of the market on Monday by buying $6 million, despite an appeal last Friday by Central Bank of Kenya Governor Micah Cheserem for them to stay in East Africa's largest economy.</p>
<p>Cheserem, alarmed by a rapid outflow of dollars fuelled by the row with the IMF, made his appeal after investors pulled out of Thursday's weekly auction of high-yield treasury bills citing market uncertainty.</p>
<p>The bank only sold 50 percent of the 14 billion shillings of bills offered while about five billion shillings of treasury bills were not rolled over.</p>
<p>Cheserem has not intervened decisively to boost the shilling, saying he would allow the currency to fend for itself, but analysts say they feared he was deliberately allowing the shilling to weaken.</p>
<p>Police have blamed the Mombasa attacks on thugs, but pamphlets have cited ethnic slogans for seizing regional power in general elections due later this year. No date for the poll has yet been set.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
