<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805118" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Pacalta surges on Ecuador oil finds.</title>
<headline>Pacalta surges on Ecuador oil finds.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Pacalta Resources Ltd jumped on Monday after the company released details on two potentially big oil finds on its acreage in Ecuador.</p>
<p>Pacalta jumped 2.15 to 21.35 on the Toronto Stock Exchange with 788,415 share changing hands.</p>
<p>In its second-quarter financial results released on Friday, Pacalta said its Mariann 8 infill development location tested from one of two geological zones at 4,000 barrels a day of 30.2 degree API crude oil.  </p>
<p>Also, its Dorine 1 prospect on the company's City Block was drilled to 9,838 feet and was cased as a multi-zone oil well, the company said.</p>
<p>Pacalta said it just started a completion and testing program from Dorine 1, but well logs indicated 60 feet of oil saturation in three separate zones. Zones included the M-1, which is the producing zone in Pacalta's prolific nearby Fanny field.</p>
<p>&quot;If you read between the lines, (the two wells) are so far ahead of my best-case expectations that it's not even funny,&quot; Martin Molyneaux, analyst with FirstEnergy Capital Corp, said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I raised my target price when I saw this thing to C$30 over 12 months and C$40 over the next 24 months.&quot;</p>
<p>The company, whose stock has soared to current levels from 1.35 in March 1996 on the strength of its exploration and production at the City Bloc in Ecuador, increased its oil output to 11,867 barrels a day in the second quarter, up from 3,628 in the same period of 1996.</p>
<p>Current production was pegged at 13,250 barrels of oil a day.</p>
<p>Pacalta also said Phase 1 of an expansion of its pipeline system to Ecuador's main pipeline was slated to be on stream in September following delays.</p>
<p>That expansion was expected to boost capacity to 25,000 barrels a day. Phase II, which ould increase capacity further to 60,000 barrels a day, was slated to be completed in November. ((Jeffrey Jones, Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
