<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805204" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Aug 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Aug 18.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Kenyan press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY NATION</p>
<p>- Six people are killed and more than 20 are injured as hundreds of people leave Mombasa for their up-country homes after violence spreads north of Mombasa.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Musalia Mudavadi says the government will renew talks with the International Monetary Fund to sort out differences that led to it halting an aid package to Kenya.</p>
<p>- Four people are killed in a explosion in a discotheque in Murang'a during a a wedding party.</p>
<p>EAST AFRICAN STANDARD</p>
<p>- Four more people are killed overnight on Saturday as violence that erupted south of Mombasa spreads to the north coast.</p>
<p>- Roman Catholic bishops call for an indefinite suspension of the general election until the dialogue on constitutional reform is complete.</p>
<p>- Many tourists overseas are cancelling their bookings for holidays in Kenya in the wake of violence at the coast.</p>
<p>KENYA TIMES</p>
<p>- Suspects arrested in connection with the violence on the coast to appear in a Mombasa court on Monday.</p>
<p>- A group calling itself Opposition United Rebels claims responsibility for the current violence in Mombasa.</p>
<p>- President Daniel arap Moi links the violence in Mombasa to tribalism incited by opposition leaders with selfish interests.</p>
<p>THE EAST AFRICAN</p>
<p>- Regional foreign ministers meeting in Kampala on the Burundi sanctions over the weekend criticse Kenya for reopening air links with Bujumbura and demanded the links be cut.</p>
<p>- The International Monetary Fund is unlikely to reach a deal with Kenya's finance minister unless he is given a fresh mandate by the government.</p>
<p>- Tanzania completes the installation of cargo and passenger screening equipment at Kilimanjaro and Dar es Salaam airports to improve airport security and passenger safety. ($1=69.8 Kenyan shillings)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
