<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805311" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Investmentbank Austria downgrades Egis.</title>
<headline>Investmentbank Austria downgrades Egis.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investmentbank Austria said on Monday it downgraded its recommendation on Hungarian pharmaceuticals company Egis Rt after Egis released disappointing first half figures last week.</p>
<p>&quot;In considering the company's first-half performance and its medium-term outlook, we are downgrading Egis from 'accumulate' to 'hold',&quot; analysts Andrea Dicso and Lance Owen said in a report.</p>
<p>They said Egis's disappointing first-half performance was partially a result of its poor performance on the Hungarian pharmaceuticals market.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short-term we do not expect any significant improvements to take place in the bleak domestic pharmaceuticals market, which will certainly continue to impact Egis,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>In forint terms, Egis's domestic sales were down 11.9 percent, its exports were up 36.8 percent, increasing the company's total sales by a modest 8.5 percent.</p>
<p>z&quot;We recognise that Egis is strongly reliant on the struggling domestic market which occupied 47 percent of the company's sales in the first half, as opposed to (peer) Richter 's lesser proportion of 30 percent,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;Furthermore, the company's growth to export markets are proceeding at a much lower pace than its counterpart Richter.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
