<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80532" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-FREE STATE-GRIQUA MATCH HOLDS INTRIGUE.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-FREE STATE-GRIQUA MATCH HOLDS INTRIGUE.</headline>
<dateline>KIMBERLEY 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>With the Currie Cup competition down to the penultimate matches of the round robin phase this Saturday, Free State's away encounter with Griqualand West promises to be the most intriguing.</p>
<p>The Free State Cheetahs, on the back of their record demolition of South-Western Districts last weekend, are lying second on the section B table with one victory more than third- placed Griquas.</p>
<p>But Griquas have proved to be a difficult side to beat at home this season - as even Taine Randell's mid-week All Blacks can testify - and Saturday's battle between the two will probably determine the eventual second placing in the section.</p>
<p>Although Free State, who have produced their exciting brand of running rugby again this year, are favoured to finish this group in second place, they will be handicapped on Saturday with the doubtful start of both frontline locks. Braam Els has measles and Ryno Opperman has a knee injury.</p>
<p>Further problems in the Free State camp include loosehead prop Os du Randt (ankle), fullback Jorrie Kruger and leftwing Jan-Harm van Wyk (both hamstring).</p>
<p>The most interesting match in section A this Saturday will see defending Currie Cup champions Natal, fielding a few of their regular bench players, host third-placed Boland at Kings Park.</p>
<p>Boland, with six wins out of 10, have impressed many this season in booking their berth in the Currie Cup quarter-finals. Their front row of Neil du Toit, Johan van der Merwe and Marius Mostert have been among the best around and the likes of fullback Stefan Terblanche, scrumhalf Christoff Lotter and centre Marius Moolman are emerging as quality three-quarters.</p>
<p>But Natal, even though not at full strength, have been South Africa's premier province this year and remain the only unbeaten side in the competition.</p>
<p>French flyhalf Thierry Lacroix will start on the bench for Natal because of an achilles tendon injury but the revamped back line of Robert du Preez, Henry Honiball, Joos Joubert, Dick Muir, Jeremy Thomson, James Small and Andre Joubert still exudes class and pace - as well as a surfeit of tries.</p>
<p>In other Currie Cup matches this Saturday, Eastern Province will be hoping to rediscover the winning formula against Border in Port Elizabeth, Western Province should outgun against lowly South-Western Districts in Mossel Bay and South-Eastern Transval will expect few problems in beating bottom-placed Western Transvaal in Witbank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIMBERLEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
