<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805596" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam adopts new AIDS detection measures.</title>
<headline>Vietnam adopts new AIDS detection measures.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam, facing a rapid increase in the number of people infected with the AIDS virus, announced new measures on Monday aimed at improving its ability to detect and control carriers of the deadly disease.</p>
<p>The official Vietnam News Agency said the National HIV/AIDS Committee had been tasked with new responsibilities &quot;for controlling HIV/AIDS patients,&quot; and asked to exert greater efforts to detect and prevent the spread of the disease.</p>
<p>It did not explain what it meant by &quot;control&quot; but said centres for treating patients would be established in provinces where incidence was high and trial treatment using the drug AZT conducted.</p>
<p>The report said that in cases where it was felt necessary families of sufferers would be informed of their infection, while prison officials would be informed of any infected prisoners under their control.</p>
<p>Vietnam's first case of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome was reported seven years ago. According to official figures 6,635 people are now infected with the Human Immunodeficiency Virus, which can lead to AIDS, and 478 have died.</p>
<p>But unofficial estimates indicate a much higher number.</p>
<p>According to recent figures released by the United Nation Children's Fund some 84,000 people are infected now. The figure is expected to rise to around a quarter of a million within three years.</p>
<p>The VNA report said &quot;the number of victims of this disease increased at a soaring rate in some localities recently,&quot; and pointed to highest incidence in Ho Chi Minh City, followed by Hanoi, the central province of Khanh Hoa, and Quang Ninh province in the north.</p>
<p>The government is concerned about the rising problems of drug abuse and prostitution in Vietnam which are seen as conduits for the spreads of AIDS.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
