<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805562" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: FOCUS-Rupiah flirts with 3,000 level vs dlr.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Rupiah flirts with 3,000 level vs dlr.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah briefly fell through the 3,000 level against the dollar on Monday as bearishness continued to afflict the currency of the world fourth-most populous country.</p>
<p>The beleagured currency briefly fell to a record low of 3,005 to the dollar before recovering slightly to 2,970/80 in late afternoon, traders said.</p>
<p>Currency dealers said trading was based on sentiment and did not reflect the real condition of the economy. One called the rate &quot;ridiculously low&quot;.</p>
<p>The continuous erosion of the rupiah over the past few weeks spurred the government to revise its inflation forecast for 1997 on Monday although some economists believed the currency could recover soon.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen some offshore selling (of dollars),&quot; said Edwin Png, the chief of the treasury department for Bank of America Jakarta.</p>
<p>&quot;Offshore parties think the rupiah is ridiculously low at this level. A lot of funds are looking for a level to sell (dollars).&quot;</p>
<p>The rupiah weakened against the dollar after the central bank scrapped its intervention band last Thursday, effectively floating the unit, on sustained speculative attacks on all regional currencies.</p>
<p>The rupiah, which started the year at 2,363 to the dollar, had fallen almost 27 percent by Monday, with further weakness seen possible.</p>
<p>It has lost about one-quarter of its value against the dollar since the beginning of July, when speculative attacks on regional currencies began.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no fundamentals anymore. It's regardless what you think about the fundamentals in the long-term,&quot; one market analyst with a U.S. investment bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone believes that in the short-term the rupiah could weaken further to the 3,100 level. I would say based on market sentiment it's going to trade there even though (investors) believe that the fundamentals are strong,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Saleh Aziz, treasury manager of PT Bank Export-Import Indonesia, said the dollar appeared to be capped at the 3,000 level but warned of corporates doing aggressive hedging now.</p>
<p>&quot;If the rupiah can fall by 300 rupiah, it can also rise easily at the same extent. If that happens, those corporates are going to get burnt twice,&quot; Aziz said.</p>
<p>Aziz said offshore investors were looking for good entry level into Indonesia because of attractive yields.</p>
<p>&quot;But their interests are put on hold because of sustained local appetite for dollars,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The U.S. bank analyst said the weakening of the rupiah also resulted from the perception that the rupiah should adjust to some extent to preserve its competitiveness in export markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation will definitely die down. It's a question of whether it's within one month or a few months. People are waiting for some stability before they come in again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>State Planning Minister Ginanjar Kartasasmita said the government will try to maintain the 1997 inflation below 10 percent despite the weakness of the rupiah against the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult for us to say inflation will not be affected by the current rupiah developments. We hope we can still control inflation. We hope inflation will be in single digits,&quot; Ginanjar told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We have predicted inflation at around six percent this year but that is before the rupiah weakness. Because of current developments it is hard to get that level. That means inflation will be higher than our prediction,&quot; Ginanjar said.</p>
<p>Economists said government's target to keep inflation a single digit was realistic because imports as a percentage of GDP were only about 25 percent last year, compared with 95 percent in Malaysia and 48 percent in Thailand.</p>
<p>Indonesia's consumer price index rose 0.66 percent in July, compared with a fall of 0.17 percent in June.</p>
<p>Indonesia posted an inflation rate of 6.47 percent in 1996 calendar year, compared with 8.64 percent in 1995. the government has previously said inflation will be capped below six percent this year.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom (6221) 384-6364; Fax (6221) 344-8404</p>
<p>-- Email: jakarta.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
