<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805762" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chicago Miniature to buy Sylvania Lighting.</title>
<headline>Chicago Miniature to buy Sylvania Lighting.</headline>
<dateline>CANTON, Mass. 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chicago Minature Lamp Inc said Monday it has signed a definitive agreement to acquire Sylvania Lighting International for about $165 million in cash.</p>
<p>Frank Ward, chairman and chief executive officer of Chicago Miniature Lamp, said the acquisition will be financed with a $250 million bank facility provided by BankBoston.</p>
<p>The deal with the privately held company based in Geneva, Switzerland, is expected to close in September, subject to customary conditions, the U.S. company said.  </p>
<p>The acquisition is expected to close in September, subject to certain customary conditions.</p>
<p>Sylvania Lighting, originally one of the first U.S. lamp manufacturers, was acquired in 1959 by GTE Corp and expanded operations globally.  In 1993, GTE sold Sylvania's North American operations to the Osram division of Siemens AG and the rest of its international operations to its current owners.</p>
<p>Sylvania Lighting had 1996 sales of about $600 million, with 75 percent derived from Europe, 15 percent from South America and 10 percent from AustralAsia.  </p>
<p>The company currently employs 4,900, operates in 30 countries and has 13 manufacturing plants in nine countries.</p>
<p>Chicago Miniature Lamp said it expects the acquisition to add to earanings in fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>It noted, however, that &quot;strategic decisions&quot; affecting operations related to the acquisition and some costs associated with the deal will result in a downward adjustment to its third quarter fiscal 1997 projections.</p>
<p>Such an impact would be more than offset by the contribution of Sylvania to operations for the fourth quarter of fiscal 1997, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANTON, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
