<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805886" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks retreat anew after rebound from Friday's losses.</title>
<headline>Stocks retreat anew after rebound from Friday's losses.</headline>
<byline>Huw Jones</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks retreated on Monday as investors sold shares in disappointment after a rebound from Friday's rout proved short-lived.</p>
<p>At 1:00 p.m EDT, the Dow Jones industrial average was off 52.03 points at 7,642.63, having given back a morning recovery of 38 points after Friday's monstrous 247-point plunge.</p>
<p>The market seemed set to limp sideways, licking its wounds at least until Tuesday's meeting of the policy-setting Federal Reserve Open Market Committee, which was expected to leave interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a relief after the last five to six days,&quot; said Alfred Kugel, senior investment strategist at Stein Roe and Farnham. &quot;We have gotten the people who were most anxious out.&quot;</p>
<p>In the broader market, declining issues led advances 8-5 on active volume of 275 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq composite index was off 10.67 points at 1,551.36.</p>
<p>The pre-weekend selloff in stocks, which was the steepest since the 1987 crash, was sparked by concern that corporate earnings may lose some of their gusto after two years of strong growth.</p>
<p>The Dow's worst fall was the 508-point meltdown on Oct. 19, 1987.</p>
<p>Wall Street was preoccupied with earnings after Gillette Co. warned last Friday that its results may not grow as much as previously expected. Coca-Cola Co., another earnings giant, also said recently that its results will be disappointing.</p>
<p>On Monday, Hewlett Packard reported, as expected, lower earnings for the latest quarter. HP's stock dropped 4-5/16 to 61-7/8.</p>
<p>The bond market was steadier, with the Treasury's key 30-year bond up 13/32, which lowered its yield to 6.52 percent from Friday's close of 6.55 percent.</p>
<p>Despite last Friday's heavy sell-off, traders said stock market fundamentals have not changed. The economy was still in good shape.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing has really changed,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the market was still in good shape, noting that the drop did not ignite the widespread jitters that usually accompany a steep collapse.</p>
<p>Wall Street had been bracing for a correction, and the consensus was that stocks were overvalued after the Dow soared 880 points since the start of the summer amid moderate economic growth.</p>
<p>Gillette was off 4-3/8 at 81-11/16, building on losses notched up Friday.</p>
<p>Geron Corp. jumped 2 at 16 after the stock price doubled Friday on news of an advance in its cloning technology.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
