<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805992" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ARCO rig to reach Arctic drill site late Mon.</title>
<headline>ARCO rig to reach Arctic drill site late Mon.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Atlantic Richfield Co. said Monday it expects a mobile oil rig to reach a new drilling site in the Arctic Sea late Monday, despite attempts by environmentalists to block the journey in the courts.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the rig to arrive on the site this evening and there's been no interference from Greenpeace,&quot; said Al Greenstein, a company spoke.</p>
<p>A federal judge on Friday ordered protesting environmentalists from Greenpeace to keep away from the rig that ARCO was towing from a site 75 miles (120 km) east of its destination. ARCO began towing the rig Saturday.</p>
<p>U.S. District Court Judge Russel Holland ordered Greenpeace activists to keep their vessel outside a moving safety buffer he established around the operation.</p>
<p>Earlier in the week, a Los Angeles-based federal judge rejected Greenpeace's bid to issue a temporary restraining order against the rig.</p>
<p>Holland also granted requests from Arco and the state of Alaska for a temporary restraining order preventing Greenpeace from interfering with transport of the drill rig to the Warthog exploratory prospect in the Beaufort Sea about 3.5 miles offshore from ANWR.</p>
<p>Greenpeace argues that offshore Arctic oil drilling is environmentally risky, and that further new oil explorationshould be stopped.</p>
<p>The U.S. Coast Guard on Monday said Greenpeace has complied with the judge's ruling but that activists kept up peaceful protests over the weekend.</p>
<p>A Coast Guard spokesman said anchoring the rig to the sea floor will take fifteen hours once it reaches its destination.</p>
<p>On Friday, the U.S Mineral Management Service (MMS) approved ARCO's exploration plan for Warthog.</p>
<p>ARCO expects to begin drilling the site in November.</p>
<p>((David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau +1 213 380 2014))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
