<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805923" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall Street focuses on threat of sputtering US profits.</title>
<headline>Wall Street focuses on threat of sputtering US profits.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Profit warnings from U.S. blue-chip companies have investors for the first time tuned into the possibility that one of the engines driving Wall Street's bull market has begun to sputter.</p>
<p>Earnings surprises from Hewlett-Packard Co., Gillette Co. and Coca-Cola Co. have some reassessing whether a slowdown in corporate profit growth may be in the works for the third quarter, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe the announcements by Coke and Gillete, coming from such stalwarts, got investors to focus on the fact that this is precisely what is going to happen,&quot; said Hugh Johnson, chief investment officer at First Albany Corp.</p>
<p>On Friday, Gillette's announcement that it expected its 1997 profits at the low end of analysts' estimates was cited among factors behind a 247-point selloff in the Dow Jones industrial average.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola said on Aug. 8 its third-quarter earnings would only be &quot;slightly higher&quot; than year-earlier results. On that day, the Dow fell 157 points.</p>
<p>Since hitting a record closing high on Aug. 6 at 8,259.31 the Dow has dropped 5.5 percent through Monday's close.</p>
<p>The Dow closed 108.70 points higher on Monday at 7,803.36, but earlier in the day was down more than 75 points, weighed down partly by a report of lower-than-expected third-quarter profits from Hewlett-Packard Co.</p>
<p>Investor anticipation of robust earnings growth through next year has been a pillar of Wall Street's record rally. Bulls could come under more pressure if there are further indications that profits will not live up to forecasts, analysts said.</p>
<p>Chuck Hill, director of research at First Call, which tracks Wall Street earnings forecasts, said he did not view the earnings news from H-P, Gillette and Coca-Cola as signaling a broad erosion of U.S. corporate profit growth.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think they have any real implication that earnings are starting to deteriorate across the board,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts are forecasting third-quarter earnings growth from continuing operations for the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 companies at 12.4 percent for the third quarter, up from about 11 percent in the second quarter, Hill said. Fourth-quarter earnings are seen up 13.8 percent, he said.</p>
<p>A key to the upbeat earnings forecasts are expectations of continued growth in profit margins, which have been fed by corporate cost-cutting and productivity improvements.</p>
<p>But bearish analysts said corporate America has done all the cost-cutting and productivity boosting it can do.</p>
<p>Without more profit-margin expansion, earnings growth may be more in line with nominal Gross Domestic Product growth of about 5 percent or 6 percent, said Michael Metz, chief investment strategist at Oppenheimer &amp; Co. This could lead to a &quot;downward revaluation&quot; in stocks, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;You just can't justify these (stock) valuations unless there is going to be a further expansion of margins,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some analysts argued that this reassesment will be limited to companies making consumer nondurable products, such as Coca-Cola, Gillette and pharmaceutical makers. These firms are under additional pressure from the strong U.S. dollar, which clips their overseas sales.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's a problem for the market overall,&quot; said Peter Canelo, U.S. equity strategist at Morgan Stanley Dean Witter. &quot;I think there is a problem for consumer mutinational corporations primarily.&quot;</p>
<p>This could lead to investors to hunt for the groups of stocks that will still be able to squeeze out strong profits in the coming months. Among these could be industrial companies, such as paper and metal makers, benefitting from improving economies overseas, and financial stocks, helped by low interest rates.</p>
<p>A wildcard for the market could be the strike at United Parcel Service.</p>
<p>A prolonged strike could hurt earnings, particularily of small companies dependent on rapid inventory restocking. But a victory by the striking Teamsters Union could trigger widespread wage demands, crimping profits and fueling inflation, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets are fearful that this strike will be bad for the markets no matter what the outcome is,&quot; Robert Froehlich, chief investment strategist at Kemper Funds, said in a research note.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
