<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="805938" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: HEL deals to dominate U.S. ABS issuance this week.</title>
<headline>HEL deals to dominate U.S. ABS issuance this week.</headline>
<byline>Aleksandrs Rozens</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asset-backed securities (ABS) issuance is expected to fall off this week from last week's hectic pace and the deals that will come to market will involve home equity loan-backed securities, experts said.</p>
<p>This week, market players expect an $800 million home equity loan ABS from Advanta, a $270 million home equity line of credit-backed (HELOC) security from GMAC and a $575 million HELOC from IMC. Green Tree, too, is expected to bring a $300 million to $400 million HEL-backed offering.  </p>
<p>About $6.5 billion in new issues came to market last week, putting the market ahead of last year's year-to-date total, said Dan Castro, asset-backed analyst at Merrill Lynch &amp; Co.</p>
<p>According to Castro, last year's year-to-date level for total ABS issuance was $84.6 billion. This year's level was $85.1 billion, he added.</p>
<p>Much of last week's issuance was credit card-backed paper, said Castro.</p>
<p>&quot;Over $4.0 billion was fixed rate credit card issuance,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The opportunity to issue asset-backed securities pooling credit card receivables at a low cost prompted several issuers to bring their offerings to market last week.</p>
<p>Deals that came to market last week included transactions from First USA, MBNA, and Chase among others.</p>
<p>The arbitrage available to issuers utilizing the swap market drove fixed rate issuance, said Tom Heidenrich, an asset-backed analyst at BancAmerica Securities Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;You may see one or two more opportunistic issuers taking advantage of the swap spread,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Merrill Lynch's Castro agreed: &quot;The arb is so compelling that issuers are jumping at it.&quot;</p>
<p>Wider swap spreads allow credit card issuers to achieve a lower cost of funding by swapping floating rate receivables into fixed rate.</p>
<p>&quot;A credit card issuer's funding is in LIBOR, so they need everything on a floating rate basis,&quot; a New York ABS trader said, referring to the London Interbank Offered Rate. Normally, he added, many of these issuers would bring to market a floating rate bond.  </p>
<p>Because of last week's hectic pace of fixed rate credit card issuance, fixed-rate credit card ABS spreads to Treasuries Monday morning were one to two basis points wider, according to market players.</p>
<p>The chop and change in Treasury prices in recent weeks has not gone unnoticed by asset-backed market players.</p>
<p>&quot;The see-sawing (in prices) may have left some investors a little skittish,&quot; said Heidenrich.  </p>
<p>While there has been a flurry of fixed-rate product from credit card issuers, at least one participant will bring to market a floating-rate ABS transaction this week.</p>
<p>Market players said Discover will bring to market a $500 million floating rate credit card ABS deal lead managed by Morgan Stanley, Chase, Bank of America, and First Chicago.</p>
<p>A New York trader said price talk on the offering, a $500 million five-year floater, was eight to 10 basis points over LIBOR. A $26 million B piece on the offering was expected to price at 28 basis points over one-month LIBOR.  </p>
<p>Issuance this week may be off from last week, but participants expected new issues business to pick up in September.</p>
<p>&quot;In September, the flood gates will open. There will $24 to $25 billion in new issues in September,&quot; said Castro.</p>
<p>Participants said that, while secondary market activity has been subdued in the last week -- most buysider focus has been on the fresh paper in the primary mart -- the coming two weeks may see secondary activity among dealers.</p>
<p>This week and next week may see heightened inter-dealer activity because some dealers were &quot;squaring their books&quot; -- that is, cleaning up balance sheets to reduce their inventory of bonds at quarter's end, according to a New York trader.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody will be watching to see what dealers do with their inventories. They will watch for how aggressively they bring them to market,&quot; the New York ABS trader said.</p>
<p>(( -- U.S. Mortgage Unit, 212-859-1668 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
