<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="806001" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chicago plans $250 mln Wacker Drive rebuilding.</title>
<headline>Chicago plans $250 mln Wacker Drive rebuilding.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chicago officials plan a $250 million reconstruction of historic double-decked Wacker Drive that could see lower portions closed for a year, a deputy transportation commissioner said Monday.</p>
<p>Chicago is seeking $200 million of federal funding and $50 million of state and local money to finance the project, said Stan Kaderbek, deputy commissioner and chief engineer for bridges.</p>
<p>The city will seek federal funding in fall 1998 for the project, which is a joint effort between Chicago and the state of Illinois, Kaderbek said.</p>
<p>Wacker Drive runs parallel to the Chicago River downtown, with the east-west section at 70, the oldest part and most in need of repair, Kaderbek said.</p>
<p>About $110 million will be needed to overhaul that segment which runs from Michigan Avenue on the east to Lake Street, Kaderbek said. Plans call for preserving its historic qualities as well, he noted.</p>
<p>The remaining segments were built in the 1950s and later and are in lesser need of repair, Kaderbek said. The double-deck concept for Wacker Drive dates to the 1909 Burnham plan for Chicago.</p>
<p>The project is undergoing preliminary engineering studies at this point and the first contracts could be let for the construction in fall 1998 if federal funding becomes available, he said.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, Chicago Newsroom, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
