<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80600" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIAN PRESIDENT ASKS IMF FOR SUPPORT.</title>
<headline>BULGARIAN PRESIDENT ASKS IMF FOR SUPPORT.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's anti-communist president Zhelyu Zhelev on Friday appealed to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for financial support for this debt-ridden Balkan country.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I sent a letter to IMF Managing Director Michel Camdessus with a personal plea for financial and moral support for reforms in Bulgaria,&quot; Zhelev said in an address broadcast on state radio.</p>
<p>Bulgaria, which relies heavily on external funding to meet foreign debt payments and stabilise its crumbling economy, hopes to win a second $115 million tranche from the IMF in October.</p>
<p>The IMF postponed the tranche until the government had fulfilled reform pledges which include closing 64 loss-making state enterprises and stabilising its troubled financial sector.</p>
<p>&quot;The unprecedented crisis is the result of inaction and half measures of the government and parliament...The delays in the past two years are fatal,&quot; said Zhelev.</p>
<p>&quot;The price, which now has to be paid by all Bulgarians, has become enormous, terrible...Bulgaria is forced to beg for help without which there is no way out of the crisis,&quot; said Zhelev.</p>
<p>Dramatic price hikes on electricity, heating, transport and other utilities have made them unaffordable for Bulgarians living on modest state wages.</p>
<p>Bank closures and sky-rocketing inflation have eroded further people's savings.</p>
<p>Six years after the collapse of the communist regime, Bulgarians worry how will they survive the coming winter with looming power cuts and food shortages.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we see the catastrophic results of self-reliance and lack of dialogue with international lending institutions,&quot; said Zhelev.</p>
<p>Zhelev urged the socialist government, largely composed of former communists, to present a clear programme for overcoming the crisis and begin its fulfillment immediately.</p>
<p>Under a reform package sealed with the IMF in July, Bulgaria stands to receive $580 million over 20 months if it meets reform targets. REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
