<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="806082" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Illinois panel critical of electric deregulation plan.</title>
<headline>Illinois panel critical of electric deregulation plan.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Proposed electric deregulation plans for Illinois too heavily favor utilities and could discourage competition, Illinois Commerce Commission said in a report released Monday.</p>
<p>The plan &quot;falls short of providing the rate reductions that are achievable through a competitive market&quot; and includes a number of anti-competitive provisions, the commission found in a report to state Senate President James &quot;Pate&quot; Philip.</p>
<p>Commission Chairman Dan Miller said in July he believed the legislation needed revision and the report's findings were not unexpected.</p>
<p>Even with promised 15 percent rate reductions for residential customers, those served by Commonwealth Edison and Illinois Power Co  IPC.N would still pay 25 and 10 percent more than the current midwest average respectively, the report states. Rate hikes could also eliminate the reductions, the commission found.</p>
<p>Commonwealth Edison, a subsidiary of Unicom Corp, and Illinois Power, a unit of Illinova Corp, supported the deregulation plan introduced to the state General Assembly in its spring session.</p>
<p>Illinois representatives approved the plan in the final days of the session, but senate sponsors opted to delay consideration of the package until fall and Philip asked the commission to provide an analysis of the bill.</p>
<p>The legislation would permit utilities 10 years to recover for investments made under regulation that would not otherwise be recoverable and provides inadequate verification of those &quot;stranded costs,&quot; the report states.</p>
<p>Those and other provisions would make it uneconomical for small customers to switch before 2008 and &quot;render the freedom to choose an illusion for the great majority of Illinois citizens,&quot; the commission reported.</p>
<p>The bill also would allow utilities to sell billions of securitized bonds and other financial instruments for transitional funding backed by ratepayers that could be used to discourage competition, the report stated.</p>
<p>Chicago lawyer Frederick Feldkamp, who has advised Commonwealth Edison on the securitization issue, defended the bill's provisions as necessary to help control costs during deregulation.</p>
<p>Proceeds generated by securitization would be limited to repayment of existing debt and equity and funding other costs associated with the transition toward deregulation, Feldkamp said.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, Chicago Newsroom, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
