<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="806160" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mortgage market firm with markets on FOMC vigil.</title>
<headline>Mortgage market firm with markets on FOMC vigil.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mortgage-backed securities (MBS) were slightly higher with intermediate Treasuries at midday Monday, but trading was stagnant before Tuesday's Federal Open Market Committee policy meeting.</p>
<p>There was little impetus to do much beside remaining portfolio adjustments before the FOMC meeting, traders said.</p>
<p>No economic data were scheduled until July housing starts on Tuesday, and there were widespread expectations that policymakers would vote to keep interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>MBS were up 1/32 to 5/32, with discount bonds slightly outpacing premium bonds. Ten-year Treasuries advanced 5/32.  </p>
<p>Among 30-year 7 1/2-percent MBS, Government National Mortgage Association bonds were up 5/32 to 101-1/32 to yield 7.38 percent, Freddie Macs gained 3/32 to 101-18/32 for a yield of 7.26 percent and Fannie Maes advanced 3/32 to 101-17/32 to yield 7.23 percent.</p>
<p>Ten-year Treasuries were yielding 6.21 percent, in the middle of recent range between 6.00 percent and 6.40 percent.</p>
<p>After tame inflation data last week pulled that yield back down to mid-range, market sentiment about rate trends and prepay strategies has turned mixed, traders said.  </p>
<p>At the range's low, home refinancing was seen jumping, forcing early prepayment of mortgage-backed securities. As Treasury yields bounced up sharply from lows amid signs of some economic strength, prepay fears subsided.</p>
<p>During the most recent yield slide, &quot;IOs (interest-only securities) have really richened up a lot. POs (principal-only securities) have gotten to be a fairly attractive trade,&quot; said one trader. POs have value because prepays were being underestimated, he contended.</p>
<p>POs quickly became less expensive, the trader said, when investors sold them to unwind prepayment hedges as rates rebounded from their lows.</p>
<p>Investors get their cash flows sooner with POs when prepayments increase. The cash flows for IOs dry up when prepayments rise.</p>
<p>Traders weren't expecting to get much direction from housing starts figures, with the market on FOMC vigil. New homebuilding in July was forecast to have risen to an annulized rate of 1.46 million units from June's 1.452 million-unit pace, according to a Reuters survey.</p>
<p>(( -- Lynn Adler, U.S. Mortgage Unit, 212-859-1677 ))  </p>
<p>According to market observers at PaineWebber Inc, the FHA authority has been curbed by an FHA provision limiting FHA ARM production to 30 percent of the prior fiscal year's total.</p>
<p>According to PaineWebber's weekly publication &quot;Mortgage Strategist&quot;, the limit on FHA production will not affect August production. But, they warned September production could be low and suggested that ARMs for October settlement could be trading rich relative to bonds for September settlement.</p>
<p>(( -- Aleksandrs Rozens, U.S. Mortgage Unit, 212-859-1668 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
