<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="806111" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bell Atlantic backs 1997 EPS estimates.</title>
<headline>Bell Atlantic backs 1997 EPS estimates.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. telephone company Bell Atlantic Corp said Monday it was comfortable with Wall Street earnings estimates of $4.90 per share to $5.00 for the year.</p>
<p>Bell, which completed its merger with NYNEX Corp on August 14, said in a statement that it had also set a target range of 10 percent to 12 percent for long-term annual growth of its earnings per share.</p>
<p>&quot;We're confident that the power of our merger will allow us to sustain that kind of performance over the next few years, even while the communications industry goes through a period of dramatic transition,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>The consensus among analysts surveyed by First Call was for Bell Atlantic to show a profit of $4.94 per share this year and $5.41 for the next 12 months.</p>
<p>Bell also said it filed pro forma earnings for the past three and a half years with the Securities and Exchange Commission, after completing the $25.6 billion merger.</p>
<p>It said adjusted earnings for the second quarter of 1997 were $1.25 per share, 12.6 percent higher than the same period a year ago. Adjusted earnings per share for the first six months of 1997 were $2.46, an increase of 12.8 percent from the previous year, it said.  </p>
<p>Bell Atlantic said pro forma adjusted earnings per share, which exclude the effects of special items disclosed previously by the separate companies, grew 10 percent in 1996 to $4.49 from $4.08 the previous year.</p>
<p>For 1995, pro forma adjusted earnings per share grew 10.3 percent from $3.70 in 1994, it said.</p>
<p>The telecommunications company has 40 million telephone access lines and 5.5 million wireless customers.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212 859 1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
