<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80632" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Loewen says Florida probes Service bid.</title>
<headline>Loewen says Florida probes Service bid.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Loewen Group Inc said Friday that Florida's attorney general is conducting an anti-trust investigation of Service Corp International's proposed takeover of Loewen.</p>
<p>Loewen, North America's second biggest funeral home and cemetery operator, said it received a civil subpoena for documents in connection with the probe.  </p>
<p>Loewen said the subpoena suggests &quot;a wide ranging investigation into the potential impact of the proposed acquisition on pricing, Medicare/Medicaid issues and market concentration for cemeteries and funeral homes&quot; in Florida.</p>
<p>Service Corp is biggest operator in the industry. Loewen this week rejected a US$2.8 billion bid by Service, which is widely expected to launch a higher hostile bid next week.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the scrutiny of the Florida attorney general's office and other state regulators as well, since SCI clearly intends to eliminate its most formidable competitor in the North American marketplace,&quot; said chief executive Ray Loewen.  </p>
<p>A Loewen spokesman said the company knew of no other states with investigations underway.</p>
<p>A combined Service Corp and Loewen would have a 23.4 percent share of funeral homes in Flordia, according to the New York Times.</p>
<p>Loewen has said it believes anti-trust concerns would be a major obstacle to the takeover, but many industry analysts have discounted that theory, saying anti-trust hurdles could be overcome.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I98100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
