<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="806565" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: DSR-Senator chairman Sager predicts more mergers.</title>
<headline>DSR-Senator chairman Sager predicts more mergers.</headline>
<byline>Julian Bray</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Karl-Heinz Sager, chairman of DSR-Senator Lines GmbH, has forecast further mergers and alliances between container shipping lines as they drive to cut costs and maintain market share.</p>
<p>In a telephone interview with Reuters from DSR-Senator's Bremen headquarters, Sager said: &quot;It is undoubtedly time for further consolidation.&quot;</p>
<p>Hanjin Shipping Co Ltd said last week it would spend 80 million marks ($44 million) to recapitalise DSR-Senator and fund its reorganisation.</p>
<p>Hanjin Shipping acquired an 80 percent stake in DSR-Senator at the start of this year to give it a stronger presence in European container shipping markets.</p>
<p>It is one of a string of recent acquisitions in the sector. Canadian Pacific Ltd subsidiary CP Ships Ltd announced last week it had agreed to acquire Contship Containerlines Ltd.</p>
<p>Sager, who founded Senator in 1987, said mergers reflected lines' demand for more control of their trades. &quot;It is a matter of concentration of power, as we have seen with the CP Ships' acquisition of Contship,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the new containership alliances developed over the past 18 months between some of the world's largest lines would take time to settle down.</p>
<p>And he claimed that a new alliance may be formed between the three major lines currently outside the existing alliances, including China Ocean Shipping Co, Kawasaki Kisen Kaisha Ltd and Yang Ming Marine Transport Corp.</p>
<p>After four months of talks, Hanjin has decided to scrap DSR-Senator's distinctive round-the-world service in favour of a series of end-to-end 'pendulum' routes.</p>
<p>For Sager, Senator's founder and a long-time advocate of round-the-world services, it marks a turning point for container shipping.</p>
<p>He said he accepted that shifts in the market made change inevitable.</p>
<p>&quot;The important point is that the round-the-world concept was valid for the liner shipping business, and remains valid in some circumstances,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But with the advent of larger and faster container ships, it has become obsolete.&quot;</p>
<p>Changing trade patterns have also affected shipping lines' plans, with the North Atlantic trade falling in significance.</p>
<p>Annual transpacific container volumes are now six to seven million twenty foot equivalent container units (teu) annually, while between Europe and the Far East four to five million teu are shipped, Sager said. In contrast, the North Atlantic trade accounts for only two million teu.</p>
<p>Hanjin acquired control of Senator to underpin its rapid expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;DSR-Senator is an ideal match for Hanjin,&quot; said R.H. Lee, Hanjin Shipping senior vice president who has responsibility for the group's new subsidiary.</p>
<p>&quot;Hanjin has been strong in the transpacific trade between Asia and the US,&quot; Lee told Reuters. &quot;But our multinational customers are looking for us to have hubs in every major region, so DSR-Senator with its European base was perfect.&quot;</p>
<p>The enlarged group, which will operate some 100 vessels with total capacity of 400,000 teu will replace the former round-the-world service with a range of new routes operated in partnership with fellow South Korean line Cho Yang Shipping Co Ltd and the Kuwait-based United Arab Shipping Co SAG.</p>
<p>The services will include with two 'pendulum' services from Europe to the US West Coast via the Far East, three or four transpacific routes and Europe-Middle East-Asia service, Sager said.</p>
<p>DSR-Senator will survive largely in name only, although Sager will stay on as chairman.</p>
<p>Lee said that Hanjin and DSR-Senator backroom functions would be merged, with the closure of DSR-Senator offices in Rostock, San Francisco, Singapore, Dubai and Genoa.</p>
<p>However, sales would remain separate. &quot;We intend to maintain our independent faces to the customer,&quot; said Lee. &quot;But that is all. Everything else will be merged.&quot; -Reuters Shipping Desk +44 171 542 4087/4012 Fax 542 5017 ($ = 1.816 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
