<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="806673" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli bonds end higher across the board.</title>
<headline>Israeli bonds end higher across the board.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli bonds closed higher on Monday as</p>
<p>traders continued buying both CPI-linked and unlinked bonds for the</p>
<p>consecutive second day, traders said.</p>
<p>Indices:</p>
<p>* Government bonds general: +0.09 pct to 111.55</p>
<p>* CPI-linked government bonds: +0.08 pct to 111.86</p>
<p>* Unlinked government bonds: +0.11 pct to 110.79</p>
<p>* Dollar-linked government bonds: +0.12 pct at 110.73</p>
<p>* Bank of Israel short-term Makam bills: +0.04 pct to 108.93</p>
<p>Volume including Makams was an average 198 million shekels ($56.5</p>
<p>million).</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the relatively high July consumer price index (CPI, published on Friday) and expectations of a rise in interest rates at the end of the month, traders are buying unlinked bonds,&quot; said Ilan Doron of Solid Financial Markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The market expects inflation for the next 12 months to be eight to 8.5 percent,&quot; Doron said. &quot;With yields around 13 percent, unlinked bonds are attractive even if there is an interest rate rise at the end of the month.&quot;</p>
<p>The July index rose by 1.0 percent, at the low end of economists' expectations of 1.0 to 1.2 percent. In June, the CPI rose by 1.1 percent.</p>
<p>Doron said trading in CPI-linked bonds had been mixed with a positive trend. &quot;Many institutional investors have to invest money in CPI-linked bonds. Also, there is a tight supply of these bonds, which is keeping the prices high,&quot; Doron said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the Bank of Israel to raise interest rates by 0.5 percentage point on August 25,&quot; an investment manager at Israel Discount Bank said.</p>
<p>The base rate has been 12.7 percent since the middle of June.</p>
<p>Prices of dollar-linked bonds rose on Monday but amid very low volume, which Doron said reflected a lack of investor interest.</p>
<p>Note: Makams are zero-coupon unlinked certificates with durations of three months to one year. The Bank of Israel issues Makams to absorb liquidity.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.52 shekels)</p>
<p>- Shoshanna Solomon, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211 x233</p>
<p>($ = 3.504 Israeli Shekels)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
