<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="806627" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro Crude Outlook - Margins, thin loadings support.</title>
<headline>Euro Crude Outlook - Margins, thin loadings support.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>European crudes have shrugged off the effect of resumed Iraqi exports and, supported by leaner than anticipated September North Sea loading programmes, should remain strong this week, traders said.</p>
<p>Thirsty U.S. demand for gasoline that has boosted margins on both sides of the Atlantic will continue to encourage high refinery throughputs, buoying crude demand.</p>
<p>Cargoes of gasoline have been tempted transatlantic, stripping bare an already tight European market for light end product, traders said.</p>
<p>Balancing the surging margins has been a tight U.S. arbitrage for crude which looks set to continue as sustained demand for vessels to load Kirkuk Blend from Turkey's Ceyhan port pushes freight rates sky high.</p>
<p>But with the eight major North Sea export streams loading 280,000 barrels per day (bpd) less in September than in August supply will be balanced to tight.</p>
<p>Some 4.14 million bpd were due to load next month, with Brent down 1.5 million barrels and Forties over two million lower.</p>
<p>Major maintenance at Gullfaks has hit output, as have problems at Snorre which forced the delay of five Statfjord cargoes from August to September.</p>
<p>Last week's cloud on the horizon was the prospect of 30 million barrels of Iraqi crude depressing underlying prices. But that threat has largely dissipated.</p>
<p>&quot;The Iraqi oil is being absorbed,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;I know several buyers of Iraq were really thirsty as they were waiting for more than a month.&quot;</p>
<p>The first Iraqi barrels to be exported since late May were loaded last Thursday at Ceyhan bound for the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone waited for Iraq to come out,&quot; said a trader with a major grade seller. &quot;Although it hit sour when it came it didn't hit sweets and they're better because of U.S. gasoline and I think that demand will continue.&quot;</p>
<p>Last week wet Brent was supported by swaps-related buying by one Wall Street trader, who bought four cargoes in the September -5 to -9 range on Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>Contracts for difference were sold off cheaply at the end of the week as the trader repositioned himself to reoffer barrels without a home, traders said.</p>
<p>Although those wet Brents were expected to weigh on the physical market the underlying demand for sweet crude should keep the Dated discount to September Brent within the 10- to 20- cent range.</p>
<p>Other North Sea grades will enjoy good premiums, with values on Draugen, Ekofisk, and Oseberg all firming late last week.</p>
<p>Other Norwegian grades, particularly the offshore loaders with fixed shipping costs, look even better placed as freight rates surge. Gullfaks and Statfjord both gained 10 cents a barrel and were set to stay buoyant.</p>
<p>While the North Sea has survived the return of Iraq unscathed the effect on Urals markets has been as predicted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
