<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="806671" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli police indicted for beating Palestinians.</title>
<headline>Israeli police indicted for beating Palestinians.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three Israeli paramilitary border policemen were charged on Monday with kidnapping and assaulting two Palestinians earlier in the month.</p>
<p>An indictment released by the Justice Ministry said the policemen took the two men to an isolated wood where they continually beat them, hitting them on the head, chest and limbs.</p>
<p>They were were rounding up Palestinians who had entered Israel without permits in the face of a closure imposed on the West Bank after a July 30 suicide bombing in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The indictment said the policemen tied the legs of one the men with a rope attached to their jeep and dragged him several metres.</p>
<p>The policemen continued to brutalise the other Arab &quot;even after he began to beg to show him mercy because he suffered from heart problems&quot;, the charge sheet said.</p>
<p>Israel's Channel One television broadcast several days ago an interview with the two Palestinians, Ahmed Moussa and Mahmoud Ghneim, who lay side by side in hospital.</p>
<p>During the interview Moussa, breathing heavily through a hospital mask, said: &quot;Each one of them carried a club and administered beatings. One of them asked me if my chest was all right and hit me in the chest. There were three who hit me.</p>
<p>&quot;One of them pointed an M-16 rifle at my head -- he pointed the rifle next to my ear and told me: 'Now you'll get out of here. If I see you again, I will kill you. You must die.'&quot;</p>
<p>In a separate incident earlier this month an Israeli court sentenced to eight months in jail two other border policemen filmed brutalising Palestinians.</p>
<p>The videotape showed the two policemen kicking some of the Palestinians in the head, kneeing one in the stomach, forcing others to do push-ups and riding one man like a donkey.</p>
<p>Last week, the Israeli human rights group B'Tselem issued a report accusing border police of almost routinely beating Palestinians.</p>
<p>It detailed 15 alleged cases of &quot;beatings, degradation and serious abuse&quot; of Palestinians by security forces over the last three months.</p>
<p>B'Tselem said border police were involved in at least 12 of the incidents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
