<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="807178" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks end broadly down on U.S. fall.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks end broadly down on U.S. fall.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>-----------------(Snapshot 4.15 p.m./0615 GMT)-----------------</p>
<p>AORD cl	    2618.5   -47.7   DJIA cl	7694.66  -247.37</p>
<p>SPI Futures	  2603     -59   US 30yr cl	6.55    -0.01</p>
<p>10yrbond futs    93.410  -0.030   Gold NYcl 329.05 Asia  326.80</p>
<p>AUD   US$0.7420 (Fri US$0.7438)   CRB Index cl  239.13    -2.34</p>
<p>NIKKEI cl	19041.10 -284.93   FTSE cl	 4865.8   -125.5</p>
<p>S&amp;P500(Globex)   896.10   -2.70   NZSE40 cl    2470.82   -24.81</p>
<p>--------------------------(Aug 18)-----------------------------</p>
<p>*Stocks recover from early lows to end 1.8 percent weaker after Friday's 3.1 percent U.S. fall. Volume 283.97 million, value A$714.99 million, 1,096 stocks traded, 212 steady, 122 up, 762 down.  </p>
<p>The Australian share market slowly moved away from its early lows to close 1.8 percent down on Monday as investors nervously awaited the next U.S. session after Friday's 3.1 percent dive on Wall Street.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index ended 47.7 points lower at 2,618.5 after hitting an early low of 2,589.8. September share price index futures fell 59 points to 2,603, a 15.5 point discount to the underlying index. Turnover was a moderate A$715 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly, if we get U.S. market weakness it will inevitably flow through to the domestic market,&quot; said David Lansley, senior treasury economist at National Australia Bank.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to know if we are seeing a real correction though. I guess the thing that really concerns us is the outlook for U.S. corporate earnings,&quot; Lansley said.</p>
<p>The Australian share market has lost around 5.3 percent since its record high 2,727.9 on July 8, while Wall Street has fallen 6.8 percent from the August 6 high of 8,259.</p>
<p>Dealers said players would also keep a cautious eye on Tuesday's U.S. Federal Reserve meeting, although no change to monetary policy is expected.</p>
<p>Domestically, the accelerating reporting season could give investors further clues on where prices are heading.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we've seen so far has been rather flat, but this reflects the past. The interesting thing will be to see what the forecasts are,&quot; one equity strategist said.</p>
<p>News Corp, Fairfax and Normandy Mining are among those releasing results this week.</p>
<p>News Corp closed three cents lower at A$5.92 ahead of Wednesday's report, expected to show a 12 percent increase in net profit before abnormal items to around A$1.42 billion compared to A$1.263 billion in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Newspaper publisher Fairfax was steady at A$3.19 pending Tuesday's figures.  </p>
<p>Fairfax is seen revealing a net profit before abnormals of A$90.3 million compared to A$102 million in the 1995/96 year. Normandy closed unchanged at A$1.61. Analysts predict that the miner will post a healthy profit increase to around A$120 million for the year to June 30.</p>
<p>Gold miner Sons of Gwalia rose 16 cents to A$5.06. It said earlier on Monday it had completed the restructuring of its hedge book announced on Friday.</p>
<p>Nickel producer QNI finished seven cents lower at A$2.11 after reporting a net profit fall to A$32.11 million in 1996/97 from A$85.89 million a year ago.  </p>
<p>Bellwether BHP ended 39.2 cents lower at A$17.108.</p>
<p>&quot;You could argue that the price of copper rather than the market generally has caused BHP to fall, together with the problems it has had recently,&quot; Kevin Lourey of Peake Lands Kirwan said.</p>
<p>Two other major miners also fell more than the overall market. WMC came down 19.1 cents to A$7.28, while Rio Tinto closed 50 cents lower at A$20.98.</p>
<p>Commonwealth Bank stocks worth nearly A$115 million were traded as it went ex-dividend by 57 cents. The bank ended 75.4 cents lower at A$15.84.  </p>
<p>Ferry operator Holyman went against the trend to closed 15 cents higher at A$1.75 in a recovery from last week's sharp fall when the company lowered its year profit forecast. News that Holyman would vary the terms of its A$49.1 million converting preference shares issue to include a free attaching option also helped, brokers said.</p>
<p>Lend Lease also gained ground, up eight cents to A$28.40. The company said on Sunday its project management and funds management units would post 40 percent higher revenues in the current year. &quot;It's a growth stock and their full-year result was good,&quot; one Sydney-based dealer said.  </p>
<p>The retail sector was the weakest with a three percent drop as profit-taking added to the general weak sentiment. Coles Myer fell 27 cents to A$6.33 and Woolworths 10 cents to A$4.10 after a good run on Friday.</p>
<p>In other local markets, 10 year T-bonds yields had risen seven basis points to 6.67 percent by 4.45 p.m. (0645 GMT) in a subdued session as players awaited developments in the U.S.</p>
<p>At the same time, the Australian dollar was trading at US$0.7423/28, slightly down from US$0.7430/35 late on Friday.  </p>
<p>-------------------------(TECHNICALS)--------------------------</p>
<p>Short-term range    Support   Restnce   RSI-14  MA-10  MA-20</p>
<p>AORD   2580/2630     2600	2630	38.14   2672   2689</p>
<p>SPI    2600/2650     2590	2640	36.10   2675   2701</p>
<p>-------------------------(KEY ACTIVES)-------------------------</p>
<p>*News Corp A$5.92 (-.03) 5.769/5.93 Vol: 2,960,081 *Fairfax A$3.19 (-.09) 3.104/3.20 Vol: 2,449,278 *Normandy A$1.61 (unch) 1.543/1.61 Vol: 2,971,069 Some stocks hold up well ahead of result reports this week. *Sons of Gwalia A$5.06 (+.16) 4.80/5.06 Vol: 87,446 Gold miner completes restructuring of hedge book.  </p>
<p>*QNI A$2.11 (-.07) 2.08/2.13 Vol: 2,280,258 Nickel producer's profit down due to metal prices, weather. *BHP A$17.108 (-.392) 16.915/17.18 Vol: 2,979,834 *WMC A$7.28 (-.191) 7.21/7.33 Vol: 2,363,659 *Rio Tinto A$20.98 (-.50) 20.81/21.123 Vol: 671,431 Miners fall more than average on weak metal prices. *CommBank A$15.84 (-.754) 15.002/15.90 Vol: 7,994,695 Share goes ex-dividend by 57 cents. *Holyman A$1.75 (+.15) 1.578/1.82 Vol: 2,081,879 Ferry operator firmer due to bargain-hunting, free option. *Lend Lease A$29.40 (+.08) 29.20/29.40 Vol: 378,880 Stock goes against trend on last week's strong result report. *Coles Myer A$6.22 (-.27) 6.20/6.51 Vol: 1,282,412 *Woolworths A$4.10 (-.10) 3.955/4.14 Vol: 1,634,777 Retailers suffer profit-taking after Friday's gains.</p>
<p>-- Martina Barsoum, Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
