<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="807142" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT -Downside still tugs BTPs, 134.32 target.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT -Downside still tugs BTPs, 134.32 target.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>September BTP futures were up in early trade on Monday but technical analysts said the contract would still feel the pressure to decline.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw quite a big move on Friday,&quot; Elizabeth Miller, technical analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell said. &quot;It went through key support at 134.73.&quot;</p>
<p>Miller said support there came from the low of August 6 and could also form the second shoulder of a head and shoulders pattern that would be confirmed by a break of 134.32, the next downside target.</p>
<p>BTPs were quoted at 135.13, up 48 basis points at 0800 GMT.  </p>
<p>On Friday, the contract slid to a 134.36 low which would be interim support.</p>
<p>Analysts at a European bank in London, were also negative, saying the close below 135.00 on Friday was bearish signal number one. But they also noted the head and shoulders neckline held, which they pinpointed at 134.30.</p>
<p>&quot;A decisive close under this will signal real danger,&quot; they said in a research note. &quot;Meanwhile if prices can close back through 135.50, it suggests a false bearish break and a better move to the upside.&quot;  </p>
<p>Miller at DMG did not expect the contract to get above the 135.65 high on Friday.</p>
<p>At the short end, September Eurolire were quoted at 93.21, up two basis points from Friday. The analysts at the European bank said the contract remained vulnerable to another slide, a view reinforced by Friday's dip. They put the next main support at 93.00 but a close back above 93.25 would bring the picture back to neutral.</p>
<p>December Eurolire were up 0.03 at 93.52.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
