<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="807272" id="root" date="1997-08-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - Aug 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - Aug 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Chinese political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Beijing. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (8610) 6532-1921. Fax: (8610) 6532-4978.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PEOPLE'S DAILY</p>
<p>- China delays launch date of Philippine satellite.</p>
<p>- Number of domestic and foreign tourists visiting the Three Gorges increases sharply.</p>
<p>- Construction approved for 1,350 megawatt power station in southwestern Yunnan province.</p>
<p>- Output value of township enterprises in central China's Hunan Province surges 49.5 percent year-on-year in the first half.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FINANCIAL NEWS</p>
<p>- Assets of Everbright Bank of China reach 51.1 billion yuan at end-June</p>
<p>- China allocates 6.915 billion yuan at end-June for resettlement of people living near the Three Gorges dam project.</p>
<p>- Sales of Haier group hit 4.813 billion yuan in the first half, up 68.5 percent year-on-year</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA SECURITIES</p>
<p>- Dong Fureng, vice-chairman of the Finance and Economic Committee of the National People's Congress, says centralisation of stock markets will reduce interference by local authorities and other irregularities.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ECONOMIC DAILY</p>
<p>- China's private sector employed about 25 million people at end-June, up 1.7 million from the end of 1996.</p>
<p>- Fixed asset investment up 10.5 percent year-on-year in the first seven months of this year.</p>
<p>- Editorial says China needs more world-class conglomerates to boost its competitiveness.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PEOPLE'S DAILY OVERSEAS EDITION</p>
<p>- China can export about 600,000 tonnes of zinc this year, and domestic zinc prices seen rising to 115,000 yuan per tonne in 1997.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA WOMEN'S NEWS</p>
<p>- China uncovered 39,015 drug cases between April and June, arresting 55,211 people.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>LIBERATION ARMY DAILY</p>
<p>- Gymnastics champion Li Xiaoshuang will not attend world gymnastics tournament because of foot injury</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>XINHUA DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>- China's rural economy has been booming since the 14th National Congress of the Communist Party of China in 1992.</p>
<p>- State survey says cash income of farmers rose 3.3 percent year-on-year in the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FARMER'S DAILY</p>
<p>- Corn output up by 200,000 tonnes this year from 1996</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MARKET DAILY</p>
<p>- China distillery Qinchi group to form $6.0 million joint venture with Italian firm to produce wine.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA BUSINESS TIMES</p>
<p>- China sees gold output at 122-130 tonnes for 1997.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ECONOMIC INFORMATION DAILY</p>
<p>- Daya Bay nuclear power station generates 6.774 billion kilowatt hours of electricity at end-July.</p>
<p>- China's car prices fall between one percent and 8.1 percent in the first half of this year.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA DAILY</p>
<p>- Transport authorities improving poor maintenance of fast-growing highway network.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
