<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="807909" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: PRESS DIGEST - BOSNIA - AUG 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - BOSNIA - AUG 19.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the highlights of the main stories in the Bosnian press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DNEVNI AVAZ</p>
<p>- The High Representative to Bosnia, Carlos Westendorp, said Serb representatives are blocking an agreement on draft laws for citizenship and a new Bosnian passport.</p>
<p>- If the current deadlock in the peace process does not ease over the next four to five months, Westendorp said he will ask the international communitty to give the High Representative's office a stronger mandate.</p>
<p>- United States envoys have set an August 31 deadline requiring the establishment of proper border crossings between Bosnia's Moslem-Croat federation and neighbouring Croatia. But Bosnian leaders first have to agree on a new flag and coat of arms otherwise there will be no way state symbols to place on border posts.</p>
<p>- The Croat side is blocking the implementation of an agreement on forming joint Bosnian Croat and Moslem police forces in Stolac and Neum, said the deputy interior minister in the Herzegovina-Neretva canton.</p>
<p>- The Moslem-Croat federation minister of education, science and culture, Fahrudin Rizvanbegovic, said he supported a proposal for establishing the first private university in Bosnia.</p>
<p>- The office for return of refugees to Brcko said that 265 Bosnian families have returned to the &quot;zone of separation&quot; near the town and more than 140 families are expected to move back over the next few days.</p>
<p>- A Malaysian building company plans to invest $3 million in a Bosnian metal works in Gracanica.</p>
<p>OSLOBODJENJE</p>
<p>- Federation authorities and Croat representatives have drawn up a plan for the return of all refugees to the central town of Bugojno. --Sarajevo newsroom, +387-71-663-864</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
