<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="807986" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Currency volatility puts Euro veg oils in gridlock.</title>
<headline>Currency volatility puts Euro veg oils in gridlock.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volatile currencies maintained their grip on the European vegetable oil market during Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Normally the Chicago weather market dominates business during the summer months, but this year we have had the added complication of volatile currencies making it very difficult to find where the market is,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Traders said it made little difference which product they were trying to trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Every where in Asia, the U.S. or Europe people are seeing possible deals blown out of the water by sudden changes in exchange rates,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>At the opening soft oil sellers jumped by as much as 2.50 guilders a 100 kilos.</p>
<p>Traders said this may have been caused by shorts.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people felt that Chicago did not come down enough on Monday to stay down, so a few shorts may have panic,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>However, most buyers were put off by the high prices and the soft oil sector failed to trade at.</p>
<p>Currency factors limit activity in the palm and lauric oil sectors.</p>
<p>Coconut oil attracted some light trade during Tuesday afternoon with Aug/Sep fetching $550 and Sep/Oct $555 a tonne cif.</p>
<p>Palmkernel oil traded at $540 for Sep/Oct and $547.50 a tonne cif for Oct/Nov.</p>
<p>At the close of business coconut oil was $5 down to $2.50 up while palmkernel oil sellers were $7.50 lower.</p>
<p>Dutch soy oil closing offers were 1.50 guilders up while rape oil was 1.50 to 0.75 guilders higher.</p>
<p>In the palm oil market crude palm oil cif Europe closed $5 to $7.50 down while products were $2.50 to $5 down.</p>
<p>--Jim Ballantyne, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8062</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
