<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808098" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa hopes to host Sudanese talks &quot;very soon&quot;.</title>
<headline>S.Africa hopes to host Sudanese talks &quot;very soon&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela said on Tuesday he planned to host peace talks between Sudanese President Omar Hassan al-Bashir and the leader of the rebel Sudan People's Liberation Army &quot;very soon&quot;.</p>
<p>Mandela, whose peacemaking efforts range from Africa to Northern Ireland and East Timor, made the remark to reporters after meeting Thai Foreign Minister Prachuab Chaiyasarn in Cape Town.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been in touch with the relevant leaders on this matter and it is likely that I will very soon be hosting both (SPLA leader) John Garang, Bashir and Ugandan President Yoweri Museveni,&quot; Mandela said, without elaborating.</p>
<p>Museveni is a member of the Intergovernmental Authority on Development (IGAD), a group of African countries working on an initiative to end the 14-year civil war in Sudan.</p>
<p>Sudanese Foreign Minister Ali Osman Mohammad Taha said at the weekend that planned peace talks with the SPLA, arranged by IGAD and due to have started on Tuesday in Nairobi, had been postponed.</p>
<p>The war in Sudan, Africa's largest country, has pitted Christian and animist rebels in the south against the Moslem and Arabised north. The rebels want greater autonomy or independence from the north.</p>
<p>Bashir visited South Africa last week for talks with Mandela. The Sudanese leader called for a ceasefire in the war with the SPLA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
