<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808058" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African rand recovered from an initial weaker move, ending off its weakest levels versus the U.S. dollar after shadowing the dollar/mark during the day.</p>
<p>At 1420 GMT the local unit was priced at 4.6940/70 against the greenback from 4.6815/6845 last on Monday after a morning weakest bid of 4.7020.</p>
<p>&quot;The rand was initially pressured by the firmer dollar but managed to fight back as the dollar/mark retreated from resistance at 1.8380,&quot; said a senior trader at a smaller institution.</p>
<p>Exporter flows had also aided the unit, he said, as had rumours of Reserve Bank intervention at the 4.7020/7025 level although this was not confirmed.</p>
<p>Dealers said London players had been in the market mainly as speculators.</p>
<p>The dollar/mark was firmer after the German Bundesbank kept its repo rate at 3.0 percent, a reported slowdown in German M3 numbers but it failed to break 1.84.</p>
<p>Market participants await the outcome of the U.S. Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting, which should hit the screens at around 1815 GMT, although it is generally expected to be a non-event.</p>
<p>On future direction, traders said they would continue their watch on the dollar/mark to anticipate the dollar/rand.</p>
<p>&quot;Rand strength will depend on the dollar/mark. It should trade between 4.65 to 4.72 over the next few days,&quot; one trader venturing an opinion said.</p>
<p>In cross rate action, the rand was last priced at 0.3907/3910 on the German mark from 0.3891/3895 late Monday.</p>
<p>Rand/yen was at 25.1505/1879 from 25.1318/1586 and against sterling it was last trading at 7.5418/5514 from 7.5396/5491.  </p>
<p>On the fixed income market, bonds wilted towards the end as jobbers sold stock ahead of the outcome of the FOMC meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;It's jobbers playing around that made the market come off but nothing serious,&quot; said a trader at a leading bank.</p>
<p>At 1420 GMT the key R150 yielded 14.155 pct from 14.10 pct in late Monday trade.</p>
<p>Bond yields were range-bound during the day as jobbers' attempts to ramp the market higher were countered by institutional buying.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been generally steady. We're basically sitting in there, waiting for fresh news on credit, M3 and inflation,&quot; commented a trader at a foreign bank.</p>
<p>He said technical factors would probably dominate over the next few days in the absence of local news.</p>
<p>The market was seen moving in a 14.07 to 14.22 percent range.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year U.S. Treasury bond was last trading at 6.51 percent yield after settling at a 6.52 percent yield in New York on Monday.</p>
<p>Foreigners bought 399.79 million rands worth of South African bonds on Monday after buying 229.66 million rands worth on Friday, the Bond Exchange said.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange turnover totalled 7.22 billion rand on Monday from 6.24 billion rand on Friday.</p>
<p>On the money market, offered rates for three-month NCDs were steady at between 15.40 to 15.50 percent, while the 90-day BA rate was also unchanged at 14.90 to 14.95 percent.</p>
<p>The South African Reserve Bank said the money market shortage rose to 8.975 billion rand on Monday after easing slightly to 8.555 billion rand on Saturday.</p>
<p>-- Vera von Lieres, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
<p>	 email: johannesburg.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
