<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808082" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Unions urge S.Africa business to revise proposals.</title>
<headline>Unions urge S.Africa business to revise proposals.</headline>
<dateline>DURBAN 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top official in South Africa's trade union federation giant Cosatu said on the second day of regional strikes on Tuesday that business should revise its position on core labour issues to reach settlement.</p>
<p>The Congress of South African Trade Unions, with its 1.9 million members, has called four days of strikes in all regions to break a deadlock over core issues in the Basic Conditions of Employment Bill due before parliament on September 15.</p>
<p>Cosatu wants a 40-hour working week phased in over five years and six months maternity leave, four of which should be paid. Business says there should be a 45-hour working week and four months maternity leave.</p>
<p>Cosatu deputy president Connie September said in the east coast city of Durban that the federation would not compromise on its demands and would not be prepared to negotiate with business unless they presented new proposals.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not open to talk about the same things over and over again. In order for us to reach the (September 15) deadline the employers have to come with a complete revision of their position,&quot; September told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;And in order to reach that deadline the government equally so has to come with a revised position. It is the only thing that will decide if we will reach that deadline or not.&quot;</p>
<p>Business and labour representatives told national radio on Tuesday morning there was no imminent breakthrough in their dispute over minimum terms proposed by Labour Minister Tito Mboweni.</p>
<p>September said recent bilateral talks with President Nelson Mandela's ruling African National Congress, Cosatu's ally, had not achieved anything substantial.</p>
<p>&quot;We did not find any settlement at that level,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Cosatu launched the four-day strike action in the Eastern Cape province on Monday and achieved a 70 percent stayaway.</p>
<p>The business chamber in Durban estimated Cosatu's call had received support from up to 70 percent of the workforce costing business &quot;millions&quot; of rand. No exact figures were available.</p>
<p>Mpumalanga, the other province chosen for strike action on Tuesday, had a patchy response. The Nelspruit chamber of commerce said smaller companies had a full turnout of workers but bigger companies reported stayaways.</p>
<p>--Durban Newsroom, +27-31 306-8646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
