<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808152" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish coalition on verge of collapse before polls.</title>
<headline>Polish coalition on verge of collapse before polls.</headline>
<byline>Marcin Grajewski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's leftist coalition government  appeared on Tuesday to be on the verge of collapse just a month before a general election.</p>
<p>The Peasant Party (PSL), the junior partner in the government, confirmed plans to oust Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz because of his farm policies.</p>
<p>&quot;A no-confidence motion against the prime minister will be submitted in parliament on Tuesday...by 21.00 (1900 GMT),&quot; PSL spokesman Aleksander Bentkowski told a news conference.</p>
<p>Government spokeswoman Aleksandra Jakubowska said the move was likely to lead to the break-up of the coalition.</p>
<p>This would mean that Poland  would be ruled by a minority government of Cimoszewicz's ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) until the September 21 election.</p>
<p>&quot;The state apparatus is efficient enough to function for several weeks even with the government based on one political entity,&quot; Jakubowska told a news conference.</p>
<p>The PSL said Cimoszewicz should go because he had blocked a decision to grant advance payments to farmers for this year's harvest. Other political parties saw the move as an attempt to boost the party's sagging electoral ratings.</p>
<p>Political analysts said the PSL -- which is trailing behind the SLD and the opposition Solidarity Election Action in the opinion polls -- would try to raise its standing with the electorate by criticising the government, if not leaving it.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe the PSL is preparing to take a position in which it would have more room for manoeuvre as far as a new coalition is concerned,&quot; political commentator Andrzej Rychard told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Peasants have signalled they are ready to form a coalition after the polls with Solidarity, the SLD's main rival in the forthcoming election.</p>
<p>Parliament will vote on the no-confidence motion next week.</p>
<p>It has little chance of success because the opposition is against it and the PSL lacks the simple majority to push it through.</p>
<p>But it may prompt the prime minister, who lashed out at the Peasants for tabling the motion, to sack cabinet ministers linked to the PSL .</p>
<p>&quot;The Peasant party should be aware that by submitting a no-confidence motion against the prime minister its ministers may lose jobs,&quot; said presidential spokesman Antoni Styrczula.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz said the Peasants' plan was &quot;irresponsible&quot; because the government should be focusing its attention on rebuilding Poland after July's catastrophic floods, which killed 54 people and caused billions of dollars of damage.</p>
<p>&quot;I can bet that no one in the world is able to understand what is going in Poland. This escapes all rational political categories,&quot; Cimoszewicz told reporters.</p>
<p>The Peasants argue that the prime minister's refusal to grant famers advance payments for grains they would deliver later this year causes tensions in the countryside and will destabilise the food market.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Marek Belka said the advances were too costly for the state budget.</p>
<p>He said on Tuesday that a decision to lower quality requirements for grain purchased from farmers by the Agriculture Market Agency (ARR), the food market regulator, was enough to help the peasants.</p>
<p>Analysts said that leaving the government just before the election would do little to boost support for the Peasants. The party's support now stands at about 10 percent compared with well over 20 percent for SLD and Solidarity.</p>
<p>&quot;This strategy of distancing itself from the government just before the election will not appear credible on the part of a party which has been in power for four years,&quot; Rychard said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
