<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808188" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak FinMin says sees H1 real GDP between 5-6pct.</title>
<headline>Slovak FinMin says sees H1 real GDP between 5-6pct.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak Finance Minister Sergej Kozlik said on Tuesday real gross domestic product (GDP) growth for the first half was in the &quot;upper half&quot; between five to six percent.</p>
<p>Kozlik said he considered the government target for 1997 GDP growth of at least six percent as &quot;achievable.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There have been some positive signals in the economy in recent days so, I think the target is achievable,&quot; Kozlik told Reuters during a regular government meeting.  </p>
<p>&quot;In the first half of the year GDP growth will be in the upper half of between five to six percent,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kozlik said industrial and construction output were still showing an uptrend which supported expectations of &quot;further economic growth&quot;.</p>
<p>Slovakia's GDP rose by a real 5.1 percent in the first quarter of this year, after real, full year 1996 growth of 7.3 percent.</p>
<p>The country's real industrial output rose by 7.7 percent, year-on-year, in June, while construction output showed an annual increase of 2.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Furthermore, there are still some projects that have to be started which can help the economy to grow further, such as EXIM Bank or the revitalisation law,&quot; Kozlik said.</p>
<p>Slovakia, battling long-lasting problems stemming from a growing trade deficit, approved a state-run Export- Import bank earlier this year in an attempt to boost sagging exports. The bank has yet to start its operations.</p>
<p>The trade gap widened to 32.572 billion crowns in the first seven months of the year, from 29.859 billion in the January-May period.</p>
<p>The revitalisation law, which still has to be approved by the parliament, is planned to help overcome financial problems of both state-run and private companies by easing their debt burdens to state and to some commercial banks.</p>
<p>-- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 421-7-521-8402</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
