<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808124" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: FEATURE - Kenya economy staggers after IMF blow.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Kenya economy staggers after IMF blow.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Green</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenyan businessmen are experiencing an unpleasant sense of deja vu. For the second time they have been cold-shouldered by the International Monetary Fund (IMF). This time it hurts even more.</p>
<p>&quot;Any of the good work done in the past three years has basically been dashed,&quot; said businessman Robert Shaw, describing the impact of the IMF's decision to suspend a key aid package to Kenya.</p>
<p>On July 31 the IMF suspended any further drawings on a $205 million three-year loan facility, saying it was dissatisfied with measures taken by the Kenyan government to tackle corruption.</p>
<p>Now termed &quot;Black Friday,&quot; by stock exchange dealers, August 1 was the second nasty surprise the IMF has given businessmen.</p>
<p>The IMF also suspended aid in 1991, spearheading donor pressure to force President Daniel arap Moi to introduce a multi-party system and liberalise the economy.</p>
<p>Notoriously stubborn, the &quot;old man&quot; of Kenyan politics held out for a year before grudgingly holding multi-party elections and introducing economic reforms.</p>
<p>Many businesses say the IMF's second aid cancellation is having a more devastating effect precisely because of the earlier reforms it insisted were introduced.</p>
<p>KENYAN ECONOMY AT MERCY OF MARKETS</p>
<p>&quot;I can't say the Kenyan economy is as robust in the 1990s after liberalisation,&quot; said John Munge, managing director of Shah Munge, a leading Nairobi brokerage house.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1990 we were in-house. The market is not as resilient as it was when it was a closed economy,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>As Kenya has become increasingly plugged into the global economy foreign investors have played a crucial role in feeding Kenya's capital-hungry markets. But businessmen see foreign money as a double-edged sword.</p>
<p>&quot;We are at the mercy of speculators,&quot; said Kassim Owango, chairman of the Kenya Chamber of Commerce and Industry. The Kenya shilling has dropped by nearly 20 percent since the IMF decision, to its lowest rate since 1993, as foreign investors withdraw funds. &quot;There's a feeling we've gone too far, too quickly,&quot; Owango added.</p>
<p>Illustrating the extent of the dependency, the governor of the Central Bank of Kenya, Micah Cheserem, has issued a statement pleading for foreign investors to retain faith in their Kenyan investments.</p>
<p>His appeals have been ignored by offshore investors  offloading record numbers of bonds and selling shares in Kenyan companies at bargain basement prices.</p>
<p>The capital flight has fuelled pressure on the shilling, threatening to hobble Kenya's fledgling manufacturing sector. &quot;Our high level of petroleum imports affects all our sectors,&quot; said Owango.</p>
<p>DONORS SAY REFORMS HURT BUT WORKED</p>
<p>Mocked by a Kenyan newspaper columnist as &quot;Our International Mothers and Fathers,&quot; the IMF has adopted a policy of &quot;Spare the rod and spoil the child&quot; in Kenya.</p>
<p>&quot;Kenya has performed relatively well. The growth rate has gone up. There is good reason to believe things will improve,&quot; said Reimer Carstens, IMF resident representative in Kenya.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of ideas being tossed around. We are all hoping the situation could come back to normal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The World Bank has also increased pressure on Moi. It has re-emphasised its demand that the government tackles graft before it gets the next $71.6 million slice of aid.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a commitment to preserve economic stability -- monetary, fiscal stability -- and contain the deficit that was not there in 1992,&quot; said Harold Wackman, the World Bank's country director in Kenya.</p>
<p>But he cautioned that with elections due before the end of the year budgetary pressures would rise as foreign investment dwindled, and the shilling weakened further.</p>
<p>&quot;If fiscal and monetary discipline were to lapse, it might look a bit like 1992, God forbid,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>OPTIMISM SHINES THROUGH RESIGNATION</p>
<p>The IMF's decision took the business community by surprise. But not everybody is wringing their hands.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we're concerned, there's no instability, as we sell coffee in dollars,&quot; said an official at the Coffee Board of Kenya, reflecting the attitude of many exporters.</p>
<p>There is even suspicion among commercial bank dealers that the Central Bank is happy to see the shilling weaken, because it will boost export earnings and make Kenya more attractive to tourists.</p>
<p>&quot;Kenya can survive without the IMF, although times were hard. For those three years the Kenyan government did survive, investors were coming into the economy,&quot; said a senior currency dealer at the Central Bank of Kenya.</p>
<p>Vidal Shah, managing director of cooking oil manufacturer Bidco, summed up the prevailing mood in the business community.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short-term, its a serious blow. In the long-term, we can handle it.&quot;</p>
<p>But as political violence overshadows the run-up to Kenya's multi-party elections, how quickly foreign money flows back into the country will be decided not by businessmen, but by politicians.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
