<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808354" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazilian businessmen turn reform saga into soap.</title>
<headline>Brazilian businessmen turn reform saga into soap.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian industry bosses, fed up with the slow pace of important reforms in Congress, hope to play on the country's passion for soap operas to get their message across to the people.</p>
<p>A new television advertisement, due to go on air Tuesday, features the plight of Rodolfo whose love for Rafaela is overshadowed by Brazil's precarious fiscal situation.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't marry you, Rafaela!,&quot; Rodolfo declares in a dramatic opening shot. &quot;Why not Rodolfo?&quot; asks Rafaela, shocked. &quot;It's the public sector deficit,&quot; the would-be groom replies before quickly listing Brazil's tax and spending problems.</p>
<p>&quot;We've shown debates and discussions in the past but people have not really understood what's at stake,&quot; said Carlos Batteste for the National Industry Confederation. &quot;We've opted this time for a lighter tone to address a serious subject.&quot;</p>
<p>Brazil's government has been trying for more than two years to approve constitutional reforms of the civil service and the pensions system. The reforms are considered crucial to attempts to cut a fiscal deficit but have run into stiff opposition in Congress.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
