<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808409" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Grounded dredger shuts Lake Maracaibo channel.</title>
<headline>Grounded dredger shuts Lake Maracaibo channel.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela's principal oil export route was shut to tanker traffic Monday night after a dredger went aground in the Lake Maracaibo shipping lane, shipping agents in Maracaibo said Tuesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Nothing is coming in and nothing is going out,&quot; the agent said of the channel which normally exports more than one million barrels of crude oil per day.</p>
<p>The port captain's office confirmed the information, but could not say when the channel would reopen.</p>
<p>&quot;The Maracaibo channel is closed since 2210 last night. The dredger Catatumbo went aground between buoys 24 and 26,&quot; the shipping agent said.</p>
<p>The channel has become a black spot for international shipping since the Greek-flagged Nissos Amorgos went aground there in February, spilling 25,000 barrels of oil. Since then, several other oil tankers have scraped the silty channel floor, but there have been no more spills.</p>
<p>&quot;The Catatumbo went aground in the same spot as the accident,&quot; the shipping agent said.</p>
<p>The channel has become so heavily silted that the port captain has cut the maximum draught from 39 foot six inches to 37 foot three inches, and many major shipping companies are using a 36 foot maximum.</p>
<p>The National Dredging Institute (INC), which operates the Catatumbo and is meant to keep the channel clear, lost its president over the Nissos spill, but shippers say the silting problem has gotten worse.</p>
<p>Only last week, Venezuela's state-owned oil company Petroleos de Venezuela (PDVSA) instructed its own fleet not to load beyond 36 feet draught after one of its ships nearly went aground at 37 foot.</p>
<p>The reduced draught means tankers load about 70,000 barrels less oil in each ship than normal.</p>
<p>((-- Tom Ashby, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2611))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
