<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808479" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian regionals stumble as Indonesian rupiah reels.</title>
<headline>Asian regionals stumble as Indonesian rupiah reels.</headline>
<byline>Phil Smith</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian regional currencies had another traumatic day on Tuesday with the rupiah under severe pressure, serious enough to prompt a massive rise in interest rates by Bank Indonesia.</p>
<p>The rupiah's dive below 3,000 per dollar spurred the central bank into action and dragged other currencies lower.</p>
<p>Also under the gun was the Hong Kong dollar where forwards and short-term interest rates shot up amid a mounting belief that a full scale speculative attack on the currency was in the offing.</p>
<p>The rupiah's problems began when the authorities last week decided to lift the old intervention bands and allow it to float. With the bands in place onshore companies had felt relatively safe but now they find themselves underhedged.</p>
<p>&quot;The locals have come on stream and it's a lot harder to contain locals than it is to contain the offshore players,&quot; said Chiang Yao Chye, Head of Asia Pacific Research at CIBC in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;The locals are hedging and in that sense it's real demand and therefore more difficult to deal with, speculators are just in there for a quick buck and they get out.&quot;</p>
<p>The rupiah regained some lost ground in late business after the rate hikes to 2,890.00 per dollar compared with its day's low of 3,030.00.</p>
<p>&quot;So far all we saw were Jakarta names out there,&quot; a Singapore dealer said. There was no sign of central bank intervention, he said.</p>
<p>It was this kind of seemingly unstoppable pressure which prompted the Indonesian authorities to say enough is enough and rates for central bank certificates (SBIs) were raised sharply.</p>
<p>One-week SIBs rose to 20 percent from 10.5, two-week to 22 percent from 11, one-month to 30 from 11.625 and three-months to 28 from 11.5.</p>
<p>&quot;If the onshore guys are doing it, it is a cause for concern. You are then going against local demand some of this is obviously commercial in nature,&quot; said one analyst, noting that the same thing happened in Thailand when capital controls were first introduced local firms still wanted U.S. dollars so the pressure remained.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, forwards remained firm and short-term rates hit 10 percent plus with the authorities pledging that speculators would be &quot;burned&quot; with high interest rates that would make it too expensive to launch a major attack on the currency.</p>
<p>The spot Hong Kong dollar ended firmer at 7.7385 after edging down to 7.7430. Most in the market do not expect a speculative attack to succeed given Hong Kong's access to substantial reserves and the political embarrassment of a devaluation so soon after the handover to China.</p>
<p>Also the competitive trade advantage that other Asian countries have got through allowing their currencies to fall does not apply to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>It simply does not depend on exports as much as Southeast Asian countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Hong Kong is more like a re-import and export hub for China. And most of its competitiveness is in the service industry. The strength of the Hong Kong dollar is not really a dominant factor,&quot; said a Singapore based U.S. bank dealer.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the Thai baht was still looking weak with the onshore rate down at 32.70 to the dollar compared with Monday's late level of 32.10.</p>
<p>The Thai central bank said on Tuesday it would lift the two-tier system &quot;only at an appropriate time and when conditions in the money market are stable.&quot;</p>
<p>The market still suspects this will be sooner rather than later and has for a long time speculated that when the three month forward contracts put on in mid-May had matured the controls would be lifted.</p>
<p>The Malaysian ringgit had a calmer day and managed to firm late in the session as the rupiah recovered after the rate hike. It was at a late 2.7870 per dollar against 2.7935 on Monday afternoon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
