<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808478" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: British lawyer rips into Singapore prime minister.</title>
<headline>British lawyer rips into Singapore prime minister.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Wong</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top British lawyer accused Singapore Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong on Tuesday of paying lip-service to full democratic principles and using the courts to oust an opposition politician from parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;This litigation is designed to bankrupt this man to keep him out of Parliament,&quot; George Carman told the High Court as he cross examined Goh in a series of defamation cases against Workers' Party (WP) leader Joshua Jeyaretnam.</p>
<p>&quot;One way of making a member of parliament bankrupt...is to use the heavy artillery of multiple actions to obtain massive damages,&quot; he said. &quot;Is that part of your strategy?&quot; he asked Goh. The Prime Minister denied any such intent.</p>
<p>&quot;You and your 10 political colleagues saw this as a method of causing financial oppression on this 71-year-old man because you wanted him out of parliament and thought the court would provide a convenient method,&quot; said Carman.</p>
<p>&quot;No. Mr Jeyaretnam is not a threat to the PAP,&quot; responded Goh in reference to his ruling People's Action Party (PAP), which has run Singapore since it became self-governing in 1959.</p>
<p>In an intense barrage of questions, Carman suggested Goh was paying &quot;lip-service to having the full rights of a democracy&quot;.</p>
<p>Goh, his predecessor, Lee Kuan Yew, and nine other PAP leaders accuse Jeyaretnam of defaming them at a last rally before January 2 elections in which the PAP won 81 of 83 seats.</p>
<p>Jeyaretnam told the rally a fellow WP candidate had filed police reports against the PAP leaders accusing them of lying.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Tang Liang Hong has just placed before me two reports he has made to police against, you know, Mr Goh Chok Tong and his people,&quot; Jeyaretnam told the rally.</p>
<p>Carman said that was &quot;part and parcel of the cut and thrust of politics&quot; which caused no damage to Goh's reputation. Goh's counsel, Tom Shields, another top London libel lawyer, said it amounted to an endorsement of Tang's widely publicised charges.</p>
<p>&quot;It is as if Tang had prepared a Molotov cocktail and gave it to Mr Jeyaretnam and at that precise moment hurled it,&quot; Goh said.</p>
<p>The trial is being monitored by human rights groups like the Geneva-based International Commission of Jurists and Amnesty International, which says it is concerned at reports Singapore has used defamation suits to limit free speech.</p>
<p>The PAP leadership denies using the courts to silence the opposition. It is a question, Goh has said, of challenging allegations that would undermine his ability to govern.</p>
<p>The case against Jeyaretnam is the second this year against a WP member. The first also stemmed from the election campaign in which the PAP turned all its weapons on Tang.</p>
<p>They accused Tang of being &quot;an anti-Christian, Chinese chauvinist&quot; who endangered racial harmony in predominantly ethnic Chinese Singapore, which has substantial minorities of Malays and Indians.</p>
<p>Goh and his colleagues sued Tang over a variety of comments, including the lying charge. Tang fled Singapore saying his life had been threatened and did not return to defend himself.</p>
<p>The cases were awarded to the PAP leaders. They won a record S$8.08 million (US$5.65 million) in damages and then sued Jeyaretnam, accusing him of endorsing Tang's charge of lying.</p>
<p>Carman said Jeyaretnam had not endorsed Tang's statements and he questioned why the PAP had sued his client.</p>
<p>Was it because Jeyaretnam, a lawyer, had acted for Tang? Was it in any way connected to this? Carman asked.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are suggesting that we took action because he appeared for Mr Tang, that is completely wrong,&quot; Goh said.</p>
<p>But Carman said Goh had filed an affadavit arguing Jeyaretnam's alleged defamation was motivated by malice because &quot;of his conduct when he acted as counsel for Mr Tang&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I really have to say you have not been truthful with the courtroom in the last five minutes,&quot; Carman told Goh, who denied the charge but conceded there was &quot;a connection&quot; between the suits and Jeyaretnam's defence of Tang.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
