<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808430" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Reinsurance sees 97 year net not lower.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Reinsurance sees 97 year net not lower.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reinsurance Australia Corp Ltd said on Wednesday it expected that profit for the full calendar 1997 year should not be lower than the 1996 result, given stable claims and no major correction in investment markets.  </p>
<p>Earlier, Reinsurance reported a half year net profit of A$35.11 million, up from A$30.23 million a year earlier. It posted a steady five cent per share interim dividend.</p>
<p>Reinsurance's net profit in 1996 was A$66.59 million.</p>
<p>Reinsurance said investment income rose 87 percent to A$$34.4 million in the 1997 first half.</p>
<p>It said it wanted to maintain the quality of its insurance portfolio and to write only business where the risk/reward ratio was appropriate.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our aim has been to maintain the quality of the portfolio and to protect our ability to write business when rates inevitably rise,&quot; Reinsurance Managing Director Michael Kelly said in a statement.</p>
<p>He said the group had repositioned its portfolio by further developing specifically targeted lines of proportional business. &quot;This allows diversification, both by geography and class, avoids the acute pricing pressures in certain sectors of the excess of loss markets and reduces volatility in the underwriting result,&quot; Reinsurance said.  </p>
<p>It said in the first half it had declined to renew a little over A$70 million of business inappropriately priced in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Our current year gross written premium has declined by 10 percent from A$350 million to A$314 million, in large part due to a reassessment of prior period premium estimates of proportional business,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Only modest growth was achieved in volume in the first half because of the strength of the Australian dollar in the first quarter and extreme competition in the industry, it said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Given claims stability comparable to last year's and no major correction in investment markets, it is anticipated that full year profit after tax should not be less than the 1996 result.&quot;</p>
<p>Reinsurance's shares closed up eight cents at A$4.19 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
