<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808566" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta stocks end sharply down on tight liquidity.</title>
<headline>Jakarta stocks end sharply down on tight liquidity.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta stocks close sharply lower after a volatile day on Tuesday on concerns over tight liquidity after the central bank raised interest rates, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta composite index closed down 1.52 percent, or 9.11 points, at 590.53 points after falling at the open, then rising to a high of 612.21 points and plunging to an intra-day low of 585.58 points after news of the central bank move.</p>
<p>In the broader market, losers led gainers by 98 to 39, with 52 counters unchanged. Total volume was estimated at 920 billion rupiah.  </p>
<p>&quot;The central bank's move had sparked selling, particularly in banking stocks, on perceptions that their earnings could be affected,&quot; a broker with a European securities firm said.</p>
<p>Although the rupiah had strengthened in late trade on foreign buying, the sharp fall in stocks was due to fluctuations in the currency market and concerns over the moves to tighten liquidity, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The rise in the interest rates has helped the currency but it hasn't done much for the stock market,&quot; said Tom Inglis, head of research for ING Barings in Jakarta. &quot;Uncertainties in the currency and the interest rates will keep equities nervous.&quot;  </p>
<p>However, brokers said, some investors had used the opportunity to accumulate stocks because many of them had reached favourable prices.</p>
<p>Brokers predicted market sentiment would remain volatile on Wednesday on extended fluctuations in the currency market coupled with concern over tight liquidity. But, at the same time, more bargain-hunters were likely to come in, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential downside of the composite index is still there but not by too much. Our market is already undervalued, I don't believe it will go down further,&quot; a broker with a Malaysia-based brokerage said. &quot;This is the right time to buy.&quot;  </p>
<p>Banking stocks including Bank International Indonesia, Bank Negara Indonesia, Lippo Bank and Bank Danamon ended lower.</p>
<p>Market heavyweight Telkom and toll road operator Citra Marga were also down due to extended fluctuation in the rupiah, brokers said.</p>
<p>Telkom was last traded at 3,500 rupiah, or down 125 rupiah, on a volume of 20.2 million shares, while Citra Marga fell 25 rupiah to close at 1,075 rupiah on a volume of 26.4 million shares.  </p>
<p>But cement counter Semen Gresik was favoured by buyers on perceptions that its price was cheap, brokers said.</p>
<p>It closed 175 rupiah higher at 3,200 rupiah on turnover of 6.1 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Helen Lumban Gaol +6221 384-6264 Fax (6221) 344-8404</p>
<p>-- E-mail jakarta.newsroom@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
