<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808590" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel holds fire after rockets hit north.</title>
<headline>Israel holds fire after rockets hit north.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Heller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel refrained from swift retaliation and said it wanted to avoid &quot;unnecessary confrontations&quot; after Katyusha rockets fired from Lebanon slammed into Galilee.</p>
<p>The pro-Iranian Hizbollah guerrilla group launched scores of Katyushas at northern Israel on Tuesday, wounding one person, as part of a round of violence that began on Monday.</p>
<p>But the guns then fell silent and there was no Israeli military response on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu visited a rocket-damaged home in the town of Kiryat Shmona. Echoing warnings Israel has made for years, he said there would be no quiet on Lebanon's side of the border if there was none in northern Israel.</p>
<p>Later, Netanyahu held consultations with his ministers of defence, foreign affairs, national infrastructure and treasury at Israeli military headquarters in the north and issued a statement that put conciliatory words before fighting ones.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the meeting, the prime minister and ministers said that Israel's desire is to stabilise and calm the situation and avoid unnecessary confrontations,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, in parallel they emphasised that Israel would not tolerate a situation in which there will be quiet on only one side of the border,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>An international monitoring group made up of Lebanese, Israeli, Syrian, U.S. and French officials will meet on Wednesday in Naqura, Lebanon, near the Israeli border to discuss the current situation, the Israeli army said.</p>
<p>The committee, established after a 17-day Israeli offensive in south Lebanon killed 200 people -- mostly civilians -- in April 1996, was to have convened on Thursday. The army said Israel pressed for the meeting to be held earlier.</p>
<p>Hizbollah Chief Sheikh Hassan Nasrallah said in Beirut the Katyusha rocketing of northern Israel was aimed at restoring the terms of the U.S.-brokered ceasefire that ended the Israeli operation last year and barred targeting of civilians.</p>
<p>Nasrallah dismissed as laughable Israel's explanation that the Jewish state was not responsible for Monday's shelling of the Lebanese port city of Sidon by militiamen of the pro-Israeli Christian commander Antoine Lahd.</p>
<p>Seven civilians were killed in the Sidon shelling.</p>
<p>Israel, which occupies a border strip in south Lebanon, said Lahd forces responsible for attacking Sidon were based in the Jezzine area outside the zone and were not under its control.</p>
<p>Israeli officials said Lahd's men were apparently avenging the killing of three youths by a roadside bomb in the area. The Israeli army accused Hizbollah of carrying out that attack.</p>
<p>Israeli President Ezer Weizman travelled with his wife to spend Tuesday night in a northern hotel in solidarity with Galilee residents.</p>
<p>&quot;Attacks against civilians should be prevented as much as possible,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;The correct policy is to stop the situation from deteriorating.&quot;</p>
<p>In a move likely to anger Israel, Palestinian President Yasser Arafat will hold &quot;national unity&quot; talks on Wednesday in Gaza with Moslem militant groups, Palestine Liberation Organisation (PLO) officials said.</p>
<p>Israel has demanded he crack down on &quot;terrorism&quot; instead in the wake of a double suicide bombing in Jerusalem that killed 16 people on July 30.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials said the talks would be a response to Netanyahu's decision to seal off the West Bank and Gaza Strip after the Jerusalem market attack.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
