<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808677" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Minn. opens session on flood repair funding plans.</title>
<headline>Minn. opens session on flood repair funding plans.</headline>
<dateline>ST. PAUL 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Minnesota lawmakers opened a special session Tuesday to finance flood repairs, consider a pay hike for all levels of state employees and a proposal to raise the minimum wage.</p>
<p>Two Republican state representatives also introduced a bill Tuesday calling for an advisory referendum in November on public financing of a ballpark for the Minnesota Twins.</p>
<p>Representatives were scheduled to take up the flood repair funding plans as senators opened discussion of the minimum wage and pay hike proposals, said Tom Smalec, spokesman for the House Democratic leadership.</p>
<p>A task force appointed by Gov. Arne Carlson has recommended $123.98 million of state aid to repair damage from the widespread flooding in Minnesota last spring, including $55.25 million of bonds for various infrastructure repairs and the purchase of flood-damaged homes.</p>
<p>Flood repair issues are expected to take one day, but discussion on minimum wage and state employee salary hikes could take another two days to complete, Smalec said.</p>
<p>Rep. Kevin Knight of Bloomington and Rep. Philip Krinkie of Shoreview proposed a referendum asking voters to what extent they believe professional sports facilities should be subsidized by the public.</p>
<p>&quot;This proposal of building a stadium has died a rather ignominious death on numerous occasions in both the House and Senate here,&quot; Knight said. &quot;The legislative leadership and the governor have refused to let it die, so we are saying let the people weigh in and say what they have to say.&quot;</p>
<p>The referendum would ask whether people believe in no subsidy, $150 million of state funding, $200 million or $300 million, Knight said.</p>
<p>Six other Republican state representatives supported the referendum Tuesday with Minneapolis mayoral candidate Barbara Carlson.</p>
<p>The projected $400 million Twins ballpark would be located on Minneapolis riverfront land under a plan advanced by Mayor Sharon Sayles Belton.</p>
<p>Gov. Arne Carlson plans to call a special session in September to consider financing plans for a new ballpark and a task force appointed by him has been debating public financing plans for the Twins, Minnesota Vikings and a new National Hockey League expansion team.</p>
<p>Vikings officials want improvements to the Metrodome or a new multipurpose stadium for football and baseball, while the governor has pledged $65 million of bonds toward a downtown St. Paul hockey arena.</p>
<p>((--David Bailey, Chicago Newsroom, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. PAUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
