<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808729" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gasoline prices jump, grains and coffee rise.</title>
<headline>Gasoline prices jump, grains and coffee rise.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gasoline prices rose on Tuesday as traders speculated that weekly oil industry reports would show an eighth consecutive drawdown in U.S. gasoline stocks.</p>
<p>In other markets, corn and soybean prices rose on concerns that cool weather would slow crop development in the Midwest. Coffee prices rose sharply on news of a truckers' strike in Colombia that was blocking coffee exports.</p>
<p>At the New York Mercantile Exchange, oil prices followed gasoline higher.</p>
<p>September gasoline ended 2.14 cents a gallon higher at 67.58 cents, with September crude oil closing up 21 cents a barrel at $20.12 and September heating oil up 0.62 cent a gallon at 55.71.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is clearly in a bullish mode. Technically and fundamentally gasoline is strong and it's no secret that the APIs were considered today as they were every Tuesday before the data comes out,&quot; said Sal Gugliara of United Energy.</p>
<p>The American Petroleum Institute (API) was expected by traders to report a drop in gasoline stocks of up to three million barrels due to high demand from summer vacation driving. That was confirmed after the close when the API said gasoline stocks fell 3.27 million barrels to 187.89 million.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade, corn and soybean prices ended mostly higher on concerns that last week's rains came too late to help some Midwest corn and continuing cool temperatures will hurt soybean yields as plants mature.</p>
<p>Soybeans for November delivery closed up 11-1/2 cents a bushel at $6.19-1/2 and corn for December delivery rose 3-3/4 cents to close at $2.67-1/4.</p>
<p>Weekly state crop progress reports issued on Monday afternoon indicated the amount of U.S. corn rated good to excellent had risen to 60 percent, up only two points from a week earlier.</p>
<p>Some traders had expected last week's Midwest rains to boost the ratings by as much as five percentage points.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people are going to be disappointed with the quality of the corn,&quot; said Jack Scoville, analyst with The Price Group.</p>
<p>&quot;As we get closer to harvest, people are going to be more disappointed in the corn than in the beans. I think there's real bullish potential there,&quot; Scoville said.</p>
<p>Forecasts for cool weather next week and into September added to the crop concerns. The National Weather Service on Monday forecast below normal temperatures in the U.S. Midwest for the period from August 24 to 28, while the agency's 30-day outlook predicted cool temperatures in September.</p>
<p>The U.S. soybean crop was rated 57 percent good to excellent in Monday's reports, up two points from a week earlier.</p>
<p>Crop scouts on an annual tour of the Midwest crop this week said Indiana crops appeared in average condition.</p>
<p>&quot;The beans are shorter than I expected and the plant population isn't quite as high , but beans can put on a lot of pods on short stems,&quot; said Rick Rottinghaus, a corn and soybean farmer from Waterloo, Iowa, who was on the tour.</p>
<p>Wheat prices drew strength from other grain pits as well as from export demand. Pakistan announced a tender for 200,000 tons of wheat, with U.S. exporters expected to earn a good share of the sale due to tight wheat supplies in Australia.</p>
<p>December wheat ended 3 cents a bushel higher at $3.75-3/4.</p>
<p>At the Coffee Sugar and Cocoa Exchange in New York, coffee prices closed sharply higher after a trucking union official in Colombia said a truckers' strike was slowing the country's coffee exports. Colombia is the world's number two coffee exporter.</p>
<p>Coffee for September delivery rose 6.90 cents a pound to close at 187.10 cents.</p>
<p>Javier Suarez, head of the Colombian Truck Drivers Association ACC, said on Tuesday that the strike by truck drivers in Colombia's main Pacific coast port of Buenaventura had blocked the export of about 21,000 bags of coffee.</p>
<p>&quot;There is the idea that the strike might spread and cut off the shipment of coffee,&quot; said Refco Inc. analyst Ann Prendergast.</p>
<p>AT the Chicago Mercantile Exchange, hog prices closed with pared gains as traders became suspicious of an early rally linked to talk that Russia was buying at least six million pounds of U.S. pork carcasses and trimmings.</p>
<p>&quot;The Russian rumor is less than one day's supply, as far as numbers are concerned. They buy from us all the time and they are one of our better customers,&quot; said Dave Maher with Securities Corporation of Iowa.</p>
<p>December lean hog futures closed at 67.275 cents a pound, up 0.725 cent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
