<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808757" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton's panel skeptical about Gulf War illnesses.</title>
<headline>Clinton's panel skeptical about Gulf War illnesses.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A spokesman for a presidential committee looking into the illnesses of Gulf War veterans said on Tuesday there was no proof yet that thousands of U.S. troops had been sickened by Iraqi chemical agents.</p>
<p>The Pentagon also said in response to a published report that no single cause of the complaints had been found despite indications that 98,000 troops might have suffered exposure in the 1991 destruction of an Iraqi chemical arms dump.</p>
<p>The New York Times said on Tuesday that five members of the 11-member Presidential Advisory Committee on Gulf War Veterans' Illnesses might support a change in the group's earlier conclusiuon that chemical agents were &quot;unlikely&quot; to be a cause of the ills.</p>
<p>&quot;Anything is possible,&quot; Gary Caruso, deputy director of the committee, told Reuters when asked about a new report to be issued by the committee in October.</p>
<p>But he stressed that &quot;existing scientific and medical research out there indicates that (the symptoms) don't correlate to low levels of exposure&quot; to agents such as sarin nerve gas at the Kamisiyah ammunition depot.</p>
<p>The committee said in an interim report to President Bill Clinton in January that wartime stress was a likely cause of complaints by more than 60,000 veterans that range from headaches to loss of memory.</p>
<p>Caruso predicted that the panel was unlikely to make any sweeping change in that conclusion unless scientific research showed that many of the ills were actually caused by low-level chemical exposure.</p>
<p>A recent report by the Pentagon and the CIA indicated that a blast cloud from the destruction of the arms dump at Kamisiyah might have drifted over some 98,000 U.S. troops.</p>
<p>Caruso cautioned, however, that the report on the explosion &quot;plume&quot; by itself did not prove that those troops suffered ill effects from any chemical agents and any such conclusion would have to be borne out by scientific evidence.</p>
<p>The committee is due to make another report to the White House in October after a final hearing on Sept. 4 and 5 in the Washington suburb of Alexandria, Virginia.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure you are aware that we are very much interested in the final supplemental report which is being assembled&quot; by the committee, Navy Capt. Mike Doubleday, a Pentagon spokesman, told reporters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But he said the report had not yet been written and declined to comment on any possible conclusions in it.</p>
<p>&quot;We have research going on right now into the effects of low-level chemical exposure. We have proposals out for other research to be conducted on the effects of various other possible sources of these illnesses,&quot; Doubleday told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;But the bottom line to all of this is that at this point in time, we know of no single cause for the illnesses that some of the Gulf War veterans have. We don't have any final answer, any single answer as to what might be causing Gulf War illnesses.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
