<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808878" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT-Dlr/mark end above 1.84 may reassure bulls.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT-Dlr/mark end above 1.84 may reassure bulls.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A handle on 1.84 marks by Tuesday's close could reestablish the dollar's long term bullish trend recovery and signal another visit to last week's highs above 1.87, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>But it must overcome key resistance first. A retake of last week's 1.8476 and 1.8465 mark highs is needed to refuel the rally, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Anything under 1.8450/1.85 keeps some pressure on the market although it's had a pretty good reversal from Friday's lows,&quot; said Greg Troccoli, technical analyst at Prudential Securities.  </p>
<p>&quot;It still has a little work to do to get back on its feet,&quot; Troccoli added.</p>
<p>Thursday's and Friday's highs are close to a 50 percent retracement of the dollar/mark downmove from 1.8913 on August 6 to the low of 1.8050 on Monday.</p>
<p>A close above 1.8450 would provide a starting point for followthrough dollar/mark gains, said Troccoli, who added that long-term trend damage has been minimal.  </p>
<p>Elsewhere, dollar/yen was set to make a one yen move in the near-term, with momentum studies favoring a sharp move higher, according to Ture Johnson, technical analyst at Bank of America. Johnson and other analysts have pegged rates well above 120 yen longer term.</p>
<p>&quot;We're back in the previous trading range before dollar/yen broke down, which was basically 118 to 119.50,&quot; Johnson said. &quot;Now we're above 118 so we're back in the previous consolidation area.&quot;</p>
<p>A mark/yen rally could fuel the dollar/yen rise, Johnson said, despite the cross's apparent weakness on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>That optimism has a narrow window, however. Johnson said a failure to find 119 yen by Wednesday would prompt a more severe selloff as deep as 116.50 or 116.30, the bottom of the current trading range.</p>
<p>Thom Worden, vice president of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell's technical analysis group, said a move back to the high of last Friday, 118.70 yen, could signal a rapid rise to 119.50. But Worden was not so sanguine on the liklihood that that might happen by Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;On the downside, if we go through the lows made in early New York near 118.05 that would mean a move to at least the 117.20/30 area,&quot; Worden said. &quot;That's the way I'm leaning.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Al Yoon, 212-859-1672))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
