<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="808967" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr/mark extends gains at U.S. noon as Dow climbs.</title>
<headline>Dlr/mark extends gains at U.S. noon as Dow climbs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar pushed past 1.84 marks at midday, bolstered by a rally in U.S. stocks and the widespread belief that G3 interest rates will remain unchanged in the near term, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the stock market and the combination of a steady (Federal Reserve) and a steady repo rate in Germany that has encouraged more buying of dollars against the mark,&quot; said Mike Malpede, senior foreign exchange analyst at Refco Group LTd.</p>
<p>The greenback had stalled out at 1.84 marks overnight, but scrambled through in late U.S. morning as European day traders squared up for the night, dealers said.  </p>
<p>The Bundesbank overnight again fixed its repo rate at 3.0 percent, as expected, and reported M3 money supply growth fell to 5.7 percent annualized in July from 6.4 percent in June, well within its target range of 3.5 percent to 6.5 percent.</p>
<p>Market players overwhelmingly expected the Federal Open Market Committee, meeting Tuesday, to keep rates steady. Forex pros continue to hail the strong, low-inflation U.S. economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Major corporate profits should stay around eight or nine percent after inflation, which is is negligible. That means the stock market and the dollar should stay strong,&quot; said Jesse Torres, chief dealer at Bank Austria.  </p>
<p>The dollar stood higher at noon at 1.8405/15 marks, up from 1.8347/52 at the open, but slightly lower at 118.25/35 yen from 118.29/34.</p>
<p>Dealers cited mark/yen's morning pullback as a dollar/yen impediment, with stops near 64.60 the failed objective of short-term players.</p>
<p>&quot;They couldn't get it up to (64.60), so we saw a good selloff in mark/yen,&quot; said Greg Perman, chief dealer at Credit Commerciale de France. &quot;There were plenty of bids in dollar/mark to soak up that interest.  </p>
<p>Yet dollar bulls remained cautious after the greenback's recent slides. Dollar/yen investors continue to watch for a Japanese official response near 120 and dollar/mark seems vulnerable to more corrective selling toward 1.80, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still possible we could see dollar/mark at 1.80 or 1.79, but in the long run, it's going to remain strong,&quot; said Torres.</p>
<p>Barring any major stock market volatility, the market will look to Wednesday's report of June U.S. international trade data and the regular Bundesbank council meeting on Thursday.  </p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar rose to 1.5155/65 Swiss francs from 1.5115/20 at the open. Sterling fell to $1.6030/40 from $1.6060/70, even as sterling/mark rallied sharply from its session lows.</p>
<p>The greenback rose to Canadian $1.3947/52 from C$1.3895/00.</p>
<p>((--Chris Stetkiewicz, 212-859-1664))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
