<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80933" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products mostly weaker, but demand holds.</title>
<headline>Med oil products mostly weaker, but demand holds.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were mostly weaker on Friday, but gas oil and fuel oil could both resume their uptrends, traders said. Gasoline prices eased as a combination of weaker crude, ample low octane supplies and slack buying interest particularly from eastern Europe left trade thin.</p>
<p>Despite weaker crude markets, naphtha stayed firm with few cargoes on offer and petrochemical demand remaining healthy, given the high price of alternative feedstocks.</p>
<p>Values for paraffinic grades were pegged around benchmark quotes cif high +$4.50 after trade into Lavera during the week.  </p>
<p>Gas oil dropped around $4.00 with futures, but demand was still very strong, especially in the eastern Med.</p>
<p>Greece's state-run Public Petroleum Corp (PPC) bought about 940,000 tonnes of 0.2 percent sulphur heating oil in its tender for delivery from October to March, traders said.</p>
<p>The tender was won by Glencore, Neoinvest, Statoil and Transax at between cif high and cif high +$1.00.</p>
<p>But award winners said actual volumes would depend on the severity of the winter and may not reach the full 940,000 tonnes. &quot;The volume is something of a moveable feast,&quot; said one.  </p>
<p>Also on Friday, Turkey bought 75,000 tonnes of 0.5 percent sulphur gas oil for delivery by October 15. The tender for delivery to Izmit was awarded to Onyx, Agip and Baycor at fob high +$9.00-10.00, traders said.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked fuel oil lost some of its recent gains, but dealers said the shortage continued. An ISAB cargo traded at high fob Med +$1.50, down from $2.40 premium on Thursday. A good quality cargo was also sold at high fob Med +$6.50 and on Thursday a low visc sold at high fob Med +$4 fob Santa Panagia.</p>
<p>Low sulphur cracked gained support from recent buying for or by the main Med consumer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
