<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="809520" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: If no quiet in Israel, none in Lebanon - Netanyahu.</title>
<headline>If no quiet in Israel, none in Lebanon - Netanyahu.</headline>
<dateline>KIRYAT SHMONA, Israel 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu warned guerrillas in Lebanon firing Katyusha rockets at Israel on Tuesday that if there was no quiet in Israel, there would be none in Lebanon.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying obviously to end the violence. And we've been doing that for the last two weeks but it must be understood that this simple formula applies: If there is no quiet on the Israeli side of the border there will not be quiet on the Lebanon side,&quot; he told reporters in northern Israel.  </p>
<p>Netanyahu spoke in a rocket-damaged house during a tour of the border town of Kiryat Shmona which was hit along with other parts of northern Israel in an attack early on Tuesday by pro-Iranian Hizbollah fighters.</p>
<p>The twin morning barrages, about an hour apart, deepened fears for the future of an agreement last year by Hizbollah and Israel not to target civilians.</p>
<p>Netanyahu appealed to Syria, the main power broker in Lebanon, to curb Hizbollah attacks, saying: &quot;Syria is able to stop this shooting. It must understand that it is also its interest. We are in contact with the United States which has already turned to Syria on this issue&quot;.</p>
<p>The Katyusha attacks followed a day of violence on Monday that killed at least 10 civilians in Lebanon, seven of them in shelling of the southern port city of Sidon by forces of pro-Israeli militia chief Antoine Lahd from their stronghold of Jezzine.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIRYAT SHMONA, Israel"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
