<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80963" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK rail consortium sets first stand-alone PFI bond.</title>
<headline>UK rail consortium sets first stand-alone PFI bond.</headline>
<byline>Aline van Duyn</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bond launched on Friday to finance a cross-Thames railway link was the first under the British government's so-called private finance initiative (PFI) not to carry a third party guarantee.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first unenhanced PFI bond, whose structure is strong enough for the bond to stand on its own merits,&quot; said an official at BZW, lead manager of the 165 million stg issue.</p>
<p>Under PFI, the government aims to shift the capital cost and risk of major new public investments into public hands and then buy back use of the services on a lease-type basis.  </p>
<p>City Greenwich Lewisham Rail Link Plc (CGLR), which issued the bond, was today awarded the contract to build an extension to the Docklands Light Railway into south-eastern London.</p>
<p>CGLR will receive payment from Docklands Light Railway for designing, building and maintaining the line for 25 years.</p>
<p>The deal is only the second capital market transaction under PFI. Road Management Consolidated (RMC) set the first in March -- a 165 million stg 25-year bond at 80 basis points over gilts.</p>
<p>RMC paid U.S. insurer AMBAC to unconditionally guarantee principal and coupon payments. The paper was rated triple-A by Moody's and Standard &amp; Poor's.  </p>
<p>The CGLR deal matures in 2020 but the paper has an average life of 16.2 years. Launched at a 130 b.p. spread over the 2017 gilt, the issue was trading at 125 b.p. over.</p>
<p>The bonds have preliminary single-A rating from Duff and Phelps.</p>
<p>The buyers were mainly British institutions, BZW said.</p>
<p>The funds will go towards the 200 million stg project. A government spokeswoman said 200 million stg was the final price and could not altered if costs over-ran.</p>
<p>CGLR's main contractors are Mitsui UK and John Mowlem, with backing also provided by London Electricity and Hyder, the Welsh water and electricity utility, BZW said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
