<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="809757" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. states draft plan to share tobacco settlement.</title>
<headline>U.S. states draft plan to share tobacco settlement.</headline>
<dateline>INDIANAPOLIS 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Representatives of 15 states and Puerto Rico said on Monday they had drafted a recommendation on how to divide the proposed $368 billion tobacco settlement.</p>
<p>While no details of the recommendations were provided, officials said under the proposal some of the funds would be allocated to anti-smoking programs and medical costs of treating smoking-related illnesses.</p>
<p>The recommendations will be presented this week to a committee of the five states attorneys general who have been the lead negotiators with the tobacco companies.</p>
<p>Indiana Attorney General Jeffrey Modisett said he hoped the recommendations would be released by next week, before Congress reconvenes.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to get them out to the states to let them know how much money each state will get under the proposal,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Modisett did not say how the money would be allocated to each state, describing the proposal for distributing the money as a &quot;blended formula.&quot; He said it would be based on such factors as population in each state, the percentage of smokers and the amount of smoking-related Medicaid costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We know Congress is in the process of looking over the proposed legislation. One of the big issues is going to be how much money is going to go to the states,&quot; Modisett told reporters at Indiana University-Purdue University at Indianapolis, where the meeting was held.</p>
<p>To settle lawsuits brought by 40 states, tobacco companies agreed in June to pay $368 billion over 25 years and curb advertising. In return, they would get protection from future lawsuits and restrictions on how heavily the U.S. Food and Drug Administration can regulate nicotine.</p>
<p>President Clinton is still reviewing the proposed deal.</p>
<p>Modisett said Congress could make major changes to the deal, but he said members of Congress he has talked to want the states to decide how the money should be divided.</p>
<p>Although it was not part of the settlement, Puerto Rico's attorney general, Jose Fuentes, attended Monday's meeting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PURI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INDIANAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
