<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="809751" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Son tells divorce court that Anthony Quinn beat wife.</title>
<headline>Son tells divorce court that Anthony Quinn beat wife.</headline>
<byline>Jeanne King</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-08-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The son of screen legend Anthony Quinn testified on Monday that when his mother brought up Quinn's extramarital affairs, the actor would hit her until she had dark bruises on her arms.</p>
<p>The son, Danny Quinn, 33, also an actor, was the first witness in what threatens to be a nasty divorce proceeding between his parents.</p>
<p>Describing the alleged beatings, he said the trouble usually started at the dinner table.</p>
<p>&quot;My mother would say something about his extramarital affairs that would irritate my father. He'd say, 'Be quiet. Shut up,' and he'd use very inappropriate, obscene language towards her,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Then he'd throw something -- dishes, breakable glass -- at her, and sometimes he would hit her on the arm.</p>
<p>&quot;They would then go to another room, and I'd hear screaming. When she returned, she'd be shaking and rubbing her arms where he had punched her. Most of the times, it was her arms but sometimes her legs. She'd come back to the room with dark bruises on her arm.&quot;</p>
<p>The 82-year-old, two-time Academy Award winner and his second wife, Italian-born Iolanda Quinn, 62, are battling it out in a Manhattan divorce courtroom over Quinn's assets, reportedly worth at least $20 million.</p>
<p>His wife of three decades says she wants an equitable settlement and is seeking more than half her husband's homes, valuable art collection, antiques and investments.</p>
<p>Quinn holds a 1965 prenuptual agreement that limits his wife to one-half of about 25 percent of his community property. She wants about 90 percent, Quinn's lawyer said in an opening statement.</p>
<p>&quot;She didn't have a lawyer, didn't speak English, and she was pregnant&quot; when she signed that agreement, her lawyer, Raoul Felder, said in his statement to Manhattan Supreme Court Justice Sherry Klein-Heitler, who will decide the case. Felder said the actor had 13 legitimate and illegitimate children.</p>
<p>The son said the &quot;beatings and punching happened so many times that I told my mother maybe she'd be better off being quiet so she wouldn't get hit.&quot; He said she did not call the police during the alleged beatings &quot;because my father would have killed her.&quot;</p>
<p>He also said Quinn had abused him as a child by &quot;putting me down verbally and subjecting me to corporal punishment.&quot; &quot; &quot;To me, the real issue is domestic violence and child abuse,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Quinn, who won Oscars for the 1952 movie &quot;Viva Zapata&quot; and the 1956 &quot;Lust for Life,&quot; never looked at his son as he testified, staring instead at the ceiling.</p>
<p>The silver-haired actor left his wife for his 35-year-old former secretary and long-time lover, Kathy Benvin, several years ago. They have two children, Antonia, now 4, and Ryan, 1.</p>
<p>Outside the courthouse, Quinn said he was &quot;terribly, terribly sorry to hear a son testify against a father.&quot;</p>
<p>But he also said: &quot;I'm glad I'm seeing it now while I'm still alive. Bing Crosby couldn't. Bette Davis couldn't. Joan Crawford couldn't. I'm glad I can defend myself.&quot;</p>
<p>The trial continues on Tuesday, with Quinn's oldest son, Francesco, set to testify about physical confrontations with his father.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
