<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="809755" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE-10 years of Shear Madness celebrated in Washington.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-10 years of Shear Madness celebrated in Washington.</headline>
<byline>Yukari Iwatani</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Concert pianist Isabel Czerny has died every night for the past ten years in the comedy whodunit &quot;Shear Madness&quot; but the play itself shows no sign of aging.</p>
<p>The premise of the show is so simple there is no script. A beautician discovers Czerny murdered in an apartment above the unisex hair salon &quot;Shear Madness&quot; in Washington's posh Georgetown neighborhood. The suspects are Tony Whitcomb, the over-the-top gay proprietor of the salon, Barbara De Marco, his gum-cracking employee, Eddie Lawrence, a sleazy con-artist, and Mrs. Schubert, a patron and Washington socialite. The audience decides who is guilty.</p>
<p>The play, which builds laughs around each of the stereotypical personalities, is celebrating its 10th anniversary at the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts with a running total of more than 4,000 performances.</p>
<p>The Washington production of &quot;Shear Madness&quot; became the third longest running nonmusical play in American theater history last October, behind Boston and Chicago productions of the same play, which occupy the first and second slots.</p>
<p>Adapted from &quot;Scherenshnitt,&quot; a serious murder mystery by German playwright Paul Portner, &quot;Shear Madness&quot; had a slow start in Boston in 1980 when co-producers Bruce Jordan and Marilyn Abrams first opened it. After getting an enthusiastic response during a preliminary run in Lake George, New York, however, and having just paid $50,000 to acquire the play's global rights, the actors turned producers held firm even when marketing advisers wanted to close the show.</p>
<p>TOO MAGICAL TO QUIT</p>
<p>&quot;It was so succesful, so magical, and the audience was so overwhelmed by it (in Lake George) we decided we had to go on further with it,&quot; Abrams recalled.</p>
<p>Fortunately their faith and determination persevered because &quot;Shear Madness&quot; caught on through word-of-mouth and the play has grossed $76 million worldwide since then. The Washington production alone has grossed $27 million.</p>
<p>The actors actually shave and shampoo on stage. As of Aug. 12, the Washington cast had used 4,153 cans of shaving cream (one can per show), 436 cans of hairspray, 474 emery boards, 29 blow dryers, 8,081 Tic Tacs breath mints, 536 bottles of nail polish and 28 gallons (106 litres) of shampoo and conditioner.</p>
<p>The producers and actors believe the magic of &quot;Shear Madness,&quot; which succeeded without setting foot inside New York City, lies in its combination of several unique qualities.</p>
<p>First, constant changes in the script have kept the 18-year-old play alive and fresh. Actors and staff not only add new jokes and throw out old material on a daily basis, they also pop in ad libs. In an effort to maintain a modern and current tone, only the rough story outline and a few jokes have remained from the original production.</p>
<p>&quot;When you're looking at 'Shear Madness' tonight, you're not looking at an 18-year-old play because the words that are being said tonight are not the same words or lines that were said 18 years ago. it's rewritten every night,&quot; Abrams said.</p>
<p>Diane Sawyer, a veteran actress who has played Mrs. Schubert in more than 1,000 performances, added: &quot;I think we all look in the newspaper hardly for the news anymore but just to see how we can put it into the show.&quot;</p>
<p>AUDIENCE ADDS UNPREDICTABILITY</p>
<p>In addition, the audience, who can ask questions and talk to the characters during the play, add an element of unpredictability, artistic director Bob Lohrman said. Jordan enjoys recounting one occasion when an audience member offered to cook a meal for Tony's dinner guests after he burned some goulash he had planned to serve.</p>
<p>&quot;The 400 people are in a sense the seventh character of the show and they don't have a script,&quot; Lohrman said. &quot;They're improvising completely so you're on stage with people totally unscripted and who try to catch you in a lie.&quot;</p>
<p>Finally, the play, which has been staged in many countries in the Americas, Europe and Australia, provides local flavor by casting local actors whenever possible and adapting the setting from city to city.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the inherent charms of the play is that it takes place today in the city in which it plays,&quot; Abrams said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fun part of rehearsing is that you get six actors from the city trying to find out what's particularly funny about that city,&quot; Jordan added.</p>
<p>In Washington, for example, when asked about her husband's profession, Mrs. Schubert replies, &quot;He's a diplomat, he doesn't do anything.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The thing that essentially has made the show such a big success is that it's an amazing combination of entertainment factors,&quot; Lohrman said. &quot;Everyone loves a murder mystery and everyone likes to try to figure out who did it. That, coupled with hilarious comedy, is an incomparable combination of things. The audience has a great time.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
