<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="809949" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway shares close higher, but Kvaerner falls.</title>
<headline>Norway shares close higher, but Kvaerner falls.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Kvaerner ASA plunged to help burden the Oslo Bourse Total index on Tuesday after the Anglo-Norwegian construction and engineering company released disappointing first-half results.</p>
<p>The Total index closed 1.08 percent up at 1,285.20 points in heavy turnover of 1.6 billion crowns to shadow a European trend following a rebound on Wall Street.</p>
<p>Kvaerner's A share alone accounted for 408 million crowns and was the most traded share of the session. The share tumbled 5.8 percent, or 27 crowns, to 431 crowns.</p>
<p>The stock was 10 crowns up when the results were announced.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures were extremely bad and show a pre-tax margin for the first and second quarter of less than one percent,&quot; said an Oslo-based analyst.</p>
<p>The London-headquartered company posted pre-tax profits up 19 percent at 840 million crowns in the first half.</p>
<p>The results fell well below expectations.</p>
<p>Industrial group Norsk Hydro, Norway's largest listed company, helped pull up the Total index by closing 13 crowns, or 2.91 percent, higher at 408 crowns.</p>
<p>--Oslo newsroom +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
