<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="80997" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GAMBIA: Gambia's army ruler wins civilian-rule election.</title>
<headline>Gambia's army ruler wins civilian-rule election.</headline>
<byline>John Chiahemen</byline>
<dateline>BANJUL 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gambia's military leader Yahya Jammeh coasted to an emphatic victory on Friday in presidential elections to end army rule in the tiny West African country, provisional results showed.</p>
<p>His main rival, lawyer Ousainou Darboe, took refuge in the Senegalese embassy in Banjul along with some family members, according to Senegalese officials in Dakar.</p>
<p>With 45 of 47 constituencies or 81 percent of the vote counted, Jammeh's tally was 199,650 votes or 55 percent of the total. Darboe received 131,035 votes or 36 percent, according to official returns issued by the electoral commission.</p>
<p>With the remaining constituencies accounting for just 70,000 votes, Jammeh's victory was assured.</p>
<p>Two marginal civilian candidates -- hotel manager Amath Bah of the National Reconciliation Party and Sidia Jatta of the small People's Democratic Organisation for Independence and Socialism -- polled 20,977 and 10,571 votes respectively.</p>
<p>Electoral commission chairman Gabriel Roberts was expected to make a formal declaration of results later.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear if there had been any direct threat to Darboe, who was reported by state television to have cast his vote in Banjul on Thursday, polling day.</p>
<p>Some of his aides were arrested during campaign violence and many said they were beaten up by soldiers after a clash with Jammeh supporters a few days before voting.</p>
<p>Jammeh's win is bound to alarm democracy campaigners in West Africa faced with a new political challenge: coupmakers exploiting the advantage of incumbency to legitimise their rule through the ballot box.</p>
<p>Such elections left political tension in their wake in Niger and Chad.</p>
<p>Jammeh, 31, seized power in a 1994 coup, toppling elected president Sir Dawda Jawara who had ruled the tiny country of one million people from independence from Britain in 1965.</p>
<p>Jammeh resigned from the army last month to contest the elections that he brought forward from 1998 following Western pressure. Western creditors froze aid and some put a temporary ban on their nationals travelling to the tourist haven.</p>
<p>Jammeh turned to Libya, Cuba and Taiwan who gave aid for new projects in health, education and infrastructure that he has openly cited to woo voters.</p>
<p>Jammeh and military associates formed the Alliance for Patriotic Reorientation and Construction that nominated him. He banned the main opposition parties and established politicians who served under Jawara, now exiled in Britain.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth and the United Nations described the electoral law and constitutional arrangements as flawed and called off plans to send observers for the poll.</p>
<p>&quot;The transition is so awkwardly designed that it leaves complete control in the hands of the AFPRC (ruling military council),&quot; a Western diplomat said, commenting on what would happen if Jammeh lost. &quot;This is a recipe for a particularly unstable situation.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GAMB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANJUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
