<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="809910" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German call money eases a tick after repo tender.</title>
<headline>German call money eases a tick after repo tender.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>German call money eased slightly on Tuesday with the market finding sufficient liquidity and relieved that, as expected, the Bundesbank announced another fixed rate, 3.0 percent repo.</p>
<p>Traders said the central call money rate slipped to 3.07 percent in morning trade from 3.08 percent on Monday as the Bundesbank reported that credit institutions held a touch more funds with the central bank on Monday.</p>
<p>Many dismissed Bundesbank council member Hans-Juergen Krupp's comments on Monday night when he said an interest rate increase would hurt the economy.  </p>
<p>One analyst noted Krupp is considered a dove on the policy-making council and it was not surprising he was opposed to lifting rates.</p>
<p>Traders said the market is now focusing on Wednesday's repo allocation when 74.7 billion marks of repos expires. Traders said they expected the Bundesbank to drain a small amount of funds from the banking market at the allocation.</p>
<p>Credit institutions held 42.6 billion marks with the Bundesbank on Monday, up from 42.5 billion marks. The average for the month so far stood at 40.6 billion marks compared with 40.5 billion marks.  </p>
<p>Banks did not borrow an appreciable amount of funds from the emergency Lombard lending facility.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt Interbank Overnight Average (FIONA) rate stood at 3.08525 percent on Tuesday compared with 3.09600 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom + 49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
