<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="809947" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK Internet '97 ad revs seen nearing 6 mln pounds.</title>
<headline>UK Internet '97 ad revs seen nearing 6 mln pounds.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Adler</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>TSMSi, a UK Internet advertising sales house, on Wednesday said it expects Internet advertising revenues for Britain to be near the top end of its earlier estimate of four to six million pounds ($9.6 million) for 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;From the end of April through end July we saw an enormous upsurge in the amount of advertising and sponsorship,&quot; Paul Simon, general manager of TSMSi, told Reuters in a phone interview. &quot;So we have revised our estimate of paid-for Web ad campaigns to the upper end of our previous estimate of four to six million pounds for UK clients.&quot;</p>
<p>TSMSi, a unit of television sales house TSMS, which is owned by United News &amp; Media Plc, acts as a third-party sales agent for Internet publishers by packaging together compatible Web sites to sell advertising space.</p>
<p>TSMSi originally forecast 1997 UK Internet advertising sales of four to six million pounds at the start of this year, but at the time thought sales would be toward the lower end of the range, Simon said.</p>
<p>Internet advertising sales in Britain in 1996 have been estimated to have been as high as one million pounds. Simon said that figure included a large number of barter deals. TSMSi's projections for 1997 are based solely on paid-for Internet advertising, he said.</p>
<p>In 1998 TSMSi projects UK Internet advertising revenues will reach about 20 million pounds, Simon said. The estimate includes only advertising driven by personal computer usage, excluding any additional revenues by the advent in 1998 of digital television in Britain.</p>
<p>Separately, Iain Osborne, marketing manager for Yahoo! UK, the Internet search guide owned by Yahoo Inc, said the start-up in 1998 of interactive TV is expected to be a major new driver of Internet usage.</p>
<p>&quot;When the Internet starts coming through the television and the Internet moves from the study to the living room, it becomes completely accessible,&quot; Osborne said.</p>
<p>A growing number of PCs throughout Europe equipped with modems is also expected to fuel Internet usage, Osborne said. Throughout Europe there are currently about nine million PCs equipped with modems. Osborne cited estimates putting modem-equipped PCs rising to 39 to 40 million by the year 2000.</p>
<p>In addition to the growth in Internet advertising in monetary terms, TSMSi's Simon noted that the range of advertisers using the medium is broadening.</p>
<p>&quot;The major spenders within the UK still tend to be IT (information technology) or IT-related companies,&quot; Simon said. &quot;But we have seen in the last six months growing experimentation by mainstream brands. ...</p>
<p>&quot;By the end of 1997 there will be around 50 UK brands (advertising) on the Web,&quot; he said, compared to about 15 to 20 earlier this year. The greatest growth is in the telecommunications, entertainment and alcoholic beverage areas.</p>
<p>Internet advertising remains an extremely small market compared to the revenues generated by advertising on other UK media, but Simon expects it to reach a significant portion of the total in a few years.</p>
<p>&quot;I generally believe that by the year 2000 it will form a significant portion of UK advertising,&quot; Simon said. Internet advertising, currently representing about 0.1 percent of total UK advertising expenditure, is expected to account for one percent of the total by the year 2000, he said.</p>
<p>Advertising expenditure in Britain totalled 11.97 billion pounds in 1996, according to the Advertising Association. The total included 3.33 billion pounds from television, 344 million pounds from radio, and 73 million pounds from cinema.</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2815 leslie.adler@reuters.com ($ = 0.622 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
