<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810048" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INSIGHT -Notionnel strives to crack 130.16 barrier.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT -Notionnel strives to crack 130.16 barrier.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>September notionnel futures on MATIF will aim to break key 130.16 resistance on Tuesday to open the way for further acceleration, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The recovery we're seeing this week in the notionnel is looking really quite healthy,&quot; said Adrian Sells, director of Crane Investment Analysis in London.</p>
<p>&quot;The immediate key is at 130.16. If we can break out of that, we could see further acceleration.&quot; Charts show the market hit a high of 130.16 on August 4.</p>
<p>By 0804 GMT, September notionnel futures were up 0.16 at 130.04.  </p>
<p>Marc Ostwald, technical analyst at London Bond Broking here, said recent low volatility suggested the contract would be locked in a narrow range.</p>
<p>He saw a band of congestion between 130.20 and 130.30 proving difficult to overcome.</p>
<p>Support-wise Ostwald said 129.70 was the initial prop, the high on August 13. &quot;Then below there, 129.48 comes in, the high on August 6, followed by a big band of congestion between 129.14 and 129.18 -- that should hold the market long term.&quot;</p>
<p>Sells said the low so far this session at 129.80 would act as first support.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we were to break that down, I wouldn't want to hang around on the long side,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Below there, Sells said the market had built quite a good base off 129.42, the low last Thursday. &quot;So in the medium term, that's the level that's really got to hold,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>By 0824 GMT, September Pibor futures were up 0.02 at 96.53.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
