<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810151" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia poised for stronger growth - Costello.</title>
<headline>Australia poised for stronger growth - Costello.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello said on Tuesday the economy could grow faster than four percent if inflation stayed low and the nation lifted savings.</p>
<p>Costello, echoing recent remarks by the central bank and by his own Treasury department, said one of the speed limits on Australian growth -- inflation -- had already been removed.</p>
<p>&quot;What's been the growth constraint on the Australian economy is high inflation and low savings. We have inflation back under two percent so one of the speed limits has come off,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The government is on track to put its budget into underlying surplus in the year ending June 30, 1999, further improving the nation's chronic savings deficiency, Costello added.</p>
<p>&quot;I think if we can kill the savings problem and if we can beat inflation, we should be looking at an economy that grows at four percent plus -- of course we should be,&quot; he told reporters as he entered a Cabinet meeting in Melbourne.</p>
<p>Costello expressed confidence in the government's forecast for growth of 3.75 percent in 1997/98.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's looking good and the budget forecasts, which are for strong growth, are quite achievable,&quot; he said. &quot;We are in a good situation here for growth,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Reserve Bank governor Ian Macfarlane said last week the economy could grow by an annual 4.5 percent or even faster over the next few years without triggering a blowout in inflation, reigniting speculation of a sixth cut in interest rates.</p>
<p>Treasury Secretary Ted Evans also painted an upbeat outlook for the economy on Monday, with accelerating growth, falling unemployment and inflation under control.  </p>
<p>But Australia's jobless rate, stuck at a stubbornly high 8.7 percent of the workforce, remains the main blot on the economic landscape, fuelling demands for more labour market reform.</p>
<p>The government has forecast the jobless rate to fall to eight percent by the June quarter of 1998, and Costello and Evans have said it may even dip slightly below that by mid-1998.</p>
<p>Costello said on Tuesday that higher growth, higher national savings and labour reforms were the key to lower unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;With that you'll see an improvement in employment as we're expecting over the course of this year,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The more flexibility you can get in practice in the labour market, the better you'll do in relation to employment,&quot; Costello added.</p>
<p>&quot;People have got to understand the better your wage and industrial relations system, the better an outcome you'll get in relation to employment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Latest official data shows the economy grew by just 2.4 percent in the year to March 1997. But new data due on September 3 is expected to show stronger annual growth.  </p>
<p>Australia's unemployment rate rose to 8.7 percent in July from 8.5 percent a month earlier. It has remained stuck around 8.5 percent for the past two years.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne Bureau 61-3 9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
