<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810205" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodian king to commemorate kidnapped Briton.</title>
<headline>Cambodian king to commemorate kidnapped Briton.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodian King Norodom Sihanouk on Tuesday said he believed kidnapped Briton Christopher Howes was dead and proposed naming a street in a Phnom Penh after the missing man.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we are hopeless that Christopher Howes is still alive because the brutal and criminal Khmer Rouge abducted him and treated him very badly,&quot; the king wrote in a letter to Second Prime Minister Hun Sen and acting head of state Chea Sim.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to give thanks to Christopher Howes, who set a great example while he was a foreign expert, volunteering to die in Cambodian territory for the lives of Cambodians, I would like you to take legal measures to (re)name ... Norodom Sihanouk Boulevard, Christopher Howes Boulevard,&quot; Sihanouk said.</p>
<p>Howes, 38, of Bristol, England, and his Cambodian interpreter Houn Hourth were abducted on March 26 last year while conducting mine clearance operations in the northwest province of Siem Reap for the British-based Mines Advisory Group.</p>
<p>Authorities believe the two men were taken to the Khmer Rouge jungle stronghold of Anlong Veng.</p>
<p>Sihanouk said he wanted to commemorate Howes' work, adding that he considered the large numbers of landmines hidden under Cambodian soil -- a legacy of decades of warfare -- the biggest problem facing the country.</p>
<p>&quot;I wish to express my deep gratitude by giving my street name to him,&quot; Sihanouk said.</p>
<p>Sihanouk has received requests from Howes' family for help in finding their son and has written several letters to the Khmer Rouge asking about the Briton's whereabouts.</p>
<p>But the Khmer Rouge have refused to acknowledge kidnapping Howes, Sihanouk has said.</p>
<p>Hopes that Howes might soon be free were momentarily raised last November when a top Cambodian general said Howes, Houn Hourth and a group of Khmer Rouge defectors had escaped from Anlong Veng and were headed for government lines. They never appeared.</p>
<p>The Khmer Rouge, whose brutal 1975-79 &quot;killing fields&quot; rule left more than one million people dead, had been fighting the coalition government formed in 1993 since reneging on a 1991 peace pact.</p>
<p>Since Hun Sen ousted his former coalition partner, the king's son First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh, on July 6, the Khmer Rouge have joined Ranariddh's forces in Cambodia's northwest to fight Hun Sen's troops.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
