<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810235" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: POLL- Singapore exports yet to show full recovery.</title>
<headline>POLL- Singapore exports yet to show full recovery.</headline>
<byline>Nick Edwards</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rising domestic output in Singapore has not yet been fully translated into an export-led recovery, economists said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll of 14 financial institutions resulted in an average growth forecast of 5.3 percent for non-oil exports year on year for July, compared to June's actual rise of 8.8 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not buying into the idea that we're seeing a sustained export-led recovery,&quot; said Daniel Lian, regional economist at NatWest Securities.  </p>
<p>&quot;Double digit economic growth for the next few months would be the only way to convince me of a recovery,&quot; he added ahead of a government announcement of July export figures expected on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Singapore's economy grew 7.8 percent in the second quarter of 1997 against 4.1 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the Ministry of Trade and Industry revised its full year forecast for gross domestic product (GDP) to between six and seven percent from five to seven percent.  </p>
<p>The economists polled forecast non-oil exports for July would grow in a range from 2.0 percent to 10.5 percent, with the average pegged at 5.3 percent. Exports rose 6.4 percent in July, 1996.</p>
<p>In Singapore dollar terms, the value of exports was seen in a range of S$7.4 billion to S$7.9 billion in the poll, compared to an actual figure of S$7.3 billion in July last year.</p>
<p>Volatility in month to month export performance has led some economists to believe there was insufficient evidence to predict sustained recovery, with fluctuating base levels from the previous year causing distortions on monthly comparisons.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we can be really positive until after the third quarter. By then I expect to have evidence of a sustained recovery,&quot; said Gan Chin Lee, senior economist at Nikko Research Centre.</p>
<p>Taking a moving average measure, other economists were heartened by an apparent emerging upward trend.</p>
<p>They also pointed to a surge in electronics output of 11.8 percent in June as being a key indicator of economic revival.</p>
<p>Electronics accounts for about 60 percent of Singapore's non-oil exports and is seen by analysts as the main factor for cautious optimism.  </p>
<p>&quot;With continued double digit growth in semi-conductor and disc drive output, which are among the main economic drivers, I expect it to have a positive impact,&quot; said Liew Yin Sze, chief economist at JM Sassoon.</p>
<p>Also influencing optimism was a rise in Singapore's total manufacturing output in June, which rose 9.3 percent year-on-year, compared to a fall of 1.2 percent previously.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a strong possibility of upside surprise this month because there was stronger output in June. The number could well be higher,&quot; said Manminder Singh, senior economist at Nomura Research Institute.  </p>
<p>&quot;Looking at the recent second quarter GDP numbers and production numbers, I think the economy could be more robust than expected and it could be reflected in the export numbers,&quot; said Amanda Choy, economist at SocGen Crosby.</p>
<p>But caution remained the overriding factor.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a bit worried that the whole market is swinging too much on monthly numbers,&quot; said Chua Piang Sze, economist at Vickers Ballas.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't say what the economy is going to do on the basis of one month's numbers. You have to look at underlying trends,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
