<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81022" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Genocide tribunal delays second trial in three days.</title>
<headline>Genocide tribunal delays second trial in three days.</headline>
<byline>Peter Smerdon</byline>
<dateline>ARUSHA, Tanzania 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda postponed on Friday the trial of a Rwandan Hutu accused of genocide.</p>
<p>In the second trial delay in three days, the tribunal court ruled Jean Paul Akayesu's trial would resume on October 31. Officials conceded the tribunal had got off to a slow and shaky start but expected it to pick up in coming months.</p>
<p>They confirmed the arrest on Thursday by U.S. authorities of a 73-year-old Rwandan priest wanted for genocide in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;Our decision is...to resume the session at the last day of October, that is October 31,&quot; said Justice Yacov Ostrovsky, Russian president of the three-judge court in Arusha, Tanzania.</p>
<p>Ostrovsky initially said Akayesu's trial would resume on Monday, but backed down when Belgian defence lawyer Johan Scheers said he needed until the end of October to prepare.</p>
<p>Scheers told reporters he was happy with the ruling as he had agreed with the prosecution on Friday to start with prosecution witnesses on October 31 before another adjournment to allow for the trial of Clement Kayishema due on November 7.</p>
<p>He said the prosecution had told him he could visit Rwanda and would be given protection to search for defence witnesses.</p>
<p>He also said he had handed over 600 pages of witness testimony and would receive an additional 150 pages soon.</p>
<p>Scheers earlier threatened to resign unless he won a delay.</p>
<p>The court also ruled that names and identities of witnesses should not be revealed to the public or media during Akayesu's trial to protect them against possible intimidation and attack.</p>
<p>But it declined to rule on a defence call for the temporary release of Akayesu, 43, a bourgmestre or government leader in Taba commune during the 1994 genocide who pleaded not guilty in late May to genocide and crimes against humanity.</p>
<p>Akayesu was brought to court from prison in handcuffs and sat attentive in a suit and tie after being unshackled.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the court postponed the trial of Georges Rutaganda, 38, from October 17 to next March because he is seriously ill but refused to release him. His defence lawyer said unless he received treatment he would die before trial.</p>
<p>Tribunal spokeswoman Beatrice Lacoste confirmed on Friday the arrest in Webb County, Texas, of Elsaphane Ntakirutimana, a former Seventh Day Adventist priest in Kibuye, western Rwanda.</p>
<p>But she said Ntakirutimana's arrest was also a setback as the tribunal had hoped to snare other suspects with him and they had apparently escaped.</p>
<p>Ntakirutimana is accused of telling Tutsis fleeing attacks to take refuge in Mugonero hospital and then participating in a day-long attack on April 16, 1994, in which hundreds of men, women and children were killed.</p>
<p>The tribunal, with a budget of $36 million for 1996, has indicted 21 suspects of whom 11 are in custody including three in an Arusha jail and one, Rutaganda, at an Arusha hospital.</p>
<p>Those in Arusha include Obed Ruzindana, a businessman arrested by Kenyan police last week in Nairobi and transferred to Arusha two days later.</p>
<p>He is also accused of taking part in the Mugonero hospital massacre and another mass slaughter at Bisesero in Kibuye.</p>
<p>Officials said work was hampered by bad communications but said the tribunal had still moved faster than a sister tribunal for the former Yugoslavia which took three years to put on trial its only suspect in custody.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now getting very close to a real trial,&quot; Tribunal Judge Lennart Aspegren of Sweden told Reuters. &quot;We had all the kind of practical problems you can think of. But on the other hand, things are now developing in a positive direction.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARUSHA, Tanzania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
