<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81049" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian ruler sacks chief of biggest newspaper.</title>
<headline>Nigerian ruler sacks chief of biggest newspaper.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's military ruler General Sani Abacha has sacked the managing director of the majority government-owned Daily Times of Nigeria Plc, the nation's biggest newspaper publisher, the paper said on Friday.</p>
<p>It said an official statement in the capital Abuja announced that Innocent Oparadike, named to the job a year ago, had been replaced with immediate effect by Peter Enahoro, Nigeria's most celebrated journalist.</p>
<p>The statement, signed by Information Minister Walter Ofonagoro and issued on Thursday, said Abacha had approved Enahoro's appointment as sole administrator of the company.</p>
<p>No reason was given for the changes but journalists at the Times group, which publishes more than 12 titles and is one of the biggest and oldest newspaper publishers in Africa, hailed the changes.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw this coming because there has been a lot of opposition to Sir Innocent in the Times,&quot; said one senior editor of the group, adding: &quot;There was a lot of jubilation yesterday when his exit was announced.&quot;</p>
<p>Oparadike and his predecessor, Tunji Oseni, a former editor-in-chief of the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries News Agency (OPECNA), have been locked in a duel on the pages of newspapers over their tenures at the Times.</p>
<p>Oseni accuses Oparadike of sacking Times executives from the Yoruba tribe and replacing them with his Ibo tribespeople while Oparadike counters that he has tried to prevent domination of the newspaper group by one ethnic group.</p>
<p>The new chief executive, Enahoro, 61, was the youngest editor of the Daily Times at 27 in the early 1960s.</p>
<p>Known as &quot;Peter Pan&quot; after a critical column he wrote in the paper at the time, Enahoro went into exile in Britain where he published a magazine called &quot;Africa Now&quot;.</p>
<p>He returned home in 1993 and was appointed chairman of the broadcasting commission, which has now licensed many private radio and television stations.</p>
<p>Enahoro is the younger brother of Anthony Enahoro, who heads the exiled National Democratic Coalition opposed to Abacha's government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
