<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810487" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Aug 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Aug 19.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-08-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Greek Cypriot press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ALITHIA</p>
<p>- Britain blames Ankara for impasse reached at Glion, Switzerland, during latest talks between Greek Cypriot leader Glafcos Clerides and Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash.</p>
<p>- Security Council will avoid pointing finger at any side when U.N. envoy Diego Cordovez briefs it tomorrow on outcome of Glion talks.</p>
<p>CYPRUS MAIL</p>
<p>- Diego Cordovez puts on brave face during discussions in London on stalemate resulting from Glion talks.</p>
<p>- Police say hit man who murdered Turkish Cypriot in Limassol on Saturday may have been member of Turkish secret services.</p>
<p>HARAVGHI</p>
<p>- Communist Akel calls for meeting of National Council to discuss Turkish threats of partial integration of occupied areas with Ankara.</p>
<p>- Accreditation council for tertiary education which ended assessment work on Monday approved 46 fields of study offered in private sector, rejected 15 and pinpointed weaknesses in 34.</p>
<p>PHILELEPHTHEROS</p>
<p>- Nicosia and Athens expected to take crucial decisions in forthcoming days on ways to break impasse on Cyprus problem.</p>
<p>- Tourist infrastructure in Paphos and Limassol will be improved by repairing pavements and renovating old buildings.</p>
<p>SIMERINI</p>
<p>- Athens and Nicosia develop intense diplomatic activity in New York ahead of discussions at U.N. Security Council on Cyprus on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
