<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810571" id="root" date="1997-08-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Aug 19.</title>
<headline>Reuters German Advertising &amp; Media Digest - Aug 19.</headline>
<text>
<p>--------------GAM------------------------</p>
<p>REUTERS GERMAN ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA DIGEST</p>
<p>-----------August 19, 1997---------------</p>
<p>News from Reuters and the German press on Advertising, Media, Brand-name Products and Consumer Trends</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA:</p>
<p>BREMEN - Kraft Jacobs Suchard decides to re-appoint incumbent agencies to its $170 million German media account. But the allocation of business will change. Ogilvy &amp; Mather's Media Consult will now handle planning and buying for the company's coffee ranges, while BBDO's Media Direction will work on the confectionery brands. (Advertising Age)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>BONN - Telecommunications group Deutsche Telekom AG is going to compensate subscribers to its online and Internet access service T-Online with two free hours of service following software troubles. (Reuters)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>ZURICH - Advertising pages in Swiss newspapers rose 1.0 percent in July compared with a year earlier, according to figures compiled by the WEMF media tracking agnecy. (Reuters)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>WALLDORF - Scholz &amp; Friends Berlin gives up the ad account of the Berliner Zeitung newspaper, effective at the end of 1997. (Kress)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS &amp; MARKETS:</p>
<p>LONDON - British media and politicians voice outrage at news that a German company had won a contract for the centrepiece of a lavish London development to celebrate the new millennium. The right-wing Daily Mail headlines its report that Munich's Koch Konstruktive Membrane company had a 6.1-million-pound ($9.8 million) contract on the 20-acre (eight-hectare) dome &quot;Made in Germany. Can't anyone in Britain build our...dome?&quot; (Reuters)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - BMW says Rover Group, its British unit, may fail to turn a profit by 2000, despite having long hoped to do so. Bernd Pischetsrieder, the chairman of BMW (Bayerische Motoren Werke AG), tells Handelsblatt newspaper that Rover, which has lost money ever since BMW bought it in 1994, was being hit hard by the strength of the pound which made it harder to export.</p>
<p>(Reuters)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>NEW DELHI - India's Him Neel Breweries Ltd and Germany's Haake-Beck Brauerei AG have set up a 550-million-rupee ($15.4 million) brewery in northern India, the United News of India (UNI) says. The beer will be marketed under the Haake-Beck brand name and will be available in India from next month. (Reuters)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Volkswagen AG, the world's fourth-largest carmaker, powered ahead in the first half of 1997 as net profits surged 73 percent to 488 million marks ($268.6 million) from a mere 12-percent rise in sales. (Reuters)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>DUESSELDORF - Swiss-based Metro Holding AG, Europe's largest diversified retail company, reports higher 1996 profits and says talks on buying a Dutch cash-and-carry chain are progressing. (Reuters)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Behring Diagnostics, a U.S.-based unit of chemical group Hoechst, says it has received approval from U.S. cartel authorities allowing it to merge with Dade International. (Reuters)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>PEOPLE NEWS:</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Harry Goering, programme director at private channel RTL 2 will leave the Munich-based station in November. He will not be replaced. (Horizont)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Silke Noetzel leaves her post as public relations director at publishing house Tewi-Verlag. Tewi and Rossipaul Medien merged in April and the PR work will be performed from a central post for both companies. (Horizont)</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>Deborah Cole, Berlin Newsroom, 49-30-203-98114</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>For further information and news, see Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. And visit us on the Internet: http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
