<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810693" id="root" date="1997-08-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Blair names Lords to aid Labour in upper house.</title>
<headline>Blair names Lords to aid Labour in upper house.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-08-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Tony Blair on Saturday named 31 new peers to boost the heavily outnumbered forces of his Labour Party in Britain's upper House of Lords.</p>
<p>The move was seen as the prelude to a complete revamp of the unelected chamber, whose pro-Conservative bias has been a grievance of British centre-left parties for decades.</p>
<p>The new Labour peers will boost the party's representation in the Lords to 157, but the Conservatives, with 494 adherents, will still be in a massive majority.</p>
<p>As well as former MPs and long-standing party workers, Blair's new troops include businessmen and people from the arts world such as film director Sir David Puttnam and novelist Ruth Rendell.</p>
<p>Blair also named 11 Liberal Democrats and five Conservatives as peers, while in a separate resignation honours list, former Prime Minister John Major named 10 new Conservative members of the Lords.</p>
<p>&quot;This will go some way to correcting a well-known imbalance,&quot; a Blair aide said.</p>
<p>Major's nominees included several former cabinet ministers, who traditionally receive life peerages on leaving the Commons.</p>
<p>But in what the British media saw as a snub, Major offered no honour to Norman Lamont, his finance minister when sterling was forced to abandon its European Union Exchange Rate Mechanism link with the German mark in 1992 and effectively devalued.</p>
<p>The House of Lords is far less powerful than the lower House of Commons, but still has the power to delay non-financial legislation from becoming law.</p>
<p>Since May 1 when Blair took power, it has twice passed anti-government amendments to bills implementing Labour's election pledges to give mini-parliaments to Scotland and Wales.</p>
<p>But Conservatives argue it occasionally rejected clauses in bills which they presented to it in their 18 years of power between 1979 and 1997, and that it acts efficiently as a chamber which closely scrutinises proposed new laws.</p>
<p>During the election campaign, Labour pledged to end the right of hereditary peers, some holding titles dating back to mediaeval times, to sit in the House of Lords.</p>
<p>This would leave it largely in the hands of &quot;life peers&quot;, such as those Blair named on Saturday, whose titles are not inherited by their children.</p>
<p>There are 327 Conservative hereditary peers and just 15 who support Labour.</p>
<p>Blair has said he would consult widely before any further reform of the Lords, such as making it directly elected.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
