<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810744" id="root" date="1997-08-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chilean judge releases a leader of German colony.</title>
<headline>Chilean judge releases a leader of German colony.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-08-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Chilean judge released a leader of the secretive German community Colonia Dignidad late on Friday night after he was arrested and questioned at length on arriving at the Santiago airport from Argentina.</p>
<p>Hartmut Hopp, spokesman for Colonia Dignidad (Dignity Colony) and a doctor in charge of the community's hospital, was released in the southern town of Parral, 200 miles (320 km) from Santiago, where he testified for two hours before judge Jorge Norambuena.</p>
<p>Hopp, 52, and his wife, Dorothea Witthahn, were charged with illegally adopting their teenaged son, Michael. The couple was summoned to testify before Norambuena on Thursday on the charges but instead fled to Mendoza, Argentina.</p>
<p>They travelled with their son and Rebeca Schaefer, adoptive daughter of Colonia Dignidad founder Paul Schaefer, who faces an international arrest warrant on charges of sexually abusing children in the community.</p>
<p>Hopp is seen as one of the most influential leaders of Colonia Dignidad and is considered close to Schaefer, 76, a former Nazi captain.</p>
<p>His departure coincided with testimony two young defectors from the colony gave before judge Hernan Gonzalez, who is investigating the child abuse charges against Schaefer.</p>
<p>The defectors -- German Tobias Muller, 24, and Chilean Zalo Luna, 18 -- said they knew of children who had been abused in the colony, including Muller himself. They said they were not allowed to read newspapers or watch television and mail was censored.</p>
<p>The two youths travelled on Friday afternoon to Germany, where they were expected to remain for three months.</p>
<p>In brief statements made as he left the Parral courthouse on Friday night, Hopp said he took his family to Argentina to assure its tranquillity.</p>
<p>The Chilean court ordered protective measures for Hopp's son, whose biological mother, Chilean Sonia Godoy, alleged he was forcefully removed from her in 1987 when she took him to Colonia Dignidad's hospital.</p>
<p>Hopp denied the charge. He said his wife and adoptive child would remain in Argentina until he considered they were no longer at risk.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel as Chilean as you, our son is Chilean, and except if the situation becomes unsustainable, of course we will return (to Chile),&quot; Hopp told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
