<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810750" id="root" date="1997-08-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Church bells toll as miracle survivor flown out.</title>
<headline>Church bells toll as miracle survivor flown out.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>THREDBO, Australia 1997-08-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>After two-and-a-half days, prayers for a miracle were finally answered here early on Saturday when a voice called from beneath a concrete slab.</p>
<p>&quot;I can hear you,&quot; croaked Stuart Diver, a 27-year-old ski instructor who lay entombed deep in the rubble of a landslide, sandwiched in a pocket of air between layers of concrete.</p>
<p>Since a hillside gave way in the picturesque ski village of Thredbo on Wednesday night, destroying two ski lodges and burying 20 people thought to have been inside them, hopes of finding someone alive had been fading by the hour.</p>
<p>The faces of rescuers showed signs of frustration and increasing despair, despite their lingering hopes of finding a survivor, until Diver's muffled voice finally rose from the debris.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe I heard a noise which was uncommon, and I got the chainsaw knocked off and laid down on my stomach and yelled out,&quot; explained firefighter Steve Hirst, matter-of-factly.</p>
<p>A hush went across rescue crews picking their way through the unstable slope and then, after a pause, a rescuer standing over a yawning cavity in the concrete raised a thumb in triumph.</p>
<p>After three nights of freezing temperatures, when the mercury dived as low as minus-12 degrees Celsius (about 10 degrees Fahrenheit), a shudder of excitement swept the hillside.</p>
<p>&quot;A miracle has occurred,&quot; a triumphant police Chief Superintendent Charlie Sanderson told reporters.</p>
<p>For 12 hours after Diver was first detected, onlookers crowded a slope opposite the landslide, peering through binoculars and camera lenses and eavesdropping on impromptu news conferences given by rescue coordinators.</p>
<p>For the first time since Wednesday night, there was something to smile about. For a moment, the mood of despair gripping Australia's main winter playground had broken.</p>
<p>As darkness fell, Diver emerged on a stretcher to the cheers of the crowd, including about 20 of his ski instructor peers who yelled, &quot;Good on you, 'Stuey'&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's fantastic,&quot; said Rebecca Thompson, a tourist from the West Australian city of Perth.</p>
<p>She has been in Thredbo village, nestled in a valley of the Snowy Mountains southwest of Sydney, for the past week and saw the picturesque village become a ghost town.</p>
<p>&quot;It's awful that we have lost lives, but they have got some fantastic workers out there. They never give up hope.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pretty surreal. It's hard to believe you are watching it (the rescue effort) on the news and then seeing it out your kitchen window,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>For the victims' family and friends, the nightmare continued. Six bodies had been found among the rubble by Saturday night, and 13 were still missing. Diver's wife, Sally, was among the dead or the missing.</p>
<p>As Diver left for nearby Canberra in a helicopter, dozens of Thredbo villagers made another sad pilgrimage to the village chapel, the tolling of church bells beckoning inside and ringing out over the beat of helicopter rotors.</p>
<p>On arrival at the national capital's base hospital, Diver was again greeted with cheers and the tooting of car horns.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a very long day and a very emotional day,&quot; said helicopter co-pilot Paul Newland</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-08-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THREDBO, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
