<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="810807" id="root" date="1997-08-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran president-elect to be confirmed in office.</title>
<headline>Iran president-elect to be confirmed in office.</headline>
<byline>Ashraf Fouad</byline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1996-08-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mohammad Khatami, an intellectually-minded clergyman embodying many Iranians' hope for social and economic change, will be confirmed as president on Sunday by the country's arch-conservative religious leader.</p>
<p>Many of Khatami's 20-million-odd supporters will be closely following the confirmation ceremony, to be followed on Monday by a formal swearing-in conducted by the Iranian parliament, another conservative bastion confronting the new president.</p>
<p>Both Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, the Shi'ite Moslem patriarch of Iran, and the parliament may well resist probable efforts by Khatami, a middle-level Shi'ite cleric, to introduce economic and sensitive social reforms demanded by much of the electorate.</p>
<p>Khatami, head of the executive in a country which abolished the prime minister's post, has yet to announce his cabinet, whose makeup will require parliamentary approval.</p>
<p>Khamenei, a former president elevated to supreme religious leader after the 1989 death of Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, will host Khatami's confirmation ceremony in the presence of senior state officials and military officers.</p>
<p>Khatami, 54, is a former culture minister who was forced to resign in 1992 because of what conservatives regarded as liberal policies.</p>
<p>Regarded as an open-minded intellectual, Khatami won the presidency by a landslide over a conservative candidate in May with the help of the votes of women and the country's youth.</p>
<p>He will be confirmed by Khamenei as Iran's fifth president since the 1979 Islamic revolution that overthrew the U.S.-backed monarchy of Shah Muhammad Reza Pahlavi.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we will have a deadlock by September or October if Khatami pushes his much-needed reform ideas. The technocrats will resist him and so will the conservative parliament,&quot; said an Iranian businessman who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Analysts and economists say change would be resisted by technocrats who are now well-entrenched in almost every ministry 18 years after many were appointed for their loyalty to Khomeini's Islamic revolution, and not for their skill.</p>
<p>&quot;It will simply not work,&quot; one analyst said of the changes, which would require drastic measures like &quot;opening up to the West, introducing World Bank-like reforms and amending the constitution to attract much-needed foreign investment.</p>
<p>&quot;The list is too long...People also want to have fun, want hope and security. They want the (ruling clergy) out of their lives,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But some are optimistic the powerful conservatives who lost the elections, securing only about seven million votes, will &quot;respect the 20 million who voted for Mr Khatami,&quot; said journalist Hamid Dehghan.</p>
<p>He agreed Khatami's battles will not be easy but if he followed a steady and gradual programme for change he might succeed, provided he also &quot;plays the 20-million card well. Timing is very important here.&quot;</p>
<p>Several analysts see Khatami's supporters as Iran's silent majority who decided to vote to stop the man who was widely tipped to win -- conservative parliament speaker Ali Akbar Nateq-Nouri.</p>
<p>One said Khatami's supporters see him as an intellectual and not a religious mullah -- the clergymen they voted against.</p>
<p>&quot;The vote was evenly distributed and had nothing to do with urban and rural areas,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;We deserve a better life. Look at Turkey, with no natural resources, and look at us with all the oil and gas.&quot;</p>
<p>British-educated economist Fariborz Raisdana said that half of Iran's families live in absolute poverty while 70 percent live in relative poverty in a country that is the world's third largest oil exporter.</p>
<p>Iran has some 60 million people and about eight percent of the world's proven oil reserves.</p>
<p>In random street interviews young Iranian men and women said on Saturday they expected Khatami to tackle high inflation, unemployment and Tehran's tense ties with the West and its Gulf Arab neighbours.</p>
<p>But Khatami will remain a Shi'ite clergyman when president and some analysts predicted no great changes as a result.</p>
<p>&quot;Khatami is one of them (clergymen) and they share many common ideas and issues which no one can divert from,&quot; said one analyst who asked not to be named. &quot;His approach might be different from the conservatives but the mainstays of the revolution cannot be changed.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-08-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-08-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
