<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81157" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugoslav 96 inflation may fall to 60 pct-institute.</title>
<headline>Yugoslav 96 inflation may fall to 60 pct-institute.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia's 1996 inflation rate could be as low as 60 percent because there are no more reasons for dramatic price increases, the Institute for Market Research (IZIT) said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;September inflation rate should remain stable and close to its August level of 2.3 percent (99.2 percent year-on-year),&quot; Slobodan Milosavljevic of the IZIT told Reuters.</p>
<p>Milosavljevic said the very low purchasing power of households and companies and the absence of investors would prevent demand from overheating.</p>
<p>&quot;But the key reason for our optimism is that October 1 would see lower fiscal liabilities for companies, who will pay less for their workers' social security and health insurance,&quot; Milosavljevic said.</p>
<p>Another encouraging sign includes the government's promise that energy prices would remain unchanged to the end of the year. Some analysts said this was a gift from the ruling Socialists before the November 3 elections.</p>
<p>&quot;The annual inflation rate of 60 percent, half of the 1995 figure, along with the stable industrial output growth would be two key achievements of the government's economic policy in this year,&quot; Milosavljevic said.</p>
<p>According to official statistics, August industrial output rose 2.1 percent on July and 9.7 percent on August 1995. The January-August figure gained 4.8 percent from a year ago.</p>
<p>However, Milosavljevic predicted the industrial output growth rate would slow towards the end of 1996 due to a recently launched 10-percent reserve requirement for commercial banks and an expected slowdown in the country's imports.</p>
<p>&quot;The new reserve requirement means commercial banks would have less funds available for giving credits to companies, but it is encouraging that the central bank clearly wants to keep control over money supply and credit market,&quot; he said. -- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
