<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81226" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Sept 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Sept 27.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Friday morning's Albanian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- Neritan Ceka, the opposition Democratic Alliance party leader, urged the constitutional court to decide on a new law according to which members of local electoral commissions who boycott the polls while voting is still under way could be sentenced to up to three years in jail.</p>
<p>- A presidential decree entitles ministries to privatise enterprises and properties they direct, including the defence ministry privatising arms factories.</p>
<p>- Exports have not yet returned to the levels posted in 1989 because production in the Albanian economy remains small.</p>
<p>- Heavy rain disrupted traffic in the country.</p>
<p>- EU's PHARE program will offer financing of $500,000 for the construction of waste disposal sites in the south-western city of Vlore.</p>
<p>- Organisers put the finishing touches to the Miss Europe '96 beauty show to be held on Saturday.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- Albanian immigrants in Sweden start a hunger strike to protest against their return to former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>- A German frigate arrived in the port city of Durres to prepare for joint military exercises with Albania next month.</p>
<p>RILINDJA DEMOKRATIKE</p>
<p>- Tritan Shehu, deputy prime minister and foreign minister, met his Austrian, Bulgarian and Portuguese counterparts in the annual U.N. General Assembly in New York.</p>
<p>- Central Electoral Commission said the participation of President Sali Berisha and of the other officials in the Democrats' campaign was constitutional, contradicting the opposition Socialists' charge.</p>
<p>- Italian embassy in Tirana denies press reports that some 500 Italian observers will monitor the October 20 local elections.</p>
<p>ZERI I POPULLIT</p>
<p>- Europe and the U.S. have spent some five million dollars on training Albanian students over the last few years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
