<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81224" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonian Tallinn Pharma shares placed by de Broe.</title>
<headline>Estonian Tallinn Pharma shares placed by de Broe.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Around 10 percent of the shares in Estonian drugs company Tallinn Pharmeutical Factory has been placed by Williams de Broe with international investors in Scandinavia and London, de Broe said on Friday.</p>
<p>Tallinn Pharmaceutical trades on the second-tier free market of the Tallinn stock market and has this week had huge activity.</p>
<p>Petri Karjalainen, head of Williams de Broe Helsinki office, responsible for Finland and the Baltics, said his securities house was behind the high volumes as it bought the shares in the market and then placed them with investors.</p>
<p>&quot;We placed 10 percent of the company with international institutional investors,&quot; Karjalainen told Reuters by telephone from Helsinki.</p>
<p>He said the stake was bought and placed at current market prices. Tallinn Pharmaceutical ended yesterday at 48.75 kroons.</p>
<p>He said that one of the reasons investors were interested in the Estonian company was that it had good prospects in Russia, where 70 percent of its output was sold.</p>
<p>He pointed out that spend per head in Russia on pharmeceutical was running at just under $10 at the moment, compared with around $200 per person in Finland.</p>
<p>He said the largest shareholder in Tallinn Pharmaceutical was a local firm called Farma, which held just over 50 percent, while the rest was held by local institutions.</p>
<p>Karjalainen said de Broe was also active in Latvia and Lithuania, both of which also have stock markets and are hungry for foreign investment.</p>
<p>-- Patrick Lannin, Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
