<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81351" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia's Orbital boosted by Indonesia deal.</title>
<headline>Australia's Orbital boosted by Indonesia deal.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Australian engine designer Orbital Engine Corp soared on Friday after the company said it would supply engines for a proposed Indonesian car in a deal an Orbital official described as a &quot;pot of gold&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;On the Indonesian front it certainly is high volume production in the automotive market, a pot of gold at the end of the rainbow for Orbital,&quot; Orbital investor relations officer Steve Hill told Reuters from Chicago.</p>
<p>No financial details were released for the deal, which Orbital officials described as the company's biggest.</p>
<p>&quot;It is really the first time the market has seen any high volume motor vehicle deals with Orbital technology,&quot; Hill said.</p>
<p>Orbital shares closed at A$1.15 (US$0.91), up 14 cents or 13.73 percent on Friday, at a two-month high, but they remained well short of the record of A$5.37 reached in November 1991.</p>
<p>However, brokers said the deal was a positive sign for the company and could see the shares start to move up again.</p>
<p>Orbital said in an announcement to the New York Stock Exchange that its Orbital Combustion Process engine (OCP) had been selected by Indonesia for use in the Maleo car project.</p>
<p>The Maleo car project is the brainchild of Indonesia's Research and Technology Minister, Jusuf Habibie.</p>
<p>Production of the Maleo has been set for 1998, with a target production of more than 100,000 units a year.</p>
<p>About 30 prototype models are due to be released next year.</p>
<p>Orbital had been working with the Indonesian government and the Maleo engineering team since mid-1995 about the use of its OCP, a direct fuel-injection system used for two-stroke engines.</p>
<p>&quot;Negotiations are at an advanced stage to establish a consortium between Orbital and its Indonesian partners to mass produce the engine for Maleo in Indonesia,&quot; Orbital said in its stock exchange announcement.</p>
<p>Orbital is listed on the Australian and New York exchanges.</p>
<p>Indonesia currently has two national car projects, the Maleo and the Timor.</p>
<p>The Timor car project is to be developed by PT Putra Timor Nasional, a company controlled by President Suharto's youngest son Humoto Mandala Putra, and Kia Motors of South Korea.</p>
<p>The Maleo deal is the first major contract for Orbital to supply its technology to the automotive market. Orbital engines currently are being used in outboard motors on boats.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a bit of a milestone for the company as it is the first time they have got a commitment to use their technology in an automobile,&quot; said Geoff Anderson, a broker at Perth-based brokerage Hartley Poynton.</p>
<p>Orbital's Hill, who is in Chicago at a trade fair, said there could be more good news soon as Orbital was in talks with other groups about the use of its technology in cars.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some extremely exciting discussions taking place in other markets, not just in Asia, although they are happening in Asia as well, but also Europe and North America on automotive four-stroke engines as well as two-stroke engines,&quot; Hill said.</p>
<p>Hill said Orbital Engine was in talks with 10 manufacturers currently about using the company's technology.</p>
<p>Orbital's technology was invented in the late 1960s by Ralph Sarich and in 1972 the technology was backed by Australia's largest company The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd, which now holds around 25 percent of the Perth-based company.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
