<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81395" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore oil products mixed, gas oil rangebound.</title>
<headline>Singapore oil products mixed, gas oil rangebound.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore oil products were mixed on Friday with gas oil remaining rangebound despite the steep losses on London's gas oil market, while naphtha slipped on lower crudes, traders said.</p>
<p>They said gas oil swaps slipped earlier in the day to trade at $27.75 per barrel, but recovered to Thursday's level on talk of emerging Chinese buying interest. Traders said China recently bought around 30,000 tonnes of first half October gas oil at under $220 per tonne c+f and was bidding at $215. A bid for mid-October gas oil was seen at $27.85, with an offer from a major seen at $28.15 for Oct 18-22, down from Thursday's $27.85.  </p>
<p>Jet fuel continued to be under supply pressure with two S.Korean refiners heard offering October barrels at 60-70 a barrel over Sigapore quotes fob. A Korean refiner recently sold a cargo to a Japanese buyers at $1.75 a barrel premium c+f. Physical jet fuel was offered lower for October 11-16 to $29.30 down 20 cents from Thursday. Another offer was seen for a later date at $29.50.</p>
<p>Nepal was close to awarding its October kerosene import tender to IPG at $245 a tonne c+f, but cancelled it due to technical problems, source said. Nepal will reissue the tender next week to seek one-two November cargoes.  </p>
<p>Naphtha fell slightly in line with lower crude values and a weaker swaps market. October swaps were quoted at $21.10/21.40, down from Thursday's close of $21.30-21.55. Gasoline was unchanged but sentiments were bullish on expectations of tightening supplies as the export-oriented Balongan, Indonesia, crude unit and cracker go down for maintenance from October 1. The 125,000-bpd crude unit down for 24-days and 80,000-bpd residue catalytic cracker down for 60-days. In Singapore, bid for 95-octane was unchanged from Thursday at $22.90 per barrel fob. Fuel oil prices remained directionless and was stuck in a $115-$118 range.--Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
