<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81490" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks end mixed in latest week.</title>
<headline>Stocks end mixed in latest week.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks were mixed in a week which saw the Federal Reserve opt to leave interest rates unchanged, and Wall Street was waiting for a slew of economic data that will indicate whether the Fed made the right choice.</p>
<p>The blue-chip Dow Jones industrial average ended the trading week Friday by rising 4.07 points to 5,872.92. It was down 15.54 points for the week.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index rose 2.07 points Friday, closing at 1,230.05, a gain of 10.36 points for the week, and drawing closer to the June 5 record high of 1,249.15.</p>
<p>Analysts also noted that market focus has begun to shift to third-quarter earnings, particularly after last week's profit warning from AT&amp;T Corp. With earnings season just two weeks away, investors were bracing for other warnings.</p>
<p>But with Wall Street hotly debating the outlook for interest rates, analysts said any evidence that the economy's strong growth continued in September would likely have Wall Street second-guessing the Fed and wondering if the central bank had fallen behind the curve on inflation.</p>
<p>Among the major economic indicators slated for release next week are the closely watched National Association of Purchasing Management (NAPM) index, due Tuesday, and monthly unemployment, wage and non-farm payrolls figures, due next Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The expectation and hope is that both reports will indicate the economy basically moderated in September,&quot; said Hugh Johnson, chief investment officer at First Albany.</p>
<p>Analysts have generally ruled out the possibility the data could push the Fed to move on rates before its November interest rate policy meeting and in fact economists are forecasting next Friday's numbers will show tamer job growth.</p>
<p>September non-farm payrolls are expected to rise by 166,000, down sharply from 250,000 in August, while the nation's unemployment rate is expected to edge up to 5.2 percent. Average hourly earnings are seen rising 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>Experts forecast a NAPM index reading of 52.5, roughly flat vs. August's 52.6 reading.</p>
<p>Even before the NAPM and jobs data, markets will get reports on personal income and consumption as well as new home sales, all due Monday.</p>
<p>Economists forecast a 0.6 percent rise in personal income and a 0.5 percent rise in personal consumption, with annualized new home sales seen at 744,000.</p>
<p>&quot;What really has been driving the economy is consumer spending and I think you'll get some short-term volatility very quickly if personal spending is higher than expected,&quot; said Robert Froehlich, chief investment strategist at Van Kampen American Capital.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that number and the housing number have the potential to move the market as much as anything else.&quot;</p>
<p>For individual stocks, with the market far less stubbornly bullish than a year ago, any sign that earnings growth is slipping is likely to be punished severely, analysts said.</p>
<p>Among other indices, the Standard &amp; Poor's index of 500 stocks rose 0.33 of a point to 686.19, down 0.82 on the week.</p>
<p>The NYSE composite inched up 0.28 to 366.27, topping Thursday's record 365.99. The index rose 0.5 from last Friday.</p>
<p>The American Stock Exchange index rose 1.28 to 568.47, up 3.27 on the week.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 6,754.329, up 5.197 or 0.08 percent. It was up 18.13 on the week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
