<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81501" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: One dead, 13 injured in riot at California prison.</title>
<headline>One dead, 13 injured in riot at California prison.</headline>
<dateline>SACRAMENTO, Calif. 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>One prisoner was killed and 13 were injured on Friday when about 100 inmates, some armed with home-made knives, began fighting at a California maximum security prison, officials said.</p>
<p>The fight broke out between groups of Hispanic and black prisoners in the exercise yard at the prison near Folsom, 20 miles east of Sacramento, Christine May, a spokeswoman for the California Department of Corrections, said.</p>
<p>The riot was brought under control in about 40 minutes when security guards opened fire on the warring prisoners. One prisoner was killed and 13 were injured, May said. The prisoner who died had a gunshot wound but it was not yet known if that was the cause of death, she said.</p>
<p>Of the injured, five had gunshot wounds and were being treated at the University of California at Davis Medical Centre near Sacramento, she said. Eight suffered stab wounds and six of those were also taken to Davis for treatment while the other two were treated at the prison, she said.</p>
<p>May did not know the condition of the injured.</p>
<p>After the prisoners ignored orders to stop fighting, security guards posted around the exercise yard first fired warning shots and then fired at the prisoners, May said. About 17 shots were fired, she said, adding that guards fire to break up life-threatening disturbances.</p>
<p>No prison staff member was seriously injured. Guards suffered &quot;at most a bruise or a scrape,&quot; May said. She said the situation was fully under control and the prison was on lockdown, meaning that prisoners were confined to their cells.</p>
<p>Ambulances raced to and from the prison and local television showed bandaged prisoners being unloaded from ambulances at the hospital.</p>
<p>The prison is a modern facility for criminals convicted of the most serious crimes. May said it is overcrowded as are all California prisons. It holds 3,200 prisoners but is designed for 1,700, she said.</p>
<p>It was not known what sparked the battle between the two groups of prisoners but an investigation has been launched, May said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SACRAMENTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
