<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81531" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Away on business - Travel tips.</title>
<headline>Away on business - Travel tips.</headline>
<byline>Michael Conlon</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some assorted notes for business travelers:</p>
<p>Moving Up</p>
<p>Yes, it really is getting harder to win an upgrade to first or business class, even with a bank-full of frequent flier points.</p>
<p>The explosion of mileage awards (banks are even handing them out now as a prize to lure home equity loan customers) has flooded the system. Meanwhile, the number of first and business class seats available hasn't increased in the past few years.</p>
<p>Frequent Flyer Magazine reports in its October issue that some travelers go through hoops to assure themselves of an upgrade -- like calling to request one at midnight on those carriers that take requests a day or two ahead of the flight.</p>
<p>For those who do manage an upgrade, or whose company policy permits that level of travel, the same issue of the magazine gives an extensive rundown of business class service by carrier, listing such things as type of aircraft, seat arrangements and whether fax or laptop dataports are available on the plane.</p>
<p>Bonus Points</p>
<p>On the hotel front, Hyatt is offering 500 bonus points to members of its Gold Passport frequent guest programme who book and complete reservations through its Internet site.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman said the promotion is designed to familarize travelers with using the Net to book a room.</p>
<p>The Hyatt site is http://www.hyatt.com and can be used to reserve space at 103 of the group's hotels and resorts in North America.</p>
<p>Busy Skies</p>
<p>It's up and away as far as crowded air traffic is concerned.</p>
<p>According to the Federal Aviation Administration and the Air Transport Association there will be 562 million airline passengers on board U.S. carriers this year, but that figure will swell to 673 million by the end of the century.</p>
<p>By the year 2007 the passenger level will hit 856 million.</p>
<p>A Personal Pillow</p>
<p>Air travelers who'd rather not use the pillows that live in the overhead bins have an alternative -- a personal pillow whose manufacturer says is a perfect size for briefcase or carry-on bag.</p>
<p>The &quot;Pillow-To-Go&quot; costs $19.95 and is antibacterial and hypo-allergenic, according to Talatech Inc. It stores rolled-up, fastened with a Velcro strip, and deploys to a 15-inch square that is 13 inches thick.</p>
<p>The pillow is made of a latex foam with thousands of tiny air channels that keep it cooler in summer and warmer in winter, the manufacturer says.</p>
<p>The company reports &quot;tons&quot; of orders since the pillow went on the market earlier this year. It can be ordered by calling 1-800-TALATECH.</p>
<p>No. 1 Mistake</p>
<p>The most common mistake travelers make is the most obvious -- getting the time or date of the flight wrong.</p>
<p>That information comes from Uniglobe Travel International Inc., which says it studied thousands of calls to a 24-hour help line it operates.</p>
<p>About a third of the calls were for reservation changes, and a large number of those were because of missed flights, the company said.</p>
<p>Top Hotels</p>
<p>The Four Seasons Hotel in Chicago has been named the top city hotel in the United States in a reader poll conducted by Andrew Harper's Hideaway Reports. It traded places with the Hotel Bel-Air in Los Angeles, which finished first last year.</p>
<p>Third place went to the Four Seasons in New York, fourth to the St. Regis in New York and fifth to the Ritz-Carlton in San Francisco.</p>
<p>The rest of the top 10 in order: The Peninsula, Beverly Hills; Ritz-Carlton, Boston; Mansion on Turtle Creek, Dallas; Ritz-Carlton, Chicago and Mandarin Oriental, San Francisco.</p>
<p>-----</p>
<p>Business travelers: Question, complaint or pet peeve? Send them to Away on Business, c/o Reuters, Room 1170, 311 S. Wacker Dr., Chicago 60606. Or via Internet E-mail Mike.Conlon(at)Reuters.com using the &quot;at&quot; sign on computer keyboards. We cannot promise personal replies but will try to address letters as space permits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
