<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81628" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USDA comments on Sept 1 Hogs and Pigs, revisions.</title>
<headline>USDA comments on Sept 1 Hogs and Pigs, revisions.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Agriculture Department comments on Sept 1 hogs and pigs inventory and revisions to June 1995-June 1996 hog inventory and pig crop estimates:</p>
<p>U.S. inventory of all hogs and pigs on September 1, 1996, is estimated at 58.2 million head, 4 percent below last year and 7 percent below September 1, 1994.</p>
<p>Breeding inventory, at 6.77 million head, is 2 percent below last year and 9 percent below two years ago.  Market hog inventory at 51.4 million head, was 4 percent below a year ago and 6 percent below September 1, 1994.  </p>
<p>The June-August 1996 U.S. pig crop was 23.7 million head, 5 percent less than last year and 7 percent below the same period in 1994.  Sows farrowing during June-August 1996 totaled 2.76 million, down 7 percent from last year and 11 percent below the same period in 1994.</p>
<p>Pigs saved per litter were a record for the quarter at 8.57 compared to 8.33 during the same period in 1995.  Pigs saved per litter during June-August 1996 by size of operation ranged from 7.50 for those operations with 1-99 head to 8.80 pigs per litter for operations with 2,000 head or more.  </p>
<p>U.S. hog producers intend to have 2.80 million sows farrow during the September-November period. This is slightly below the actual farrowings during the same period in 1995 and seven percent below 1994.  Farrowings for December 1996-February 1997, at 2.71 million sows, are expected to be down one percent from last year and six percent below two years ago.  </p>
<p>Revisions:</p>
<p>All inventory and pig crop estimates for June 1995 through June 1996 were reviewed using final pig crop data, official slaughter data, and import and export data in U.S. level balance sheets.</p>
<p>Based on the review, March-May 1995 pig crop was decreased 730 thousand (2.7%), June-August 1995 pig crop was decreased 221 thousand (0.9%), December-February 1996 pig crop was decreased 425 thousand head (1.8%), and the March-May 1996 pig crop was decreased 398 thousand head (1.6%). The June 1995 hog inventory was decreased 600 thousand head (1.0%), September 1995 inventory was decreased 520 thousand head (0.9%), December 1995 hog inventory was decreased 500 thousand head (0.9%),and both the March and June 1996 inventories were decreased 800 thousand head (1.4%).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100119">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
