<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81711" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Disney, ABC sued by Children's Broadcasting.</title>
<headline>Disney, ABC sued by Children's Broadcasting.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Children's Broadcasting Corp. said Friday it filed a lawsuit to stop Walt Disney Co. and ABC Radio Networks Inc. from allegedly trying to copy the Children's Broadcasting radio programming format and force it out of the children's radio market.</p>
<p>Children's Broadcasting said it also is seeking significant damages from Disney and ABC.</p>
<p>The suit alleged that ABC and its new parent company Disney deliberately used the relationship between ABC and Children's Broadcasting to gain confidential business information about CBC and then used it to develop and market a competing children's radio network with the same format.</p>
<p>Children's Broadcasting had a strategic relationship with ABC from 1995 until late July, when ABC Radio Networks Inc. terminated its operations agreement with CBC.</p>
<p>When the two companies were working together, ABC was the national sales representative for Children's Broadcasting and was responsible for scheduling and billing of network commercial time on CBC's Radio AAHS network.</p>
<p>CBC, in a statement, charged that ABC and Disney &quot;tried to gain an unfair competitive advantage at a time when they were serving in a capacity of trust.&quot;</p>
<p>Children's Broadcasting, based in Minneapolis, filed the suit in the U.S. District Court for the District of Minnesota.</p>
<p>Walt Disney Co. spokesmen were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Children's Broadcasting's Radio AAHS has an affiliated network of 32 stations featuring a mix of music, news, stories and games for children ages 12 and under.</p>
<p>CBC stock was down 50 cents to $4.875 in morning trading on the Nasdaq. Disney was up 37.5 cents at $62.375 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
