<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81738" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French EdF board approves management changes.</title>
<headline>French EdF board approves management changes.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The board of French state-owned utility Electricite de France (EdF) approved on Friday a controversial management change that concentrates power in chairman Edmond Alphandery's hands and creates two vice-chairmen posts and an executive committee.</p>
<p>EdF said in a statement &quot;the new organisation aims to shorten the lines of decision-making and constitutes a close team made up of directors in charge of important operations.&quot;</p>
<p>Some EdF employees opposed the shake-up, which requires a change in an administrative decree dating back to 1959.  </p>
<p>Up to now, most of the key decisions at the EdF were not made by the chairman but the managing director, who was appointed by the government.</p>
<p>The management structure will come into effect once the cabinet has approved the resignation of the current managing director, Francois Ailleret, who will then be re-appointed as a vice-chairman and take charge of EdF International. He will also be responsible for managing economic and financial risk and contacts with EdF's major partners in France and abroad.</p>
<p>A new managing director will be named by the end of the year, the EdF said. A second vice-chairman, Pierre Daures, will be named to handle nuclear safety and strategy.</p>
<p>A six-strong executive committee will be set up under Alphandery's chairmanship to oversee operations.</p>
<p>The Industry Minister Franck Borotra brought his support to Alphandery's reforms after the plan ran into criticism among some head office staff who protested against what was reported in French newspapers as an excessive concentration of power. Alphandery was the former finance minister under the previous conservative government.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
