<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81801" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish debt/currency market closing report.</title>
<headline>Swedish debt/currency market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish long yields continued to track foreign markets lower on Friday while shorter maturities inched higher and the crown firmed.</p>
<p>&quot;We were on our way to a recoil phase late on Thursday, but nothing came out of it. We've been tracking Italy all day long,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Nine-year bond yields fell eight basis points to 7.39 percent and dealers said the undertone was still quite positive.</p>
<p>The spread between Swedish and German long yields decreased seven basis points to 131.  </p>
<p>The shortest maturities, however, climbed a bit and the yield curve flattened further.</p>
<p>&quot;People are selling short-term mortgage bonds, which have put pressure on the short end of the curve. There is probably some profit-taking,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Behind the profit-taking was the fact that Sweden's central bank, the Riksbank, has slowed its pace of cutting the repo rate and in the short term the curve could flatten more.</p>
<p>&quot;The Future Rate Agreements show that the market obviously is not discounting so many more cuts,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>One chief dealer said another reason the curve was flattening could be the Riksbank's decision to intensify its currency dealing. This could have a negative impact on shorter yields if the Riksbank decides to sell crowns, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some speculation that the Riksbank is building up its currency reserve ahead of (a possible link to) Europe's Exchange Rate Mechanism,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The crown firmed to 4.3480 against the mark compared to 4.3650 late on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom, Barbara Taltavull +46-8-700 1019</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
