<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81854" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistani newspapers want Afghan policy review.</title>
<headline>Pakistani newspapers want Afghan policy review.</headline>
<byline>Tahir Ikram</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's government was urged by Pakistani newspapers on Friday to review its policy towards Afghanistan as the Taleban Islamic militia took control of the capital Kabul.</p>
<p>&quot;The fast-moving developments in Afghanistan call for urgent consultations and a comprehensive review of the Afghan policy,&quot; the English-language daily The Nation said.</p>
<p>It said there should be a serious endavour in Islamabad to quantify the implications of a Taleban takeover in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>No Pakistan government comments on Kabul's fall were immediately available because of the Islamic weekend here.</p>
<p>&quot;The Taleban are an unknown quantity in terms of their political orientation, barring the vague perception that they are a religious-motivated outfit,&quot; The Nation said.</p>
<p>The Taleban movement burst on to the Afghan scene in late 1994 after it was formed by Islamic religious students led by Mullah Muhammad Omar, a former guerrilla fighter who was wounded several times in battles with Soviet soldiers in the 1980s.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately the Iranians are averse to Taleban, which makes the scenario even more intricate and calls for an extremely cautious approach to harmonise conflicting interests in the Afghan settlement,&quot; The Nation said.</p>
<p>&quot;Preserving Pakistan's friendly ties with Iran is above all an imperative of the region's geo-politics and Islamabad will have to be prepared for the delicate balancing act.&quot;</p>
<p>The Peshawar-based Frontier Post said the best solution for Afghanistan would have to be found through talks among all factions.</p>
<p>&quot;A solution on the basis of force cannot be a lasting one. The Taleban, or for that matter, other strong Afghan groups, must realise that they cannot dictate terms for long.&quot;</p>
<p>The mass circulation Urdu language daily Nawa-i-Waqt (voice of the time) said the United States and Pakistan had been accused of supporting Taleban and that did not augur well for the national interest of the country.</p>
<p>&quot;President Farooq Leghari should review Pakistan's foreign policy towards Afghanistan,&quot; it urged.</p>
<p>President Burhanuddin Rabbani's government, which fled Kabul before the city's fall, has often accused Pakistan of helping the Taleban but Pakistan denies the charge.</p>
<p>&quot;We reject these accusations with the contempt they deserve,&quot; a Pakistan Foreign Ministry spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had and will continue to observe total neutrality while we must maintain a close watch on the events as they develop.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
