<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="81892" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Taleban hang ex-president after capture of Kabul.</title>
<headline>Taleban hang ex-president after capture of Kabul.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Afghanistan's Taleban commanders moved swiftly to demonstrate control over Kabul on Friday by executing former President Najibullah and declaring an Islamic system in the war-wracked country.</p>
<p>The bodies of Najibullah and his brother Shahpur Ahmadzai were seen by witnesses hanging from a concrete traffic-control post at the gates of the presidential palace as a crowd of more than a thousand people crowded around to watch.</p>
<p>&quot;We killed him because he was the murderer of our people,&quot; Noor Hakmal, a Taleban commander who entered the city from Charasyab, south of Kabul overnight, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Hakmal said the Taleban was searching the city for President Burhanuddin Rabbani, Prime Minister Gulbuddin Hekmatyar and military chief Ahmad Shah Masood but there was no word on their whereabouts.</p>
<p>Taleban leaders said in a statement from Pakistan the movement would enforce an Islamic system in the country.</p>
<p>The statement by Mullah Omar, quoted by the Afghan Islamic Press news agency in Pakistan, declared Afghanistan a &quot;completely Islamic state&quot; where it said a &quot;complete Islamic system will be enforced&quot;.</p>
<p>Celebratory bursts of machine-gun fire and occasional explosions echoed across the city at dawn but the Afghan capital was relatively calm as Taleban fighters set up checkpoints to search vehicles, the witnesses said.</p>
<p>All key government installations appeared to be in Taleban hands including the Presidential Palace and the Ministries of Defence, Security and Foreign Affairs.</p>
<p>No government forces were visible on the city's streets.</p>
<p>Adbul Rahim Ghafoorzai, Afghanistan's deputy foreign minister, said that in the face of attacks from the radical Islamic Taleban militia, the government had planned a &quot;strategic retreat&quot; to prevent civilian casualities.</p>
<p>The minister, who was attending the U.N. General Assembly session, spoke to Reuters Television shortly before witnesses in Kabul said Taleban forces had captured the city.</p>
<p>He said he hoped that Afghanistan's former King, Zahir Shah, ousted in 1973 and now in Rome, would return to the country as even the Taleban would accept him in a leadership role.</p>
<p>Troops had been seen leaving Kabul some hours before, on the only government-controlled road out of Kabul.</p>
<p>Witnesses said tanks, artillery and trucks loaded with soldiers headed north, apparently towards Jabal us-Sharaj, the headquarters of military chief Masood at the entrance to the Panjshir valley.</p>
<p>Kabul itself was quiet on Friday.  Civilians were walking in the streets in the morning past Taleban fighters manning checkpoints and crossroads.</p>
<p>Some people were returning to their homes in the eastern suburbs laden with belongings after fleeing earlier fighting.</p>
<p>The Afghan Islamic Press news agency said Mullah Omar, who is based in the southern Afghan town of Kandahar, had suspended all Afghan ambassadors in foreign countries, ordered them not to spend any government money and asked countries where they were accredited not to deal with them.</p>
<p>The news agency quoted Omar as urging Kabul citizens not to leave their homes and asking those who had left to return. He said the Taleban would guarantee their lives and property.</p>
<p>Taleban forces entered the city from the west, east and south at about 1.00 a.m. (2130 GMT Thursday).</p>
<p>The Taleban captured Kabul after a two-day offensive in which hundreds of people were killed on both sides, according to the International Committee of the Red Cross.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
