<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82054" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Sept 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Sept 27.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following business stories Friday:</p>
<p>* A.H. Belo Corp said it will buy the Providence Journal Co for $1.5 billion in cash and stock.</p>
<p>* Orders for durable goods dropped 3.1 percent in August.</p>
<p>* Federal prosecutors filed charges against Normandy America Inc Chairman Christopher Bagdasarian, alleging conspiracy, securities fraud, bank fraud and perjury in connection with sale of the company's stock. Bagdasarian denied the allegations.</p>
<p>* Net inflows in August of $1.68 billion into high-yield, junk-bond funds topped the previous record of $1.58 billion set in November 1992.</p>
<p>* PepsiCo Inc said it would restructure its international beverage operations to cut $100 million in costs, which will result in charges of at least $525 million.</p>
<p>* Household income rose in 1995 for the first time in six years, the Census Bureau reported Thursday, gaining 2.7 percent to a median $34,074.</p>
<p>* The U.S. Department of Transportation gave ValuJet Inc permission to resume flying after the airline was grounded three months ago.</p>
<p>* Invesco Plc and AIM Management Group said they were in merger talks.</p>
<p>* Michel Camdessus, newly reappointed as managing director of the International Monetary Fund, asked member nations for more than $100 billion to protect an increasingly volatile international financial system.</p>
<p>* Silicon Graphics Inc's stock price fell sharply after the company warned it would not meet Wall Street's estimates for its fiscal first quarter.</p>
<p>* Cie Generale des Eaux said three foreign companies - British Telecommunications, Mannesmann AG and SBC Communications Inc - would invest nearly $2.7 billion for stakes in its new telephone company.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk  (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
