<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82189" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu facing first political test by fire.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu facing first political test by fire.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Heller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>In &quot;what's all the fuss about&quot; tones, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu sat in a posh Paris hotel trying to point reporters towards a light at the end of a tunnel.</p>
<p>Israel's opening of an ancient passageway near Islamic holy sites in Jerusalem would be good for Palestinians and attract tourist dollars, he insisted on Wednesday even as bullets began to fly in the West Bank and Gaza.</p>
<p>By Friday, some 50 Palestinians and Israelis were dead in the West Bank and Gaza. A now-sombre Netanyahu was back home after a three-day tour of Britain, France and Germany which he cut short by several hours in response to the violence.</p>
<p>Israeli opposition leaders charged that Netanyahu, in his zeal to show who is boss in Jerusalem, had stumbled badly in failing to gauge the fury his order to open the tunnel would cause among Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a right-wing government with two left feet,&quot; former cabinet minister Yossi Sarid, a member of the left-wing Meretz party, said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing that was done was to enable visitors and tourists -- Moslems, Jews and Christians to walk 400 metres (yards) straight ahead to the end instead of having to make a U-turn,&quot; Netanyahu said at the Paris briefing.</p>
<p>But in what appeared to be implicit criticism of the government, Israeli army chief Amnon Shahak told Israel Radio on Friday he was given only several hours notice before the tunnel, excavated under the Labour government but kept shut, was opened in the dead of night.</p>
<p>Asked if Netanyahu had miscalculated, a senior official said: &quot;If it gets to the point where Israel has to take into account global implications for every move it takes in Jerusalem, it's in big trouble.&quot;</p>
<p>The official's comment reflected government thinking that as the self-proclaimed sovereign over one of the most politically sensitive cities in the world, the Jewish state should have a free hand in Jerusalem as long as holy places are not harmed.</p>
<p>The PLO wants East Jerusalem, captured by Israel in the 1967 Middle East war, as the capital of an independent Palestinian state.</p>
<p>&quot;Another scenario could have easily been written in which the whole thing would have simply blown over,&quot; the official insisted.</p>
<p>Now, Netanyahu is facing his own &quot;Cuban crisis&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's like Khrushchev against Kennedy -- a wily, veteran leader, Yasser Arafat, testing the mettle of a young relatively inexperienced leader,&quot; the official said. Palestinian President Arafat, 67, has led the PLO since 1964. Netanyahu, 46, has been prime minister for 101 days.</p>
<p>In 1962, Soviet leader Nikita Khrushchev's deployment of nuclear missiles in Cuba brought the world to the brink of atomic war. A U.S. naval blockade around the island and tough talk from President John Kennedy made &quot;the other guy blink&quot; and the missiles were withdrawn.</p>
<p>In this crisis, the United States is trying to get Arafat and Netanyahu to meet and try to salvage a peace process that has turned towards war.</p>
<p>But as diplomatic efforts continued, violence erupted on Jerusalem's Temple Mount, Islam's third holiest shrine, on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
