<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82287" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Sept 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Sept 27.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Washington Post carried the following stories on its front page on Sept. 27:</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>RAMALLAH, West Bank - At least 35 Palestinians and 11 Israelis died in the broadest eruption of violence in the West Bank and Gaza Strip since Israel conquered the territories in 1967.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>AL-BIREH, West Bank - Palestinian marchers defy Israelis with stones and anger, egging on comrades in the police force to use their assault rifles against Israelis who ostensibly were their partners in peace.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - A genetic mutation common in U.S. whites slows the progression of AIDS in people infected with the AIDS-causing virus, according to a new study.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The House Ethics Subcommittee investigating Speaker Newt Gingrich voted unanimously to expand its probe to examine whether the speaker provided accurate, reliable and complete information to the panel.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The capital's crumbling Woodrow Wilson Bridge should be replaced by a 12-lane, $1.5 billion drawbridge, a regional panel concluded.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - A drug ring posing as a church group smuggled cocaine and prostitutes into the Lorton Correctional Complex and filmed a pornographic video in the prison chapel, officials said in announcing 30 arrests.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - Household income rose for the first time in six years while the proportion of Americans living below the poverty line fell last year, the Census Bureau reported.</p>
<p>---</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
