<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82315" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German upper house votes to move to Berlin.</title>
<headline>German upper house votes to move to Berlin.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Fleck</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's upper house of parliament, the Bundesrat, voted on Friday to join the government and lower house when they move to Berlin, the capital of unified Germany, in 1999.</p>
<p>Thirteen of Germany's 16 regional states represented in the Bundesrat backed the proposal to move to Berlin, reversing a narrow decision made five years ago to remain in the sleepy Rhineside city of Bonn.</p>
<p>But regional leaders from around Bonn said moving the Bundesrat to Berlin would betray the spirit of German federalism, the system that helped rebuild post-war Germany into a democratic state.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no country where the two legislative bodies are separated,&quot; Bavarian premier Edmund Stoiber told German ZDF television. &quot;If you look at Rome or Paris or any other important capital city and you see both chambers are in the same place.&quot;</p>
<p>Even though Bavaria had been strongly opposed to the government and lower house moving to Berlin when parliament voted Berlin five years ago, Stoiber said that the states would only be hurting themselves now if they stayed in Bonn.</p>
<p>&quot;The federal character of Germany is clearly demonstrated by the fact we have 16 (regional state) capitals,&quot; Stoiber said, brushing aside criticism that too much power will be concentrated in Berlin.</p>
<p>&quot;The political music plays in Berlin. If we stayed in Bonn we would become second rate.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bundesrat must approve about half of all legislation the lower house passes.</p>
<p>Bonn's mayor Baerbel Dieckmann, fighting to maintain a high profile for the city, said she was &quot;extremely disappointed&quot; and complained that 1,000 jobs would be lost.</p>
<p>Ironically, five years ago when the Bundesrat first voted to stay in Bonn, local city leaders -- still stunned by the lower house's vote to leave -- said that only 300 jobs were dependent on the Bundesrat staying in Bonn.</p>
<p>Johannes Rau, the premier of Germany's most populous state, North Rhine-Westphalia which includes Bonn, accused Bundesrat members of reneging on their promise to stay.</p>
<p>&quot;Once you have given your word, you can't just go back on it,&quot; Rau said, warning the costs of moving the 672-member lower house, several government ministries and the Bundesrat 600 km (375 miles) east to Berlin could spiral out of control.</p>
<p>But others argue it would also be a waste of money if officials had to shuttle between the two legislative chambers hundreds of miles (km) apart.</p>
<p>In its resolution, the Bundesrat said if it stayed behind in Bonn it would lose its influence.</p>
<p>Berlin city planners, who have long hoped that the Bundesrat would someday elect to join the lower house in moving to Berlin, have already set aside the Prussian House of Lords building that is just a few hundred metres (yards) south of the Reichstag where the lower house will meet.</p>
<p>Even Chancellor Helmut Kohl, who has supported efforts to keep some federal ministries in Bonn, had called the Bundesrat's 1991 decision to stay behind after the rest of the government moves to Berlin absurd.</p>
<p>The government plans to move from Bonn, a quiet town of 300,000 that was West Germany's provisional capital between 1949 and 1990, to Berlin, a city of 3.4 million, in 1999 in time for presidential elections.</p>
<p>Despite the exodus to Berlin, seven of the government's 16 ministries, including defence and health, will stay in Bonn to help cushion the economic blow for the city.</p>
<p>About 18,500 government officials, mostly in the upper levels of the bureaucracy, will be moving to Berlin. The Bundesrat meets once a month and has a staff of 200.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
