<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82320" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French unemployment surges to record high.</title>
<headline>French unemployment surges to record high.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>French unemployment leapt to a record in August, with the biggest monthly increase in more than three years pushing the jobless rate to 12.6 percent at a time when government economic policy is under increasing fire.</p>
<p>The number of people out of work in France jumped 39,500 in August to 3,085,100 and the jobless rate based on International Labour Organisation (ILO) criteria, which exclude jobseekers who did any work, hit a record 12.6 percent, up from 12.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an extraordinary number, quite a shock,&quot; said Philippe Brossard, an economist with ABN Amro investment bank in Paris.</p>
<p>The leap in jobless numbers will turn up the heat on Prime Minister Alain Juppe, whose policy of austerity and spending cuts is coming under increasing criticism from the ranks of his own centre-right ruling coalition as well as trade unions.</p>
<p>&quot;This is going to raise the gloom and unhappiness in the parliament. We're heading for a tough political weekend,&quot; said Brossard.</p>
<p>Juppe has called a parliamentary confidence vote for next Wednesday in an effort to unite his fractious coalition. Sniping from within his own RPR party prompted President Jacques Chirac to intervene in Juppe's defence on Thursday.</p>
<p>Juppe has been counting on an upturn in the economy in the second half of this year and had got a fillip from news earlier this week that household spending was gathering pace.</p>
<p>But the latest jobless figures will do nothing to help his efforts to talk up public morale as Juppe and Chirac fight to dispel gloom and crank up consumer spending and business investment. Juppe himself acknowledged the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;The bad unemployment figures published this morning will undoubtedly not help put an end to criticism within the ranks of the majority,&quot; Juppe told fellow deputies from his Gaullist RPR party at an annual conference in Le Havre, northern France.</p>
<p>Brossard and several other specialists said the latest news reinforced the view that there would have to be further interest rate cutting by the Bank of France to help the economy.</p>
<p>Economists said it was still hard to measure the social and political fall-out.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly it's important because it comes amid tensions in the government, but as long as Chirac supports Juppe we should not have too much of a political fight,&quot; said David Naude, an economist with JP Morgan bank.</p>
<p>Despite already simmering labour union tension, Naude said the surge in unemployment could actually have the effect of cowing people rather than sparking unrest.</p>
<p>&quot;When people see jobless numbers rising they may be less willing to demand pay rises or strike,&quot; he said. &quot;It's not clear-cut.&quot;</p>
<p>Valerie Plagnol, an economist at Credit Commercial de France said: &quot;It does increase the potential for social tensions when there is little hope for unemployment and these are only August numbers. There were plans to cut more jobs in a number of sectors in September.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It also means that pickup in household consumption in third quarter won't be supportive for the fourth quarter (economic growth). The momentum beyond third quarter cannot be assured at all,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>French unemployment had fallen by 20,000 in July but that drop had been written off by economists as an aberration due to seasonal factors.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures are the reflection of an economy that remains weak. I would expect unemployment to keep edging up to reach around 12.7, 12.8 percent by the end of the year,&quot; Jean-Louis Mourier, economist at Louis Dreyfus Finance said in the wake of the August data.</p>
<p>The monthly jump in unemployment was the biggest since March 1993, when there was a surge of 55,000, a labour ministry official told Reuters. The unemployment rate among people under 25 years old rose to 24.6 percent from 24.5 percent in July.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
