<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82353" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Cocoa physicals limited to light origin sales.</title>
<headline>Cocoa physicals limited to light origin sales.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Physical cocoa trading remains slack in Europe, with dealers on Friday reporting only light selling from origins Nigeria and Cameroon and the focus of attention remaining on the level of Ivorian arrivals.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders are having a pretty uneventful time at the moment. There's a little bit of origin material offered but not in any significant quantity,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Another said shippers had been unwinding long positions and that had helped keep the market in check.</p>
<p>Continental Europe-based traders agreed, saying industry looked to be fairly well covered and that main crop cocoa beginning to arrive at ports in the Ivory Coast was dominating attention.</p>
<p>Traders cited reports, which some traced back to French trade houses, of signs that early arrivals indicated the crop may be smaller than initially thought. The Ivory Coast has announced its 1996/97 marketing season will start on October 15.</p>
<p>But others said contrary reports were also doing the rounds with some traders saying initial arrivals indicated a big crop.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had some requests for early shipments which may mean the crop is going to be large,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Demand for cocoa products was also subdued. Traders noted a little interest in nearby cocoa butter but added that chocolate makers had stayed away from the market in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The latest port data showed stocks in Amsterdam to be high but slipping from the huge levels that piled up over the summer months in preparation to be delivered against September.</p>
<p>SGS Europe detailed inventories at just over 470,000 tonnes at the end of August, against 500,000 tonnes a month earlier.</p>
<p>--David Evans, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
