<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82355" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Hoechst sent expired drugs to Bosnia as aid.</title>
<headline>Hoechst sent expired drugs to Bosnia as aid.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading German pharmaceutical company admitted on Friday that it had sent a consignment of expired drugs to Bosnia as aid.</p>
<p>Confirming a report to appear on German television, Hoechst AG said it had sent a batch of drugs to war-torn Bosnia after the warranty had lapsed. But the company said humanitarian reasons prompted the donation.</p>
<p>A Hoechst spokesman said that four years ago the company had responded to an aid organisation's plea for medical supplies. Hoechst donated 36 packages of antibiotics to Bosnia-Herzegovina after explicitly warning that the drug's expiry date had passed two months earlier, Hoechst spokesman Heiner Harder said.</p>
<p>German television network ZDF released an advance text of a report to be broadcast Friday night that alleges outdated German pharmaceutical products were sent to Bosnia, including highly corrosive disinfectants from communist East Germany.</p>
<p>Responding to allegations that Hoechst had sent the drugs to Bosnia in order to pull them out of the western European market where they could not longer be sold, Harder said the company's donation had been made purely for humanitarian reasons.</p>
<p>&quot;Our rules were violated during that incident,&quot; Harder said. &quot;We can understand the action from a humanitarian point but we cannot accept it.&quot;</p>
<p>He stressed that the drugs, sent by the company's Swiss unit, were still effective even after the expiration date had expired.</p>
<p>As a rule Hoechst, which receives hundreds of requests for aid annually, only donates medication which has at least six months left before reaching its expiry date, Harder said.</p>
<p>According to an investigative report by ZDF the batch of antibiotics was discovered, unused, in the city of Mostar and must now be disposed of within the country.</p>
<p>In addition to the drugs, television reporter Egmont Koch said his team had also uncovered masses of highly corrosive disinfectants, which had been shipped from former East Germany to the region.</p>
<p>Koch declined to give the names of the companies whose products, including appetite suppressants, mouthwash and anti-malaria pills, were found alongside the Hoechst drugs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
