<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82383" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: EU agrees to tighten extradition cooperation.</title>
<headline>EU agrees to tighten extradition cooperation.</headline>
<byline>Janet McEvoy</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union justice ministers on Friday signed a convention aimed at tightening cooperation on extradition to prevent people suspected of terrorism in one EU member state walking scott free in another.</p>
<p>&quot;The new instrument considerably increases the number of situations likely to give rise to extradition. The extradition threshold will be lowered,&quot; Irish Justice Minister Nora Owen told a news conference after the ministerial signing ceremony.</p>
<p>The convention, seen as essential to creating the security necessary to allow EU citizens to travel freely within the 15-nation bloc's borders, was rushed through after a diplomatic row between Belgium and Spain over extradition in February.</p>
<p>The convention, which must now be ratified, means that an EU country will not be able to refuse extradition of a suspected criminal on the grounds that the offence was a political one.</p>
<p>They will also be unable to refuse extradition of their own nationals, although Germany and Portugal, who will have to amend their constitutions to come into line with that provision, will have five years to come into line.</p>
<p>Under the convention, for example, a person suspected of conspiring with the Mafia, or taking part in terrorism or drug trafficking could be extradited.</p>
<p>The convention also breaks new ground in providing for extradition for tax offences, Owen said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first time that this particular crime will be allowed under extradition -- this is a new departure and I welcome it,&quot; said Owen, whose country holds the rotating EU presidency.</p>
<p>The extradition convention was able to be signed after Spain and Belgium earlier this week finally put an end to their row over a Belgian court's refusal earlier this year to extradite two alleged Basque separatist activists.</p>
<p>At the time Spain broke off judicial relations with Belgium.</p>
<p>ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) have killed some 800 people since 1968, when they started a violent drive for Basque independence.</p>
<p>The two countries said in a joint statement on Tuesday they hoped their accord would allow them to re-start full cooperation on extradition requests in the &quot;shortest time possible&quot;, even before ratification of the EU convention.</p>
<p>The extradition treaty also facilitates the so-called Schengen agreement, an ambitious border free exercise fully implemented at the moment by seven EU countries, which was nearly wrecked by the Belgo-Spanish row.</p>
<p>The accord, linking Belgium, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, France, Germany, Spain and Portugal, is seen as a possible model for a future passport control free zone in the EU as a whole.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
