<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82409" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Parliamentary leader quits over 97 Italy budget.</title>
<headline>Parliamentary leader quits over 97 Italy budget.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader in the lower house of parliament of the centrist Italian Renewal party, a partner in Italy's centre-left government, said he had resigned from his post on Friday in a protest over the draft 1997 budget.</p>
<p>Diego Masi, whose party is led by Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini, said he was stepping down because he could not support what he called an &quot;all-tax budget&quot;.</p>
<p>Masi's spokesman said the move did not imply that the party would quit the government. The resignation was criticised by the party's leader in the upper house, Ottaviano Del Turco.</p>
<p>&quot;In the Senate we will criticise the budget but we will have a positive approach,&quot; Del Turco said.</p>
<p>Masi, who remains a member of parliament, issued his statement as Prime Minister Romano Prodi's cabinet was meeting to approve the budget, designed to help Italy meet the grade for membership of Europe's planned single currency.</p>
<p>A government source said the package aimed to cut the deficit by 62.5 trillion lire ($41.12 billion) and would include 12.5 trillion lire raised from a special, one-off &quot;Euro-tax&quot; and a further 12.5 trillion from &quot;Treasury operations&quot;.</p>
<p>Italian Renewal was founded just before last April's general election by Dini, who was then prime minister at the head of a stop-gap technocrat government. It has 26 members in the Chamber of Deputies (lower house) and 11 members in the Senate.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +39 6 6782505</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
