<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82500" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Human rights group calls for sanctions on Nigeria.</title>
<headline>Human rights group calls for sanctions on Nigeria.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading human rights group on Friday called on Commonwealth ministers to impose sanctions on Nigeria, saying the Abuja government was violating its citizens' rights with impunity.</p>
<p>The London-based group Human Rights Watch/Africa made the comments as it released a 52-page report condemning the Nigerian military government's planned transition to democracy.</p>
<p>In a statement, the group attacked &quot;the detention and imprisonment of opposition politicians, human rights and pro-democracy activists, trade unionists and journalists, as well as restrictions on freeedom of expression...and movement&quot;.</p>
<p>The eight-nation Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group (CMAG) meets in New York this weekend to decide whether to impose sanctions on Nigeria in a bid to propel the government toward democracy.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth, a grouping of Britain and its former colonies and protectorates, suspended oil-rich Nigeria last November after the execution of author Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other minority-rights activists.</p>
<p>CMAG agreed on the sanctions -- including a ban on sporting links and arms sales -- in April but later decided to freeze them until this weekend's New York meeting to give Nigeria a further chance for talks.</p>
<p>&quot;Human Rights Watch calls specially on CMAG...to urge the Commonwealth member states to implement the sanctions recommended by CMAG in April, and also to adopt an asset freeze and arms embargo,&quot; the group urged.</p>
<p>&quot;Human Right Watch calls for international pressure to be maintained and intensified to ensure the Nigerian government takes meaningful steps to improve the human rights situation.</p>
<p>The rights group dismissed recent reforms by the government of General Sani Abacha as cosmetic. Last year he set out a plan to restore civilian rule by October 1998, but CMAG says this is too long.</p>
<p>CMAG comprises Malaysia, Zimbabwe, Jamaica, Ghana, Britain, New Zealand, South Africa and Canada.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COMWH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
