<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="82992" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Sept 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Sept 27.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Alain Juppe decides not to extend a government incentive package granted to buyers of new cars, beyond Monday expiry date. Last month of scheme boosted auto sales, with a record 200,000 orders in September.(Les Echos, La Tribune, Le Figaro, Liberation).</p>
<p>-- Court puts airline Air Liberte under legal administration for six-month period. (Les Echos, La Tribune, Le Figaro, Liberation)</p>
<p>-- British Telecom to invest 8.85 billion francs in Generale des Eaux telecoms branch Cegetel, along with Germen Mannesman and U.S. SBC. (Les Echos, La Tribune, Le Figaro, Liberation)</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- Paribas posts a four-billion-franc profit for the first half.</p>
<p>-- Alcatel Alsthom and SNECMA expect to break even by end of year.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE DESFOSSES</p>
<p>-- Textile group DMC to shed 1,500 jobs in Germany and France.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- CGIP says plans to buy a 28 percent stake in auto parts maker Valeo from holding Cerus, plans to sell stake in U.S. packaging group Crown Cork and Seal for around 3 billion francs.</p>
<p>LIBERATION (Economic section)</p>
<p>-- Cost of explosion of Ariane-5 rocket in June 1996 estimated around 2 billion francs.</p>
<p>THE INTERNATIONAL HERALD TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- Luxury goods group LVMH profits climb five percent to 1.54 billion francs, but gray market weighs on earnings.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
