<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83003" id="root" date="1996-09-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - September 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - September 27.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the highlights of stories reported in the Irish press on Friday.</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- The government welcomed the decision of the Irish Congress of Trade Unions (ICTU) to enter talks on a new national wage agreement.</p>
<p>- Irish national carrier Aer Lingus is close to completing a deal to sell 60 percent of its Airmotive subsidiary to the German airline Lufthansa.  </p>
<p>- The Irish pound fell again in foreign exchange markets on Thursday with some participants saying they saw signs of the central bank intervening to sell the currency.</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- Diarmuid O'Neill, the suspected IRA terrorist shot dead in London ths week, had strong connections with the Basque area where the separatist guerrilla organisation ETA is active.</p>
<p>- Guinness brands, including its flagship stout and top-selling lagers Carlsberg and Budweiser, have increased their share of the buoyant irish beer market this year, the company said on Thursday.</p>
<p>- The umbrella body for Irish accountants said in its pre-budget submission to the government that the tax system must be used innovatively to initiate, encourage and develop indigenous and foreign enterprises to increase job opportunities in Ireland.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 660 3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
