<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83027" id="root" date="1996-09-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: CYCLING-SWISS DOMINATE AS ZUELLE PREPARES TO CELEBRATE.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-SWISS DOMINATE AS ZUELLE PREPARES TO CELEBRATE.</headline>
<dateline>SEGOVIA, Spain 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alex Zuelle looks set to celebrate his first Tour of Spain win by heading an all-Swiss trio on to the winner's podium on Sunday after following home compatriot Tony Rominger in Saturday's time-trial.</p>
<p>Rominger's win moved him ahead of Italy's Roberto Pistore into third place in the overall standings, two minutes behind fellow Swiss Laurent Dufaux who retained second place behind Zuelle.</p>
<p>Sunday's final stage over 165 kms, starting and ending in Madrid, is over mainly flat terrain and expected to finish in a sprint.</p>
<p>Rominger won the stage from Zuelle by 13 seconds, with Dufaux finishing fifth, over two minutes back in provisional timings.</p>
<p>It was Rominger's second time-trial win of the Vuelta and a splendid achievement for a man who seemed to have dropped out of contention after a poor third stage.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm happy, since then I've moved up from 91st place to third,&quot; said Rominger.</p>
<p>The stage also marked the return to form of Laurent Jalabert, who fell from second to 20th place overall earlier in the week after suffering a stomach upset.</p>
<p>Jalabert came in third, one minute 47 seconds behind Rominger in provisional timings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEGOVIA, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
