<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83051" id="root" date="1996-09-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: HORSE RACING-CARSON'S LIFE WAS IN DANGER.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-CARSON'S LIFE WAS IN DANGER.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jockey Willie Carson's life was in danger after he was kicked by a horse in the paddock at Newbury races eight days ago, his doctor disclosed on Saturday.</p>
<p>Asked if the incident had put Carson's life in danger, consultant Myrddin Rees told BBC radio: &quot;Absolutely. This was a severe injury and if I put it another way, I had a very restless weekend the first weekend he was in.&quot;</p>
<p>Rees added: &quot;He remains in remarkably good spirits and over the past week he has shown a resilience and courage, qualities that have made him the champion jockey that he is.&quot;</p>
<p>Rees said Carson's injuries, which included a laceration to the liver, would have been more serious had he not been wearing a body protector.</p>
<p>The jockey, who was allowed out of intensive care on Friday, digested his first piece of solid food on Saturday and will stay in hospital for at least another week.</p>
<p>Rees said: &quot;However, the progress we are seeing is quite astounding. I am extremely pleased and I have no doubt that in time he will make a full physical recovery and he can choose whatever he wants to do.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
