<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83085" id="root" date="1996-09-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-DEPORTIVO BEAT BETIS TO GO TOP IN SPAIN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DEPORTIVO BEAT BETIS TO GO TOP IN SPAIN.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deportivo Coruna replaced Real Betis at the top of the Spanish first division on Saturday, recovering from a goal down to beat the leaders 2-1.</p>
<p>With 11 points from five games, Deportivo go one point ahead of Betis and third-placed Barcelona, who play on Sunday.</p>
<p>Croatian midfielder Robert Jarni put Betis ahead after just two minutes when he left Deportivo keeper Jacques Songo'o standing with a superbly curled free-kick.</p>
<p>But after a strong start Betis seemed to relax and the game became scrappy with the referee failing to clamp down on some heavy challenges.</p>
<p>With former Ajax man Finidi George in fine form down the right wing, Betis had most of the play in the the second half.</p>
<p>But sloppy marking let in Frenchman Mickael Madar to set up Brazilian forward Rivaldo for a simple equaliser 20 minutes from time and the visitors went home with three points after Madar was allowed a free header 10 minutes later.</p>
<p>In other games played on Saturday, Espanyol followed up their midweek UEFA Cup victory by winning 5-1 at home to first division new boys Extremadura, a side without a single point in five games. </p>
<p>The newcomers have conceded 15 goals while scoring only twice.</p>
<p>Athletic Bilbao came from behind to win 2-1 at Racing Santander, while Real Sociedad lost ground on the leaders in a goalless draw at home to Valladolid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
