<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83180" id="root" date="1996-09-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian governor orders arrest of AIDS patients.</title>
<headline>Nigerian governor orders arrest of AIDS patients.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Nigerian military administrator has ordered the immediate arrest and confinement of all AIDS patients in his state to curtail the spread of the deadly disease, the News Agency of Nigeria (NAN) reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>Navy Captain Joe Kalu-Igboamah of the northern Adamawa state gave the order on Friday when he visited the specialist hospital in the state capital Yola.</p>
<p>He said the patients should be confined to where they could receive treatment rather than been allowed to &quot;mingle with and spread the virus to other people.&quot;</p>
<p>AIDS has killed more than 5,000 people in Nigeria, Africa's most populous nation at 100 million, in the last six years, according to the latest official publication.</p>
<p>The health ministry publication released in May said between 1989 when the first case of the disease was reported locally and December 1995, &quot;a total of 5,201 Nigerians have died of AIDS.&quot;</p>
<p>Nigerian health officials have long warned that AIDS (Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome) was on the rise in the populous nation where promiscuity is prevalent.</p>
<p>&quot;Reported cases in Nigeria have shown a marked increase since 1992,&quot; the ministry report said, adding that more than 50 percent of the deaths from AIDS were recorded last year.</p>
<p>Conclusions from surveys carried out in the country suggest there are at least 650,000 HIV-positive people in Nigeria.</p>
<p>HIV is the virus that eventually causes AIDS, which destroys the body's natural immunity and leaves infected people helpless against other diseases. It has no known cure yet.</p>
<p>Nigeria launched a campaign in 1991 to control the spread of AIDS. Each of Nigeria's 30 states now has a coordinator for the AIDS campaign.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
