<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83221" id="root" date="1996-09-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Burma troops intensify pressure on activists.</title>
<headline>Burma troops intensify pressure on activists.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Charles</byline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burma's military rulers prevented Nobel peace laureate Aung San Suu Kyi making a speech on Saturday as troops arrested several democracy supporters at checkpoints set up to stop people reaching the opposition leader's home.</p>
<p>Heavily armed security police and military intelligence officers were deployed on several blocks of University Avenue for the second day to stop a congress of Suu Kyi's National League for Democracy (NLD) party from taking place.</p>
<p>A Reuter photographer saw about 20 people sitting in a military truck with their heads down. They had refused police requests to leave the intersection leading to Suu Kyi's house.</p>
<p>Police refused to comment on the arrests.</p>
<p>The three-day NLD meeting, due to start on Friday, was called to celebrate the party's eighth anniversary. But the ruling State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) decided to block the meeting because it threatened national stability, a government official told Reuters.</p>
<p>The SLORC ordered the detention of 109 activists due to attend the meeting. The official said they were being held in local guest houses for questioning and would be released when the situation calmed down.</p>
<p>Suu Kyi has been seen walking down University Avenue but no one has heard from her since the congress was blockaded early on Friday.</p>
<p>Repeated attempts to reach Suu Kyi by telephone failed, leading to speculation her phone line had been cut as it was during her six years of house arrest that ended in July 1995.</p>
<p>Many Rangoon residents had clearly not heard of the blockade and hundreds came to attend her regular weekly speech on Saturday afternoon.</p>
<p>Police told Reuters the barriers would stay in place at least through Sunday.</p>
<p>Weekend speeches are the only forum for Suu Kyi to get her message out. The government has banned distribution of leaflets or anything deemed threatening to national stability.</p>
<p>The NLD, born in 1988 amid a wave of unprecedented demonstrations by people opposed to military rule, won a landlside victory in a 1990 election which was never recognised by the SLORC.</p>
<p>Suu Kyi, daughter of Burma's revered independence leader, Aung San, was under house arrest at the time. The party congress was to have been the first time Suu Kyi would meet the elected representatives of the NLD as a group.</p>
<p>In May, the goverment thwarted an attempt to hold a similar congress and detained more than 260 NLD delegates. Most were later released but some were charged and jailed.</p>
<p>The SLORC has also accused foreign governments, especially the United States, of helping the NLD organise the party meeting to undermine the country's peace and stability.</p>
<p>In Washington U.S. State Department deputy spokesman Glyn Davies dismissed the charge as &quot;bogus&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Aung San Suu Kyi is a strong figure in the democracy movement and she makes the calls about what happens in the NLD. She doesn't need advice from us.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
