<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83235" id="root" date="1996-09-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Injured HK activist apologises for trouble.</title>
<headline>Injured HK activist apologises for trouble.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Hong Kong activist injured after jumping into the sea to protest Tokyo's claim to disputed islands in the East China Sea has apologised for his action, Japan's Jiji Press reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sorry for creating such a great problem,&quot; Fong Yu Yuen was quoted by Jiji Press as saying from a Japanese hospital where he was taken on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I jumped into the sea wanting to experience what it feels like swimming in Chinese waters. I am saddened that David Chan died.&quot;</p>
<p>On Thursday, the voyage to the islands by a Hong Kong protest group ended in tragedy when group leader Chan drowned after he and four others jumped into the storm-whipped sea in defiance of a blockade by Japanese coast guard patrol boats. Fong said he did not want to worsen relations between Japanese and Hong Kong people, but added he believes the islands are Chinese territory.</p>
<p>Japan has claimed sovereign rights to the islands and refused to acknowledge that the dispute is still open for discussion with China.</p>
<p>Tokyo's claim dates to 1895, when Japan defeated China and seized Taiwan and other territories. China has claimed sovereignty over the islands for centuries.</p>
<p>The uninhabited islands are known to the Japanese as the Senkakus and to the Chinese as the Diaoyus.</p>
<p>Fong briefly met the press at the hospital in Ishigakijima island of Okinawa Prefecture, where he was taken for treatment by Japanese coast guards on Thursday.</p>
<p>Fong was recovering and should be ready to leave the hospital next week, a spokesman for Japan's Maritime Safety Agency said.</p>
<p>Fong's family and David Lan, the head of the Hong Kong representative office in Tokyo, are in Ishigakijima to visit Fong, a foreign ministry official told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
