<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83341" id="root" date="1996-09-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. presses for all-Africa crisis force - report.</title>
<headline>U.S. presses for all-Africa crisis force - report.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton has approved an ambitious plan to organise, train, equip and help deploy an all-African force of 10,000 troops to intervene in that continent's crises, the Washington Post reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>Quoting unidentified senior administration officials, the newspaper said the African Crisis Response Force (ACRF) would be sent to countries where insurrection, civil war or campaigns of genocide threatened mass civilian casualties.</p>
<p>The ACRF would not intervene in the fighting but would establish and protect safe areas where civilians could gather and receive humanitarian assistance, according to the report.</p>
<p>Officials estimated it would cost about $25 million to set up the force next year and about $40 million if the troops had to be deployed.</p>
<p>The United States was prepared to pick up half the cost and was counting on European allies to come up with the rest in cash, equipment or training, officials told the Post.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the force would be created only if the United States could get necessary support from African and European countries.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State George Moose was leading a team through Africa this week soliciting troop commitments from Zimbabwe, Botswana, Ethiopia, Uganda, Tanzania, Kenya, Mozambique and Senegal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
