<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83409" id="root" date="1996-09-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian police detain arms-laden ship in Bombay.</title>
<headline>Indian police detain arms-laden ship in Bombay.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A ship carrying ammunition and small arms, including grenades and Russian-made AK-56 rifles, was detained at Bombay port on Thursday, police officials said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Police said the Burmese-flagged MV Pacdream was scheduled to stop at Madras before heading for Chittagong in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Deputy police commissioner Madhu Shinde said the ship's Korean captain claimed it had been chartered by the United Nations but he had no documents to prove this.</p>
<p>A senior U.N. official in Delhi said he had no knowledge of the ship.</p>
<p>&quot;I know nothing about this ship or its destination. I am caught completely by surprise,&quot; U.N. resident representative H.C. Graf von Sponeck told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Pacdream arrived in Bombay to discharge some general cargo on September 17.</p>
<p>A senior police official said the ship started its journey in Houston, Texas, and had called at Mobile, Haiti, Durban, Mombasa and Karachi before reaching Bombay.</p>
<p>&quot;The ship was detained because it did not have relevant documents or the Indian government's permission to carry arms and ammunition,&quot; said Shinde.</p>
<p>The ship's 23-man crew -- four Koreans, including its captain, and 19 Burmese nationals -- were also detained, police said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
