<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83441" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: ATHLETICS-SPAIN'S ANTON WINS IN BERLIN ON MARATHON DEBUT.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-SPAIN'S ANTON WINS IN BERLIN ON MARATHON DEBUT.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's European 10,000 metres champion Abel Anton, making his debut in a marathon, broke away with less than two km remaining to win the 23rd annual Berlin marathon on Sunday.</p>
<p>Cheered on by huge crowds totalling more than two million, Anton won in 2 hours nine minutes and 15 seconds and collected the first place prize of 30,000 marks ($20,000).</p>
<p>It was the ninth fastest marathon of 1996, although the flat and fast Berlin course has produced three world year best times since 1990.</p>
<p>Francis Naaly of Tanzania finished 21 seconds behind Anton in second place with a time of 2:09.36. Last year's winner, Sammy Lelei of Kenya, was a disappointing third in 2:09.52.</p>
<p>Lelei had won last year's race in 2:07.02 -- the second fastest marathon time ever run -- and had started Sunday's race brimming with optimism about an even faster run.</p>
<p>With 19,532 runners from 70 countries, Berlin is the world's third largest marathon after New York and London.</p>
<p>Anton said: &quot;When we hit the 40-km point, I knew I could win. With the success I had here today, I think I will concentrate on the marathon more in the future. I believe I can run it in under 2:08.&quot;</p>
<p>Colleen de Reuck of South Africa won the women's race in 2:26:36, but made it only a few steps past the finish line before being sick.</p>
<p>Renata Kokowska of Poland was second in 2:27.41 and Marlene Renders of Belgium third in 2:27.42.</p>
<p>De Reuck, who lowered her previous best marathon time by more than five minutes, said: &quot;I went out a little bit too fast and that's I think why I had some problems later.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
