<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83450" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BADMINTON-INDONESIANS DOMINATE U.S. OPEN.</title>
<headline>BADMINTON-INDONESIANS DOMINATE U.S. OPEN.</headline>
<dateline>ORANGE, California 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia dominated the finals of the U.S. Open Badminton Championships Saturday, winning four of the five events -- the men's and women's singles and doubles.</p>
<p>Top-seeded Joko Suprianto remained atop the international men's singles rankings after beating Denmark's second-seeded Poul-Erik Hoyer-Larsen 15-13 15-13 Saturday night at the Orange County Badminton Club.</p>
<p>With his victory over Hoyer-Larsen, the 1996 Olympic gold medallist who was rated third in the world, Suprianto earned $13,000 of the tournament's $200,000 purse.</p>
<p>In men's doubles, a patchwork team of Chandra Wijaya and Sigit, playing in their first tournament together, upset Malaysia's second-seeded Yap Kim Hock and Cheah Soon Kit 18-16 15-10.</p>
<p>Wijaya and Sigit, who usually play with other partners, were unranked as a pair internationally as the U.S. Open began. Yap and Cheah, the 1996 Olympic silver medallists, were third.</p>
<p>Indonesians took the women's events, too. Top-seeded Mia Audina, the 1996 Olympic silver medallist in women's singles, won her first major tournament.</p>
<p>Audina, rated fourth in the world, earned an 11-5 12-9 victory over second-seeded Camilla Martin of Denmark, the world's sixth-ranked player.</p>
<p>In women's doubles, top-seeded Rosiana Zelin and Eliza, the world's third-ranked team, swept Britain's second-seeded Joanne Goode and Julie Bradbury 15-7 15-5.</p>
<p>Two Olympic gold medallists from South Korea won the mixed doubles championship. Kim Dong Moon and Chung So Young swept Britain's Chris Hunt and Denmark's Helene Kirkegaard 15-5 15-7.</p>
<p>Kim, ranked third in the world in mixed doubles with Gil Young Ah, won his gold medal in Atlanta. Chung earned hers in women's doubles in 1992.</p>
<p>Suprianto had to repel rallies in each game against Hoyer-Larsen. In the first game, Suprianto took leads of 5-1 and 10-6 before Hoyer-Larsen moved ahead, 11-10. However, Suprianto scored all five of his remaining points on the Dane's unforced errors.</p>
<p>Suprianto built advantages of 6-0 and 11-4 in the second game, then Hoyer-Larsen narrowed his deficit to 14-13.</p>
<p>But after regaining service, Hoyer-Larsen lost it when he hit a line drive into the net. Suprianto secured the championship when the Dane hit a drop shot into the net.</p>
<p>&quot;I was making too many unforced errors,&quot; said Hoyer-Larsen, who was playing in his first tournament since the Olympics. &quot;But I still have the speed that I need to go against the best in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Wijaya and Sigit also had to frustrate rallies in their first game. The Indonesians had a 10-5 lead when Yap and Cheah forced a 13-13 tie and a tie-breaking set.</p>
<p>The unranked pair then moved ahead 16-14 before the Malaysians tied the score at 16. But after regaining service, Sigit's drop shot and Wijaya's line-drive winner gave the Indonesians the victory.</p>
<p>&quot;We were a bit tired after last night,&quot; Cheah said about his team's three-game semifinal victory. We lost our consentration after the first game.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORANGE, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
