<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83543" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Macro policy should seek bank soundness - IMF study.</title>
<headline>Macro policy should seek bank soundness - IMF study.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nations should make banking sector stability a primary goal of their macroeconomic and structural policies, IMF experts said Sunday in a study of &quot;significant banking sector problems&quot; suffered by more than 130 of the 181 IMF member countries since 1980.</p>
<p>&quot;We argue that the presence of an unsound banking system is a very major constraint on macroeconomic policy management and that banking system soundness should be viewed as an objective itself of policy,&quot; said Carl-Johan Lindgren, chief of the Banking and Supervision division at the IMF's Monetary and Exchange Affairs Department.  </p>
<p>The publication, authored by Lindgren, Gillian Garcia and Matthew Saal, and titled &quot;Banking Soundness and Macroeconomic Policy,&quot; was presented Sunday during the annual meeting of the World Bank and IMF.</p>
<p>Among the study's recommendations, was the need to act swiftly in the event of banking collapse.</p>
<p>&quot;One thing that we do say is make sure there is a strong exit policy...that when banks go bad, which happens in all banking markets, you deal with it early and forcefully,&quot; said Lindgren.  </p>
<p>&quot;Banks should exit the market the moment they come close to insolvency,&quot; he added, noting that banks often become insolvent -- unable to pay debts as they fall due -- long before they become illiquid -- short of cash.</p>
<p>The authors said that financial deregulation has added to the risks banking systems face, although deregulation should not be viewed as a cause of banking problems.</p>
<p>They said fraud is frequently a problem in banking, but noted that their findings found fraud was responsible for only about 10 percent of losses in the U.S. Savings and Loan Crisis.</p>
<p>When asked whether France had gone too far in using taxpayer money to bail out troubled Credit Lyonnais, presenter Manuel Guitian, director of the IMF's Monetary and Exchange Affairs Department, suggested banking sector stability should be among a government's first priorities.</p>
<p>&quot;When a government decides to intervene in a particular banking case because it feels that its necessary for the system at large ... then it's money well spent,&quot; said Guitian.</p>
<p>-- Noah Barkin, Washington Newsroom, 202-898-8300</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
