<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83549" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Performance is business computing priority - study.</title>
<headline>Performance is business computing priority - study.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Perry</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>After years of downsizing, corporate computing executives are placing performance and prospects for creating revenues ahead of cost cutting as their top priorities, according to a new study.</p>
<p>The study to be released on Monday, prepared by Find/SVP's Strategic Research Division, also finds that a high percentage of respondends are concerned they are creating high volumes of data which are not being properly managed.  </p>
<p>A vast majority, some 93 percent of those surveyed in the U.S., are concerned about performance and response time, up nine percent from a survey a year ago, while concern over data security has diminished by seven percent to 86 percent.</p>
<p>Greater concern over performance comes as many companies are incorporating Internet technologies into their computing environments, and some using public networks fear congestion will turn the World Wide Web into the &quot;World Wide Wait&quot;.  </p>
<p>In a sign managers of corporate 'glass house' data centers expect to gain a central role in the growth of distributed computing, executives project 35 percent growth over the next two years in the number of servers under their control.</p>
<p>Janice Porell, vice president of strategic marketing at EMC Corp, which commissioned the study, said it was a sign that downsizing as a trend, especially in the United States, now appears to be losing momentum.  </p>
<p>&quot;It looks to us like information is becoming more critical to the organization,&quot; she said in an interview, adding that rather than simply being viewed as a cost, this trend &quot;supports the notion of providing a competitive edge.&quot;</p>
<p>Large-scale organizations are thus looking to information officers to play far more of an entrepreneurial role, using information processing to provide market leadership.</p>
<p>&quot;Once you're ahead, everyone else is in catch-up mode,&quot; said Porell, noting companies are increasingly looking to retain their most highly valued computing services in-house.  </p>
<p>Illustrating this trend, nearly 70 percent of U.S. respondents said they have already or are currently organizing their computing strategies around information rather than around technology, as they had in the past.</p>
<p>Noting more than three-quarters of respondents have or are planning to use Internet technology, the survey said there was &quot;a strong indication that IT strategies are increasingly focused on using information to reach business goals.&quot;  </p>
<p>Existing and new online applications are viewed as the main sources of the exploition of information technology, with database applications mentioned by 89 percent of U.S. respondents as the major contributor to growth.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, given increased effort to access and utilize corporate data, respondents also identified information bottlenecks as the next unsolved critical problem for managers.</p>
<p>In the U.S., 71 percent said business productivity is hurt by poor file server performance, and 66 percent said customer service is degraded, while at least 60 percent noted adverse impact on time-to-market and competitiveness.  </p>
<p>Significant for EMC, the top-ranking open systems supplier of storage devices, is that 92 percent of U.S. participants said they would consider a storage-based file server solution attached directly to the network to address the bottleneck.</p>
<p>Tranferring data in differing formats between different systems is named as another major source of information bottlenecks, and 90 percent of respondents said they would consider using storage to ease the problem where possible.</p>
<p>Three quarters of managers said open enterprise computing is generating a rapid or very rapid rise in the need for storage and retrieval capabilities, the survey found.  </p>
<p>Four out of five U.S. organizations are bringing open servers under the central control of the data center, with benefits ranging from improved backup and storage to better use of computing staff.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, 37 percent of those polled said that 10 times the amount of critical data remains outside the data center and unavailable to the organization.</p>
<p>Even higher levels of concern about ability to manage business-critical information in open computing environments exists in Europe and Japan, with similar levels of concern over business objectives jeopardized by computing problems.  </p>
<p>The survey is based on interviews with information technology executives and managers in 700 organizations, including 300 in the United States, 300 in six European countries -- Belgium, France, Germany, Italy, the Neatherlands, and Britain -- and 100 in Japan.</p>
<p>The survey was based on an eligible universe of 33,909 organizations with at least 1,000 employees in the United States and 18,268 organizations with 500 or more employees in the European countries. REUTER SGP</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
