<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83573" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Agreement on IMF's GAB finalized - French sources.</title>
<headline>Agreement on IMF's GAB finalized - French sources.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Group of Ten has finalized an agreement for doubling International Monetary Fund emergency resources -- the General Arrangements to Borrow, French sources said on Sunday.</p>
<p>They said a new group, including countries contributing to IMF emergency funds for the first time, would meet at least once a year to supervise the &quot;New Arrangements to Borrow.&quot;</p>
<p>The group, which would also include G-10 members, would have a rotating presidency.</p>
<p>The Group of Ten in a statement earlier on Sunday welcomed progress made in doubling the IMF's emergency funds and recommended that the process be brought to a rapid conclusion.</p>
<p>The wording of the statement appeared to suggest that the final agreement had not yet been reached.</p>
<p>The sources said that under the agreement, around a dozen new countries would bring fresh resources to the New Arrangements to Borrow, doubling the $25 billion in emergency funds currently available under the General Arrangements to Borrow, to which G-10 countries contribute.</p>
<p>The emergency funds are used by the IMF to help countries facing serious financial crises such as the one which hit Mexico in late 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GTEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
