<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83600" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. House approves BIF/SAIF, banking changes.</title>
<headline>U.S. House approves BIF/SAIF, banking changes.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The House in a rare Saturday session approved banking measures to deal with the remnants of the savings and loan crisis and ease regulatory burdens on banks.</p>
<p>The measures cleared as part of fiscal 1997 federal budget accord that passed 370-37 and now goes to the Senate for a vote Monday.</p>
<p>The cornerstone of the banking legislation is a provision to beef up the Savings Association Insurance Fund (SAIF) with a one-time charge totaling $4.7 billion to put the SAIF at its required level. SAIF insures deposits at thrifts.  </p>
<p>Then banks would share in the thirfts' $793 million annual interest payments on Financing Corp. (FICO) bonds issued as part of the savings and loan bailout. Banks would ultimately pay $10 billion to $12 billion over about 20 years for sharing the FICO interest payments.</p>
<p>The banking provisions would pave the way for the merger of the thrift industry into the banking industry. The intention is for the Bank Insurance Fund, which insures deposits at banks, to eventually merge with the SAIF and for banks and thrifts to ultimately have one charter.  </p>
<p>The bill also provides a $3.1 billion offset for increased education and domestic program spending.</p>
<p>House Banking Committee chairman Jim Leach, R-Iowa, said the bill was less extensive than he would have liked but provides increased security for SAIF and forms that baiss for long-term banking modernization.</p>
<p>Rep. Henry Gonzalez of Texas, ranking Democrat on the panel, said the bill accomplished its main objectives. &quot;We completed the essential business of resolving BIF/SAIF and we prevented the rollback of many consumer protections and repeal of many bank safety and soundness provisions.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
