<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83732" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia miner sees copper costs under 60c/lb.</title>
<headline>Australia miner sees copper costs under 60c/lb.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>MIM Holdings Ltd said on Sunday it expected production costs from its A$290 million Enterprise copper mine extension at Mount Isa to average less than US$0.60 a pound by about 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;It's high grade, it's deep, but with the technology we have we think we can achieve a very satisfactory cost position at Isa, which I think reflects the quality of that ore body,&quot; MIM's managing director Nick Stump told the Nine Network's Business Sunday programme.</p>
<p>MIM typically keeps its production costs a secret, although analysts have estimated they are running at about US$0.71 a pound at the current deposit being mined at Mount Isa.</p>
<p>This compares with costs of US$0.40 a pound or less among some of the lowest-cost producers.</p>
<p>Asked if Mount Isa was making losses, Stump said the mine was operating &quot;about break even at this time,&quot; but added &quot;it was really hard to tell&quot;, due to copper prices and the Australian dollar exchange rate.</p>
<p>In August, MIM reported a net profit after abnormals for the year to June 30 of A$170.6 million, but said the Mount Isa operations recorded a loss in June.</p>
<p>The stronger the local currency, the less funds MIM can repatriate from U.S. dollar-denominated export sales, while each one U.S. cent change in the copper price on a per pound basis means A$3.77 million to the company's bottom line.</p>
<p>&quot;Last week we had a US$0.85 (per pound) copper price and a US$0.80 exchange rate,&quot; Stump said.</p>
<p>&quot;Pretty tough, but of course this is new territory because the price has fallen faster and further than anybody expected because of the Sumitomo fiasco,&quot; Stump added.</p>
<p>Japanese trading house Sumitomo Corp in mid-June revealed some US$1.8 billion in losses from rogue copper trades, sending the international metal price into a tailspin.</p>
<p>Citing last week's sale of most of the company's oil and gas interests to Santos Ltd for A$45.1 million, Stump said a diposal programme of non-core assets was &quot;well advanced&quot;.</p>
<p>Stump also said he expected development of the George Fisher zinc prospect near Mount Isa to proceed.</p>
<p>MIM is currently studying the feasibility of bringing the prospect on stream as zinc production at Mount Isa nears an end.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure George Fisher will be mined,&quot; Stump said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
