<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83748" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - September 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - September 30.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top stories from selected Singapore newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE STRAITS TIMES:</p>
<p>- Singapore plans new sports centres and stadia island-wide under a Singapore $360 million plan for facilities to promote healthy lifestyles.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong has an active, but not rigid, routine for exercise, diet and relaxation, including tennis and golf, he tells the media.</p>
<p>- A Middle East peace settlement is set for early this week in Washington.</p>
<p>- Property agents are looking quietly for buyers for a string of commercial properties.</p>
<p>- The Indian government's largest trading company, State Trading Corp of India Ltd, plans to set up its first overseas subsidary in Singapore and hopes to do US$100 million in business in first year.</p>
<p>- Troubled Scotts Holdings forms special committe to review transactions over past few years with directors-related companies.</p>
<p>THE BUSINESS TIMES:</p>
<p>- In final rush to meet year-end targets and win market share, motor traders are not just slasing margins but also adopting new price-cutting tactics.</p>
<p>- Jardine Fleming Investment Management in Hong Kong, troubled fund management arm of Jardine Fleming, says up to US$3 billion of assets under its control are &quot;vulnerable&quot;.</p>
<p>- U.S. House of Representatives passes sweeping securities deregulation measure.</p>
<p>- Jack Chia-MPH is on an acquisition trail, new chairman Chatri Chiarapurk says.</p>
<p>- Sea View Hotel reports three per cent decline in group net earnings to Singapore $3.84 million for year to June 30, 1996.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom 65-8703080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
