<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83757" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Thousands mourn HK activist killed off Japan isles.</title>
<headline>Thousands mourn HK activist killed off Japan isles.</headline>
<byline>Tan Ee Lyn</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Up to 10,000 people holding candles, many sobbing with grief, streamed into a Hong Kong park on Sunday night to mourn a Hong Kong protest leader who drowned last week in a dispute over a group of East China sea islands.</p>
<p>Activist David Chan was killed last Thursday when he jumped off a protest ship in defiance of a Japanese blockade near the uninhabited rocky outcrops which Japan calls the Senkakus and which China claims as the Diaoyu isles.</p>
<p>For the third time in two weeks, crowds poured out their anger and dramatised a cause that has united rival pro-China, pro-Taiwan and pro-democracy camps in the British-ruled territory, which is populated mainly by Chinese.</p>
<p>Mourning banners were strung across the soccer pitches of Hong Kong's Victoria Park, and several Chinese communist red flags with golden stars bobbed among the tearful crowd.</p>
<p>Japan has claimed the islands northeast of Taiwan since 1895 and China has claimed them for centuries. Both governments, reluctant to wreck their relations over the issue, are at a loss how to deal with the two-month-old wave of nationalist passion that has swept Chinese communities in East Asia.</p>
<p>The 45-year-old media consultant's body was flown home to a hero's welcome on Friday. A new protest flotilla carrying 50 activists will set sail in a week's time.</p>
<p>&quot;He lived a great life and died a hero,&quot; said 70-year-old Lily Sum as she joined the outpouring of grief by a crowd that a police officer estimated was up to 10,000 strong.</p>
<p>&quot;My heart is sorrowful, when I see his face tears well up in my eyes,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>A big photo of Chan, dozens of wreaths and a wooden trunk symbolising his coffin, decked in a communist Chinese red flag, stood under a banner in Chinese characters with the words, &quot;Profound condolences on David Chan's death&quot;. Other banners carried the slogan &quot;Eternal glory to David Chan&quot;.</p>
<p>Chan's wife Lau shun-hing, infant son and daughter, as well as his six brothers and sisters, were mobbed by people offering condolences. The widow, a black shawl draped over shoulders, convulsed and sobbed in grief.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever the public say about his death, it has woken up all Chinese around the world to this issue,&quot; his brother Tony said.</p>
<p>&quot;Chan is the first casualty. There is no doubt he was a pioneer in the &quot;Protection of the Diaoyu Islands' movement,&quot; Chan's co-campaigner Andy Tse said, addressing the crowd, as the weeping widow listened and held her daughter's hand.</p>
<p>The crowd, including politicians from across the spectrum, stood with their candles for three minutes of silence and gave the traditional three bows in respect of the dead protest leader. They then sat on the ground listening to speeches.</p>
<p>Patriotic Chinese songs rang out, &quot;Arise Chinese sons and daughters, We are angry now, We'll protect the Diaoyu Islands&quot;.</p>
<p>The songs encouraged Chinese everywhere to unite and struggle for the islands. &quot;Forget left and right, political ideology, Vent our anger together against our enemy.&quot;</p>
<p>Hundreds of police were deployed, scattered everywhere in the park and around it, and thousands more were on standby, in case anti-Japanese emotions turned nasty. Japan's consulate on Thursday asked for special protection for Japanese properties and businesses in Hong Kong, fearing a backlash.</p>
<p>Pro-China politician Tsang Yok-shing broke down in tears in the middle of his speech, as he said: &quot;We must fight Japanese militarism and condemn their claims on the Diaoyus. Martyr Chan has given his life for China and the Chinese people.&quot;</p>
<p>Hysterical applause rang out from the crowd as speaker after speaker -- Chan's relatives, friends and activists -- called on Chinese people everywhere to unite and join the Diaoyu crusade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
