<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83795" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippines says debt payment ratios shrinking.</title>
<headline>Philippines says debt payment ratios shrinking.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines' debt payment ratios have been shrinking despite an increase in the size of the country's foreign debt, the Central Bank said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The debt service ratio to exports of goods and services shrank to 12.82 percent in the first six months of the year, from 17.19 percent in the same period last year, a bank statement said.</p>
<p>For full year 1995, the ratio was 14.50 percent -- meaning 14.50 cents had to be allocated to debt payments for every $1 earned from exports. This was almost half the 27.23 percent ratio for 1990, it added.</p>
<p>During the foreign exhange crisis that beset the country in 1984, two years before late president Ferdinand Marcos was ousted in a popular revolt, the ratio stood at 37 percent.</p>
<p>The debt service ratio to gross national product likewise fell 6.42 percent during the period as against 7.07 percent a year ago, the central bank added.  </p>
<p>Despite a 32 percent increase in the country's foreign debt to $37.778 billion in 1995 from $28.549 billion in 1990, the ratio of debt service to GNP fell to 6.23 percent last year from 8.05 percent in 1990, the bank said.</p>
<p>The Philippines has also strengthened its foreign exchange cover against debt payments.</p>
<p>Gross international reserves reached $10.06 billion by the end of June improving the foreign exchange cover against debt payments by 382.15 percent. This meant the Philippines had more than three times the reserves needed to amortise its foreign debt for the period, the bank said.</p>
<p>In 1995, the country's $7.762 billion reserves provided 162 percent cover of total debt repayments of $4.766 billion for that year. The reserves totalled $2.048 billion in 1990, which was only 57 percent of $3.547 billion debt payments, the bank said.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8936 Fax 817 6267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
