<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83793" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Third tremor in 9 days rocks southern Philippines.</title>
<headline>Third tremor in 9 days rocks southern Philippines.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strong earthquake jolted parts of the southern Philippine island of Mindanao for the third time in nine days on Saturday night, but police said on Sunday they had no reports of casualties or damage.</p>
<p>A seismologist at a hotel in southern Butuan city said guests rushed out into the streets when the tremor occurred at 10:10 p.m. (1410 GMT) on Saturday. It measured 6.2 on the open-ended Richter scale.</p>
<p>The tremor was centred 14 km (8.5 miles) southwest of Surigao city, near Butuan, and originated about 200 km (125 miles) below the earth's surface, said Narciso Diongzon of the Philippine Institute of Volcanology and Seismology.</p>
<p>&quot;If the earthquake had occurred closer to the surface, there might have been damage but it was quite deep,&quot; he said from Manila.</p>
<p>Diongzon said the tremor was felt strongest in Butuan, 800 km (500 miles) southeast of Manila, but Butuan police colonel Timoteo Conol said he had no reports of casualties or damage.</p>
<p>&quot;It has happened several times before so we were not alarmed,&quot; Conol said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's Royal Observatory placed the magnitude of the tremor at 5.9 on the Richter scale.</p>
<p>It was the third tremor to hit the Surigao area in nine days. An earthquake of 6.3 magnitude rocked Surigao on September 20 followed by one of 5.9 a day later. No casualties or damage were reported then either.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
