<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83923" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Turner's charity less than meets the eye - Forbes.</title>
<headline>Turner's charity less than meets the eye - Forbes.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ted Turner claims he is more generous to charities than other billionaires, but that may not always be the case, Forbes magazine reported.</p>
<p>In an article in its current issue listing the 400 richest Americans, Forbes said that the Atlanta businessman, who owns Cable News Network and the Atlanta Braves baseball team, has given $1 million a year in each of the last three years to his alma mater, Brown University.</p>
<p>But it said that in 1994 he announced he was giving $25 million to Brown as well as $25 million apiece to two other educational institutions.</p>
<p>In addition, the magazine reported that earlier this year Turner promised that his charitable foundation would get $350 million in Turner Broadcasting System Inc. stock.</p>
<p>But it said that over the summer the 57-year-old billionaire changed his mind.</p>
<p>&quot;I've decided to keep my 10 percent holding (in Time Warner) intact and fund my foundation piecemeal each year,&quot; the magazine quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>By holding on to the stock and not giving it all to the foundation at once, he assures that he will be the largest shareholder of Time Warner Inc. once its merger with Turner Broadcasting is completed, the magazine said.</p>
<p>Ted Turner will own 10 percent of Time Warner, a shade more than other major shareholders including John Malone, chairman of Tele-Communications Inc., the nation's largest cable company and a major Time Warner shareholder.</p>
<p>Forbes estimated Turner's net worth -- assets minus liabilities -- at $2.1 billion, putting him in the top 50 wealthiest Americans.</p>
<p>Turner and officials of Turner Broadcasting were not immediately available to comment on the article.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
