<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83925" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Czech premier says banking sector is healthy.</title>
<headline>Czech premier says banking sector is healthy.</headline>
<byline>Nigel Stephenson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus said on Sunday the country's banking system, which has seen several institutions put under forced administration in recent months, was fragile but healthy.</p>
<p>Asked if there was a crisis in the sector, Klaus told reporters &quot;No. The term crisis is used just by the political leaders and is not a real description of the situation of the banking sector in the Czech Republic.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts have blamed problems in the banking sector for a recent weakening of the Czech crown against the dollar.  </p>
<p>But Klaus, premier since 1991, said banks which had encountered problems were &quot;rather small.&quot; &quot;Fragility of the system is something natural in a newly-born banking system after 50 years of no banking at all and I am pretty sure that the system is healthy. I'm really not afraid,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Czech National Bank on Friday gave approval for its administrators of  Podnikatelska Banka to settle with ceditors and wind up the bank, CTK news agency reported.</p>
<p>Podnikatelska, with headquarters in Prague and five branches, was put under forced administration in June and shut after losses of more than one billion crowns ($36 million). It was the eighth bank to come under central bank supervision.</p>
<p>Since then, three other banks have been put into forced administration, including Agrobanka, the fifth largest.</p>
<p>Klaus, in an earlier speech to the Institute of International Finance, said the fragility of the banking sector was one of a number of factors keeping real interest rates and margins between interest rates on credits and deposits relatively high.</p>
<p>But Klaus, a champion of pro-market economic transition, said the Czech Republic had completed a difficult stage of transformation after seven years.  </p>
<p>&quot;Economic growth of around five percent a year seems to be a feasible middle-term prospect,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The economy grew 4.8 percent 1995.</p>
<p>The biggest restraint to economic growth was the low rate of unemployment of about three percent which meant labour was short and there was a net inflow of foreign workers.</p>
<p>Relatively high growth had contributed to high domestic demand for imports, creating a significant trade deficit.</p>
<p>The deficit widened to 100.9 billion crowns in January-August from 59.5 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade deficit is, therefore considered to be the most important single economic problem of the current period,&quot; he said, adding that the Cezch Republic, which is keen to join the European Union, suffered from protectionism in various markets.</p>
<p>Klaus said that despite overall growth, Czechs were starting to see disparities in income and prosperity.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic has carried out a mass privatisation programme which officials in other Eastern European countries, including Russia, have cited as a model.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
