<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83957" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Commonwealth skirts talk of Abuja sanctions.</title>
<headline>Commonwealth skirts talk of Abuja sanctions.</headline>
<byline>David Ljunggren</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commonwealth ministers ended their first day of talks on how to push Nigeria back into the democratic fold amid signs that once again they might back away from imposing sanctions on the oil-rich African state.</p>
<p>The eight-nation Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group (CMAG) broke up at 11:15 p.m. EDT (0315 GMT) on Saturday after two hours of talks on how to deal with Nigeria, which was suspended from the 53-nation grouping last November.</p>
<p>CMAG agreed a set of sanctions against Nigeria in April but suspended them immediately. In June they extended the freeze until the New York meeting in order to give the military government of General Sani Abacha more time to talk.</p>
<p>The CMAG delegates were uncharacteristically tight-lipped as they left the Malaysian U.N. mission where the talks were held, but a Commonwealth spokesman said they had had a very worthwhile discussion.</p>
<p>&quot;The meeting focussed on how to keep the dialog going. There was virtually no talk about sanctions,&quot; he told reporters. Ministers are due to resume the second and final day of talks at 9:30 a.m. (1330 GMT) on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth, a grouping of Britain and its former colonies and protectorates, suspended the populous west African nation last November after the execution of author Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other minority-rights activists.</p>
<p>If CMAG does reject sanctions it could indicate a rethink by Canadian Foreign Minister Lloyd Axworthy, whose frustration with what he saw as foot-dragging by other members boiled over a few days ago when he denounced &quot;appeasers&quot; in the grouping.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth spokesman said ministers had kept their tempers but there were plenty of solemn faces on view as the delegates made for home.</p>
<p>The media is normally given broad access to CMAG meetings but in another indication of the underlying tension, officials at the Malaysion mission evicted reporters into the rain before talks began.</p>
<p>Relations among CMAG states eroded last month when they called off a fact-finding mission after Nigeria refused to let ministers meet human rights campaigners and opposition groups.</p>
<p>Axworthy said on Friday it would be pointless to send a mission to Nigeria if its remit were restricted to meeting officials, but other CMAG states say some sort of dialog has to be maintained with Abuja.</p>
<p>Nigeria -- which insists on discussing its suspension from the Commonwealth before any other topic -- seems unlikely to change its mind about the remit of any future CMAG mission.</p>
<p>Axworthy announced in June that Canada would unilaterally impose the sanctions -- which included a ban on sporting links and arms sales -- but experts said the only measure to have any effect would be a world-wide embargo on oil sales.</p>
<p>Britain and New Zealand oppose the idea on the grounds that it would hurt ordinary Nigerians. An embargo would only work with the support of the United States, which buys 40 percent of its oil from Nigeria.</p>
<p>CMAG comprises Malaysia, Zimbabwe, Jamaica, Ghana, Britain, New Zealand, South Africa and Canada.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COMWH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
