<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83955" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton hears golden oldies, gets beanpot.</title>
<headline>Clinton hears golden oldies, gets beanpot.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>David Crosby propped his guitar on his ample stomach. Joe Walsh looked kind of stooped. Stephen Stills had a skullcap-sized bald spot.</p>
<p>Back when they were young and restless in the '60s and '70s, they would not have been caught dead at a campaign rally. But fast-forward to 1996, and here they were playing golden oldies for President Bill Clinton and Democratic Sens. John Kerry and Edward Kennedy of Massachusetts.</p>
<p>It was Saturday night at Fleet Centre, the spit-shined replacement for the venerable Boston Garden where the Boston Celtics played basketball. About 12,000 people turned out for a concert to raise $1 million for Kerry's difficult re-election campaign against popular Republican Gov. William Weld.</p>
<p>Clinton, who as a young man drove around Hot Springs, Arkansas, singing Elvis Presley songs, tapped his foot to the music and had a big grin on his face, seated in the front row between Kennedy and Kerry.</p>
<p>The irony of having one-time foes of the establishment performing at a campaign rally was not lost on Kerry, who seemed to be recalling some fond memories of his own from the '60s.</p>
<p>&quot;Who would have even thought 30 years ago that we'd be here listening to these same people at a political rally -- and still keep our clothes on!&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He went on to rail against smoking tobacco and gave Clinton a beanpot full of Boston baking beans -- &quot;the best of Boston with the understanding that this is better than McDonald's.&quot;</p>
<p>There was plenty of nostalgia for the over-40 set.</p>
<p>Peter, Paul and Mary had the crowd swaying with &quot;Puff the Magic Dragon&quot; and &quot;Blowin' in the Wind.&quot; Joe Walsh of the Eagles brought back memories with &quot;In the City.&quot;</p>
<p>Another Eagles star, Don Henley, sang a few songs, but was perhaps more noteworthy for delivering a political speech honouring Clinton for making 1.7 million acres (680,000 hectares) of redrock canyon in southern Utah a national monument and protected from coal mining.</p>
<p>Crosby, Stills and Graham Nash showed signs of the masterful harmony that once made them one of America's hottest groups.</p>
<p>Updating the anti-war song, &quot;Find the Cost of Freedom,&quot; to 1996, they dedicated it to the men and women of the armed forces &quot;in harm's way.&quot;</p>
<p>Crosby looked to have rebounded from a liver transplant, but his girth was such that his stomach was a good prop for his guitar.</p>
<p>The trio was joined at the end by Carly Simon, the Massachusetts legend who rarely performs before live audiences. She sang harmony for &quot;Teach Your Children,&quot; and in introductory remarks referred to Senator Kennedy as &quot;President Kennedy.&quot;</p>
<p>It was the end of a long day for the president, who rose before dawn in Houston to spend the day campaigning in Rhode Island and Massachusetts. He and his exhausted entourage arrived back in Washington at 2 a.m. EDT (0600 GMT) on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;You can travel the length and breadth of this country,&quot; Kennedy told him to roars from the crowd, &quot;But you'll never get a better reception than in Massachusetts!&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
