<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83962" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton gives and receives in Massachusetts.</title>
<headline>Clinton gives and receives in Massachusetts.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-09-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>- President Clinton arrived in Massachusetts Saturday bearing election-year gifts for the state and then attended an evening fundraising concert and two receptions that generated $2 million for Democrats.</p>
<p>At Logan Airport, Clinton announced with Massachusetts Sens. Edward Kennedy and John Kerry that the compromise budget deal reached earlier in the day with Congress included $50 million to reactivate the Quincy, Mass., shipyard that was closed several years ago because of an industry downturn.</p>
<p>It also included &quot;important funds&quot; to continue the cleanup of Boston Harbor, said Clinton, after stepping off Marine One after flying from Fall River.</p>
<p>The president said the budget would also provide funds to establish a financial management education center in Southbridge, Mass. for military personnel. The Pentagon would release $5 million for it next week and classes would begin March 1.</p>
<p>Asked if this was election-year pork, Clinton said: &quot;If they didn't have independent merit, it would have been difficult to get them in these times that have been particularly contentious.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is not something that just came up overnight tied to the election cycle. This is a multi-year effort,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Clinton attended the concert in the city's new Fleet Center, which replaced the fabled Boston Garden, following a long day of campaigning in Texas, Rhode Island and Massachusetts.</p>
<p>The back-to-the '60s concert lineup included Peter, Paul and Mary, Carly Simon, ex-Eagle Don Henley and Crosby, Stills and Nash.</p>
<p>Officials said the night raised $1 million for the Democratic National Committee and $1 million for Kerry, who is locked in a tough re-election fight with William Weld, the state's Republican governor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
