<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="83979" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Prodi sees Italy deficit-GDP goal lagging in 1997.</title>
<headline>Prodi sees Italy deficit-GDP goal lagging in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi, seeking to get Italy in shape for European monetary union, said in remarks published on Sunday the deficit-GDP ratio may still lag the Maastricht target in 1997 despite a tough budget.</p>
<p>La Stampa newspaper quoted Prodi as saying that the ratio was likely to be 3.6 to 3.8 percent in 1997, falling short of the three percent goal laid down by the treaty and required for entry into a single European currency planned for 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, we may still lack a point of GDP to make up, but with this result we can deal with our European partners on equal terms for entry into Economic and Monetary Union,&quot; Prodi said.</p>
<p>&quot;Because the effort is enormous, they must recognise that.&quot;</p>
<p>European Commissioner Yves-Thibault de Silguy said on Sunday in Washington that more and more of countries may be ready to meet the EMU criteria after big efforts to tame budget deficits.</p>
<p>&quot;Italy has made a huge effort to meet the conditions to be able to switch to the Euro,&quot; he said. But he added that there was no question of softening Maastricht standards for EMU entry.</p>
<p>Prodi's centre-left government on Friday unveiled a budget to cut 62.5 trillion lire ($41.12 billion) off next year's deficit. It must be passed by parliament by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The government said the heart of the budget was worth 37.5 trillion lire, with 25 trillion coming from planned spending cuts and 12.5 trillion from fresh revenues.</p>
<p>In addition, the government plans to raise 13 trillion lire from a special &quot;Euro tax&quot; and 12 trillion from so far unspecified treasury operations. La Repubblica quoted Prodi as saying details of the Euro tax would be unveiled within a week.</p>
<p>Prodi said he hoped the Bank of Italy would now cut interest rates. &quot;We're waiting for Fazio,&quot; he said, referring to Bank governor Antonio Fazio, who has said he wants to see a rigorous budget before consenting to any monetary easing.</p>
<p>The Bank cut its discount rate in July to 8.25 percent from nine percent after keeping it unchanged for more than a year.</p>
<p>Prodi said a cut was needed because the lira was too strong.</p>
<p>&quot;The right exchange rate for our currency should be between 1050 and 1070 against the mark and instead we risk going back into the Exchange Rate Mechanism under the 1,000 quota and that, for our exporting companies, would be a big problem,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Also because I am not optimistic like (Economy Minister Carlo Azeglio) Ciampi on the economic recovery.&quot;</p>
<p>The lira is currently quoted around 996.47-87 to the mark.</p>
<p>Prodi, who was briefing newspaper journalists, has come under fire from opposition and business leaders for raising taxes instead of cutting pensions and healthcare benefits.</p>
<p>But Prodi said pensions would be tackled in due course.</p>
<p>He also suggested that funds raised by forthcoming privatisations -- Italy is due to sell off state phone monopoly Stet and electricity group Enel early next year -- could be ploughed back into the budget deficit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
