<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84039" id="root" date="1996-09-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan cop death in Bhutto case seen as homicide.</title>
<headline>Pakistan cop death in Bhutto case seen as homicide.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani police said on Sunday a member of the police squad involved in the shootout with Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's estranged brother may have been murdered.</p>
<p>Inspector Haq Nawaz Sial was found dead on Saturday at his police residence with a bullet wound to the head.</p>
<p>Sial was one of the police officers who took part in the shootout in which Murtaza Bhutto and his seven body guards were killed on September 20 in Karachi.</p>
<p>Police had initially said Sial's death was suicide.</p>
<p>They said in an overnight statement they were investigating new evidence from Sial's family and from government-appointed doctors who performed an autopsy on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering this, the police investigation is currently directed at determining whether it was a case of suicide or homicide,&quot; a police statement said.</p>
<p>A police official who asked not to be named said &quot;the medico legal evidence suggests that though the single bullet fired was aimed at the right temporal region of the deceased inspector, it may have been fired from a distance of a couple of feet&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the autopsy team had failed to find traces of gunpowder on Sial's hands which could have been conclusive evidence of suicide.</p>
<p>The police statement also said Sial's wife had seen two masked men fleeing after being woken by a gunshot.</p>
<p>Murtaza's supporters have accused police of ambushing and killing him. Police say they fired in self-defence after Murtaza's bodyguards started shooting.</p>
<p>Two policemen, including Sial, suffered injuries.</p>
<p>The southern Sindh province government was likely to issue a report on the findings in the doctors' autopsy report later on Sunday, police said.</p>
<p>Doctors investigating Murtaza's killing said on Thursday the wound suffered by Sial during the shootout was &quot;self-suffered&quot;.</p>
<p>The police had posted two guards outside Sial's official residence soon after the team's report was made public.</p>
<p>The Sindh government on Tuesday had set up the medical board to investigate whether or not the wounds suffered by the policemen resulted from the shootout.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
