<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84152" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-GWYNN DOUBLE IN 11TH BEATS L.A., GIVES PADRES TITLE.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-GWYNN DOUBLE IN 11TH BEATS L.A., GIVES PADRES TITLE.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pinch-hitter Chris Gwynn's two-run double in the 11th inning gave the San Diego Padres a 2-0 win and three-game sweep of the Los Angeles Dodgers Sunday -- and their first National League West title in 12 years.</p>
<p>The Padres needed all three games of the improbable sweep at Dodger Stadium to win their second division title, and they got them. They will face the Central Division champion Cardinals in a best-of-five series beginning Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We wanted to win and go to St Louis,&quot; said Padres manager Bruce Bochy. &quot;We wanted to be National League champions since spring training and today we had a chance to make that happen.&quot;</p>
<p>Both teams came into the game assured of playoff berths. With the wild card, the Dodgers earned a series with the World Series champion Atlanta Braves starting Wednesday.</p>
<p>Steve Finley and Ken Caminiti opened the 11th with singles off Chan Ho Park (5-5) and Gwynn belted a 1-1 pitch over the head of centre fielder Chad Curtis to clear the bases.</p>
<p>&quot;It feels good in the sense I could contribute,&quot; said Gwynn, a .178 hitter this season. &quot;It's been tough on me and my teammates have been patient.&quot;</p>
<p>While his less-celebrated brother had the big hit, Tony Gwynn won his N.L. record seventh batting title.</p>
<p>Gwynn was 0-for-4 in five appearances and finished at .353. Four hitless appearances were added to his totals to reach the required total of 502 at-bats, and his resulting .349 average was still better than that of Colorado's Ellis Burks, who finished at .344.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I'm Chris Gwynn's brother,&quot; Tony Gwynn said. &quot;It means more to me that Chris got the base hit than me winning the batting title.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't played well the last week or so but now I've got to say the regular season doesn't matter,&quot; Eric Karros said. &quot;We weren't tense. Maybe tired, I don't know. San Diego played the same amount of games we did. There's no excuse.&quot;</p>
<p>Dario Veras (3-1) pitched three scoreless innings for the win and Trevor Hoffman got his 42nd save.</p>
<p>At Colorado, the Rockies achieved a host of offensive milestones as Andres Galarraga, Vinny Castilla and Steve Decker homered in a 12-3 rout of the San Francisco Giants.</p>
<p>Galarraga had three hits and three RBI for 150 RBI in the season, the most in the majors since Tommy Davis's 153 for the Dodgers in 1962. Galarraga's 47th homer tied George Bell and Juan Gonzalez for the most in one season by a Latin American.</p>
<p>Castillo's dinger made the Rockies the second team in major-league history with three 40-homer players, joining the 1973 Braves. It also was Colorado's 221st homer of the season, tying the N.L. mark achieved by the 1947 Giants and 1956 Reds.</p>
<p>Dante Bichette had two hits and drove in his 139rd and 140th runs for the Rockies, who boast the first teammates with at least 140 RBI in the same season since Walt Dropo and Vern Stephens had 144 apiece for the 1950 Red Sox.</p>
<p>Ellis Burks' first-inning double was his 45th, tying Charlie Hayes' team record.  He added a single in the fourth and finished with 392 total bases, the most since Hank Aaron had 400 for the Milwaukee Braves in 1959.</p>
<p>The crowd of 48,162 was the 132nd straight sellout for the Rockies, who led the majors in attendance for the fourth straight year with 3,891,014 fans at Coors Field.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Esteban Loaiza allowed one earned run over 7 2/3 innings and Dale Sveum and Keith Osik hit two-run homers as the Pittsburgh Pirates made Jim Leyland a winner in his final game as their manager with an 8-3 win over the Cubs.</p>
<p>In his 11 years in Pittsburgh, Leyland compiled an 849-860 record and won three straight division titles from 1990-92.</p>
<p>Leyland's name surfaced for other managerial jobs, mainly the Marlins, after he asked to be released from the final four years of a contract estimated to pay $1 million per season.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a couple of teams interested,&quot; Leyland said. &quot;I guess formally or officially teams will be able to talk to me tomorrow.</p>
<p>In Houston, Tony Eusebio's double with none out in the bottom of the 10th scored James Mouton with the winning run as the Astros edged the Marlins 5-4.</p>
<p>Florida (80-82) finished with the best record in franchise history, but failed in its bid for a .500 season.</p>
<p>Retiring Marlins outfielder Andre Dawson pinch hit in the sixth with runners on second and third and two out, but popped out. Dawson finished with 438 home runs and 1,591 RBI.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no regrets, it was a great career,&quot; said Dawson, the N.L. Most Valuable Player award in 1987.</p>
<p>In Montreal, Andy Stankiewicz and Yamil Benitez had two-run singles in the Expos' 6-3 win over the Atlanta Braves.</p>
<p>Atlanta's Tom Glavine tuned up for the playoffs by allowing one hit over three shutout innings to start the game.</p>
<p>In St Louis, Barry Larkin hit a pair of homers and drove in three runs and Hal Morris extended his hitting streak to 29 games, longest of the season, to lead the Cincinnati Reds to a 6-3 victory over the Cardinals.</p>
<p>In New York, Ricky Otero drove in a career-high five runs and David Doster had three RBI for the Philadelphia Phillies in a 9-5 victory over the Mets.</p>
<p>Lance Johnson of the Mets doubled in four at-bats and finished the year with a league-high 227 hits. He became the first player in baseball history to lead the National and American Leagues in hits in a season. Johnson paced the A.L. with 186 for the White Sox last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
