<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84354" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NETCOM CEO agrees with Q1'98 profit f'cast.</title>
<headline>NETCOM CEO agrees with Q1'98 profit f'cast.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>NETCOM On-Line Communication Services Inc's chief executive officer said he is comfortable with Wall Street expectations that U.S. operations will turn profitable during 1998's first quarter.</p>
<p>David Garrison, CEO, president and chairman of NETCOM, said that timeframe would be 13 quarters after the company went public. NETCOM is an Internet service provider, catering particularly to business users. It is the largest ISP in the United States. Garrison, speaking to the Montgomery Securities Investment Conference, did not include international operations because the company has just started globalizing.  </p>
<p>Earlier this year, NETCOM launched a globalization effort and now has operations in Canada, the United Kingdom and, as of today, Brazil. Launching these operations requires significant start up costs.</p>
<p>&quot;As you saw in our second quarter, global initiatives certainly do pressure margins,&quot; Garrison said in an interview when asked if NETCOM's margins would be pressured by the globalization efforts. But he said that, as a large Internet service provider addressing business users, global expansion makes good business sense because customers want Internet access from many places.  </p>
<p>Garrison did not comment on when consolidated operations would turn profitable. But he said other measures of success in his business are positive.</p>
<p>The number of NETCOM subscribers has doubled in the last year and analysts expect it to reach one million by year-end 1997, Garrison said, adding that he agrees with that forecast.</p>
<p>He said NETCOM's churn rate -- the percentage of new customers who quit the service before a year is up -- is &quot;significantly better&quot; at 55 percent than online services. Commercial online services are competitors.</p>
<p>Garrison said NETCOM's typical customer uses the Internet for business productivity. This type of customer, as opposed to people who want Internet access because they are curious about the Net, are willing to pay a higher price for Internet service and relieve the company of pricing pressure because they are more interested in customized service instead of lower prices. NETCOM charges $19.95 a month for Internet access and services.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
