<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84443" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Russia still seeks lower yields - finance minister.</title>
<headline>Russia still seeks lower yields - finance minister.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia will stick to its plans to cut interest rates, despite last week's spike in yields on its Treasury bills, Russian Finance Minister Alexander Livshits said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not change our policy, the policy of lowering yields,&quot; he told reporters outside a meeting of the International Monetary Fund's development committee.</p>
<p>Livshits said this was the only way to lower interest rates. &quot;Next year we are aiming for rates of 25-30 percent,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>At an auction of six-month GKO discount T-bills last week, yields spiked upwards to about 80 percent from the mid-60s.</p>
<p>Yields were steady on a three-month issue and dealers said a bank with close ties to the government had bought much of the issue.</p>
<p>Dealers said the government had paid the high yields on the six-month issue, in part to pay striking workers.</p>
<p>Russia eased access to its government securities market for non-residents in August in an effort to reduce yields.</p>
<p>The IMF would like the market to be further liberalised. The high yields are seen as crowding out investment.</p>
<p>But Russian officials, wary of what happened in Mexico, say they need some restrictions to be able to control the flow of funds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
