<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84555" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sylvan Learning adopts shareholder plan.</title>
<headline>Sylvan Learning adopts shareholder plan.</headline>
<dateline>COLUMBIA, Md.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sylvan Learning Systems Inc said on Monday it adopted a shareholder rights plan to protect the company's long-term interests in case of an unsolicited takeover attempt.</p>
<p>The plan would encourage potential buyers to negotiate with Sylvan's board of directors, giving the board the ability to achieve the best possible value for shareholders, it said.  </p>
<p>Under the plan, each common stock holder as of the close of business on October 7 would receive a distribution on November 7 of one right for each common share held.</p>
<p>Rights would become exercisable and would detach from the common stock a specified period of time after any person became a beneficial owner of 15 percent or more or Sylvan's common stock, or began a tender or exchange offer to become a beneficial owner of 15 percent or more, Sylvan said.  </p>
<p>The existing holdings of R. William Pollock and additional common stock issued to him in connection with Sylvan's purchase of Drake Prometric LP in December 1995 were exempt, the company said.</p>
<p>Pollock beneficially owned more than 15 percent of the common stock on September 27, the company said.</p>
<p>Once exercisable, each right would entitle the holder to buy one hundreth of one share of Series A Junior Participating Preferred Stock for an additional purchase price of $157 per share, after adjustment for Sylan's three-for-two stock split, the company said.  </p>
<p>Sylvan said the plan was not adopted in reponse to any present effort to buy it or its securities.</p>
<p>The company said it could redeem the rights at a price of $0.05 per right at any time prior to a specified period after a person had become the beneficial owner of 15 percent or more of its common stock.</p>
<p>The rights would expire on November 7, 2006, the company said.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBIA, Md."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
