<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84602" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products mixed, gas oil strongest.</title>
<headline>Med oil products mixed, gas oil strongest.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were mixed on Monday, with gas oil still the market leader.</p>
<p>Gasoline prices were easy despite early gains gains in NWE. Traders said supplies at most refineries were still fairly lengthy and some refiners were looking at arbitrage options.</p>
<p>Outright values for premium unleaded were pegged around $207.50 a tonne cif Lavera.</p>
<p>Naphtha stayed firm with few cargoes on offer and petrochemical demand remaining healthy. Traders said there were some full range cargoes available but these were unable to meet petrochemical users requirements for high paraffinic grades.  </p>
<p>Values for paraffinic grades were pegged steady around quotes cif high +$4.50 cif Lavera. Gas oil was stronger in line with futures and a tight physical market.</p>
<p>Italian refiners were sold out of low sulphur diesel for the first half of October, and said spot avails later in the month look set to be snapped up by a Belgian refiner looking for third decade product into the south of France.</p>
<p>Diesel was pegged at quotes high +$2/$$2.50 fob Sicily.  </p>
<p>Despite the Oct 1 deadline for the introduction of 0.05 percent sulphur diesel across the EU, Portugal's Petrogal was in the market looking for 0.2 percent automotive diesel, having obtained a waiver until March 1997, traders said.</p>
<p>A Greek trader said Greece had also won a deferral until January next year.</p>
<p>Several prompt Russian cargoes were on offer, but demand for early October material was limited after a trader supplying Greece picked up a cargo on Friday at $1.50 over Oct IPE.</p>
<p>Fuel oil prices were little changed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
