<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84708" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: U.S. envoy to Burundi holds talks with Buyoya.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy to Burundi holds talks with Buyoya.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's military leader, battling a Hutu rebellion and economic sanctions, held talks with a U.S. presidential envoy on Monday but both sides refused any public comment.</p>
<p>&quot;I am here as part of an effort to advance the peace process,&quot; was all that U.S. envoy Howard Wolpe told reporters after 2-1/2 hours of discussion with Major Pierre Buyoya, president since the Tutsi-dominated army's takeover on July 25.</p>
<p>Buyoya's spokesman Jean-Luc Ndizeye said the presidency had no comment.</p>
<p>Wolpe is visiting African countries which imposed a complete trade and transport embargo on landlocked Burundi on July 31, in protest against the coup and to pressure the army to accept negotiations with Hutu rebels led by Leonard Nyangoma.</p>
<p>On Sunday Ndizeye linked Wolpe's visit to the first African tour starting next week by outgoing U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher, who will meet some of the key pro-sanctions African presidents in Arusha, Tanzania, on October 11.</p>
<p>A regional summit on Burundi is planned for October 12 in Arusha. African diplomatic sources said the Americans may hope to arrange a breakthrough meeting between Buyoya and Nyangoma, with Christopher in attendance and the U.S. taking much of the credit, during that summit.</p>
<p>Wolpe said nothing in Bujumbura on Monday to confirm the speculation but was meeting other political and civic figures here this week.</p>
<p>Ndizeye said on Sunday the military regime expected Wolpe to insist on immediate talks with Nyangoma, whose Forces for the Defence of Democracy (FDD) is the largest armed Hutu faction.</p>
<p>&quot;But we can't do that. Buyoya can't just go and shake Nyangoma's hand tomorrow,&quot; Ndizeye said.</p>
<p>Yet the pressure to make peace with Nyangoma is building up. Hutus are 85 percent of Burundi's six million population and there is broad support for the rebels, described as &quot;terrorists&quot; by the army.</p>
<p>Large parts of the country are no-go areas. Main roads are potential death-traps from ambushes against soldiers and Tutsis, leading to heavy reprisals by the army.</p>
<p>The regional trade embargo has blocked coffee and tea exports and driven up the price of oil and basic goods. Prices of some foods have doubled in the past two months.</p>
<p>An army spokesman confirmed on Monday a series of clashes in the past week in Muramvya province, east of Bujumbura.</p>
<p>He told reporters two soldiers were killed and five, including the Muramvya brigade commander, were wounded in the attacks. The spokesman put rebel losses at least 10 and said at least three civilians died. Reports by witnesses to the violence put the civilian death toll far higher.</p>
<p>Some foreign relief organisations oppose the sanctions saying ordinary civilians are the main victims. So far the regional sanctions committee has made only sparing exemptions on humanitarian imports.</p>
<p>The World Food Programme (WFP) said on Monday it had approval for the first time to import fuel from neighbouring Rwanda. Jean-Luc Siblot, head of the WFP in Burundi, said the planned imports of 150,000 litres of diesel and 65,000 litres of petrol would be shared between aid agencies.</p>
<p>About 150,000 people have been killed in the past three years of ethnic war in Burundi. There is no accurate figure for current losses because insecurity in the tiny country of six million people prevents aid workers from moving freely.</p>
<p>Wolpe was appointed by President Bill Clinton before the coup, to underline U.S. concern over Burundi's dangerous drift, two years after the genocide of up to one million people in Rwanda.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
