<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84845" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary struck depository deal with Cedel Bank.</title>
<headline>Hungary struck depository deal with Cedel Bank.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's central clearing and depositary house Keler Rt signed a depository agreement with the Luxembourg-based international clearing and settlement bank Cedel Bank, the partners said on Monday.</p>
<p>Hungarian beneficiaries of the agreement, including the Budapest Stock Exchange, expect increased investments here as a result of the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;The access to the Hungarian securities market via Cedel Bank in itself raises the status of the market and separates it from those of other emerging markets,&quot; Keler's General Manager Peter Basch told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result (of the deal) we expect substantial portfolio investments to appear on the Hungarian market,&quot; Basch said.</p>
<p>This link, which goes into effect from October 7, will allow Cedel Bank clients to settle their Hungarian securities transactions through the direct Cedel Bank-Keler connection, Keler said in a statement.</p>
<p>The agreement also includes ING Bank, which acts as cash correspondent bank.</p>
<p>Keler, which officially became national depository in July 1995, was rated an eligible depository last December under the U.S. Investment Company Act.</p>
<p>Keler opened an account with Cedel Bank in June this year to take advantage of new investment opportunities offered when Hungary became a member of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) in March, it said.</p>
<p>The arrangement enables Hungarian investors to settle their foreign securities transactions via Keler as well as to exercise their relevant rights, obtain cash proceeds and other investment entitlements, it said.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
