<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="84928" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico peso closes firm as dealers dump dollars.</title>
<headline>Mexico peso closes firm as dealers dump dollars.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mexican peso reversed early weakness to close firm after dealers dumped surplus dollar positions in late trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market had its ups and downs. At first the peso was under pressure, apparently from demand to close end-of-month dollar positions,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Then in late trade dealers stepped in to sell surplus dollars,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The benchmark 48-hour peso and its 24-hour counterpart closed 0.3 and 0.1 of a centavo firmer, respectively, at 7.5380/7.5410 and 7.5330/7.5380 per dollar.</p>
<p>Several traders agreed that early demand for dollars was actually due more to speculation than to cover end-of-month and -quarter positions.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel that what happened was that a bank tried to put pressure on the dollar by speculating in early trade,&quot; a trader said. &quot;Then they were left holding dollars they had to sell.&quot;</p>
<p>The same-day peso earlier closed 2.25 centavos weaker at 7.5445/7.5480 per dollar.</p>
<p>Traders said the peso might be weakened on Tuesday if the market expected primary interest rates to rise.</p>
<p>-- Alexis Quinones, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9555</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
