<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85110" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan protests to Haiti in row over China.</title>
<headline>Taiwan protests to Haiti in row over China.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan on Monday protested to Haiti against a recent agreement between the Caribbean nation and China to exchange trade offices, worrying that it may lose one of its 30 diplomatic allies to Beijing.</p>
<p>Vice Foreign Minister Cheng Chien-jen summoned Haiti's ambassador in Taipei, Sonny Seraphin, on Monday morning to express the island's dissatisfaction and concerns over the agreement, state-funded television reported.</p>
<p>Seraphin said on television after meeting Cheng that Haiti was committed to the &quot;long tradition of a very friendly relationship&quot; with Taiwan despite the agreement.</p>
<p>Taiwan has promised to give Haiti hundreds of garbage vans and police vehicles in the latest move to maintain ties when Foreign Minister John Chang visited in August.</p>
<p>Beijing has regarded Taiwan as a renegade province since the Chinese civil war split them in 1949, and tries to isolate the island. Only 30 countries, mainly in Africa and central America, recognise the Republic of China government in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Beijing won the latest diplomatic battle in August, winning Niger back four years after the African state turned to Taiwan from China.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
