<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85122" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong gold end down on European sales.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong gold end down on European sales.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong bullion edged down on Monday from its New York close on European sell orders, but activity was paralysed by a severe attack of bearishness, gold dealers and traders said.</p>
<p>Bullion prices dipped slightly on professional selling and European sell orders on precious metals, gold traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Turnover was very small,&quot; a bullion trader at a European bank said, noting that there had been some two-way professional business.</p>
<p>The market felt resistance at US$380.60 and strong support at about US$379.90, and gold sources noted that intra-day trade had been marked by low bids and high offers.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a generally bad feeling in the market,&quot; a gold trader at an international bullion house's local office said.</p>
<p>Bullion ended at US$379.95/380.45 an ounce Monday against New York's US$380.15/65 close on Friday.</p>
<p>Local gold ended HK$7 lower at HK$3,503 a tael.</p>
<p>The carry over charge at the Chinese Gold and Silver Exchange fell to -6 from -5.5 on Friday.</p>
<p>While physical demand was normally healthy at current price levels, an overall bearish sentiment had pushed buyers to the sidelines in anticipation of a further price drop, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Players don't want to sell at this level, they don't want to buy either, which is why the market is stuck in the doldrums,&quot; a source at an international bank's Hong Kong office said.</p>
<p>Other gold traders said that the physical market had been largely saturated at the US$382 level, but that buying could resume if prices ducked even lower.</p>
<p>The premium on gold bars were still hovering around 55-60 U.S cents, sources said.</p>
<p>BULLION -</p>
<p> Hong Kong midday - US$380.30/80</p>
<p> Hong Kong open   - US$380.30/80</p>
<p> Hong Kong close  - US$379.95/380.45</p>
<p> New York close   - US$380.15/65</p>
<p>HONG KONG TAEL MARKET -</p>
<p> Midday	     - HK$3,505</p>
<p> Open		 - HK$3,505</p>
<p> Close		- HK$3,503</p>
<p> Previous close   - HK$3,510</p>
<p>-- Mishi Saran (852) 2843 6358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
