<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85133" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Future of Burma opposition movement in question.</title>
<headline>Future of Burma opposition movement in question.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Charles</byline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The future of Burma's democracy movement, hit by a new wave of arrests and repressive tactics by the military regime, is more uncertain than ever as activists await the government's next move, diplomats said on Monday.</p>
<p>The National League for Democracy (NLD), led by Nobel Peace laureate Aung San Suu Kyi, and the ruling State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) are playing a tense waiting game, the diplomats said.</p>
<p>&quot;They've been winding each other up now for years,&quot; one diplomat said. &quot;It's an end game now.&quot;</p>
<p>They said the SLORC, which seized power in 1988, must now decide if it will take further action against the NLD, perhaps by banning the party's vital weekend speeches or possibly by outlawing the party.</p>
<p>&quot;We're waiting to see how it will play out. Will they just let everything go back to status quo or will another shoe drop?&quot; a diplomat said. &quot;Will they say they are banning the party or closing off her house? I won't be surprised at anything now.&quot;</p>
<p>Most diplomats said they had not expected such a strong reaction by the SLORC to the NLD's plans to hold a three-day party congress September 27-30.</p>
<p>To prevent the meeting from taking place, the government said it detained 109 NLD members for questioning. It said the meeting was illegal and threatened the nation's stability.</p>
<p>NLD sources said about 500 party members or supporters had been arrested since Thursday. It said the party had called the meeting to celebrate its eighth anniversary.</p>
<p>&quot;It should not be necessary for a political party to seek permission from the authorities to carry out its legitimate activities,&quot; the NLD said in a statement received on Monday.</p>
<p>The SLORC also set up police-manned checkpoints on all roads leading to Suu Kyi's University Avenue home, where the meeting was due to take place, and prohibited any one from travelling on the road since early on Friday morning.</p>
<p>Officers arrested up to 100 democracy supporters on Saturday who refused to move away from the blockades as ordered, NLD sources said. The official would not say how many had been put into trucks but said they all had been released.</p>
<p>Although police had said the blockades were due only to be up through Sunday, they remained in place on Monday with armed police still preventing anyone from passing through.</p>
<p>The government also suggested in official media that it might ban the NLD's weekend speeches. The speeches, given by Suu Kyi and two other top NLD officials on Saturdays and Sundays, are the only real way for the party to get its word out.</p>
<p>In a sweeping law seen aimed at the NLD, the SLORC in June banned any individual or organisation from saying or publishing anything seen as destabilising or contrary to the government.</p>
<p>The speeches, which are often taped by listeners and then transcribed and distributed throughout the country, are often the only way NLD supporters can hear from their leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;If they ban the speeches, it will be a big blow to the NLD,&quot; one local analyst noted.</p>
<p>NLD officials said they did not expect the SLORC to allow the speeches to continue, and many diplomats agreed.</p>
<p>But how far the repression might be taken was anyone's guess, the diplomats said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think either side wants bloodshed,&quot; one said. &quot;But it's a very volatile situation.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Unless reason prevails (Suu Kyi) may try her hardest to really push them to arrest her. That would give her a martyr status,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Most analysts and diplomats say the SLORC was likely to be very hesitant to re-arrest Suu Kyi, who was released from six years of house arrest in July, 1995.</p>
<p>Many nations have warned against escalating the repression. The United States is discussing a sanctions bill that could be enacted if the situation worsens or if Suu Kyi is re-arrested.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
