<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85164" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr closes off in US after setting 32-mth yen high.</title>
<headline>Dlr closes off in US after setting 32-mth yen high.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar closed lower versus the mark and backed off a 32-month high set against the yen after comments by Japanese finance officials drove Japanese investors from the yen.</p>
<p>The dollar reached a high of 111.68 yen but was capped by profit taking and U.S. fund selling betweem 111.60 and 111.70, said Jeffrey Yu, senior dealer at Sanwa Bank.</p>
<p>Japanesee investors started the run on yen after weak Japanese industrial production data reinforced comments over the weekend from Senior Japanese finance officials, who said Japanese interest rates should stay low.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of it was (Japanese) investment houses and institutional investors trying to invest overseas with higher yields,&quot; Yu said. &quot;That is what the main push from Japan was.&quot;</p>
<p>In U.S. trade, the dollar closed at 111.38/43 yen, down from 111.50/60 at the open and at 1.5246/51 marks, down from 1.5272/77.</p>
<p>Japan's Finance Minister Waturu Kubo, said over the weekend that he sees the Bank of Japan (BOJ) keeping its easy monetary stance to ensure gradual economic recovery.</p>
<p>In addition, BOJ Governor Yasuo Matsushita said the recent decline in long-term Japanese interest rates may reflect changes in sentiment towards Japan's economic prospects.</p>
<p>The Japanese officials were attending a meeting of finance ministers and central bankers from the Group of Seven (G7) major industrial nations in Washington over the weekend.</p>
<p>Officials at the G7 gathering avoided most comments on the dollar but remained upbeat. Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer said all G7 countries were interested in a strong dollar while U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin reiterated his support for a strong dollar again on Monday.</p>
<p>But the remarks from Kubo and Matsushita were given added weight on Monday by data showing Japan's industrial activity fell 1.9 percent in August.</p>
<p>The yen slid slid broadly on Monday, reaching its lowest level versus the pound since May 1993 and also retreating against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;Mark/yen is staying bid, that is actually what is keeping things going a little bit,&quot; said Richard Vullo, vice president at HypoBank, in New York. &quot;That is kind of keeping dollar/mark from going.&quot;</p>
<p>Japanese interest rates are the lowest of any major nation, prompting Japanese investors to shed yen-denominated assets more actively than their non-Japanese counterparts shed assest of countries like Germany.</p>
<p>This has given the dollar more of a lift against the yen than the mark, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just nominal yields,&quot; said Mark Gargano, foreign exchange manager at First Union National Bank. &quot;You've got 0.50 percent (depost rates) in Japan and you've got 3.0 percent in Germany.&quot;</p>
<p>Moreover, the yen may have recieved an extra shove amid speculation that capital will flow out of Japan more freely in the second half of the Japanese fiscal year, which starts Tuesday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Customers from Tokyo just had to buy dollars after the old fiscal half-year,&quot; said Yu.</p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar fell to 1.2540/50 Swiss francs from 1.2560/70 at the open and to Canadian $1.3617/22 from C$1.3625/30.</p>
<p>The pound rose to $1.5650/60 from $1.5615/25 and the Australian dollar closed at $0.7912/17, down from $0.7927/32.</p>
<p>-- Alden Bentley 212 859 1667</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
