<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85416" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Yankee flurries seen for U.S corporate bond market.</title>
<headline>Yankee flurries seen for U.S corporate bond market.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A flurry of activity is expected to hit the corporate bond new issue market with dealers reporting a slew of yankee debt offerings lining up to tap the market.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing a lot of names come to market,&quot; said one syndicate source. &quot;The pace is definitely picking up...a lot of yankee issuers are expected to tap the market near-term.&quot;</p>
<p>The recent dip in U.S. Treasury yields should continue to spur the corporate bond new issue market as corporations capitalize on lower interest rates to finance debt, dealers added.  </p>
<p>The following issues are expected to come to market, syndicate sources said.</p>
<p>Union Pacific Resources is expected to price $400 million in A3/A-rated two-part debt consisting of $200 million in 10-year debt and $200 million of 30-year debt.</p>
<p>Loewen Group is expected to price $350 million in a two-part senior guaranteed notes deal consisting of $175 million five-year debt and $175 million seven-year debt via Smith Barney.</p>
<p>Medpartners is also expected to tap the market with $300 million in Baa3/BBB-rated 10-year debt also via Smith Barney.  </p>
<p>Conagra is expected to issue $400 million in two-part debt via Smith Barney. The deal is expected to consist of a 30-year bullet and a 30-year with a 10-year put option.</p>
<p>In yankee issues, $1.0 billion in two-part debt is expected to come to market out of Petronas. The deal consist of $500 million each in five and 10-year debt.</p>
<p>Brazil is expected to price $750 million in global debt in a five or ten-year maturity via Chase Securites.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is extremely interested in this because Brazil is such a rare Euromarket borrower,&quot; said one syndicate manager.  </p>
<p>Another $750 million out of Argentina in 10-year global debt is seen being issued soon via Goldman Sachs and Salomon Bros.</p>
<p>Banco Nationale de Paris is also seen tapping the market with $350 million in 10-year subordinated yankee debt out of Salomon Brothers in early October.</p>
<p>Norsk Hydro is expected to tap the market with $250 million in 20-year debt via Morgan Stanley.</p>
<p>Banco Santander is expected to price $150 million in 10-year subordinated yankee notes.</p>
<p>In addition, South Africa is gearing up to launch its first yankee issue ever via Merrill Lynch, sources added.  </p>
<p>The South Africa deal is expected to consist of $250 to $300 million of a 10-year maturity.</p>
<p>In other issues, Unisys Corp is expected to price $250 million in eight-year senior notes via Bear Stearns.</p>
<p>Boyd Gaming Corp is expected to price $200 million in seven-year notes via Salomon Brothers. Price talk on the issue is 250 to 275 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>Frontiervision is expected to price $200 million in senior subordinated notes due 2006 via JP Morgan Securities.</p>
<p>Among private placements, Uniforet Inc, RSL Communications and Genesis Health Ventures are all expected to issue 144A debt.</p>
<p>In the government market, the 30-year U.S. Treasury bond is trading off 10/32 at 97-23/32 to yield 6.93 percent.</p>
<p>--Nancy Leinfuss, 212-859-1675</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
