<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85490" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Canadian judge steps up to tribunal hot seat.</title>
<headline>Canadian judge steps up to tribunal hot seat.</headline>
<byline>Ian Geoghegan</byline>
<dateline>THE HAGUE 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian judge Louise Arbour moves into the judicial big league on Tuesday, heading up a United Nations mission to bring to justice those responsible for genocide and massacre in the former Yugoslavia and Rwanda.</p>
<p>Appointed by the U.N. Security Council for a four-year term as Chief Prosecutor at the Hague-based criminal tribunal for the former Yugoslavia, Arbour also takes on the job of getting the faltering Rwandan tribunal up and running.</p>
<p>Arbour sees the Yugoslav tribunal, the first international body for the prosecution of war crimes since the Nuremberg and Tokyo trials after World War II, as &quot;the most important chapter in the history of criminal and international humanitarian law.&quot;</p>
<p>She is reported to relish the prospect of establishing the tribunal's unique international criminal law, drawn from several national codes and enshrined in U.N. statute.</p>
<p>&quot;My greatest aspiration is to be part of laying the foundation for a permanent international criminal court, to show these tribunals can produce the kind of quality we expect from a model domestic system,&quot; she said recently.</p>
<p>Both the Yugoslav and Rwandan tribunals are pressing ahead with their work but face serious obstacles -- budgetary restraint, lack of cooperation and minimal encouragement from the international community that established them.</p>
<p>Acutely aware of mounting frustration at delays in arresting indicted war criminals, Arbour promises tougher action.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no single issue more important to the survival of this tribunal...than the actual arrest of indicted war criminals. That will be my very top priority,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She likens the prosecution of war criminals to a long-term investment, where initial saving is painful, but where there is faith in the long-term pay-off.</p>
<p>&quot;There cannot be any real suggestion that we should abandon -- just because it's too painful -- the long-term benefit of reaffirming our moral values...deterrence, rehabilitation, reconciliation, that is brought about by a society that stands firm against crime.</p>
<p>&quot;We must resist a tendency to shrug the shoulders and have an amnesty. I will be there encouraging that we not do that.&quot;</p>
<p>The Yugoslav tribunal, set up by the U.N. in 1993, has indicted over 70 Serbs, Croats and Moslems suspected of war crimes during the Bosnian conflict. Only seven are in custody.</p>
<p>&quot;I have a four-year term. I am very keen..very aggressive. We have indicted many people with the most serious crimes. I intend to bring every single one of them to trial,&quot; she says.</p>
<p>While the Hague court began its first trial -- of Bosnian Serb Dusan Tadic -- in May, its Rwandan sister, investigating alleged genocide during the 1994 civil strife that left up to one million minority Tutsis and moderate Hutus dead, decided last week it was not yet ready to go to trial.</p>
<p>Arbour moves to the Netherlands after five years on the Ontario Court of Appeal, before which she sat on the Ontario Supreme Court and taught law at Toronto's York University.</p>
<p>A bi-lingual native of Montreal, Arbour recently presided over a federal commission which decreed that male guards were wrong to have strip-searched a group of rioting female prisoners at Kingston Womens' Prison in Ontario in 1994.</p>
<p>Touted as one of Canada's leading judges of the future, Arbour, a past vice-president of the Canadian Civil Liberties Association, has campaigned for voting rights for prisoners and has a reputation for humanitarianism.</p>
<p>The Canadian press holds her in some reverence, quoting her friends as saying that &quot;there's not very much - nothing at all, really - that can be said in criticism of her&quot;. She has &quot;a reputation for efficiency, pragmatism and candour&quot;.</p>
<p>Born 49 years ago to parents with a modest hotel chain, Arbour attended convent school in Quebec during which time her parents divorced. As editor of the school magazine, she also earned a reputation for irreverence.</p>
<p>She has published extensively on criminal procedure, human rights and civil liberties in both English and French. She and partner Larry Taman, Ontario's deputy attorney-general, have three teenage children.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE HAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
