<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85539" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - September 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - September 30.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for Reuters by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi. Tel:3326806, 3326813, 3326849  Fax:+91-11-3351006 E-mail:</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>Indian Express</p>
<p>FORMER PRIME MINISTER KEEPING HIS FINGERS CROSSED</p>
<p>Former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao is keeping his fingers crossed and hoping for the best in the next hearing in Lakhubhai Pathak cheating case. Today he appears before special Central Bureau Investigation judge in the Lakhubhai case. On Sunday, Prime Minister Deve Gowda called on the former Congress party leader to give him moral support.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>CASHLESS OPERATIONS PUT CORPORATES IN A BIND</p>
<p>A substantial decline in cash generation by companies last year accounts for this year's slow down in corporate growth. A study shows cash generated from operations by some top corporates fell by almost half in 1996 compared to the previous year. Even as turnover and profits grew by over 25 percent, the cash tap dried up leading to a crunch in the first half of this year. Analysis shows this shortfall in cash was caused by piling up of inventories and receivables of companies.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>CREDIT POLICY TO COME DOWN ON EXPORTERS, IMPORTERS</p>
<p>The new credit policy may penalise exporters and importers who fail to comply with procedural norms laid down by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI). It plans to slap a penal rate of six to eight percent above the normal 18 percent interest rate on those failing to submit their bills of entry within 30 days of remittance. RBI also plans not to grant exporters any extensions if they do not bring foreign exchange into the country within 90 days of actual export taking place. RBI is considering a two percent rebate on post shipment credit to exporters bringing in foreign exchange within stipulated time.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>FRESH COAL MINING NORMS DEMANDED</p>
<p>Multinational companies have refused to invest in the coal mining sector until the Coal Mining Act is amended. During talks with the Prime Minister's Office, a consortium of Australian companies demanded permission to make aerial surveys of an indentified state. They also argued in favour of a blanket permission to mine whatever mineral they discovered in the state. The mines department agreed to amend the Mining Act, but refused to accept other conditions.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>SHIPPING CORPORATION SHELVES GDR ISSUE</p>
<p>Shipping Corporation of India (SCI) postponed its plans for a global depositary receipt (GDR) issue. It would go in for a $50 million external commercial borrowing (ECB) instead as part of its fund raising exercise for fleet expansion. SCI has already applied to the Finance Ministry for the necessary approvals. SCI decided to keep its GDR on hold until such time as the company was able to optimise on its debt equity at 1.75:1 in the international market, company officials said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>INDIA-SPECIFIC RANKING SYSTEM FOR BANKS LIKEY</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) is formulating a new ranking system for commercial banks suitable for Indian conditions. Banking circles said RBI planned to introduce the confidential ranking system in the industry during the present fiscal year as per the Padmanabhan committee recommendations. The committee had suggested the implementation of the Camels system, the globally accepted ranking mechanism to banks operating in India. The key parameters under this are capital adequacy, asset quality, management quality, earnings, liquidity position and systems and procedures.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>INDIAN OIL PLANS 50 BLN RUPEE REFINERY VENTURE</p>
<p>Indian Oil Corp (IOC) is proposing to erect a six million tonnes per annum Export Oriented Unit (EOU) refinery in the South. The 50 billion rupee project is to be set up in joint venture with Madras Refineries Ltd. However, IOC's proposal may run into problems as the Oil Ministry feels IOC's plans to put up a new EOU refinery may not be economically viable. IOC is planning a joint venture partner for its LPG facility at Haldia. Sources say Petronas with whom IOC has a tie up in place is a strong contender.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>INFLATION RISES FURTHER TO 6.25 PERCENT</p>
<p>Maintaining its unabated rise for the sixth consecutive week, the annual rate of inflation gained 0.23 percentage point to touch a 37-week high of 6.25 percent for week ending September 14. The sharp increase is attributed to a rise in international petroleum prices. The inflation rate was placed at 8.6 percent during the corresponding period of the previous year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>SELLING PRESSURE SENDS BANK SHARES CRASHING</p>
<p>Bank scrips lost value steadily on the Bombay bourse over the previous month even as domestic state-owned banks prepared to raise around 30 billion rupees collectively from the primary market early next year. The trend intensified with medium-sized bank shares facing selling pressure in the last few trading sessions. Even State Bank of India, the one to be least affected because of its large market captalisation, saw intense selling pressure for more than a week.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>SHARES SLUMP ON SELLING PRESSURE, POLITCAL UNCERTAINTY</p>
<p>Speculatives suffered sharp losses pushing the bourse index below the crucial 3,300-point support level in the last week. The market witnessed narrow movements and registered low volume of business with little support coming from Foreign Instituional Investors and domestic Institutional Investors. The operators' unwillingness to enter into fresh commitments saw scrips fall under heavy selling pressure and record sharp to moderate falls at the close of the week.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer</p>
<p>LIQUIDITY CRUNCH LOOMS LARGE OVER CORPORATES</p>
<p>Top corporates are reportedly planning to cut down their production. This is being planned in view of poor output to sale ratio and subsequent high inventory built up during the first quarter of the current fiscal. Industry sources say, most of the companies did not sell even half of what they produced between April and August this year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>ENGINEERING EXPORTS TO TOUCH 150 BLN RUPEES</p>
<p>Engineering exports in the current financial year are expected to go up to 150 billion rupees, Engineering Export Promotion Council past president and senior member M.C. Shah said. He said engineering exports had gone up substantially from a meagre 50 million rupees in 1995 through the conscious efforts of both the industry and the government. He, however, regretted that of late the industry's problems were not viewed in right earnest by official circles and was skeptical about the targetted exports of $10 billion by the year 2001.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>GOVERNMENT FIRM ON LOWERING RATES</p>
<p>The central bank is in talks with banks to bring down nominal interest rates in view of the sharp deceleration in inflation. The government, on its part, would ensure that inflationary expectations are dampened, thus easing real interest rates, the Finance Minister said. RBI along with the Finance Ministry has decided to ask banks to lower interest rates. Real interest rates had soared with inflation sharply coming down.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
