<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85546" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian state renames Madras as Chennai.</title>
<headline>Indian state renames Madras as Chennai.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's southern state of Tamil Nadu has changed the name of its capital city from Madras to Chennai with effect from Monday, the United News of India (UNI) said.</p>
<p>The city gave up its name acquired during British colonial rule to return to an ancient title through a bill passed by the state assembly last month.</p>
<p>Many Tamil scholars say that Madras, which is located on the Bay of Bengal coast, was earlier called Chennapatnam, or Chennai for short, after an ancient regional ruler, Chennappa Naicker.</p>
<p>Some historians say Madras was named after a Portuguese family called Madeiros. Others say the area was named &quot;Madarsa,&quot; or an Islamic school, in an area where Moslem traders used to live, and later came to be called Madras.</p>
<p>The renaming of the city was carried out by a new government of the regional Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam party, which came to power after elections in May this year. The party leans heavily on ethnic Tamil sentiments for political support.</p>
<p>Last year, the Shiv Sena party which came to power in the western state of Maharashtra renamed Bombay, the nation's financial capital, and now calls it by its old name, Mumbai.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
