<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85548" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Taleban asks Afghan warlord to make way.</title>
<headline>Taleban asks Afghan warlord to make way.</headline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Afghanistan's Taleban Islamic militia on Monday asked the forces of northern warlord General Abdul Rashid Dostum to allow its fighters passage into the north, but the demand was rejected, a Taleban commander said.</p>
<p>A United Nations official visiting the area urged the Taleban to go to Dostum's people in friendship rather than war after the general's forces advanced to about three km (two miles) from those of Taleban, reporters visting the area said.  </p>
<p>It was not immediately clear whether the Taleban, who conquered the capital Kabul on Friday, wanted the passage through the famous Salang Highway to attack some northern provinces still held by forces loyal to ousted president Burhanuddin Rabbani or wanted to capture Dostum's territory.</p>
<p>Dostum has so far stayed away from the fighting between Taleban and the former Kabul government, which he also opposed. In recent months, Rabbani has been trying to strike an alliance with Dostum while Taleban also said after taking Kabul that it wanted to settle important matters with him through talks.</p>
<p>Dostum's forces advanced several km (miles) south of the Salang tunnel on Monday as the Taleban asked for the passage, witnesses said. Villagers in the area packed goods on trucks and buses and left northwards fearing a confrontation between the two forces.</p>
<p>A Taleban commander, Mullah Ghulam Mohammad, told reporters the Taleban had asked Dostum's forces to make way for them, but the request had been rejected. &quot;We told them to let the Taleban cross because Dostum does not represent the north,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
