<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85668" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reader's Digest to face Yahoo! on Internet.</title>
<headline>Reader's Digest to face Yahoo! on Internet.</headline>
<byline>Michael Connor</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The publisher of Reader's Digest on Tuesday will announce an Internet search service meant to tidy up the unruly World Wide Web and make it presentable for millions of mainstream consumers.</p>
<p>Readers Digest Association Inc. executives said the LookSmart search service will rank and sort some 85,000 Web sites more sensibly than such rivals as Yahoo! Inc. and Infoseek.</p>
<p>LookSmart and a companion Web site dubbed Reader's Digest World will be promoted in the company's magazines -- including the monthly Reader's Digest with some 27 million subscribers -- online and in the 500 million pieces of mail it dispatches each year to potential buyers of Reader's Digest videos, recordings and books.</p>
<p>Both Web services will be launched Oct. 28.</p>
<p>Reader's Digest also wants joint marketing ventures for LookSmart, similar to ones Reader's Digest has in place with cosmetics giant Avon Products Inc. and Meredith Corp., publisher of Better Homes and Gardens and other lifestyle magazines, Sarah Hamman, director of the company's new media projects, said during an interview.</p>
<p>She declined to discuss specifics of possible deals.</p>
<p>Like Reader's Digest magazine, founded more than 70 years ago, does with magazines, newspapers and books, LookSmart will cull and evaluate sites from the hundreds of thousands on the World Wide Web and simplify reaching the best, LookSmart President Evan Thornley said.</p>
<p>&quot;What most users want most of the time is organisation of the (sites) into categories,&quot; he said. &quot;The people with jobs and mortgages ... that's the majority of people. They want a Web that helps meet their needs.&quot;</p>
<p>LookSmart, a majority-owned subsidiary of Reader's Digest Association, expects advertising to provide nearly all its revenues. Technology companies would be the first sponsors, eventually to be followed by consumer-brand companies as the Internet becomes a mass medium, Thornley said.</p>
<p>Unlike other search engines, or online catologs of Web sites, LookSmart's displays will fill only one full computer screen and will need no scrolling. Advertisements will be fixed on the bottom one-eighth of the user's screen, Thornley said.</p>
<p>LookSmart's revenues are likely to match or exceed those of similar search engines, which run at about a $10 million annual pace, Thornley said.</p>
<p>Hamman said LookSmart would provide Reader's Digest, whose biggest businesses are selling books and other entertainment by mail, with a new sales outlet.</p>
<p>&quot;This gives us another gateway to customers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The company's second site, Reader's Digest World, will contain material from Reader's Digest magazine, information from the company's special-interest and improvement books, and an electronic outlet for buying any of some 300 products Reader's Digest will offer online.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
