<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="85916" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - UK credit data show consumers spending fast.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - UK credit data show consumers spending fast.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Solid money supply growth and a higher than expected leap in consumer credit showed British spending on the high street continues unabated, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Consumer credit leapt a net 997 million pounds ($1.56 billion) in August. Economists had forecast a jump of around 870 million.</p>
<p>Coupled with July's increase of 1.053 billion pounds, the second highest on record, the figures show consumer spending is speeding up and suggests the case for further interest rate cuts has all but disappeared, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;To sustain July's increase in credit suggests there has been a change up in gear in consumer credit,&quot; said John Shepperd, chief economist at Yamaichi International. &quot;The take-off in the consumer sector is really under way.&quot;</p>
<p>The increase in borrowing suggested August's sharp increase in retail sales was not one-off, he said. British retail sales leapt 1.0 percent in August and 4.4 percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>UK M0 money supply data, released at the same time as the credit figures, showed 7.0 percent year-on-year growth in the amount of notes and coins circulating the economy in September.</p>
<p>That is below August's 7.4 percent rise but high compared with a government monitoring range of one to four percent and hardly signals a slowdown in economic activity, analysts said.</p>
<p>Ciaran Barr, UK economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, said the drop in M0 was largely due to a fall in bankers' operational deposits. Underlying growth in notes in circulation remained firm, he said. &quot;The consumer sector is looking a lot happier.&quot;</p>
<p>Barr said low interest rates -- base rates have been cut four times since December, taking them to 5.75 percent -- meant personal sector loans were unusually cheap.</p>
<p>A robust recovery in the housing market meant spending on expensive household goods like washing machines was rising, much of it thanks to low interest or interest-free credit deals.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a return to the sort of credit culture of the late 1980s although it won't go that far,&quot; Barr said.</p>
<p>Senior BankAmerica economic adviser Jeremy Hawkins said the data could douse lingering hopes that interest rates could fall again. &quot;The data are stronger than expected and should further undermine hopes that base rates may be cut one more time,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Barr said interest rates could rise early in 1997, before elections due by May next year. &quot;The recovering economy will demand it by then,&quot; he said. &quot;But if it comes, it will only be a small increase.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Britain's ruling Conservatives would fight the election on the basis that they will run the economy better than the opposition Labour Party.</p>
<p>In that case, economic prudence may be more effective than tax and interest rate sweeteners.</p>
<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer (finance minister) Kenneth Clarke said at the weekend the British electorate would not be fooled by pre-election tax cuts, and said he would not reduce them simply to win votes.</p>
<p>He also said he would not be afraid to raise interest rates if necessary. &quot;The markets believe, apparently, that I won't put up interest rates in any circumstance this side of an election. That is nonsense,&quot; he told Britain's GMTV.</p>
<p>Shepperd at Yamaichi said the economic rationale for tax cuts had disappeared. &quot;But a small cut in taxes balanced by more stringent spending plans is still the most likely outcome.&quot;</p>
<p>($1=.6408 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
