<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="86308" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: U.N. Afghan envoy aims to arrange peace talks.</title>
<headline>U.N. Afghan envoy aims to arrange peace talks.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Fleck</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Nations' special envoy to Afghanistan Norbert Holl said on Monday he was trying to arrange peace talks among the country's warring factions.</p>
<p>He told German radio he would visit two more groups after his meeting with the dominant Taleban Islamic militia, which took the capital Kabul on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Afghanistan solution can not be found by talking to Taleban alone,&quot; he said. &quot;You have to talk to all the parties.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking from Kabul, Holl said that during a visit to the Taleban's headquarters in the southern Afghan town of Kandahar on Saturday, Taleban leaders said they soon hoped to be ruling the Afghan state from Kabul.</p>
<p>&quot;The decisive thing for me was that I told the Taleban that we, the U.N, wanted to continue and deepen its dialogue with Taleban,&quot; Holl, who is German, said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no way of getting round the Taleban and the Taleban said it had no intention of pushing the U.N. into a corner but had a keen interest in talking to us too and that it placed great value on U.N. cooperation,&quot; Holl said.</p>
<p>Holl said he was given red carpet treatment when he met the leaders of the two-year-old militant Sunni Moslem movement, which grew out of religious schools in refugee camps in Pakistan.</p>
<p>He met Taleban's number two leader Mullah Mohammad Rabbani, whom the media has dubbed Afghanistan's new prime minister, for 2-1/2 hours of talks.</p>
<p>Rabbani leads Taleban's governing council.</p>
<p>&quot;Taleban said openly they will send their political heavyweights to Kabul, I think it's only a matter of time before they move there...The Taleban is trying to organise itself and to turn the new power structure into the instruments of a normal state,&quot; Holl said.</p>
<p>Holl said he raised the issue of the execution of former president Najibullah, who was snatched from the U.N. compound where he had stayed since anti-communist Mujahideen guerrillas took over the capital in April 1992.</p>
<p>Holl described this as a &quot;tragic development&quot; but declined to elaborate on what was said during the talks.</p>
<p>The U.N. Security Council deplored the &quot;brutal execution&quot; of Najibullah, who had been under U.N. protection at the time, late on Saturday.</p>
<p>Taleban captured Kabul with barely a shot fired on Friday and extended its power when its fighters captured the stronghold of former Afghan government military chief Ahmad Shah Masood, north of the Kabul, on Monday.</p>
<p>As soon as it established itself as the ruling force in Kabul, Taleban set up an interim ruling council which vowed to turn Afghanistan into an Islamic state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
