<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="86301" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany's Otto Versand, Tellit sign insurance deal.</title>
<headline>Germany's Otto Versand, Tellit sign insurance deal.</headline>
<dateline>BERGISCH-GLADBACH, Germany 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>German direct-selling insurer Tellit, which is part of the Colonia group, and major mail order firm Otto-Versand have signed a co-operation agreement covering sales of insurance policies to Otto customers, both companies said.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Tellit secured access to more than five million Otto customers. With a group turnover of 12.5 billion marks in 1995, Hamburg-based Otto is one of the world's largest mail order companies.</p>
<p>This week, Otto sent a letter to 500,000 customers, promising up to 30 percent lower auto insurance costs.</p>
<p>Otto spokesman Detlev von Livonius said that the first mailshot was a test. &quot;However, we expect a long-term cooperation.&quot; Otto was not acting as a broker for Tellit. &quot;We are doing all mailings ourselves. We would not give our addresses to anyone,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Tellit chief executive Klaus Sticker said that both companies would divide the profit from the operation, after deducting the costs. &quot;In normal mailings, we would expect returns between 1.0 and 3.5 percent,&quot; he said. &quot;We hope for a higher rate from the Otto cooperation.&quot;</p>
<p>Otto is of specific interest to Tellit because the majority of its customers are women -- who are regarded as &quot;better risks&quot; by motor insurers, Livonius said. In addition, mail order customers are used to buying goods and services by mail or phone.</p>
<p>In addition to special prices for women drivers, Tellit offers a rebate for drivers parking their cars overnight in garages, and 30 percent for a second car in the family.</p>
<p>Tellit was set up in 1994 and is fully owned by Colonia Konzern Holding, which in turn is controlled by UAP of France.</p>
<p>The direct-selling insurer currently has 70,000 customers in motor insurance. In early 1996, it started to sell other private insurance lines, too, and founded its own life insurance subsidiary.</p>
<p>The company has no salesmen, it operates only via mailshots and telephone. In 1995, premium income was 25 million marks, for 1996, Sticker expects 65 million marks.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Insurance News 44 171 542 2769</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERGISCH-GLADBACH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
