<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="86369" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Futures lift desultory Madrid stocks at close.</title>
<headline>Futures lift desultory Madrid stocks at close.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Madrid stocks rebounded in late trade on Monday, lifted by active futures trading and end of the trading period manuevres.</p>
<p>Dealers said the upward tendency would be short term at best, because the market was at resistance levels.</p>
<p>The General index was up 1.82 points, 0.50 percent, at 368.27 and the Ibex-35 gained 20.51 points, 0.49 percent, to 4,215.57.</p>
<p>The volume of trade increased in late trade in line with the &quot;The market has turned around without much happening and it remains to be seen what will happen at slightly higher levels than the closing ones where we are finding resistance to climbing,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The change in direction also increased the volume of trade until nearly 43 billion pesetas in business was done.</p>
<p>Banks benefitted most with Popular surging up 1.59 percent with a strong volume of 124,270 shares traded. Dealers did not give a reason for the volume of interest in the bank, which began climbing on Friday after news of a dividend increase.</p>
<p>Telefonica rose 15 pesetas to 2,385 with 3.7 million shares traded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
