<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="86543" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-WMC sees 1996/97 gold output flat.</title>
<headline>RTRS-WMC sees 1996/97 gold output flat.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>WMC Ltd said on Monday it expects its year-on-year output of gold to be flat in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Lower producton from the company's Hill 50 mine will decline, while production will be up at its St Ives operation, the company said in its 1995/96 annual report.</p>
<p>WMC's equity gold production totalled 744,552 ounces in 1995/96. A study into expanding the St Ives mine is expected to be completed in the current year, the report said.</p>
<p>WMC said it saw markets for two other key products, alumina and aluminium, improving in calendar 1997.  </p>
<p>WMC's 40 percent-owned Alcoa World Alumina and Chemicals joint venture has more than one million tonnes of spare alumina refinery capacity and was well-placed to supply additional requirements, the report said.</p>
<p>It also foreshadowed improvements on its record production of intermediate nickel concentrate and matte in 1996/97 following the completion of a new acid plant at its smelter works in Kalgoorlie, Western Australia.</p>
<p>In 1995/96 the company produced 94,805 tonnes of concentrate and 77,316 of matte.  </p>
<p>The new plant is geared to reduce the smelter's down time due to air quality control restrictions to around five percent from the current 25 to 30 percent, the company said.</p>
<p>Additional concentrate for the smelter will come via an expansion underway of WMC's Mount Keith mine to 42,000 tonnes a year, the report said.</p>
<p>Outside of Australia, the company aims to finalise agreements and begin feasibility studies in 1996/97 for development of the Zarmitan gold mine joint venture in Uzbekistan and its interests in Cuban nickel projects.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
