<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="86611" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: NEC, Packard Bell set up PC sales unit in Japan.</title>
<headline>NEC, Packard Bell set up PC sales unit in Japan.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>NEC Corp said on Monday that it and its U.S. personal computer (PC) affiliate Packard Bell NEC Inc (PB NEC) had jointly established a Japanese unit to sell IBM-compatible PCs in Japan.</p>
<p>The new company, Packard Bell NEC Japan K.K., will sell PB-NEC brand desktop and notebook PCs developed by the U.S. parent, a joint venture set up earlier this year by Packard Bell, U.S. firm Zenith Data Systems, and NEC.</p>
<p>Including non-voting stock, NEC owns about 40 percent of PB NEC, as a result of its $283 million investment in Packard Bell in February, a NEC spokesman said.</p>
<p>The new Japanese unit will also sell Packard Bell-brand PCs in Japan, which have already been sold in Japan for five years.</p>
<p>The new firm, capitalised at 200 million yen, aims to sell a total of 40,000 PCs in the initial year to March 31, 1997, and 150,000 in the second year, its president, Makoto Tsuruta, told a news conference.</p>
<p>NEC's subsidiaries will support the new firm's distribution, maintenance and production, he said.</p>
<p>NEC already sells its own proprietary-architecture PCs in Japan and holds a 40 percent share of the country's PC market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
