<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="86966" id="root" date="1996-09-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks dip at open in slow trade.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks dip at open in slow trade.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian shares dipped at the opening in slow trading on Monday as investors awaited some guidance on local interest rates.</p>
<p>A Reserve Bank of Australia board meeting is scheduled for Tuesday and, while a rate cut is not generally expected, many in the market do not rule it out completely.</p>
<p>At the opening, the All Ordinaries index lost 3.1 points to 2279.9.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been quiet with not all that much in it,&quot; said dealer Duncan Gamble of brokerage Wilson HTM, adding that many were taking a wait and see approach to interest rate prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;People are holding back to see what the Reserve bank does on interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Major miner CRA featured early, with brokers saying a combination of diminishing selling pressure following September options expiry and more favourable market sentiment than the other big miners, BHP and WMC, drove the shares 20 cents higher to A$19.15.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some pressure off the market after the exercise of put options on Friday and better sentiment on CRA,&quot; Gamble said.</p>
<p>Falls outnumbered rises by a ratio of about seven to six, while about 42 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
