<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87070" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Companies expand leases in Alaska's Colville area.</title>
<headline>Companies expand leases in Alaska's Colville area.</headline>
<byline>Yereth Rosen</byline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A trio of oil companies expanded their holdings Tuesday in the Colville River area of Alaska's North Slope by being the only bidders in a state lease sale.</p>
<p>Atlantic Richfield unit Arco Alaska Inc., Anadarko Petroleum and Union Texas Petroleum, bidding in partnership, won five new tracts in the area for a total $2.02 million, according to preliminary figures released by the Alaska Division of Oil and Gas.  </p>
<p>Arco was the 56 percent shareholder in the partnership, with Anadarko and Union Texas each holding 22 percent.</p>
<p>No other companies bid in the small lease sale, which comprised only 13 tracts covering about 15,400 acres.</p>
<p>The three oil companies have worked together in the past few years to explore the Colville delta, located about 50 miles west of the trans-Alaska pipeline's northern terminus at Prudhoe Bay.  </p>
<p>Results of their exploration work has been largely confidential, although Union Texas last year announced that early work indicated the Colville area held 100 million geologically recoverable barrels, said Ken Boyd, director of the Alaska Division of Oil and Gas.</p>
<p>With Arco, Anadarko and Union Texas together drilling about 18 Colville-area wells in the past few years and conducting extensive seismic work there, &quot;They probably have a leg up. They know the area,&quot; Boyd said.</p>
<p>&quot;The knowledge factor is very high and it would have been very difficult to compete against that group,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The Colville River Exempt Lease Sale 86A comprised land split between state ownership and that of the Barrow-based Arctic Slope Regional Corp., an Inupiat Eskimo regional group established by the 1971 Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act.</p>
<p>Arctic Slope owns the majority share of the tracts that received bids, Boyd said. The state's share is probably under 5 percent, he said.</p>
<p>The tracts that received bids also carry a sliding-scale royalty for any oil produced there, and royalty rates on the tracts are generally much higher than the normal 12.5 percent state royalty share for the North Slope.  </p>
<p>Leasing in the area had been delayed while the state and Arctic Slope resolved longstanding ownership disputes.</p>
<p>Tuesday's lease sale allowed Arco, Anadarko and Union Texas to consolidate holding acquired previously and to advance toward formal unitization of the Colville area, Boyd said.</p>
<p>Arco Alaska spokesman Ronnie Chappell said the company will soon unveil some of its Colville exploration results, now that the lease sale has been completed.  </p>
<p>Although other companies declined to bid in Tuesday's sale, Boyd said industry interest in the area is keen because because the federal and state governments are seeking to open the adjacent 23 million-acre National Petroleum Reserve-Alaska to new oil exploration.</p>
<p>The federally owned petroleum reserve, on the west side of the Colville River, holds proven oil deposits but has not been seriously explored for about two decades, Boyd said.</p>
<p>&quot;The question is, what's going on on the other side of the river,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
