<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87102" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Europe close to stability pact - Luxembourg PM.</title>
<headline>Europe close to stability pact - Luxembourg PM.</headline>
<byline>Myra MacDonald</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe is very near agreement on a budget stability pact which will play a crucial role in ensuring countries do not make a dash to get into monetary union and then let their deficits go again, Luxembourg Prime Minister Jean-Claude Juncker said in an interview on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We more or less had agreement in Dublin. If we had time to deepen the question, it would have been possible to reach a final decision,&quot; he said referring to a meeting last month at which European Union finance ministers agreed in principle on a stability pact but deferred a final decision for more talks.  </p>
<p>Juncker, who is also Luxembourg's finance minister, said the EU should try to agree by the end of the year on whether membership of the Exchange Rate Mechanism was a necessary precondition for joining Economic and Monetary Union in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it would be a contribution to the credibility of the whole process if finance ministers could deliver an answer (on the ERM). We have to deliver a clear answer before the end of the year,&quot; he told Reuteres.</p>
<p>The EU's Maastricht treaty calls for currency stability within normal bands for two years.  </p>
<p>Britain insists if it chose to, it should be allowed into EMU in 1999 despite its reluctance to join the ERM, and says that currency stability, rather than ERM membership, should be what counts.</p>
<p>Italy and Finland, meanwhile, are considering joining this year to leave no room for doubt on their eligibility for EMU.</p>
<p>Juncker, speaking after a diplomatic row blew up between France and Italy after French President Jacques Chirac questioned whether Rome would be ready for EMU, suggested the existence of the stability pact should prevent such rows.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have to be sure when we make the choice (on who joins EMU in 1999) that all member states which have qualified will be able to respect the criteria for the time to come,&quot; he said. &quot;The stability pact...is as important as the (Maastricht) treaty itself,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Behind the Italian-French row are fears that countries might make a dash for EMU through one-off measures, and then face new fiscal problems that might weaken the euro when it is launched and force up interest rates across the continent.  </p>
<p>EU leaders will agree in early 1998 on who will join EMU, based on monetary and fiscal performances in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision will be a political decision. It was never meant to be a technical decision,&quot; Juncker said. &quot;Among the elements, the stability pact will have great importance. We have to be sure the effort will be sustainable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he criticised any attempt to prejudge the decision and said that if countries really proved they could meet and sustain Maastricht standards there was no reason for euro interest rates to suffer any risk premium.  </p>
<p>&quot;I'm not too much in favour of pre-judgements which are of no value when we gather to make our decision,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The stability pact, he said, should include automatic sanctions so countries would know they would definitely be fined if their deficits went above three percent of gross domestic product, unless they could prove their economies had suffered &quot;temporary and exceptional circumstances&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to define exactly what we understand by exceptional and temporary. I think we will be able to do it.&quot;</p>
<p>His comments echoed those of Luxembourg Treasury director Yves Mersch, who said on Monday the EU was 95 percent close to agreement on the stability pact, which finance ministers hope will be approved by EU leaders at a Dublin summit in December.</p>
<p>He also said he was sure Belgium would qualify for EMU despite its heavy debt, but even if it did not, Luxembourg, which is in a currency union with its larger neighbour, would join anyway.</p>
<p>&quot;Luxembourg would enter monetary union even if Belgium did not. We have no other choice,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
