<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87310" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rep. Gonzalez seeks audit of Fed banks' vaults.</title>
<headline>Rep. Gonzalez seeks audit of Fed banks' vaults.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rep. Henry Gonzalez, senior Democrat on the House Banking Committee asked the Federal Reserve to immediately direct the undertaking of independent audits of all the Fed's currency and coin operations.</p>
<p>In a statement, Gonzalez of Texas said his request was based on a recent General Accouting Office (GAO) report on the Los Angeles Fed which found &quot;serious internal control and reporting problems and the L.A. bank's inability to precisely account for the currency flowing through the bank from month to month.&quot;  </p>
<p>Gonzalez has also directed his staff to develop criminal referrals for the Justice Department, should they be warranted. The referrals, he said, would be &quot;to address the problems of deliberate alterations of cash records that were ordered by the L.A. branch management.&quot;</p>
<p>GAO is the non-partisan investigative agency of Congress.</p>
<p>Gonzalez alleged the GAO report pointed out the L.A. branch's inadequate controls. &quot;Because there have been embezzlements in the past, this is a vulnerability that needs to be addressed immediately,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He questioned the Fed's response that there was never any money missing in the L.A. branch's vault and that a team of 40 examiners counted the money on the weekend of September 6, 1996. &quot;This does not mean that there was never any cash taken,&quot; Gonzalez said.</p>
<p>The Justice Department prosecuted two Fed employees for walking out of cash departments of two Fed banks with money. They covered their theft by altering Fed records of currency sent for destruction. These cases occured in 1994 and involved $267,000 taken from the New Orleans branch and $70,000 embezzled from the Boston branch.</p>
<p>GAO said it found an alteration of the L.A. branch cash report so that $178 million missing in cash reports for October, November and December 1995 was kept secret.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
