<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87412" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEnergy ends test at Mass. power station.</title>
<headline>COMEnergy ends test at Mass. power station.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commonwealth Energy Co's startup testing of its 584 megawatt (MW) unit 2 at the Canal Generating Station in Sandwich, Mass., was completed Monday, a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The official date of testing ends Sept 30,&quot; said spokesman Peter Dimond, adding there were plans to further assess the unit that was in overhaul for more than year so it could use natural gas as well as fuel oil</p>
<p>The unit has been producing power to the regional grid during testing.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's been burning gas at full load,&quot; Dimond said.</p>
<p>Following the modification, Canal's unit 2 could burn up to 75,000 million British thermal units a day of natural gas or 10,000 barrels a day of one-percent sulphur fuel oil.</p>
<p>Dimond noted the capacity of the unit would be downgraded from its current level.</p>
<p>The utility decided to upgrade the unit to give it more flexibility and because gas is cleaner burning than oil.</p>
<p>Commonwealth Energy's Canal Electric Co subsidiary is the operator of the plant, and jointly owns the unit with Montaup Electric Co, a subsidiary of Eastern Utilities Associates.</p>
<p>Canal Electric also operates and wholly-owns the adjoining 560 MW unit.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
