<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87565" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICAN GENERALS FACE TRUTH COMMISSION SUBPOENAE.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICAN GENERALS FACE TRUTH COMMISSION SUBPOENAE.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's Truth and Reconciliation Commission on Tuesday threatened to subpoenae top apartheid-era generals, unless they came clean on at least 60 human rights violations attributed to the police force.    </p>
<p>The ex-police generals promised in August to cooperate with the commission, mandated to uncover past abuses, to avoid being forced to testify.</p>
<p>But Alex Boraine, the commission's deputy chairman, told a news conference their written submission was incomplete and that the TRC wanted the generals, who include former police commissioner Johan van der Merwe, to rewrite it before Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;After giving very careful consideration to it (the report) we decided that it was totally unsatisfactory,&quot; Boraine said.</p>
<p>South African Nobel peace laureate Desmond Tutu, who heads the commission, also told the news conference that the TRC would in future take sterner action against alleged perpetrators of apartheid crimes who did not voluntarily appear before it.    </p>
<p>&quot;We are saying this velvet glove does in fact have a fist of steel, which can be used when it seems necessary.&quot; </p>
<p>He said the commission had instructed its offices nationwide to start preparing subpoenae, but did not name any offenders.</p>
<p>The retired Anglican archbishop said that since the truth body had started its work in April, it had mostly heard harrowing tales of abuses from victims, and requests for amnesty had come from people already convicted and in prison.</p>
<p>&quot;But the one part of our work...which we have not succeeded in dealing with, has been to provide people with information -- who killed so and so, and if they did do it, who gave them the orders,&quot; Tutu said, explaining the TRC's stricter approach.</p>
<p>President Nelson Mandela set up the commission to probe abuses by all sides in three decades of race war. </p>
<p>It has power to grant amnesty to perpetrators of abuses who fully confess to their deeds, but has yet to make any breakthroughs in exposing those with blood on their hands from apartheid's dirty war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
