<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87866" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: PRESS DIGEST - Zambia - Oct 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Zambia - Oct 1.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Zambian press on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ZAMBIA DAILY MAIL</p>
<p>- Zambia Consolidated Copper Mines Ltd (ZCCM) miners in the Copperbelt Province have given striking teachers until Wednesday to call off their strike or face eviction from the ZCCM houses they occupy. The teachers in the mining townships are striking for better wages.</p>
<p>- Zambia Railways and National Railways of Zimbabwe have 84 million sterling stuck in the liquidated Bank of Credit and Commerce Internatinal in the UK, deputy transport minister Gilbert Mululu said on Monday. He said that the two railways were trying to recover the money through the liquidators of the fallen bank.</p>
<p>TIMES OF ZAMBIA</p>
<p>- More than 200 public works department workers in the mining town of Ndola and scores of lecturers at Copperbelt University have gone on strike to push for improved pay.</p>
<p>THE POST</p>
<p>- The Law Association of Zambia on Monday demanded that the government reverse a new constitution it said was flawed and discriminatory. Association chairman George Kunda said the constitution would enable the Frederick Chiluba government to remain in office even after its five year mandate expired at the end of October.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
