<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87897" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian defence minister frets over army crisis.</title>
<headline>Russian defence minister frets over army crisis.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Defence Minister Igor Rodionov appealed to President Boris Yeltsin on Tuesday for extra money to ease a crisis in the army and said the situation there was becoming unbearable.</p>
<p>Rodionov has played down any talk of a rebellion in the armed forces, but he told a news conference that a lack of funding could lead to uncontrollable processes which could weaken Russia's combat readiness.</p>
<p>&quot;I appeal to society, the president, the government and parliament. We must find a way out of this extremenly difficult and critical situation which the army is in today because of the lack of funding,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He called for a backlog of wages to be paid by the state, adding: &quot;The situation is becoming unbearable.&quot;</p>
<p>The army, the pride of Soviet society, has suffered from underfunding and low morale since the superpower fell apart and many soldiers have not been paid for months.</p>
<p>Security chief Alexander Lebed, who backed Rodionov's appointment as Russian defence minister, said last week that the army was close to mutiny because of frustration at government negligence and unpaid wages.</p>
<p>Rodionov said at the time that the situation was under control, but he made clear on Tuesday that the armed forces faced a deep crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;In short, the Defence Ministry regards the situation as controllable and manageable but the armed forces are going through a period of sharp crisis,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the main problems included the lack of funding, long delays in personnel being paid by the state and a tendency towards a decline in combat readiness. Under current budget plans, the army would face another tough year in 1997, he said.</p>
<p>Rodionov supported plans to create a fully professional army but said the lack of finances meant it would take longer than planned and could be completed only by the year 2000.</p>
<p>He said the aim was to cut the armed forces from about 1.5 million now to 1.2 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
