<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87903" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Aeroflot says Boeing, P&amp;W deals linked.</title>
<headline>Aeroflot says Boeing, P&amp;W deals linked.</headline>
<byline>Viktor Anoshkin</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian flag carrier Aeroflot's planned purchase of 10 Boeing 737-400 airliners is linked to its purchase of Pratt &amp; Whitney engines for the Ilyushin 96 airliner, the head of Aeroflot said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Chief executive Yevgeny Shaposhnikov said the purchase of the 10 jets from Boeing Co would be financed by Western banks.</p>
<p>But he said it was part of the same package as the controversial purchase of 20 Russian Il-96 planes powered by United Technology Corp Pratt &amp; Whitney engines, which is financed by the U.S. Export-Import Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;We see the purchase of 10 Boeing 737s and the Il-96M project as a single package,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Final agreement on the purchase of the Boeings could be signed by the end of this year, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It may happen the day after the Il-96M agreement is signed,&quot; Shaposhnikov said.</p>
<p>Earlier this year Russia and the U.S. reached an aviation agreement providing for $1 billion in Eximbank funding to sell the Pratt &amp; Whitney engines and other U.S. parts for the Il-96 ordered by Aeroflot, while opening the Russian market to U.S. and other foreign aircraft.</p>
<p>Boeing initially objected to the deal but withdrew its opposition as long as it did not lead to similar loans for purchases of its competitors' aircraft. Eximbank cannot fund projects which would hurt U.S. industry.</p>
<p>Sources at Aeroflot Russian International Airlines have put the total cost of the 10 planes at around $350 million.</p>
<p>Shaposhnikov told a news conference that Aeroflot's purchase of Boeing planes would not hurt Russian aviation companies.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not see any problems because this move will open new working places at the Voronezh aviation plant where the Ilyushin-96M will be produced,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We need hundreds and hundreds of new aircraft,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last month Farid Mukhametshin, premier of Russia's autonomous region of Tatarstan, denounced Aeroflot's decision to buy Boeings in 1997 and 1998, saying it would hurt the crisis-ridden Russian aviation industry.</p>
<p>Russian plane-maker Tupolev is based in the Tatarstan capital, Kazan.</p>
<p>Aeroflot and Tatarstan signed an agreement on Tuesday in which Aeroflot agreed to buy Tupolev 214 planes if they could be brought up to Western standards.</p>
<p>Mukhametshin told the news conference that under the agreement he had signed with Shaposhnikov, Aeroflot and Tatarstan would seek federal government funding for the domestic aviation industry next year.</p>
<p>On Monday Ilyushin said the cargo version of the Il-96 was almost ready for its first flight, but final assembly was being delayed because Ilyushin and Voronezh did not have enough money to pay Russian suppliers for essential parts.</p>
<p>-- Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
