<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87910" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poland's Kaczmarek to be treasury vice minister.</title>
<headline>Poland's Kaczmarek to be treasury vice minister.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's former privatisation minister Wieslaw Kaczmarek agreed to become deputy minister in a new treasury ministry, formed on Tuesday, which has subsumed his portfolio, presidential spokesman Antoni Styrczula said.</p>
<p>After a ceremony appointing Peasant Party member Miroslaw Pietrewicz as treasury minister, Styrczula told reporters: &quot;Vice-Minister Kaczmarek will be responsible for privatisation, including capital privatisation, restructuring of enterprises and the National Investment Funds.&quot;</p>
<p>Kaczmarek, of the dominant ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) in the ruling coalition, had been reluctant to accept the post in the new ministry, fearing Pietrewicz may not maintain the course of privatisation he himself had followed since taking office in 1993.</p>
<p>Some analysts had also expressed anxieties over the future of privatisation, linchpin of Poland's economic reforms, as the smaller Peasant party has been critical of many sales of state assets in the past.</p>
<p>The SLD was forced to concede the new treasury ministry to the its Peasant partners as the price for their cooperation in implementing a reorganisation of government ministries starting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Tuesday's swearing in of the reformist Kaczmarek to oversee sales of individual firms to investors, prepare others for privatisation, and steer the country's mass privation programme was designed to bring reassurance that his policies would continue.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
