<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87944" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria's airline to return three leased planes.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria's airline to return three leased planes.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's troubled national carrier Balkan Airlines, hit by heavy losses in recent years, will return its three leased Airbus A320s planes, a Bulgarian official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Balkan returns two Airbus A320s planes very soon and the third one will be returned later this year after its contract with a Turkish airline expires,&quot; a transport ministry official, who declined to be named, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Balkan had leased four Airbus A320s from the Japenese Orix Corp but returned one of them a year ago. Two A320 planes were detained in London and Amsterdam for unpaid fees last December.</p>
<p>The state-run airline also leased two Boeing 767-200s from Air France and three Boeing 737-500s from Australia's Ansett between 1990 and 1992 to upgrade its aging fleet.</p>
<p>The transport ministry said the leasing contracts were &quot;shameful&quot; and slammed the national carrier's mismanagement which had contributed to losses of five billion levs since the contracts were signed.</p>
<p>Debt-ridden Balkan increased its losses in the first half of 1996 by 510 million levs against the same period last year.</p>
<p>British consultancy firm KPMG will help Balkan Airline to work out a programme aimed at stabilising its finances and it is expected to be ready by October 30.</p>
<p>Bulgaria began procedures to privatise the national carrier in 1992 but in January 1995 the Privatisation Agency suspended them, citing a lack of buyers.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
