<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="87973" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Unibanka hits fresh high on Latvian bourse.</title>
<headline>Unibanka hits fresh high on Latvian bourse.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in leading bank Unibanka rose to another high on Tuesday although overall bourse activity was little changed from last week's levels, the stock exchange said.</p>
<p>Unibanka rose to 2.09 lats from 2.03 lats on trade of 22,839 lats, most of the day's 43,980 lats business.</p>
<p>Trade at the last session on Thursday was 40,750 lats. The bourse will this week start a third session on Wednesdays.</p>
<p>Riga Transport Fleet, the other share on the official list, traded 10,570 lats and its was unchanged at 89 santimes.</p>
<p>On the secondary list, Mangali Shipyard was the most active at 3,150 lats and its shares added one santime to 30.</p>
<p>The Riga Yeast factory turned over 2,635 lats and rose to 85 santimes from 82 santimes while the Riga agricultural machine plant traded 2,471 lats and rose one santime to 12.</p>
<p>Kaija fish cannery, normally the most active on the secondary list, turned over just 900 lats of its stock but demand was high at 146,625 shares while supply was just 849. Its price shot up to 74 santimes from 65.</p>
<p>-- Patrick Lannin, Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
