<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88046" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Oct 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Oct 1.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Tuesday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- All could be prepared for the Croatian Danube region elections if they were to be held on December 15, said at yestereday's government press conference, deputy Prime Minister Ivica Kostovic.</p>
<p>- The goal of Croatian Radio-Television (HRT) is the strengthening of pluralism and democracy, said its director Ivica Mudrinic during HRT's Council session.</p>
<p>- The average net salaries in Croatia in August up by 3.9 percent compared to July and now stand at 2,071 kuna.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Funerals: It is more expensive to die than to live in Croatia, as a nice funeral coupled with a burial place cost the same as a one-room apartment.</p>
<p>- More airplanes needed if Croatian Airlines is to meet the needs of tourism.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Croatian government regular press conference: A law to be passed against money laundering.</p>
<p>- Pensions being received by Croatian citizens from the occupied sections of the country: The state is not trying to &quot;bribe&quot; the Serbs with pensions.</p>
<p>- I already have enough work for the next three years, claims the newly appointed chief prosecutor of the Hague tribunal, Louise Arbour. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
