<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88327" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Kurd rebels gun down Turkish village teachers.</title>
<headline>Kurd rebels gun down Turkish village teachers.</headline>
<dateline>HANTEPE, Turkey 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pools of blood on the banks of the Tigris River marked the spot where four Turkish primary school teachers were shot dead on Tuesday by what police said was a Kurdish rebel hit team.</p>
<p>Residents in the village of Hantepe said two armed men abducted seven teachers from their state-paid lodgings overnight, took them to the nearby riverside and killed four of them in a hail of bullets.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the (Kurdistan Workers Party) PKK,&quot; a security official told Reuters in Hantepe, a run-down southeastern village of around 100 houses in Diyarbakir province.</p>
<p>Two of the victims were a young married couple, villagers said. The rebels, who have often killed Turkish teachers in the past, released the three other, female, captives.</p>
<p>The PKK say they target teachers, most of whom are from outside the region, because they symbolise the forced assimilation of Kurdish children into Turkish culture. Teaching the Kurdish language is forbidden in Turkish schools.</p>
<p>Human rights group Amnesty International said in a report released on Tuesday that the rebels have killed 90 teachers since they took up arms for Kurdish self rule in 1984. More than 20,000 people have died in the bitter conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;Who killed our teachers?&quot; an 11-year-old pupil, who identified herself as Emine, said at the place where her teachers were gunned down. Body parts lay on the ground.</p>
<p>&quot;We want teachers here but after this none will come,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Hundreds of village schools in the southeast are empty because teachers appointed from western Turkey have refused to take up their posts in fear of the rebels.</p>
<p>Soldiers detained around eight Hantepe residents for questioning, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The killing was the latest in a string of attacks near Diyarbakir, the southeast's main city, which security officials say may be organised by elusive rebel commander Semdin Sakik.</p>
<p>The PKK killed three private security guards and kidnapped two others at a dam around 25 km (13 miles) west of Hantepe late on Monday night, security officials said.</p>
<p>A group of about six rebels with a heavy machinegun and assault rifles opened fire on a cafe frequented by policemen in Maden town outside Diyarbakir on Monday night, killing two junior civil servants and wounding 17, including six policemen, officials in nearby Tunceli said.</p>
<p>Sakik, also known as &quot;Fingerless Zeki&quot;, is believed to have come to Diyarbakir province from northern Iraq in the last month on his way to Tunceli province.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANTEPE, Turkey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
