<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88378" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt disgruntled with short-term U.S. diplomacy.</title>
<headline>Egypt disgruntled with short-term U.S. diplomacy.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Wright</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>In snubbing U.S. President Bill Clinton's invitation to a Middle East summit in Washington this week, Egypt is sending a message of protest against a U.S. diplomatic strategy based on short-term pacification.</p>
<p>In public Egyptian leaders have said they are staying away from the summit because they have no expectations that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu will change his policies towards the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak told reporters on Tuesday he still had faith in Clinton's goodwill despite reservations about the summit, which will bring together Netanyahu, Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat and King Hussein of Jordan.</p>
<p>&quot;President Clinton is doing his best although he may not reach what he expects. The man is busy with his campaign but yet he is keen on maintaining stability and peace in this part of the world,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>But in the background Egyptian leaders are faulting the United States for arranging a summit which in the eyes of Arabs could end up absolving Netanyahu of responsibility for the latest outbreak of violence in the West Bank and Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>&quot;The Egyptians know the philosophy of the summit is to save Netanyahu and to score electoral points for Clinton. It will not address the crux of the matter,&quot; an Arab diplomat said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Americans want to keep everything calm until after the presidential elections in November and the Israelis are exploiting that to create new facts on the ground. It was very important for Egypt not to sanctify that,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In the name of &quot;evenhandedness&quot;, U.S. diplomats repeatedly decline to criticise Israeli actions which the rest of the world calls violations of U.N. resolutions or international law.</p>
<p>Egypt usually grumbles quietly about the U.S. attitude but does not go further because it knows that the United States has more influence over Israel than any other country.</p>
<p>Egypt also receives $2 billion a year in U.S. aid, though the aid has been losing value in real terms for more than 15 years and is less and less important to the Egyptian economy.</p>
<p>Mubarak also likes to emphasise the role of Egypt, the first Arab country to make peace with Israel, as an indispensible participant in any talks on the future of the Middle East.</p>
<p>&quot;But in this case, there were limits to how much they could take,&quot; said the Arab diplomat.</p>
<p>Mubarak may also have been piqued that Clinton upstaged his own plans for a meeting with Arafat and Netanyahu in Cairo.</p>
<p>That would have been a different kind of summit, better prepared and more likely to end in Israeli commitments to carry out agreements between the Palestinians and the previous Israeli government, Egyptian officials say.</p>
<p>Egyptian Information Minister Safwat el-Safwat said in an interview broadcast on Monday that the lack of preparation was an important factor in Egypt's decision to stay away.</p>
<p>&quot;Egypt's point of view (was)...that a meeting of foreign ministers should prepare the agenda and the draft statement. It must be clear that the aims of the summit do not include providing cover for Netanyahu's shameful anti-peace policies,&quot; added an editorial in the government newspaper al-Akhbar.</p>
<p>It noted that Netanyahu excluded in advance any discussion of the Israeli archaeological tunnel in Arab East Jerusalem -- the spark that ignited the violence in which 57 Palestinians and 15 Israeli soldiers were killed last week.</p>
<p>&quot;So what are the issues which will be discussed, when everyone knows that excavating and opening the tunnel was behind the explosion of rage?&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Mubarak made a similar point about the agenda on Tuesday, implictly criticising Washington's faith in the usefulness of merely bringing people together and making them agree to talk.</p>
<p>&quot;What kind of negotiations, negotiating what?...Nowadays we should work on implementing the previous agreements which have been signed with Mr Rabin and Mr Peres (the Israeli prime ministers who made peace with the Palestinians),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless the people feel or trust the progress in the peace process, I think it is detrimental to attend (the summit) and listen and to agree with what Mr Netanyahu says,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The truth is that I do not see much good coming from this summit,&quot; added al-Akhbar editor Galal Duweidar. &quot;All the indications confirm that holding it in Washington will put it under pressure and divert its decisions in favour of Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The feeling that it is important to please the (American) Jews will prevent Clinton from taking any practical position against Israeli conduct,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
