<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88393" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton breaks promises, cannot be trusted - Dole.</title>
<headline>Clinton breaks promises, cannot be trusted - Dole.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>KIRTLAND, Ohio 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>With the campaign's first presidential debate only days away, Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole hammered away at the trust issue Tuesday, telling Americans not to believe what President Bill Clinton will say.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the Clinton and Dole camps sparred over the president's hosting of a Middle East summit in Washington, with Dole labeling it as another example of Clinton's &quot;photo-op foreign policy.&quot;</p>
<p>The White House said the comment was an example of Dole's frustration at not being able to make news. Senate Minority Leader Tom Daschle said Dole was dangerously close to interfering with Clinton's conduct of the nation's foreign policy and should back off.</p>
<p>Speaking in a community college gymnasium lined with &quot;Trust Dole&quot; placards and packed with 2,000 supporters, Dole portrayed himself as a man whose word is his bond up against a president who has left a string of broken campaign promises behind him.</p>
<p>&quot;When you are listening to the debates, ask yourself this question: 'Would you buy a used campaign promise from this man?&quot; Dole asked a cheering crowd in his first campaign appearance since visiting a Jewish delicatessen in Miami Beach last Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll win the debate by just showing up. He doesn't believe in what he says .... I spent a lifetime keeping my word,&quot; Dole said as he offered up what he called a &quot;consumer's guide to the debates.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Buyer beware, what you see is not what you get. The real cost is way over list price. High maintenance costs will shoot up unexpectedly. The politician veers uncontrollably to the left except in the face of oncoming elections when he rolls to the right,&quot; Dole said of his opponent.</p>
<p>&quot;And that's why on Nov. 5 the American people are going to demand a factory recall of Bill Clinton and his liberal policies,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He mocked Clinton's failure to deliver a middle-class tax cut as he promised in the 1992 campaign and asked, &quot;Have any of you seen this cut?&quot;</p>
<p>As boos and shouts of &quot;no&quot; echoed across the hall, Dole said: &quot;Bill Clinton makes promises that are liberal and makes promises that are conservative. But the only promises he keeps are his liberal promises.&quot;</p>
<p>Since last Thursday Dole was keenly focused on preparations for Sunday's 90-minute encounter with Clinton in Hartford, Connecticut. He spent four days at his Florida apartment preparing and planned to do the same this week.</p>
<p>Tennessee Republican Senator Fred Thompson, a former actor, has been working with Dole, playing the part of Clinton in mock debates. Thompson went to Dole's Washington campaign headquarters to work with the former Senate majority leader after he returned from his Ohio trip late Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>It was Dole's 12th trip to Ohio since the general election campaign began and polls showed that 27 percent of the electorate were still undecided in the key state.</p>
<p>Nationally polls showed Dole trailing Clinton by between 11 and 25 percent, with the president's standing leaping as he weighed in on such foreign policy issues as Iraq and the Middle East peace talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIRTLAND, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
