<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88481" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton signs budget into law before deadline.</title>
<headline>Clinton signs budget into law before deadline.</headline>
<byline>David Lawsky</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton signed a budget bill into law late on Monday, clinching his top spending priorities in a major victory over the Republican-led Congress.</p>
<p>In a statement Clinton said the new law &quot;moves us further toward our goal of a balanced budget while protecting our values and priorities -- educating our children, providing a clean environment, fighting crime, protecting our families from drugs and combating terrorism.&quot;</p>
<p>The law took effect before a midnight deadline, opening the spending spout for fiscal 1997 starting on Tuesday. Hours earlier the Senate passed the bill 84-15, acting two days after the House passed it, 370-37.</p>
<p>Clinton successfully demanded an extra $6.5 billion of spending with the lion's share going to his top priority of education. House Republicans, anxious to return home and campaign in the weeks before the November 5 election, abandoned earlier demands to slash spending.</p>
<p>Senate Democratic Leader Tom Daschle called the shift a &quot;remarkable retreat from the Republican positions of two years ago, when the majority party in Congress demanded deep cuts in education and the environment and a slowing of Medicare growth that Clinton said would ultimately require cuts in benefits.</p>
<p>Analysts at conservative think tanks agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;Essentiallly the Republicans took this big boulder (of budget cuts) and rolled it 90 percent of the way up hill and then let it fall right back on them,&quot; said Steven Moore of the Cato Institute, calling the budget a &quot;big win&quot; for Clinton.</p>
<p>But Republicans calculated that compromise was necessary. They had been blamed for two partial government shutdowns resulting from disagreement over the budget, and saw their popularity evaporate in public opinion polls.</p>
<p>This time Republicans pledged to avoid similar fights. And that meant they had to give in to some of Clinton's demands for additional spending.</p>
<p>&quot;It's more than we would like to have done but the White House insisted on adding more money for a number of programmes,&quot; said Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott, a Mississippi Republican.</p>
<p>The law funded the military, national parks, education, jobs programmes, environmental protection and law enforcement, the White House, foreign aid, health research, and many other activities, combining six spending bills.</p>
<p>It also incorporated a once-contentious immigration bill and a badly needed measure to strengthen the thrift insurance fund. It included a measure ensuring that people who commit domestic crimes cannot purchase guns. And it sold broadcast airwaves and expand anti-terrorism measures.</p>
<p>The spending law provided $244 billion for the military and about $356 billion for other domestic programmes. The administration had wanted the military budget cut by $3.5 billion and asked for $10 billion in extra domestic spending.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
