<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88523" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE announces support for regulatory reform bill.</title>
<headline>CSCE announces support for regulatory reform bill.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange Inc on Tuesday threw its support behind a legislative bid to ease regulatory restrictions on U.S. futures trading.</p>
<p>On Saturday, Representative Thomas Ewing (R-Ill) introduced a bill to the House to reform some provisions of the Commodity Exchange Act. Although the bill, proposed in the final hours of the 104th Congress, was seen as largely symbolic, advocates have said they plan to reintroduce it when the next Congress convenes in January.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is encouraging to see that Congress recognizes that the Commodity Exchange Act needs to be streamlined to assure the continued competitiveness of the U.S. futures industry,&quot; CSCE president James Bowe said in a statement.</p>
<p>Bowe's statement echoes similar plaudits by the Chicago Mercantile Exchange and the Chicago Board of Trade.</p>
<p>On Monday, CBOT chairman Patrick Arbor praised the Ewing bill, which he said aims to do away with federal laws and policies that are &quot;out of step with new market realities, puttting us at a competitive disadvantage.&quot;  </p>
<p>Ewing is chairman of the House agriculture subcommittee on risk management and specialty crops.</p>
<p>The bill, H.R. 4276, seeks to subject all new rules proposed by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to a strict cost-benefit analysis. It would also shorten the CFTC's review period of newly-proposed futures contracts.</p>
<p>Under the bill, trading by large institutions and other sophisticated market participants, known as &quot;appropriate persons&quot;, could be exempt from most futures regulation.  </p>
<p>In doing so, the bill would permit futures market to &quot;perform on an even playing field with current over-the counter derivatives markets,&quot; CSCE's Bowe said.</p>
<p>&quot;This new legislation would help us to maintain our competitive position in the future, as we balance important and necessary regulartory goals with practical and realistic oversight systems,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Wendy Pollack, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
