<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88556" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hollywood Madam Fliess ordered into drug rehab.</title>
<headline>Hollywood Madam Fliess ordered into drug rehab.</headline>
<byline>Steve James</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reputed Hollywood Madam Heidi Fleiss was ordered on Tuesday to enter a residential drug rehabilitation clinic after she admitted violating terms of her bail by using illegal drugs.</p>
<p>Fleiss, who is due to be retried this month in state court on charges of pandering, was brought in handcuffs into federal court on Tuesday after being arrested last Friday for the bail violation.</p>
<p>She had been due to be sentenced for her federal conviction on money-laundering and tax-evasion charges related to the high-priced call-girl racket she ran in Hollywood, but that sentencing was postponed until Oct. 24, while Judge Consuelo Marshall dealt with the drug issue.</p>
<p>Under the terms of her $150,000 bail, Fleiss was required to undergo periodic testing for drug use.</p>
<p>The daughter of a prominent Los Angeles area doctor, Fleiss, 30, was convicted in 1994 of three counts of pandering in a prostitution ring and sentenced to three years in prison.</p>
<p>But that conviction was reversed by a state appeals court because of improper jury conduct. The same jury acquitted her on a charge of providing cocaine.</p>
<p>Fleiss, looking haggard after a weekend in jail, told the judge on Tuesday that she had suffered a relapse and used the illegal drug methamphetamine.</p>
<p>&quot;I admit (giving in) to the pressure and having a relapse,&quot; Fleiss said.</p>
<p>Her lawyer, Donald Marks, told the U.S. District Court that Fleiss had called him last week to tell him she had used drugs. Marks said he notified the U.S. Attorney's office and she was subsequently arrested at her Santa Monica boutique on Friday night.</p>
<p>&quot;Miss Fleiss has been clean for two years and was tested extensively, sometimes three times a week.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first incident in the two years she has been under intense pressure. The fact that she came clean (about drug use) has got to mean something. It shows her honesty, forthrightness and willingness to accept that she reverted back to using drugs,&quot; said Marks.</p>
<p>After discussing Fleiss' record in chambers with a representative of the Impact House drug rehabilitation centre, Judge Marshall ordered her to enter the residential programme rather than remaining in prison awaiting federal sentencing and the start of the new state trial next week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
