<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88565" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT wheat closes lower on weather, soybean drop.</title>
<headline>CBOT wheat closes lower on weather, soybean drop.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Improved weather for seeding the U.S. winter wheat crop and another sharp drop in soybeans drove CBOT wheat futures to a lower close, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was more fund liquidation,&quot; said Ron Kucha of O'Connor and Co. &quot;Funds usually liquidate for two or three days in a row so we'll see what tomorrow brings.&quot;</p>
<p>Weather forecasts for the U.S. Midwest indicated conditions more conducive for seeding the 1997 U.S. winter wheat crop.</p>
<p>Traders said wheat futures were recently boosted into near neutral territory on daily charts.</p>
<p>The nine-day relative strength index (RSI) had dropped to 23.7 on September 17 and Tuesday had moved back to 50.842.</p>
<p>Technicians generally view an RSI of 20 or less as indicative of an oversold market while a level of 80 or more is considered an overbought market.</p>
<p>The 14 day RSI Tuesday was at 46.063 and the December contract closed above its 18 day moving average (MA) of $4.30-7/8 and below the 40 day MA at $4.46-3/4.</p>
<p>Wheat closed one to 3-3/4 cents per bushel lower, with December down 2-1/4 at $4.33-3/4. March was 3-3/4 lower at $4.18-3/4.</p>
<p>Wheat futures volume was estimated at 19,000 contracts, down slightly from 19,873 Monday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In wheat options, Refco Inc sold 350 December $4.50 calls at 8-1/2, the traders said. Continental Grain bought 250 March $4.20 calls and sold 250 March $4.60 calls at 13-3/4 cents.</p>
<p>Wheat options volume was estimated at 5,000 contracts, down from 5,620 Monday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
