<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88560" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY property taxes up despite more state aid -- group.</title>
<headline>NY property taxes up despite more state aid -- group.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Even though New York State has sharply boosted how much aid it sends to cities and towns, local property taxes have doubled and likely will keep rising unless stricter limits are imposed, a study found.</p>
<p>On average, the amount New York state residents paid rose by 77 percent to $4,548 from $2,572 from 1984 to 1994, CHANGE New York found, citing data provided by the state Office of Real Property Tax Services.</p>
<p>Yet at the same time, aid from the state jumped by almost the same amount, climbing $6.7 billion or 75 percent. As this leap exceeded the rise in the state's net receipts from state personal income taxes, the non-profit group said Albany in effect had given the localities all of the additional funds it collected.</p>
<p>While the data on state aid do not include Medicaid reimbursements, CHANGE-NY, noted that while counties and New York City tend to blame their higher property taxes on this progam, it accounts for less than half the rise.</p>
<p>The tax lobbyists faulted the state's constitutional tax limits on counties, cities and towns, saying they had failed to halt big rises in property taxes. In the 10-year period that was studied, total assessments rose to $23.4 billion from $11.8 billion.</p>
<p>While the state constitution bars cities and villages from setting property taxes in any given year at more than two percent of the preceding five-year average of assessed valuation, local law can raise the cap to two percent.</p>
<p>And no tax limit applies to towns, which increased property taxes by 90 percent or $934 million, or school districts, which assessed $8.5 billion in 1994, more than double the $4.2 billion level in 1984.</p>
<p>&quot;Absent taxing limits on local taxing authority -- limits that apply to school districts and towns as well as counties, cities and villages -- there is little to prevent property taxes in New York from continuing to rise faster than property owners can afford to pay them,&quot; the group concluded.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
