<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88586" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Perot rebuffed in U.S. court to get into debates.</title>
<headline>Perot rebuffed in U.S. court to get into debates.</headline>
<byline>Michael Posner</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Presidential candidate Ross Perot failed in a federal court challenge on Tuesday to get included in televised presidential debates between President Bill Clinton and Republican challenger Bob Dole.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Thomas Hogan rejected a request by the Reform Party leader for a restraining order to prohibit the debates unless he was a participant in the two encounters, the first scheduled for this Sunday in Hartford, Connecticut.</p>
<p>The ruling also applied to another minor party candidate, John Hagelin of the Natural Law Party, who had also sought a court ruling to stop the debates unless he was included.</p>
<p>Jamin Raskin, one of Perot's lawyers, said there would be an appeal to the U.S. District Court of Appeals.</p>
<p>The second presidential debate is scheduled for Oct. 16 in San Diego and a vice presidential debate between Vice President Al Gore and Republican Jack Kemp is due to be held in St. Petersburg, Fla., on Oct. 9.</p>
<p>Raskin and lawyers for Perot and Hagelin argued that the bipartisan Commission on Presidential Debates violated Federal Election Commission rules that sponors of debates must use &quot;objective&quot; criteria to select debaters.</p>
<p>They said their candidates qualified under objective criteria used by the debate commission which has been making recommendations for presidential debates since 1988.</p>
<p>Among the criteria were that candidates should be on enough state ballots to be able to win the necessary 270 electoral votes to become president.</p>
<p>The lawyers for Perot and Hagelin argued that the debate commission had used &quot;subjective&quot; criteria in deciding that only Clinton and Dole had &quot;a realistic chance&quot; of getting elected in the Nov 5 race.</p>
<p>Perot's legal team argued that the debate commission consulted &quot;pollsters and pundits&quot; in interviews to decide whether Perot had a realistic chance of winning and decided he did not in violation of his rights.</p>
<p>Perot's lawyer argued that rules of the Federal Election Commission had been violated and rules of that commission and the debate commission were unconstitutional.</p>
<p>Lewis Loss, a lawyer for the bipartisan debate commission, argued that the commission had no powers to force anyone to debate even if Hogan said Perot and Hagelin should debate.</p>
<p>A ruling requiring Perot or Hagelin to debate would threaten the debates taking place at all, Loss said.</p>
<p>He said an order from the court affecting the debates &quot;poses a substantial risk that there would be no debates.&quot; Loss argued that both Clinton and Dole were &quot;skittish&quot; anyway about debating in the first place.</p>
<p>Negotiators for Clinton and Dole agreed with the commission's recommendation for only Clinton-Dole debates although Clinton had preferred that Perot be included, while Dole opposed Perot's inclusion for fear he could take votes away from him.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
