<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88598" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US spot prods mixed after close, Gulf gasoline up.</title>
<headline>US spot prods mixed after close, Gulf gasoline up.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot products prices were mixed after the NYMEX close on Tuesday tracking futures, with differentials getting little lasting bounce from news of a fire Monday at Conoco's refinery in Lake Charles, La.</p>
<p>Conoco confirmed that a fire had broken out at its 180,000 barrel per day plant late Monday afternoon and that three people were injured, but said the incident had &quot;no output impact.&quot;</p>
<p>But differentials on Gulf Coast M3-grade conventional unleaded gasoline did briefly firm about over 1.25 cents a gallon as traders covered their shorts upon the deadline for scheduling back-28th cycle material, traders said.</p>
<p>They later retreated to about 3.0 cents below the November print, still 0.65 firmer than Monday diffs. &quot;But where are the buyers?&quot; one Gulf trader asked, saying M3 sellers had gotten few nibbles after the morning flurry of buying.</p>
<p>New York reformulated A4-grade reformulated, meanwhile, remained about 0.25 cent above the November print.</p>
<p>&quot;The switch to distillates is helping gasoline a lot,&quot; another Gulf trader said, adding heating oil supplies were becoming better offered.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, heating oil differentials were holding stable in both centers as November futures edged slightly lower.</p>
<p>The market awaited release later in the afternoon of new weekly API data, with traders predicting they will show a moderate gain in distillate stocks and a small rise in gasoline supplies.</p>
<p>-- Ransdell Pierson, New York Energy Desk 212 859-1632</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
