<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88627" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Steps weighed to fight sudden rolls by Boeing 737s.</title>
<headline>Steps weighed to fight sudden rolls by Boeing 737s.</headline>
<byline>Robert Trautman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal air safety officials on Tuesday weighed changes to the rudder area of Boeing 737 aircraft after the still-unexplained crashes of two of the popular airliners, but they deferred action for two weeks.</p>
<p>The changes proposed to the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) by its staff would try to prevent the sudden and uncontrolled rolls -- rotations around a plane's long axis -- thought to have caused the crashes.</p>
<p>The changes would take the form of recommendations that the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) set new safety standards for the approximately 2,600 737s flying worldwide.</p>
<p>The FAA in August proposed some other changes to the 737's control system but said the planes were already safe and the changes were to make them still safer.</p>
<p>While NTSB officials think the sharp, sudden rolls caused the two accidents, they have not yet found out why the 737s went into rolls.</p>
<p>In one case, in 1994 at Pittsburgh, a USAir 737 went into a sudden roll and crashed, killing all 132 people on board. In the other, at Colorado Springs, Colorado, in 1991, a UAL Corp. United Airlines 737 rolled and crashed, killing 25 people.</p>
<p>Officials said the recommendations might not get to the causes of the accidents but &quot;would improve the level of flight safety&quot; of the planes.</p>
<p>The NTSB said recommendations to the FAA would have the agency require Boeing to make changes to preclude loss of control of the plane by the pilot if the rudder shifted and locked into an extreme position.</p>
<p>Officials explained that the rudder usually automatically shifted to prevent yawing -- movement of the nose from side to side -- but if it went into an extreme position, it could send the plane into a sharp roll.</p>
<p>The board was also considering a requirement that indicators be installed in the cockpit to tell the pilot the position of the rudder. There is now no such indicator to tell a pilot if unusual actions of the plane might be due to a so-called hard-over rudder position.</p>
<p>It also considered new yaw control system redundancies.</p>
<p>The NTSB was also weighing a recommendation that pilots be given improved training in responding to unusual plane movements caused by mechanical problems as well as those due to weather phenomena.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
