<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88703" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - U.S. T-bond volatility lower post-NAPM.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - U.S. T-bond volatility lower post-NAPM.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for U.S. Treasury bond futures options were lower just after noon on Tuesday as traders took advantage of a window between releases of key data to adjust for time decay.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it (volatility) was overpriced on Friday last week. They (market makers) came in on Monday and never took anything out in terms of theta. So it was running rather rich coming into today,&quot; said one options dealer, speaking from the floor of the Chicago Board of Trade.</p>
<p>Volatilities held firm into the release of NAPM data in the morning but then sold off, he said.  </p>
<p>Traders were forced to discount volatility because it was their only chance ahead of Friday's release of U.S. employment data for September, he said.</p>
<p>This occurred even though bond futures rallied on the National Association of Purchasing Management data, and the market remained jittery about the upcoming employment report.</p>
<p>&quot;I think generally you want to buy it (volatility) but if you start taking out days without taking out the theta, you'll end up with volatilities over 12 and 13 percent,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Fred Sturm, debt options and futures analyst at Fuji Securities, questioned how much faith the market really has that futures can climb higher.</p>
<p>&quot;How much more bullishness is there, really? We've had our big short-covering rally after the Fed decided to sit on its haunches last week,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lower volatility could indicate that options traders believe futures are likely to be stable near-term, he said.</p>
<p>He discounted theories that a weak employment component to Tuesday's NAPM data could foreshadow weakness in Friday's employment data, which in turn could help futures rally.  </p>
<p>&quot;That's neither a strong nor a reliable correlation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At 1215 CDT/1715 GMT, implied volatilities for November and December T-bond options were each down 0.25 percentage point at 10.75 percent and 10.25 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been no steady trade that would stand out. It was quite busy in the morning before the number and then directly afterwards, but it's been quiet ever since,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Implied volatilities for eurodollar futures options were flat at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange, dealers said.  </p>
<p>December at-the-money eurodollar options were trading at 11.7 percent while March was quoted at 15.85 percent.</p>
<p>One CME dealer said he did not expect to see volatilities fall until after Friday's employment data.</p>
<p>&quot;Vols going to hold up pretty well all week,&quot; he said. &quot;You should see some premium buying by people taking some shots at what they see for the number.&quot;</p>
<p>-Danielle Bochove,(312)408-8750</p>
<p>E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
