<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88716" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. planning to remove carrier from Gulf.</title>
<headline>U.S. planning to remove carrier from Gulf.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States is planning to remove the aircraft carrier Carl Vinson from the Gulf next week, leaving only the carrier Enterprise in the waterway near Iraq, a U.S. defense official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Barring unforseen circumstances, the tentative plan is to take it (the Vinson) out next week,&quot; the official, who asked not to be identified, told Reuters. Defense Secretary William Perry said last week that Iraq was &quot;backing off&quot; from a recent confrontation with Washington.  </p>
<p>The move of the Vinson, which is scheduled to return to its home port in Bremerton, Washington, after six months at sea, would leave the Enterprise in the strategic waterway to watch over southern Iraq. An announcement of the move is expected by the Pentagon this week.</p>
<p>The Enterprise was recently moved to the Gulf from the Adriatic to join the Vinson after Iraqi President Saddam Hussein's military forces attacked Kurds in northern Iraq and Iraqi missiles were fired at U.S. warplanes policing &quot;no-fly&quot; zones over northern and southern Iraq.</p>
<p>Iraq at first vowed to keep shooting missiles at U.S. and allied aircraft, but later promised to halt such attacks, which followed a strike by American air- and sea-launched cruise missiles against air defense targets in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;All of the evidence that I've seen in the last four or five days is positive,&quot; Perry told reporters traveling with him on a European trip last week. &quot;I do truly believe that Iraq is backing off the threatening actions they were taking a week ago, but we will watch it very carefully, very carefully, every day, every hour.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
