<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88806" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. corp bond issuers gear up to come to market.</title>
<headline>U.S. corp bond issuers gear up to come to market.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A slew of new issues are expected to rain down on the corporate bond arena as issuers gear up to bring debt to market, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The tone in the market is very optimistic...we're seeing quite a bit of issuance coming to market,&quot; said one syndicate source.</p>
<p>Dealers said many names are circulating the new issue arena; but it's difficult to gauge how much business will come as no official dates have been set on upcoming deals.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're hearing a lot of names in the market but it's tough to peg when these deals are coming because no official calendar exists,&quot; another syndicate source said.</p>
<p>Dealers expect a recent drop in U.S. Treasury yields to spur more issuers to tap the primary market while the rate environment remains favorable for financing debt.</p>
<p>The following issues are expected to come to market, syndicate sources said.</p>
<p>Union Pacific Resources is expected to price $400 million in A3/A-rated two-part debt consisting of $200 million in 10-year debt and $200 million of 30-year debt.  </p>
<p>Loewen Group is expected to price $350 million in a two-part senior guaranteed notes deal consisting of $175 million five-year debt and $175 million seven-year debt via Smith Barney.</p>
<p>Medpartners is also expected to tap the market with $300 million in Baa3/BBB-rated 10-year debt also via Smith Barney.</p>
<p>Allegiance Healthcare is expected to issue $500 million in a three-part debt via Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>Airtouch Communications is expected to tap the market with $250 million in seven-year debt via Lehman Brothers.  </p>
<p>Among foreign issuers, Argentina launched its $750 million 10-year bond issue via joint lead managers Goldman Sachs and Salomon Brothers. Price talk on the issue is 445 to 450 basis points over the 10-year U.S. Treasury note.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm hearing the Argentina deal is a blowout in London,&quot; said one high-grade syndicate source in New York.</p>
<p>Brazil is also expected to price $750 million in global debt in a five or ten-year maturity this week, dealers said.</p>
<p>In addition, South Africa is gearing up to launch its first yankee issue ever via Merrill Lynch, sources added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
