<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88918" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: Arafat to visit France after Washington summit.</title>
<headline>Arafat to visit France after Washington summit.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat is to travel to France on Friday for talks with President Jacques Chirac, French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Arafat will be in Paris on Friday night coming back from Washington and will be able to meet the president,&quot; he said during a meeting of EU foreign ministers.</p>
<p>Arafat is currently in Washington to attend a U.S.-led Middle East peace summit due to begin later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He held talks in Luxembourg on Monday night with some EU foreign ministers before travelling to the United States.</p>
<p>France, which has sought a greater role in the Middle East peace process, has been reported to be upset at being excluded from the Washington summit.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Jacques Rummelhardt put a brave face on French frustrations when he told reporters in Paris: &quot;We wish sucess to the Washington meeting. Everything that can contribute to restore calm and get the peace process going again is welcome.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that France believed there was no alternative to the application of agreements signed between the Palestinians and Israel's past Labour government, including those calling for final status talks about Palestinian areas.</p>
<p>He said President Jacques Chirac and de Charette spoke to Arafat by telephone several times in the past few days and he said he expressed regrets France was not invited to the talks in Washington.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
