<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="88917" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Yemen, Eritrea agree arbitration over Red Sea.</title>
<headline>Yemen, Eritrea agree arbitration over Red Sea.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yemen and Eritrea have agreed to go to an arbitration court to solve their territorial dispute over islands located on tanker routes at the Red Sea's southern entrance, France said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The French Foreign Ministry, which mediated in the row, said the two countries reached the agreement on Monday and would sign a compromise on Thursday in Paris creating an arbitration court.</p>
<p>&quot;The two sides agreed on all the provisions of an arbitration compromise creating an arbitration court to settle their dispute,&quot; the ministry said.</p>
<p>Arab Yemen and African Eritrea, facing each other across the Red Sea, both claim sovereignty over the small, arid Hanish islands.</p>
<p>They asked the United Nations to mediate after the dispute triggered clashes which killed at least 12 people last December. U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali turned the negotiating process over to France, which offered international arbitration procedures.</p>
<p>Egypt and Ethiopia had also exerted mediation efforts to end the conflict.</p>
<p>The islands are near vital shipping lanes used by more than 100 ships daily carrying 125,000 barrels of oil shipped by Gulf producers to customers in Europe via Egypt's Suez Canal.</p>
<p>The conflict took a turn for the worse last August when Yemen threatened to take military action if mediation failed to defuse a crisis triggered by dispatch of Eritrean troops to Lesser Hanish island.</p>
<p>Eritrea later said it had withdrawn its forces.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ERTRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
