<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89024" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Soaring Olivetti debts unsettle investors.</title>
<headline>Soaring Olivetti debts unsettle investors.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Olivetti's soaring debts have again highlighted the struggling information technology company's poor state as analysts prepare to question it later this week on financial and strategic issues.</p>
<p>Group debts almost doubled in July and August and analysts said they were still in the dark over whether this was a seasonal hiatus or heralded a worsening of the situation.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no record of debt movements month by month, so the the new figure highlights the need for a clear strategy to get the debt down,&quot; said one Milan-based industrial analyst.</p>
<p>Olivetti announced late Monday that its debt had surged to 2.39 trillion lire ($1.6 billion) at the end of August from 1.26 trillion lire in June. Although the company said it would come down by the end of the year, it gave no details.</p>
<p>It said its debt had increased due to a seasonal rise in payments to suppliers of around 450 billion lire, heavy spending on restructuring and investments in its 41.3 percent owned mobile phone consortium Omnitel.</p>
<p>&quot;The debt level is a big surprise and will make Olivetti's task of recovery more difficult due to the high cost of debt servicing,&quot; said an analyst with a London securities house.</p>
<p>The rise in debt levels unnerved market sentiment and, with investors unsure what this meant for company strategy and possible sell-offs, its shares drifted off 5.42 percent to 531 lire on a lower Milan stock market.</p>
<p>The rising debt level drew attention to meetings with analysts in Milan on Thursday and in London on Friday where Olivetti's new chief executive, Roberto Colaninno, will try to soothe the nerves of the group's long-suffering investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Colaninno will have to give investors a clear perception about what is really happening at Olivetti,&quot; said the Milan-based analyst.</p>
<p>Analysts said it would need to answer strategic questions on what will happen to its personal computer company, what businesses are due to be sold off and what the future holds for its fast-growing mobile and fixed-line telecommunications interests.</p>
<p>Further pressure was exerted on Olivetti by Italy's small shareholders association and the committee of small Olivetti shareholders which demanded the election by shareholders of a new board as the only way of saving the company.</p>
<p>The two shareholder groups have asked foreign funds, which control up to 25 percent of Olivetti's shares, not to be content with just one member on its board representing shareholders, as suggested by Olivetti.</p>
<p>Foreign fund investors want to nominate lawyer Dario Trevisan as a non-executive director. Trevisan has voted on behalf of foreign funds at Italian shareholder meetings but has no previous experience as a non-executive director.</p>
<p>The group on Monday confirmed its first-half 1996 pretax loss of 440.2 billion lire, first published in early September, and an operating loss of 80.8 billion lire.</p>
<p>The day after Olivetti published its half year figures, its director general in charge of finance and auditing, Renzo Francesconi, resigned after challenging the accuracy of the company's results.</p>
<p>This led stock market watchdog Consob into inquiries into the financial affairs of Olivetti, which on Monday said 150 pages of details on its financial accounts had answered all the questions posed by Consob. ($1=1,520 lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
