<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89037" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks ends lower in consolidation.</title>
<headline>French stocks ends lower in consolidation.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares finished with losses with the market consolidating after recent strong gains, traders said. The market largely shrugged off a weaker-than-expected report from the U.S. National Association of Purchasing Managers.</p>
<p>Stocks in the luxury goods sector rose, while oils and Air Liquide declined.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index ended down 9.60 points or 0.45 percent at 2,123.21, while the CAC-40 futures contract was down at 2,128 from 2,134 on Monday's close.</p>
<p>Volume was a solid 4.55 billion francs.  </p>
<p>* In the luxury sector LVMH firms 0.09 percent to 1,122 francs, Dior 1.32 percent to 612, and Hermes 3.96 to 1,259. All benefit from dollar appreciation and catch-up effect after recent underperformance</p>
<p>* Sanofi gains 3.02 percent to 436 francs, boosted by registration of the Irbesartan hypertension drug, which is expected to generate between $500 million-$1 billion in sales when it is marketed</p>
<p>* Accor gains 2.82 percent to 656 francs on newspaper reports a Cie Generale des Eaux executive, Jean-Marc Espalioux, could be named as the next chairman.  </p>
<p>* Air Liquide eases 1.88 percent to 785 francs onthe back of its first-half results. Dupont-Denant cut its recommendation.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
