<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89045" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish seize half a tonne of cocaine on boat.</title>
<headline>Irish seize half a tonne of cocaine on boat.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Marshall</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish customs officials said on Tuesday they had discovered more cocaine aboard a trawler seized in a southern port and now believe the haul to be one of the largest ever shipments of drugs from South America to Europe.</p>
<p>Liam Hurley, director of the Customs National Drugs Team, said more than half a tonne of cocaine had now been found in secret compartments inside the Sea Mist, a converted trawler impounded at the weekend while en route from Venezuela.</p>
<p>&quot;It's huge. We have found 420 packets and two bales of cocaine,&quot; Hurley told Irish radio. &quot;The definitive weight and purity will be determined by the police forensic laboratory, but we would estimate it as somewhere between 500 and 600 kg.&quot;</p>
<p>Irish police said they had arrested five crew members -- two West Indian men, two men with addresses in England, and a 19-year-old Venezuelan woman. The woman's two-year-old son also arrived in Ireland on the trawler.</p>
<p>Police said the trawler left Venezuela in September and was heading for continental Europe when storms and engine trouble forced it into the shelter of Cork harbour on the south coast of Ireland on Friday.</p>
<p>Locals became suspicious of the trawler -- it was not flying a flag and crew members gave different reasons for its presence in the area -- and the police were alerted.</p>
<p>Irish police said they believed the shipment was destined for France or Denmark, but were investigating the possibility of an Irish connection in the operation. Two of the ship's crew members were arrested at a private house in Cork on Sunday.</p>
<p>Information about the seizure was being passed to Interpol and more arrests elsewhere in Europe were possible, police said.</p>
<p>Ireland's miles of remote coastline make an ideal haven for drugs smuggling and custom officials say the country has become a hub for the international drugs trade, used as a trans-shipment point for the import of drugs into Europe.</p>
<p>In 1995, the Customs National Drugs Team seized drugs with a street value of more than 35 million punts ($56.13 million)in Ireland. But the haul discovered aboard the trawler dwarfs this total, with an estimated value of around 200 million punts depending on purity, Irish radio said.</p>
<p>($1=.6235 Punt)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
