<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89062" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Prada reconstructs 90s woman - inside out.</title>
<headline>Italy's Prada reconstructs 90s woman - inside out.</headline>
<byline>Charlotte Cooper</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian designer Miuccia Prada deconstructed womenswear at the Milan spring/summer 1997 shows on Tuesday and put it back together again -- inside out.</p>
<p>Prada, using the transparency of chiffon, set sliplike skirts and tunics over more conventional linen and silk underskirts, giving the appearance of clothing worn inside out.</p>
<p>&quot;The underskirt becomes a skirt and vice versa, the jacket becomes a shirt, the under can be over,&quot; Prada said at the display on the third day of the Milan ready-to-wear shows.</p>
<p>Cream underskirts were overlaid with gauzy blues, blood or wine reds and moss greens and set off either by platform wedge black patent leather sandals or light-hued, high-heeled shoes decorated with a darker vine motif and clasped at the ankle.</p>
<p>Skirt lengths varied, with straight underskirts long or mini and overlaid with a loose sheath of chiffon, while hemlines on some poplin skirts dropped lower behind and fanned into a tail.</p>
<p>Blouses were either entirely transparent or backed by camisole tops with &quot;the demure and the immodest alternating... the lingerie is an integrating part of the transparent.&quot;</p>
<p>Prada also moved away from her retro-70s look to include a short-cropped scarlet jacket trimmed with a mandarin collar, cuffs and lower border in cream, worn by supermodel Kate Moss.</p>
<p>Short nightdress-style frocks scooped out at the neckline and trimmed with a small frill were on offer with the top layer in one shade of red and the underlay in another.</p>
<p>For evening, Prada introduced rich embroideries, demure dark vines and willow-leaf patterns set on light backgrounds and full length mandarin collared tunics split up both sides to reveal shimmering light golden underskirts.</p>
<p>Design house Byblos provided a bright and bubbly contrast with a collection of fluorescent lime greens, fuchsia and orange in slip dresses, tailored jackets and close-fitting minis.</p>
<p>For sophisticated daywear, Byblos paraded wide-legged &quot;pyjama pants&quot; and broad-shouldered trouser suits in cream and black pinstripes, shaped at the waist and set off by outsized flowers at the lapel.</p>
<p>Models wore black off-the-shoulder mini and long sheathes trimmed at low necklines with black feathers, filmy apricot or coral slips with lacy, scallopped hems and red tights as well as outfits with a hotter toned orange, green and red flower print.</p>
<p>Glamour designer Gianni Versace was presenting his second line Istante later on Tuesday while on Wednesday design duo Dolce &amp; Gabbana and stylist Krizia unveil their latest collections.</p>
<p>Thursday and Friday bring fashion house Gucci and designer Gianfranco Ferre, and Versace presents his main collection on Saturday with Giorgio Armani closing the shows with his top line Giorgio Armani label on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFAS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
