<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89076" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Ahold upbeat about Spanish joint venture.</title>
<headline>Ahold upbeat about Spanish joint venture.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch supermarket giant Ahold NV made a long-awaited breakthrough into the Spanish food retail market on Tuesday, forging a 50/50 joint venture with Caprabo, set to contribute to group profits in the medium term.</p>
<p>The first move by the joint venture, dubbed Store 2000, was the takeover of 10 supermarkets in Madrid in a deal worth &quot;several millions of guilders&quot;, Ahold said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our two companies plan to jointly develop a national supermarket-hypermarket business in Spain, excluding Catalonia and the Baleares, where Caprabo has its own supermarket operations,&quot; Ahold said.</p>
<p>Spokesman Hans Gobes was upbeat about the venture, which he called a mid to longer term investment.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe we can generate -- in the next five to 10 years -- the same growth as we see in Portugal,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;But it's a much bigger market (in Spain) so the scale is considerable.&quot;</p>
<p>In the second quarter of 1995, sales in local currency at Ahold's Pingo Doce and Feira Nova stores in Portugal rose 14.0 percent.</p>
<p>Barcelona-based Caprabo was founded in May 1959 and operates 90 supermarkets and hypermarkets with total sales of 85 billion pesetas and a staff of 3,500.</p>
<p>Gobes said the joint venture would not affect the group's earnings per share target of 15 percent growth per annum.</p>
<p>He added the group would still look out for acquisition opportunities in southern Europe. &quot;We have always looked in the southern part of Europe -- in Spain and Italy -- and we will continue to do that now with our start in Spain,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gobes said further acquisitions by the joint venture in Spain would occur in time.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that we can grow in a steady way and that there are quite a number of opportunities in Spain so we will deliver when we have another one,&quot; Gobes said.</p>
<p>He said Ahold aimed to be a dominant player in the Spanish food retail market. &quot;It's too early to predict market share, but we've always believed that we have to be market leader or number two, so we want to be dominant players (in Spain),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been looking for quite a number of years for a good partner (in Spain) and now we believe we've found an excellent one,&quot; Gobes added.</p>
<p>&quot;They have excellent management and know-how about food and non-food retailing. They know the territory very well...so we really have the right team to make excellent progress.&quot;</p>
<p>By 1350 GMT, Ahold shares were up 0.70 guilders at 97.60, off an earlier new year record high of 97.80 guilders.</p>
<p>-- Jennifer Scott, Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
