<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89075" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Carmakers battle over stagnant European market.</title>
<headline>Carmakers battle over stagnant European market.</headline>
<byline>Christine Tierney</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The world's carmarkers unveiled dozens of eye-catching models at the Paris car show on Tuesday, hoping to gain an edge in a cut-throat but stagnant European market.</p>
<p>Manufacturers packed every segment of the market with new entries, ranging from Ford Motor Co's Ka minicar to Porsche's sporty new Boxster, to inspire reluctant customers when the show opens to the public on Thursday.</p>
<p>The French carmakers' association CCFA began a two-day press preview on a high note on Tuesday, announcing an 86 percent surge in new car sales in France for the month of September.</p>
<p>But carmakers attribute the September sales rally in France to last-minute purchases ahead of the expiry on Monday of a new-cars-for-old rebate scheme and say the outlook is bleak.</p>
<p>They expect French car sales to plunge in coming months, dragging down the European market.</p>
<p>&quot;For 1997, forecasts are still very pessimistic with no expected growth,&quot; the chairman of French carmaker PSA Peugeot Citroen Jacques Calvet told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said the main source of pressure was fiscal belt-tightening throughout Europe as governments struggle to meet the economic criteria set in the Maastricht Treaty to create a single European currency.</p>
<p>&quot;While these policies might in the end encourage economic recovery in Europe, in the very short term they are sure to cause stagnation,&quot; Calvet said.</p>
<p>Consulting firm DRI/McGraw Hill expects western European car sales to grow by just 0.6 percent in 1997 after an estimated rise this year of 5.8 percent to 12.7 million.</p>
<p>The British and Italian markets are expected to grow by more than two percent and the German market is expected to grow 1.3 percent, but the French market is expected to shrink by nearly six percent in 1997, said DRI car analyst Arthur Maher.</p>
<p>&quot;The Italian market isn't very good right now,&quot; Fiat SpA managing director Roberto Testore told reporters.</p>
<p>He said third-quarter sales were not encouraging, but the group expected to boost sales in the rest of Europe by 40 percent this year, helped by a renewed product line.</p>
<p>Fiat's success in Europe is also due to the Italian lira's relative weakness against the German mark and the French franc although the Italian currency has rebounded from its lows.</p>
<p>In a market distorted by incentive schemes, currency disparities, Japanese import quotas and a fierce price war, carmakers are trying at the show to shift the spotlight back onto products designed for evolving tastes and demographics.</p>
<p>But they are bolstering their launches with aggressive marketing campaigns in a sign that suggests the price rivalry in Europe is not about to subside.</p>
<p>Renault announced last week that it would lower car prices through outright reductions or by adding equipment at no extra charge. &quot;To sell cars you need two things -- cars that people feel like buying, and prices they can afford,&quot; Renault chairman Louis Schweitzer said in an interview with the Figaro newspaper.</p>
<p>Volvo Cars will launch a marketing offensive in the fourth quarter to recapture lost market share in Europe. &quot;Our strategy now is to work according to a quarter-by-quarter attack scheme,&quot; the president of Volvo's Europe marketing division Hans-Olov Olsson told Reuters.</p>
<p>Fiat is offering its own new-cars-for-old rebate in France.</p>
<p>The Peugeot group said it was not planning to match its rivals' offers. &quot;We have always considered that our role was to discern the tastes of our clients...in terms of price, security, quality,&quot; Calvet said.</p>
<p>He said the group had succeeded in preserving its share of the European market this year to rank third among the Big Six.</p>
<p>But the competition is expected to widen as carmakers tackle new niches to broaden their model line-ups and establish a presence in promising segments such as minicars and multi-purpose vehicles expected to outpace the overall market.</p>
<p>Mercedes-Benz made its debut in the minicar segment with the introduction at the show of a luxury A class model.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
