<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89119" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal main opposition leader puts job on line.</title>
<headline>Portugal main opposition leader puts job on line.</headline>
<byline>Jose Barata</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of the main opposition to Portugal's minority Socialist government has threatened to resign unless his party backs proposals for internal reform.</p>
<p>In a move that could turn up the political heat in Portugal, conservative Social Democrat chief Marcelo Rebelo de Sousa told Reuters he would step down if a national congress this weekend spurned his call for change.</p>
<p>The withdrawal of Rebelo de Sousa, just a week after the leader of the small, right-wing Popular Party stood down, would plunge the whole centre-right of Portuguese politics into crisis.</p>
<p>It would leave the Socialists, four seats short of a majority in the 230-seat parliament, virtually unchallenged on the political front.</p>
<p>&quot;If my proposals are not approved...I will explain to the congress that (that means) they want another leadership and not mine,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview on Monday night.</p>
<p>The constitutional expert and former political commentator, who took over as head of the party after it lost power for the first time in 17 years in elections in 1995, will present a package of measures.</p>
<p>He wants to give more power to the central party machine in the choice of parliamentary candidates in order to weaken the role of local party barons. Other changes include the direct election of local party officials, the updating of membership lists and reform of the system of financing.</p>
<p>On the direct election issue, however, he is opposed by the powerful youth wing and the local party in Oporto, Portugal's second city, which both want direct election extended to include the party leader and the national committee.</p>
<p>Both are currently chosen by the party congress.</p>
<p>All proposals must be approved by a 60 percent majority of the congress which meets in Lisbon from October 4-6.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident that people see that this reorganisation is necessary,&quot; the party leader said. &quot;(And that) only my leadership prevents the party plunging in the coming months and years into crisis,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The fast-talking Rebelo de Sousa, who is not a member of parliament, has struggled to establish his authority over the traditionally fractious party which was dominated for a decade until the last election by former prime minister Anibal Cavaco Silva.</p>
<p>Opinion polls show Rebelo de Sousa trailing the ex-premier by a large margin in the estimation of the party faithful and the PSD has not closed any of the gap on the Socialists, who won 112 seats in the October 1, 1995 vote.</p>
<p>The PSD has 88 while the remaining seats are split equally between the Communists and the Popular Party, whose leader Manuel Monteiro announced his resignation last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
