<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89125" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Eurotunnel continues talks with creditor banks.</title>
<headline>Eurotunnel continues talks with creditor banks.</headline>
<byline>Pierre Tran</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Troubled Channel Tunnel operator Eurotunnel kept up intensive talks with its bankers on Tuesday in a desperate bid to keep going.</p>
<p>The co-chairmen of the Anglo-French company, Alistair Morton and Patrick Ponsolle, were negotiating with six banks to break a logjam on debt refinancing after a mandate expired on Monday for court-appointed mediators who have been helping in the talks.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel has been seeking to rejig around 70 billion francs ($14 billion) of debt and unpaid interest owed to its syndicate of 225 banks since it froze payments last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The negotiations are continuing,&quot; a Eurotunnel spokeswoman told Reuters. &quot;It's very, very hard and every millimetre counts. It's rather like &quot;Mission: Impossible',&quot; she said, referring to the cult action film and TV series.</p>
<p>The stakes in the negotiations were raised by Eurotunnel in February when it asked the president of the Paris commercial court, Jean-Pierre Mattei, to name Jean-Pierre Badinter and Lord Wakeham as mediators.</p>
<p>That move infuriated the banks, which saw it as the first legal step that could lead to a loss of control and a court-driven solution, with the implicit threat of an insolvency ruling by the court president if they did not accept.</p>
<p>The court president has the discretion to allow the negotiations to continue if it appeared there were hopes of an agreement. &quot;He could allow a period of a few hours or a few days,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>But overhanging the talks was the insolvency option, if the two sides were unable to strike an accord.</p>
<p>Lawyer Georges Berlioz, adviser to the Adacte Eurotunnel shareholder group, said there were three possibilities -- a debt agreement, no agreement and an insolvency process, or no agreement but the court allows more time for talks.</p>
<p>Although no one wanted insolvency, the consequences were more serious for banks than the shareholders, he said.</p>
<p>Shareholders, at least 600,000 of them in France, have seen at least two-thirds of their investment drain away since they invested in the 1987 flotation at 35 francs per share. The company also issued new shares in 1994 at 24 francs.</p>
<p>Banks have received millions in fees and interest payments.</p>
<p>Under French insolvency rules, the aim is to protect the company as a going concern, with up to 18 months of protection from creditors with a view to a long-term restructuring. Eurotunnel breaks even at the operating level, before its debt service burden, and could continue functioning.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Eurotunnel's share are suspended until the outcome of the talks. The shares closed on Friday at 9.20 francs per share in Paris and 113.5 pence in London.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
