<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89445" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EMU reserve shift to dent dollar, boost Euro role.</title>
<headline>EMU reserve shift to dent dollar, boost Euro role.</headline>
<byline>Mike Dolan</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A single European currency is expected to cause a multi-billion dollar adjustment in global central bank reserves, presenting the biggest challenge to the dollar's dominance as a benchmark currency since World War Two.</p>
<p>Economists estimate that net effect of the reserves shift could depress the value of the U.S. currency over time.</p>
<p>It could also enhance the credibility of the euro by offsetting any flight of private capital to dollars on early uncertainty about the stability of the new currency when it is launched in 1999.</p>
<p>A large reserves windfall from excess dollars in the new euro zone could also be used to reduce government debt, easing concerns about fiscal strains after European economic and monetary union (EMU) and boosting the single currency.</p>
<p>The conclusions are drawn from a number of official and private studies conducted by the European Commission and the U.S. Federal Reserve to private banks and investment houses.</p>
<p>&quot;The impact of EMU on demand for reserves comes against a backdrop of a steady accumulation of dollar reserves by EU countries in recent years,&quot; said Joe Prendergast, foreign exchange strategist at Merrill Lynch in London.</p>
<p>&quot;After EMU, these dollars will become increasingly surplus to requirements.&quot;</p>
<p>Studies estimate the drop in demand for dollar reserves within the European Union (EU) could be as much as $200 billion around or after EMU. EMU is now widely expected to start with between six and eight countries on January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;It is argued that official dollar holdings could decline on the order of 35 percent or more from current dollar holdings, although the range of uncertainty is quite large,&quot; according to a report written in 1994 by Michael Leahy, staff economist at the Board of Governors of the U.S. Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>A reserve imbalance will occur partly because European Union countries starting monetary union will have far more foreign exchange reserves, mostly stored in dollars, than is typically needed by a single currency area or a single central bank.</p>
<p>A possible eight-country euro area of Germany, France, the Netherlands, Belgium, Luxembourg, Austria, Ireland and Finland is estimated to have a total of about $200 billion worth of foreign exchange reserves at present.</p>
<p>The reserves these countries denominate in each other's currencies (mainly German marks) will automatically be converted to euros, or domestic currency, on EMU day. This will lead to the effective disappearance of as much as $50 billion which will no longer be foreign exchange, analysts said.</p>
<p>Yet, even with that reduction in reserves the euro zone will still have $150 billion of reserves, almost entirely in dollars. This is still seen as far greater than needed.</p>
<p>For one, the Maastricht Treaty only requires 50 billion European currency units (about $63 billion) to be transferred to the European Central Bank (ECB) at the start of EMU. That still leaves an excess of about $90 billion in EU coffers.</p>
<p>Another way of looking at optimal levels of ECB reserves suggests that, based on an import-to-reserves ratio consistent with the average in industrial countries at present, the ECB would only need about $80 billion. That corresponds to estimated imports of about $700 billion from outside the euro area.</p>
<p>Even if the European central banks decided to hold $100 billion worth of reserves in the initial days of the euro to enhance the perceived stability of the unit, it would still have about $50 billion of excess dollars. The total excess reserves in the euro zone would then be about $100 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Excess reserves represent an economic loss,&quot; said Avinash Persaud, head of European currency research at J.P. Morgan, who wrote a report on the subject in August.</p>
<p>&quot;Here is capital that fiscally hard-pressed governments will want to put to other more productive uses.&quot;</p>
<p>This extra cash could then be used either to reduce debt levels or relieve the burden on spending and deficits.</p>
<p>On September 20, for example, Belgian central bank governor Alfons Verplaetse said the proceeds of Belgian gold sales in recent years might be used to cut national debt.</p>
<p>J.P. Morgan estimates that if the windfall was used to reduce the budget deficits of the eight countries listed as likely EMU candidates, it would bring down the average deficit to 2.0 percent of gross domestic product. That compares with the three percent target in the Maastricht Treaty.</p>
<p>Goldman Sachs economist Martin Brookes, in a report published in September, said he expected the surplus reserves in the euro zone would be between 45 and 75 billion Ecu ($55 to $95 billion) and would be run down gradually.</p>
<p>&quot;This surplus is too large to be run down abruptly without causing disruption to financial markets,&quot; said Brookes.</p>
<p>Brookes said using reserves to redeem foreign currency debt would be a way of minimising the foreign exchange market impact of winding down the surplus, while being positive for European bond markets by reducing total public sector debt.</p>
<p>However, using the surplus to finance government spending would necessitate selling dollars for euros.</p>
<p>The euro could similarly gain in stature against the dollar from the change in non-ECB central bank reserves and the use of the euro for trade invoicing and investment, analysts said.</p>
<p>After EMU, J.P. Morgan estimates 17 percent of the world's exports will originate in the European core, slightly more than the U.S. and twice that from Japan.</p>
<p>But economists say that additional trade in smaller, less liquid currencies also could be denominated in euros, increasing the euro's share of world trade to as much as 25 percent. That would correspond with extra demand for euros of about $400 billion, they estimate.</p>
<p>Euro demand from non-core, non-European central banks, as a result, would also rise by more than $100 billion.</p>
<p>Even if the total demand for euros -- the excess EU core reserves, the $100 billion demand from non-EU central banks and the $400 billion demand from exporters and importers -- was spread out evenly over 10 years it would mean about $60 billion extra a year would be needed, said Persaud.</p>
<p>This process will sharply accelerate the already steady decline in the dollar's reserve dominance, economists said. At the end of 1994, the dollar accounted for about 63.3 percent of world currency reserves against 79 percent 20 years earlier.</p>
<p>After EMU, the euro's share of world reserves could rise to as high as 30 percent of world reserves, twice the German mark's share currently, Germany's Dresdner Bank estimates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
