<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89686" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: New Thai army chief vows neutrality in polls.</title>
<headline>New Thai army chief vows neutrality in polls.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's new army chief vowed on Tuesday to steer the military clear of politics and said the armed forces would remain neutral in general elections next month.</p>
<p>&quot;The soldiers will be neutral in politics. Every candidate shares an equal right to campaign in the military barracks and soldiers are free to make their own decision while voting,&quot; said General Chetta Tanajaro, who took his post on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no...guidance that will influence their decision to vote for any particular party,&quot; he told reporters after a ceremony to mark his assuming the position.</p>
<p>Chetta replaced General Pramon Phalasin, who retired.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa dissolved parliament last week and called for fresh elections on November 17.</p>
<p>The Thai military, which still wields influence over domestic politics, has launched 17 coups or coup attempts since 1932 when the country switched to parliamentary democracy from absolute monarchy.</p>
<p>The last coup was in February 1991, when the military overthrew the elected government of General Chatichai Choonhavan without firing a shot.</p>
<p>Chatichai now leads the opposition Chat Pattana party and is tipped to be a prime ministerial candidate if his party fares well in the election.</p>
<p>The junta that staged the 1991 coup yielded the government to General Suchinda Kraprayoon, who resigned as military supremo and army chief the day he became prime minister in April 1992.</p>
<p>Protests against Suchinda's taking the premiership without having run for election drew huge demonstrations in Bangkok that were crushed by the military during four bloody days in May 1992.</p>
<p>The crisis ended when King Bhumibol Adulyadej intervened and Suchinda resigned in disgrace.</p>
<p>A new elected government under Chuan Leekpai took office in July 1992. Chuan lost power to Banharn in July 1995 elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
