<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89703" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan steel mills bank on houses as markets shrink.</title>
<headline>Japan steel mills bank on houses as markets shrink.</headline>
<byline>Yuzo Saeki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Faced with waning demand from their mainstay customers in the car and electronics industries, Japanese steel mills are banking on the booming housing market.</p>
<p>Steelmakers such as Nippon Steel Corp, Kawasaki Steel Corp and Sumitomo Metal Industries Ltd are promoting steel-framed housing in a country with a traditional and enduring attachment to wooden homes.</p>
<p>The steelmakers are looking to carve out a lucrative new market for their steel products as many of their traditional customers in Japan's manufacturing industry have shifted their production -- and steel orders -- overseas.</p>
<p>Kawasaki Steel built an experimental steel-framed house in Japan last autumn. In cooperation with locally based contractors, the company plans to start construction of at least six steel-framed houses in the current business year, company officials said.</p>
<p>Nippon Steel and NKK Corp, Japan's two largest steelmakers, said they had also started building several steel-framed houses this year.</p>
<p>In Japan, which has sweltering summers and is prone to earthquakes, houses have traditionally been made of wood.</p>
<p>&quot;We were faced with the question of how to make up for the fall in domestic demand as our big customers moved their production overseas,&quot; said Tomohiko Kimura, a general manager at the flat rolled products division at Sumitomo Metal Industries. &quot;One of the answers was steel-framed houses.&quot;</p>
<p>Steel-framed houses use formed galvanised steel sheet. Coated with zinc to prevent rusting, it has been used mainly for automobile bodies and home appliances such as refrigerators and washing machines.</p>
<p>But domestic demand for steel products has been declining steadily since the early 1990s in light of the so-called &quot;hollowing out&quot; of the economy, caused by major manufacturers shifting production overseas to cut costs.</p>
<p>Demand for galvanised steel sheet in Japan was more than 10 million tonnes in 1991, but had dropped to 8.4 million tonnes in 1995. Galvanised steel sheet is also a very lucrative product for steelmakers. The sheet is currently marketed at around 100,000 yen ($900) per tonne, compared with 45,000 yen ($405) for H-shaped steel bars.</p>
<p>The Kozai Club, a steel industry organisation, is backing the steelmakers' efforts and aims to obtain government approval for this type of steel-framed housing as early as next April.</p>
<p>It said it plans to make the steel frame system available to all home builders throughout Japan in the hope of popularising steel-framed houses. It also plans to set up an organisation for training builders and accrediting contractors.</p>
<p>A Kozai Club official said that if 200,000 steel-framed houses were constructed annually this could create demand for one million tonnes of galvanised steel sheet.</p>
<p>A house with floor space of about 150 square metres would use five tonnes of the steel sheet.</p>
<p>The housing market has been booming in Japan due to rock-bottom interest rates. In 1995, there were 1.47 million housing starts in Japan and economists predict that the figure is likely to reach 1.5 million this year.</p>
<p>&quot;In order for steel-framed houses to attract future home owners, the new housing system must prove that it is as comfortable as wood-structured houses to live in and that it has cost advantages,&quot; said Haruo Masuda, a general manager in Kawasaki Steel's construction materials department.</p>
<p>Kimura said Sumitomo Metal Industries would be able to supply steel frames at a price 20 to 30 percent lower than that of wooden frames.</p>
<p>Michikatsu Hirano, a professor of architecture at the Science University of Tokyo, said that, at least in theory, steel-framed houses could offer the same structural durability and other qualities as conventional houses. ($1=111 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
