<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89782" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia's Mahathir says no need to weaken ringgit.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's Mahathir says no need to weaken ringgit.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said on Tuesday there was no need to weaken the ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see the need to lower the ringgit,&quot; he told reporters at an energy conference.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't like the manipulation of the currency to the point where we lose control,&quot; he said when asked if the country would let the currency weaken.  </p>
<p>He said the ringgit was a convertible currency whose value was affected by movement of other currencies, but there was excessive speculation in the Malaysian unit.</p>
<p>&quot;The deliberate move to lower the value of the ringgit is just to make more money,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reporters were seeking clarification to his comments in New York last week, which had caused a sharp fall in the ringgit.</p>
<p>Mahathir said in New York he believed in the need for a &quot;competitive exchange rate&quot; that reflects what he called &quot;long-term market forces&quot;.  </p>
<p>Dealers quoted Mahathir as reaffirming that central bank intervention in foreign exchange market would be limited to smoothing out sharp short-term fluctuations.</p>
<p>- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
