<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89876" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq sees UN consensus against &quot;hijack&quot; of oil deal.</title>
<headline>Iraq sees UN consensus against &quot;hijack&quot; of oil deal.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq's Foreign Minister Mohammed Saeed al-Sahaf said he saw a consensus among foreign ministers at a UN General Assembly meeting in New York for a speedy implementation of Baghdad's long-delayed oil-for-food deal.</p>
<p>Sahaf, speaking to Iraqi television on Monday night from New York, said all the ministers he met had called for the $2 billion accord, signed in May, to be carried out soon.</p>
<p>&quot;I noticed quite clearly and unambiguously that there is consensus... (among) the Europeans and others,&quot; Sahaf said.</p>
<p>&quot;They are unanimous that implementation of the memorandum of understanding must be speeded up and that the time that was wasted, by countries which are known, was a loss and an unjustified and illegitimate action,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sahaf did not say which ministers he had met.</p>
<p>&quot;The attempt to hijack the Memorandum of Understanding -- and some of them used this expression -- signed by Iraq and the United Nations is illegitimate,&quot; Sahaf added.</p>
<p>Under the plan six years of trade sanctions imposed on Iraq for its 1990 invasion of Kuwait would be eased to allow the export of $2 billion worth of oil over six months. The plan is on hold because of Iraq's military backing of a rebel Kurdish faction over its rivals in the north of the country.</p>
<p>The intervention prompted U.S. missile strikes against Iraqi military installations and warnings that the oil-for-food deal, authorised under U.N. Security Council Resolution 986, would be delayed for months.</p>
<p>The latest delay led the United Nations to appeal for $39.9 million in emergency aid to Iraqi civilians hit by malnutrition and disease. It said clashes in the north &quot;further exacerbated an already dismal humanitarian situation throughout Iraq.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If you read 986 you won't find any clause in the Memorandum of Understanding which permits a third party to interfere in its implementation,&quot; Sahaf said. &quot;Those responsible for its implementation were Iraq and the U.N.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the deal $1.13 billion would be earmarked for purchase of food and medical aid. The rest would go towards reparations to individuals, firms and to Kuwait for damage suffered as a result of Iraq's seven-month occupation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
