<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="89975" id="root" date="1996-10-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - October 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - October 1.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the highlights of stories reported in the Irish press on Tuesday.</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- Loyalist Ulster Defence Association prisoners have withdrawn support for the peace process after the discovery of a car bomb in Belfast city centre planted by dissident republicans.</p>
<p>- The opposition Fianna Fail party, led by Bertie Ahern, have experienced a drop in their ratings in the latest Irish opinion poll published on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>- Four-fifths of voters are in favour of changing the Irish Constitution to make it more difficult for criminals to get bail, according to the same poll.</p>
<p>- Ireland is now experiencing a retail boom with consumers spending more on everything from cars to holidays while savings have fallen to their lowest level since 1989, according to the latest quarterly report from the Economic and Social Research Institute.</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT  </p>
<p>- The faltering peace process was plunged into a new crisis on Monday night when loyalist paramilitary prisoners withdrew their support for the inter-party talks and unionist politicians hardened their preconditions on arms decommissioning.</p>
<p>- Fianna Fail's ambitions to head the next Irish government get a severe blow on Tuesday with a new opinion poll showing it had lost support over the past three months.</p>
<p>- The Irish economy is expected to grow by about six percent this year, a slight deceleration from 1994 and 1995 but still far above the likely European Union growth rate of under two percent, the Economic and Social Research Institute said.  </p>
<p>- Over 60 million Irish pounds of funding under the European Union-supported Industry Research and Development Initiative has been approved for 895 projects promoted by 343 businesses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
