<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90074" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. to speed post-disaster passenger lists.</title>
<headline>U.S. to speed post-disaster passenger lists.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven major U.S. airlines have agreed to give the State Department lists of passengers on planes in overseas accidents so families can be notified quickly, the carriers' trade group said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Air Transport Association (ATA) said the carriers sent a memorandum of understanding to the State Department outlining their plans to hand over manifests in the event of disasters outside the United States involving U.S. citizens.</p>
<p>It said it expected the department would accept the memorandum, pending rules that are being written on ways to speed notification of families of disaster victims.</p>
<p>Many family members of victims have complained in past disasters that airlines have been slow to make passenger lists available and to notify next-of-kin.</p>
<p>A presidential task force formed after the July 17 crash of a Trans World Airlines Inc 747 off Long Island called for a more efficent notification process.</p>
<p>The ATA said the seven signatories to the memorandum accounted for the bulk of international traffic originating in the United States, adding other airlines might join later.</p>
<p>They were American Airlines, part of AMR Corp, Continental Airlines Inc, Delta Air Lines Inc, Northwest Airlines Corp, TWA, United Airlines, a unit of UAL Corp, and USAir Group.</p>
<p>The ATA said it and representatives from American, Continental and USAir had been working on the memorandum since last spring with the State Department and families of victims of past accidents.</p>
<p>ATA president Carol Hallett said in a statement that the airlines had long sought to improve coordination with the State Department.</p>
<p>ATA senior vice president and general counsel Robert Warren said the association's aim was to increase cooperation between airlines and the State Department &quot;so we can better respond to the needs of accident victims and their families.&quot;</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton last month designated the National Transportation Safety Board the prime coordinator of information to families of victims of aviation disasters in the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
