<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90158" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS-AT&amp;T offers 40 markets digital PCS service.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-AT&amp;T offers 40 markets digital PCS service.</headline>
<byline>Therese Poletti</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>AT&amp;T Corp. Wednesday introduced its next-generation wireless service, which combines a phone, pager and personal messaging system in a single device that works across the country.</p>
<p>The service, initially available in 40 major markets, requires just one phone to call, send and receive voice mail, with a message-waiting indicator; and receive text and numeric messages from personal computers and text dispatch services. Caller ID allows users to see the number of caller.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the largest wireless service launch in the history of the industry,&quot; said Steve Hooper, president of AT&amp;T's Wireless Services business, at a press conference in New York.</p>
<p>Users of AT&amp;T Digital Personal Communication Services (PCS) can stay in touch even as they travel across the country.</p>
<p>The new service will use AT&amp;T's currently available cellular network and will expand its geographical range when the company unveils its digital-based PCS services starting in the first quarter of 1997, using the air wave frequencies purchased in the Federal Communications Commission PCS auctions.</p>
<p>Digital technology also offers customers greater privacy and increased resistance to cellular service fraud, AT&amp;T said.</p>
<p>The service comes with improved batteries that allow customers to talk longer, or leave their phones on for extended periods of time, using a &quot;sleep mode&quot; feature.</p>
<p>&quot;These are strange and wonderful times in the telecommunications industry,&quot; AT&amp;T Chairman Bob Allen told reporters. &quot;We are in the early stages of a revolution and customer expectations. Customers have been surfing the Internet, they are moving into electronic commerce ... They are very interested in and have discovered wireless big time.&quot;</p>
<p>The telecommunications giant is initially offering the service to 70 million potential customers. Its market will expand to more than 212 million more potential customers, or more than 80 percent of the U.S. population, when it begins offering digital-based services using PCS frequencies.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T Digital PCS customers will pay a flat rate in the United States of 60 cents per minute for &quot;roaming&quot; calls -- those made from outside the customer's &quot;home,&quot; or local, calling area. The company said it will offer a range of service packages, starting at $24.99 per month, which do not require consumers to sign on for a whole year.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T said the new wireless phones will cost from $150 to $250, depending on the model. New phones that access both digital and analog (used in cellular) frequencies will be available next year.</p>
<p>Some models can be in a ready mode for as long as 60 hours before recharging is required -- two to three times longer than traditional wireless phones, it said.</p>
<p>The company said its AT&amp;T Digital PCS is available in major markets, including Seattle; Sacramento, Fresno and Ventura, Calif.; Miami, Tampa, Orlando and West Palm Beach, Fla.; Portland, Ore.; Las Vegas; Salt Lake City; Boise, Idaho; Dallas, San Antonio and Austin, Texas; Oklahoma City and Tulsa, Okla.; Pittsburgh; Minneapolis; and a number of markets in the New York metropolitan area and Northern New Jersey.</p>
<p>Analysts said AT&amp;T is trying to get a jump on the looming competition for nationwide wireless services expected to be launched this year and next from companies like Sprint Corp., Nextel Communications Inc., and others.</p>
<p>&quot;Going into the future they will receive blistering competition from other wireless players,&quot; said David Goodtree, director, telecom strategies at Forrester Research in Cambridge, Mass. &quot;Going into the future average subscriber revenue will shrink ... because of new market entrants and pricing pressures.&quot;</p>
<p>AT&amp;T's wireless business is still a small percentage of the overall AT&amp;T revenue base, analysts said. Simon Flannery, a J.P. Morgan analyst, estimates that AT&amp;T Wireless will reach $3.6 billion in revenues this year, about 6.8 percent of AT&amp;T's total projected revenues in 1996 of $52.7 billion, excluding spin-offs.</p>
<p>&quot;It does show that on the wireless side they are ahead of the pack,&quot; Flannery said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
