<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90161" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CRW to spin off unit, focus on Telespectrum.</title>
<headline>CRW to spin off unit, focus on Telespectrum.</headline>
<dateline>KING OF PRUSSIA, Pa. 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>CRW Financial Inc said on Wednesday it is selling its receivable management and debt collection division and spinning off its Casino Money Centers unit to shareholders.</p>
<p>After the sale and spin-off, the company's remaining asset will be its 6,162,130 shares of TeleSpectrum Worldwide Inc.  </p>
<p>CRW said it would have 2,829,738 shares of common stock if all of its warrants, options and convertible preferred shares were converted to common stock.</p>
<p>Proceeds from the warrants and options would be used to retire $8.3 million of debt, while proceeds from the division sale would be used to pay a dividend, buy back shares, or increase the capital of Casino Money Centers prior to the spinoff, CRW said.</p>
<p>The spinoff is expected by the first quarter of 1997, CRWZ said. Casino Money Centers plans to pursue acquisitions in the check cashing and cash advance industry, the company said.</p>
<p>CRW said it does not plan to pursue further acquisitions and would allow shareholders to value their shares based on CRW's stake in TeleSpectrum stock and the value to be realized from the sale of the division and the spinoff.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KING OF PRUSSIA, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
