<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90236" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Trump sees Q3 earnings above expectations.</title>
<headline>Trump sees Q3 earnings above expectations.</headline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trump Hotels &amp; Casino Resorts Inc Chairman Donald Trump said the company expects to earn $0.95 a share in its third quarter ended September 30, well ahead of forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect over $0.95 a share, which is higher than predicted by the Street,&quot; Trump told investors at the Salomon Brothers Gaming and Lodging Conference here.</p>
<p>Analysts expect the company to earn $0.78 a share in the third quarter, according to First Call.</p>
<p>Trump also said the company's new riverboat in Buffington Harbor, Indiana is expected to generate $65 million in cash flow 1997, its first full year of operation.  </p>
<p>Trump's Chief Executive Officer Nicholas Ribis said the company expects an &quot;announcement&quot; regarding Trump's plans in the United Kingdom on Thursday, but he declined to offer any details about the announcement.</p>
<p>In Atlantic City, Trump's Taj Mahal casino reported the strongest month for revenues in its history with nearly $58 million flowing into the hotel's coffers in September. That tops a record of $50 million set in August last year.</p>
<p>Trump also plans to change the name of its newly acquired Trump Castle hotel to Trump Marina. Plans call for Trump to dock its 432-foot yacht nearby and build a glass-enclosed walkway to it. The yacht will add 35,000 square feet of casino space and is scheduled to open in the fourth quarter of 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
