<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90243" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Newmont Gold sees Q3 EPS over $0.31.</title>
<headline>Newmont Gold sees Q3 EPS over $0.31.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newmont Gold Co said on Wednesday its third quarter earnings would beat its total earnings for the first half of 1996 because of record gold production.</p>
<p>The company, which is 91 percent owned by Newmont Mining Corp, said in a statement it earned $0.31 per share in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>It said it produced 650,000 ounces of gold in the third quarter.  </p>
<p>Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer Ronald Cambre said the company had an excellent performance in each of its four operations during the quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;This means that we are well on our way toward producing 2.2 million ounces of gold for the year and achieving our goal of a 10 percent increase in earnings per share,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the third quarter of 1995, both Newmont Mining Corp and operating subsidiary Newmont Gold earned $0.25 per share on production of 504,300 ounces.</p>
<p>The First Call mean estimate for the third quarter 1996 was $0.25 per share.  </p>
<p>Cambre also said Newmont was on target to reach its goal of 2.5 million ounces of annual production in 1997, which would mean lower cash costs and earnings per share growth.</p>
<p>He also said Newmont's roaster for processing refractory ores at Carlin, Nev., was operating at its design rate of 8,000 short tons of ore per day, after initial start-up problems.</p>
<p>The Zarafshan-Newmont joint venture in Uzbekistan was also steadily improving, he said, with production of nearly 90,000 ounces of gold in the third quarter.  The Minahasa mine in Indonesia had also reached design rates, Cambre said.  </p>
<p>The company would increase gold reserves net of depletion in 1996, he said.  Cambre said a number of projects were in the advanced stages of development, including La Herradura in Mexico, scheduled to begin production in 1998 and Batu Hija in Indonesia, expected to start in late 1999.</p>
<p>Advanced exploration projects were also underway in Alaska, Ecuador, Peru and Southeast Asia, he said.</p>
<p>He also said the company would implement a joint venture agreement with Uzbekistan and Tokyo's Mitsui &amp; Co Ltd to develop gold deposits in the country's Angren region.</p>
<p>The region is about 60 miles south of the capital city Tashkent and hadsan operating underground gold mine and mill as well as several known gold deposits, Cambre said.</p>
<p>The Uzbek government said the region has total identified resources of 7.6 million, Newmont said.</p>
<p>Newmont had a 40 percent interest, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
