<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90310" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lira too weak, dlr should rise-Belgium's Verplaetse.</title>
<headline>Lira too weak, dlr should rise-Belgium's Verplaetse.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian lira is undervalued, but the U.S. dollar could go higher, Belgian central bank governor Alfons Verplaetse said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Verplaetse told a small group of agency journalists, &quot;As an economist, I think the depreciation of the lira...has been more than is justified by differences in prices and costs.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked also about the dollar's exchange rate, he said he shared the view of other Europeans that the currency could rise further.</p>
<p>&quot;I would prefer the dollar somewhat stronger. The normalisation should go on somewhat,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Looking ahead to the start of European monetary union in 1999, Verplaetse said he would very much welcome Italy's participation in the currency union from the start providing it can meet the entry conditions in time.</p>
<p>But he added that he believed Italy would join the currency union very soon after the start even if it were not able to meet the economic goals laid down in the Maastricht Treaty in time for the launch.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure that very fast Italy will be a part of EMU, if not from the first day,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Asked whether Italy might already have disqualified itself for EMU entry by withdrawing its currency from Europe's Exchange Rate Mechanism in 1992, Verplaetse said he did not believe this alone would bar Italian entry.</p>
<p>The Maastricht Treaty calls for would-be EMU currencies to have been trading stably in Europe's ERM for at least twow years before they can be deemed eligible for EMU.</p>
<p>Noting that it was up to Europe's heads of state to make this decision, Verplaetse said his personal view was that exchange rate stability coupled with a commitment to keep the nominal exchange rate stable would be sufficient.</p>
<p>Asked about the example of Finland, which is rumoured to be on the point of putting its currency into the ERM, he said he could not imagine governments would insist it was not qualified for EMU entry if it were a only few months short of the target.</p>
<p>--Janet Northcote, Washington Newsroom +1 202 898 8300</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
