<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90371" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Asset Investors adviser sold for $11.45 mln.</title>
<headline>Asset Investors adviser sold for $11.45 mln.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asset Investors Corp said Wednesday that its external adviser, Financial Asset Management LLC, was sold by M.D.C. Holdings Inc for $11.45 million.</p>
<p>Financial Asset Management was sold to FAM Acquisition LLC, a newly formed company that will be owned by an investment group led by Terry Considine and Thomas Rhodes, it said.</p>
<p>The purchase price included $6 million in cash and $5.45 million in notes issued by FAM Acquisition LLC to M.D.C. Holdings.  </p>
<p>After related expenses, M.D.C. will report an after-tax gain of about $2.5 million, or $0.11 per fully diluted share, in the third quarter of 1996, M.D.C. Holdings said.</p>
<p>Asset Investors, a real estate investment trust, said the transaction will not lead to a change in its management agreement with Financial Asset.</p>
<p>Considine is chairman, president and chief executive of Apartment Investment and Management Co, a real estate investment trust. Rhodes is president and director of National Review Inc and previously was a general partner at Goldman, Sachs &amp; Co.  </p>
<p>As part of the transaction, Larry Mizel - chairman, president and chief executive of M.D.C., and Spencer Browne, president of Financial Asset, and a director, president and chief executive of Asset Investors, resigned as directors and officers of Asset Investors.</p>
<p>Browne also resigned from his positions as president, chief executive and a director of Commercial Assets Inc, an affiliate of Asset Investors.  </p>
<p>The vacancies on the Asset Investors board are to be filled by Considine, who has been named chairman and co-chief executive, and Rhodes, who has been appointed vice chairman and co-chief executive.</p>
<p>Leslie Fox has been named president and chief operating officer of Asset Investors. Fox most recently was the company's chief operating officer.</p>
<p>M.D.C. Holdings is a homebuilder.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
