<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90441" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-CANTONA SAYS HE PLANS TO END HIS CAREER IN ENGLAND.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CANTONA SAYS HE PLANS TO END HIS CAREER IN ENGLAND.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eric Cantona said on Wednesday he would end his playing career in England and might go into coaching if he felt he could offer something new.</p>
<p>&quot;I won't play again in France,&quot; Manchester United's French ace said. &quot;I will finish playing in England and probably stay there.</p>
<p>&quot;But I am still available to play for the French national team. My critics would like me to say I'm not available, but I am,&quot; Cantona said on French television.</p>
<p>&quot;If it meant being creative I would like to stay in football as a trainer,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Cantona, who has 45 French caps, said he was worried for the future of football in his country, which will host the World Cup finals in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;It could become like Denmark or Norway when the 20 best players are abroad. People go to football to watch one or two players. Those responsible are at the top (of the game).&quot; Half of France's national team squad play in Italy or Spain.</p>
<p>Cantona, who rarely gives interviews, was a guest on a television chat show where he also talked about his co-producing of a French version of the play &quot;Who's afraid of Virginia Wolf&quot; in a Paris theatre.</p>
<p>&quot;I might take a course in acting,&quot; said Cantona, who has a small part in a film currently on general release in France.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
