<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90627" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Share trading mixed on Nigerian bourse.</title>
<headline>Share trading mixed on Nigerian bourse.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading ended mixed on the Nigerian stock market on Wednesday with share prices of major companies down, brokers said.</p>
<p>Strong gains by cement, food and oil shares pushed the all-share index up only slightly to close at 6505.31 on Wednesday from 6501.88 on Monday. Tuesday was a public holiday.</p>
<p>Brokers the index did not move up much on Wednesday because of a steady decline of leading companies.</p>
<p>Conglomerate Lever Brothers which began to slide last week further dropped 10 kobo to 25.60 naira, the same margin lost by Nigerian Breweries at 12.70 naira and Guinness at 8.80 naira.</p>
<p>Afribank, the country's fourth biggest, dropped 10 kobo to 5.70 naira while United Bank for Africa and NAL Merchant Bank each closed five down at 5.15 naira and 5.25 naira.</p>
<p>Tyre maker Dunlop also fell 10 kobo to 12.00 naira, the same as Chemical and Allied Products which closed at 7.60 naira.</p>
<p>Vitafoam shares went 15 kobo down to 5.00 naira because investors were still offloading them.</p>
<p>Ashaka Cement led the sector with a 25 kobo rise to 17.15 naira, followed by Benue Cement at 5.50 naira, up 15 kobo.</p>
<p>Blue chip oil shares Total, Unipetrol, National Oil and Mobil added 20 kobo each to reach 46.00 naira, 39.90 naira, 31.20 naira and 38.10 naira, respectively.</p>
<p>Nestle Foods went 10 kobo up to 30.60 naira while Union Dicon Salt gained 12 kobo to 34.42 naira. ($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
