<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90663" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAWI: PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Oct 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Oct 2.</headline>
<dateline>BLANTYRE 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Malawi press on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE NATION</p>
<p>- More than 40 Malawians were last Friday deported by the South African government in a cargo plane after some of them were jailed for three weeks as illegal immigrants, reports The Nation. Obrien Chinkhuntha, one of the deportees, said more than 80 others are still being held in South African jail awaiting to be deported.</p>
<p>- Malawi's primary and post primary school teachers have threatened to boycott marking final examinations and have given government until Sunday, to receive their leave grants.</p>
<p>The Malawi Teachers Union in a statement said it will call for a nationwide demonstration starting on Monday, October 7, until all teachers are paid their leave grant dues.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MALAWI BROADCASTING CORPORATION</p>
<p>- Malawi leader of opposition parties Gwanda Chakuamba said the national assembly will not sit this October following a boycott by the country's two main opposition parties to protest against President Bakili Muluzi appointing into his cabinet members of the opposition without the parties' consent.</p>
<p>Chakuamba who is also vice president for the country's main opposition, Malawi Congress Party (MCP) told a rally in Mangochi, southern Malawi on Monday, that parliament has no majority party and therefore according to the laws, the ruling United Democraic Front (UDF) cannot conduct business in the house this October without the opposition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLANTYRE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAWI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
