<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90720" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Foreign firms flock to Yugoslav trade fair.</title>
<headline>Foreign firms flock to Yugoslav trade fair.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslav companies received a symbolic welcome back to the international business community in Belgrade on Wednesday at the opening of an international trade fair coinciding with the formal lifting of sanctions.</p>
<p>Over 150 companies from 19 countries hoping to renew old business links flocked to the Belgrade Fair, where exhibitors include Western giants like British Airways, Skoda, ICL, Ericsson, Alcan, Volvo, Philips, Alcatel and Bosch.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very pleased that sanctions have been lifted,&quot; Roger Shoshoua, director of the London-based International Trade and Exhibitions J/V Ltd which is organising the exhibitions, told the opening ceremony.</p>
<p>&quot;All those companies agreed to come and reestablish their presence in this market. They want to cooperate and invest.&quot;</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the U.N. Security Council voted 15-0 to formally end the trade, travel and transport embargoes suspended against the Yugoslav republics of Serbia and Montenegro in November.</p>
<p>The sanctions were originally imposed on Belgrade in 1992 for its role in fomenting war in neighbouring Bosnia.</p>
<p>Yugoslav trade minister Djordje Siradovic appealed for an end to the remaining &quot;outer wall&quot; of U.S.-led sanctions that continue to block its membership of the U.N. General Assembly and financial institutions like the World Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;We did everything needed to establish and develop cooperation with the world,&quot; said Siradovic, whose ministry is sponsoring the Belgrade Fair.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we expect the world to make a small step and eliminate the outer ring of sanctions and stop discrimination against our economy on the international market.&quot;</p>
<p>Belgrade economists said little would change until the outer wall collapsed and the country won access to international financial institutions.</p>
<p>Most of Yugoslavia's major manufacturers ran down their operations during the sanctions years, and urgently need foreign finance to help crank up production to pre-war levels.</p>
<p>Although the sanctions were suspended after 1995's Dayton peace accord, the U.N. used the threat of reimposing them as a stick to ensure Belgrade's cooperation with last month's Bosnia elections and maintained the so-called outer wall of sanctions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
