<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90724" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's PTS says stake owner unclear.</title>
<headline>Russia's PTS says stake owner unclear.</headline>
<dateline>ST PETERSBURG, Russia 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The ownership of a stake of nearly 20 percent in St Petersburg telecoms company PTS will not be clear until the next shareholders meeting in April next year, a PTS official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Mikhail Rozenberg, head of the securities department at AOOT Sankt-Peterburgskaya Telefonnaya Set, told Reuters that two stakes totalling 19.5 percent sold this year by two St Petersburg banks were now owned by two offshore Cyprus companies, according to the PTS share register.</p>
<p>&quot;We tried to find out using our channels who is behind these companies, but could not find out anything,&quot; Rozenberg said.</p>
<p>The Kommersant-Daily newspaper said on Wednesday that PTS, or its joint venture with St Petersburg's long-distance telecoms company MMT (AO Mezhdugorodny Mezhdunarodny Telefon) could be behind the two Cypriot firms.</p>
<p>Rozenberg said that PTS owns 95 percent of the venture, AO Telekominvest.</p>
<p>He said the offshore firms had bought a 7.5 percent stake in PTS this year from Baltiisky Bank and a 12 percent stake from Bank Sankt-Peterburg.</p>
<p>At the end of August a Bank Sankt-Peterburg spokesman said the bank had sold PTS shares for several tens of millions of dollars.</p>
<p>PTS's biggest shareholder is the state telecoms holding company AO Svyazinvest, with a 41.8 percent stake. The government plans to sell a 25 percent stake in Svyazinvest in the near future.</p>
<p>Deutsche Morgan Grenfell said that if PTS had acquired the shares, either directly or through Telekominvest, it would strengthen the influence of PTS management against Svyazinvest and strengthen Telekominvest's to become a major regional telecoms provider in the North-West.</p>
<p>It would also boost PTS's share price by restricting supply of the stock.</p>
<p>Ten north-western telecoms companies, including PTS and MMT, have set up an association to improve telecoms infrastructure in the region.</p>
<p>PTS closed on the Russian Trading System at $0.685 after $21.125 on Tuesday, following a 30-for-1 share split.</p>
<p>--Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83951">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST PETERSBURG, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
