<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90786" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Belgrade pleased sanctions over, Sarajevo critical.</title>
<headline>Belgrade pleased sanctions over, Sarajevo critical.</headline>
<byline>Peter Greste</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rump Yugoslavia on Wednesday broadly welcomed the U.N.'s decision to end sanctions, but economists warned the country's revival still hinged on an end to an &quot;outer wall&quot; of sanctions that remains in place.</p>
<p>Late on Tuesday, the U.N. Security Council voted 15-0 formally to end the embargoes on trade, travel and transport that had already been suspended in November against the Yugoslav republics of Serbia and Montenegro.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we have all together finally come out of the most difficult period in our country's modern history,&quot; Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic said in a statement.</p>
<p>Belgrade's state-run newspapers splashed the news across their front pages with triumphant editorials and large photographs of Milosevic.</p>
<p>But independent analysts were more cautious, insisting that Yugoslavia's problems were far from over.</p>
<p>The sanctions were originally imposed on Belgrade in 1991 for its role in fomenting war in neighbouring Bosnia.</p>
<p>Although they were suspended after the Dayton peace accord last year, the U.N. used the threat of reimposing them as a stick to ensure Belgrade's cooperation with last month's elections in Bosnia.</p>
<p>But the United States said it would still oppose Yugoslavia's re-joining the U.N. General Assembly and other U.N. bodies as well as institutions like the World Bank until further demands were met.</p>
<p>Belgrade economists said this so-called &quot;outer wall&quot; of sanctions is the key issue, and while Tuesday's decision was a major psychological boost, real progress depended on Yugoslavia's access to international financial institutions.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that some media consider this to be a major event has more to do with internal politics,&quot; said one senior political analyst who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;What is most important of all is that the outer wall of sanctions remain in place. It is informal, but it exists and acts very negatively on us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The end of sanctions is positive in that after they were introduced many countries imposed special trade regulations which will now be abolished. But trade is not our problem. Reviving production is.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of Yugoslavia's major manufacturers ran down their operations during the sanctions years, and are looking to foreign finance to help crank up production to pre-war levels.</p>
<p>An adviser to the independent Foreign Trade Institute Zivojin Jevtic said the end of trade sanctions had weakened the outer wall and gave the government an added tool to chip away at it in negotiations with organisations like the World Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.N.'s decision will certainly ease things, but will not open doors automatically,&quot; Jevtic said.</p>
<p>He also warned that the West may still try to block access to the U.N. and international finance to keep a stick in reserve, in case Belgrade strays from earlier promises.</p>
<p>These include cooperating with a U.N. war crimes tribunal, easing tensions in the restive Serbian province of Kosovo, which is dominated by ethnic Albanians, and settling claims and other issues with the former Yugoslav states.</p>
<p>Neighbouring Bosnia also criticised the U.N. for giving up a key tool for keeping Belgrade in line.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm afraid the international community has lost a very poweful weapon against the Belgrade regime by lifting the sanctions,&quot; senior advisor to President Alija Izetbegovic, Mirza Hajric, told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
