<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90802" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Oct 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Oct 2.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>BURSA</p>
<p>- Bucharest stock exchange stayed close to trading on Tuesday and will reopen on Thursday.</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Parliament's lower Chamber of Deputies passed bill granting farmers 500 billion lei to cover losses caused by natural disasters in agricultural year 1995/96.</p>
<p>- Prices of Bucharest housing are expected to rise constantly over next seven years due to shortage.</p>
<p>- Chamber of Deputies will soon take vote on bill on special road fund which will give 1.0 trillion lei to National Road Administration to use for road rehabilitation and construction.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Chamber of Deputies voted against bill on privatisation of commercial banks. Bill will be rediscussed by new parliament after November polls.</p>
<p>TINERETUL LIBER</p>
<p>- National Bank will give troubled banks  Banca Dacia Felix SA and  Renasterea Creditului Romanesc Credit Bank SA credits to be able to meet individual deposit redemption applications.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>- Most newspapers deal with incident two days ago in which ruling Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) was accused of leading a fake opinion survey aimed at shoring up lost electoral ground ahead of November polls.</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Eight people were admitted to hospital with meningitis diagnosis in last 24 hours.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Visiting Romanian Foreign Minister Teodor Melescanu will meet U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry to tackle Romania's integration into NATO.</p>
<p>- Chamber of Deputies rejected bill saying assets of children and youth organisations prior to 1989 should be managed by state.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Opinion poll taken by Urban Sociology Centre shows Romanians like best election campaign of Emil Constantinescu, leader of Democratic Convention main opposition bloc.</p>
<p>- Eugen Radulescu, general manager in National Bank, was appointed Romania's representative to IMF.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- Bucharest mayor Victor Ciorbea delivered report on his activity in first 100 days after election in June polls.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- U.S. Army General George Joulwan, allied commander of NATO forces in Europe, starts visit for talks with Romanian officials on cooperation within Partnership for Peace and NATO-led IFOR peacekeeping mission in Bosnia. ($1.0=3,261 lei)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
