<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90841" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chilean utilities mull natgas pipeline project.</title>
<headline>Chilean utilities mull natgas pipeline project.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean state power company Colbun Machicura SA said it has held talks with generator Empresa Nacional de Electricidad (Endesa) on building a natural gas pipeline in central Chile.</p>
<p>The duct would supply natural gas to power plants that the companies are planning to build near the town of Quillota. The gas will come from a pipeline being built by the GasAndes group from Mendoza in central Argentina across the Andes to Santiago.</p>
<p>&quot;The most likely is that if we go ahead with this project, it would be with another company,&quot; said president Jaime Toha.  </p>
<p>&quot;Endesa is an electricity company which has interests similar to ours...we have discussed this issue (with Endesa).&quot;</p>
<p>GasAndes is planning to build a pipeline to fuel the electricity stations, but Colbun believes it could be cheaper to build its own pipeline.</p>
<p>&quot;We are considering different ways for transporting the gas, including the offer we have received from GasAndes as well as the possibility of developing our own scheme,&quot; said Toha.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope we will reach a decision in the next few weeks.&quot;  </p>
<p>Colbun and Endesa are planning to invest a total of $400 million in the gas-fired power plants which will each have capacity of 370 megawatts.</p>
<p>--Rodrigo Martinez, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595x205</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
