<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90852" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: INTERVIEW - Cemex sees slow Mexico recovery.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Cemex sees slow Mexico recovery.</headline>
<byline>David Luhnow</byline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cement maker Cemex SA knows the road to recovery for its business in Mexico will be long and bumpy.</p>
<p>After plunging some 26 percent in 1995, Mexican cement sales volumes are expected to recover a slim 3-5 percent this year and roughly six percent next year, company officials say.</p>
<p>It will take until 1998 or 1999 for cement sales in Mexico to return to 1994 levels, before a devastating peso crash caused a sharp recession and a virtual standstill in large-scale construction.  </p>
<p>&quot;Construction has not played the role of catalyst as it has in previous recoveries in Mexico,&quot; Hector Medina, head of Cemex's Mexico operations, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Medina said the government is unlikely to resort to populist public spending as it did in the past to speed the recovery. But he said the cautious approach will create a more solid recovery when it does come.</p>
<p>Another brake on the recovery of the cement business is a fragile banking system, which may be unable provide new credit to fund construction projects anytime soon, he said.  </p>
<p>For the Mexican unit, which accounts for about 41 percent of the group's revenues, exports have also been a saving grace. Exports have grown to 2.97 million tonnes last year from one million tonnes during 1994. Medina sees exports from Mexico hitting between four and 4.5 million tonnes this year.</p>
<p>&quot;From our point of view, we can keep this up (the growth in exports),&quot; he said, pointing to a booming Asian market as Cemex's main export target.</p>
<p>&quot;In the case of Taiwan, there is another two to three years of opportunity as the island shifts its production capacity from one side of the island to the other,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Also easing the pain of the fall in domestic cement sales was a 17 percent price rise in Mexico in July, a move that will help the company's third quarter earnings. But Medina said higher prices mean little if volumes don't recover.</p>
<p>&quot;The recovery is uneven...In some parts of the country, like Guadalajara, there are no (large-scale) projects. None,&quot; he said. &quot;In Tijuana, volumes there are as big as they were in 1994 in Guadalajara -- a city several times its size.&quot;</p>
<p>Medina estimated the company's cement prices still lag recent cost increases, especially in energy prices, by about 15 to 20 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
