<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90881" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian peso gains, ends off highs at 1,019.00.</title>
<headline>Colombian peso gains, ends off highs at 1,019.00.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's peso gained in active trading on the back of a surge in oil dollars entering the country but it closed off the day's highs, interbank dealers said.</p>
<p>They said the local currency closed at 1,019.00, up 4.3 pesos from Tuesday's close but well off its intraday high of 1,015.50, a level that had not been seen since mid-January.</p>
<p>Traders said a sudden demand for cheap dollars from the corporate sector, when the U.S. currency hit its low for the day, pushed the peso lower ahead of the close.</p>
<p>It still managed to hold above key resistance at 1,020.00</p>
<p>Dealers reported 337 trades for a total of $127 million and said the peso's intraday low was 1,022.60. It was the second consecutive day in which the peso move sharply higher but dealers said the central bank had not intervened to halt its gains.</p>
<p>Leading exporters have asked the bank to undercut the peso artifically, to help stem their foreign exchange losses and make Colombian goods more competitive abroad.</p>
<p>But the bank, which likes a strong peso as a cushion against inflation, has said it has no intention of altering the currency's daily floating exchange rate band.</p>
<p>-- Juan Guillermo Londono, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
