<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90933" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Dazed Chileans await news of Peru crash survivors.</title>
<headline>Dazed Chileans await news of Peru crash survivors.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Too dazed to talk, relatives of people on board Aeroperu flight 603 waited on Wednesday at Santiago's international airport for news of survivors as the word &quot;canceled&quot; flickered onto information screens.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't, I can't,&quot; was all one woman could say as she shuffled out of a lounge where Aeroperu gave what little news it had to relatives.</p>
<p>&quot;They've just kept us here waiting,&quot; said Ricardo Canecho, whose son-in-law Victor Chue was on the plane.</p>
<p>Shielded from reporters by a glass wall, few of the 30 or so relatives were crying, but many looked dazed and shocked. A doctor took the blood pressure of a few people who looked on the brink of collapse.</p>
<p>The Boeing 757, carrying 70 people, dropped off the radar and plunged into the Pacific shortly after take-off from Lima en route to Santiago.</p>
<p>Raul Chiappas, general manager for Aeroperu in Miami, said 21 of the passengers had boarded the jet after connecting from an earlier Aeroperu flight from Miami.</p>
<p>There was no sign of any grieving relatives by 9 a.m. (1300 GMT) at the Aeroperu counter at Miami International Airport.</p>
<p>The only information Aeroperu's local Chilean office had was a brief statement read to reporters by its local manager, Jeffrey Stand, saying the plane was &quot;missing.&quot; It said nothing of survivors.</p>
<p>It was unknown how many Chileans were on board.</p>
<p>If the death toll is confirmed, it would be the second time this year an air disaster in Peru claimed many Chileans. A Boeing 737 belonging to airline Faucett crashed near Arequipa in March, killing 123 including a Santiago student group and many other Chileans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
