<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="90961" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News - Oct 3.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News - Oct 3.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>TNT Ltd looks certain to be subject to one of Australia's largest takeovers after the A$20 billion Dutch postal and telecommunications group Royal PTT Nederland NV yesterday offered A$2.45 for every TNT share in a A$2 billion friendly takeover. The deal came a day after TNT sealed the A$325 million sale of its 50 percent stake in Ansett Australia. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>United States investors drove the Dow Jones Industrial Average to a close of more than 5,900 for the first time ever yesterday following comments by Treasurer Peter Costello concerning U.S. Federal Reserve chief Dr Alan Greenspan's bid to play down prospecive U.S. inflationary and interest rate pressures. Shadow Treasurer Gareth Evans said the remarks showed Costello was unfit to be Treasurer. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Ahead of tomorrow's National Summit on Tax Reform in Canberra, Coopers &amp; Lybrand released a survey on consumption taxes around the world to show Australia is the only developed country imposing a wholesale sales tax and those under-developed countries which have a WST also exact a tax on services. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Macquarie Bank is set to list a A$300-$400 million trust on the Australia Stock Exchange by the end of the year. The first to be listed on the Australian Stock Exchange, the trust will be managed by Macquarie Infrastructure Funds Management, a joint ventre between Macquarie's funds management arm and its corporate finance arm. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a move set to create the biggest single player in the highly prospective Bengal Basin, the UK's Cairn Energy has made a A$365 million offer for Sydney-based Command Petroleum. The bid has won support from Command directors and major sharehlder SOCO Australia Pty Ltd, a subsidiary of US-based Snyder Oil Corporation. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In the second deal to be poached in the new competitive New South Wales wholesale electricity market, Integral Energy has won the contract to supply energy to the University of New South Wales Kensington campus from its larger rival Energy Australia. The Kensington campus uses more than 40 gigawatt hours of energy a year, which is more than A$2 million in annual electricity expenditure. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>TNT Ltd's board has unanimously recommended a A$2 billion friendly cash takeover by Dutch postal and telecoms giant Royal PTT Nederland NV (KPN). TNT stock finished 48.5 percent higher yesterday after the Dutch group snapped up almost 58 million TNT shares, as well as 9.9 percent of its converting preference shares. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Released in time for tomorrow's tax reform summit in Canberra, a Committee for the Economic Development of Australia discussion paper prepared by Dr Vince FitzGerald yesterday recommended a broadening of the indirect tax base either through a goods and services tax or value added tax. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Long-term bond yields hit 30-month lows yesterday after Treasurer Peter Costello repeated comments made to him by U.S. Federal Reserve chairman Dr Alan Greenspan. Costello said Greenspan had been very optimistic about the inflation outlook, indicating higher interest rates in the United States would be unlikely. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>As part of its plan to create a A$1 billion-plus global oil company focusing on the Indian subcontinent, the United Kingdom's third largest independent oil and gas company, Cairn Energy Plc, yesterday made a scrip bid for Australian oil company Command Petroleum, which values Command at A$375 million. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Optus Communications has sold its 28.5 percent stake in telephony service provider One.Tel back to the company for a sum of about A$20 million in a move which Optus chief executive Ziggy Switkowski says frees Optus of the ties of an equity interest in &quot;one of the players&quot;. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Announcing yesterday it had concluded refinancing of corporate debt facilities, swapping a A$1.83 million facility with a new US$1.2 billion debt structure, Woodside Petroleum is now free to embark on the next phase of liquefied natural gas processing expnsion on the North West Shelf. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Dutch group Royal PTT Nederland NV (KPN) believes the acquisition of Australian transportation group TNT will establish one of the world's leading specialised distribution operations if the A$2 billion bid is successful. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Building products supplier James Hardie Industries yesterday conceded the group's profit will fall over the next year due to a tough Australian market. Hardie managing director Keith Barton believes that despite the group's plans for expansion in the U.S., poor local trading will dominate the group's bottom line. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Telecommunications service provider One.Tel has shelved indefinitely plans to list on the Australian Stock Exchange. This news followed the announcement that One.Tel's shareholders - Jodee Rich, FAI and James Packer - had bought back the 28.5 percent stake held by Optus Communications. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Institutional demand for the National Mutual share offer has significantly exceeded the 280 million shares which were made available on the first day of the institutional offer. With an almost even spread of local and foreign bidders on the first day, Natonal Mutual has given the institutions an indicative price range of between A$1.35 to A$1.55. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although BankWest has reported a solid A$48.3 million profit for the half year to August 31, it has warned that a tightening of interest margins in the second half would make some impact on the Perth-based bank's earnings. Although confident of meeting th A$100.2 million prospectus forecast, BankWest has cautioned it is operating in a highly competitive market. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to figures released by the Australian Bureau of Statistics on manufacturing production, less than half of Australia's 58 key industries recorded a rise in production in August. With 26 of the 58 sectors recording an increase in production, the wdespread gloom haunting Australian manufacturing continues. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Following months of secret negotiations, Dutch postal and telecommunications group Royal PTT Nederland (KPN) announced a A$2 billion takeover bid for transport giant TNT. KPN announced a cash offer of A$2.45 a share yesterday, with the bid receiving stron backing from the TNT board. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>National Mutual Holdings claims it has been inundated with demand for shares in its planned A$2.55 billion float. After the first day of its institutional book building process, National Mutual said demand was in excess of the 280 million shares set aside for institutions. Page B2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Building materials group James Hardie has felt the pinch of the slump in the housing and building construction industry, forcing it to warn of a &quot;deterioration&quot; in first-half profits. Despite a downgrade in expected earnings, the group announced it would invest A$40 million in a fibre cement plant in the United States. Page B2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Cairn Energy, the British oil and gas group, has confirmed plans of a A$375 million takeover of Command Petroleum. Cairn revealed this news by offering a deal of two shares for every 13 Command shares and a cash offer of A$1.10 a share for those shareholders wanting to sell. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Western Australian-based bank BankWest has posted a A$48.3 million profit in its first semester of being a publicly listed company. The result was a 5.2 percent increase on the half-year to September 1995, and 2.3 percent ahead of the prospectus forecast. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Victoria state government may be out-of-pocket tens of millions of dollars in privatisation receipts after Aluvic posted a lower profit and predicted tough times ahead. The State-owned aluminium group, earmarked for privatisation, reported a 45 percent drop in after-tax profit, to A$13.9 million for the year to June 30. Page B3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
