<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91012" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: ASEAN arms buildup could fuel insecurity - Manila.</title>
<headline>ASEAN arms buildup could fuel insecurity - Manila.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>An uncontrolled arms buildup among Southeast Asian nations could fuel regional insecurity and drive some of them to launch hostile actions against their neighbours, a top Philippine military official has warned.</p>
<p>Commodore Artemio Arugay, Philippine armed forces deputy chief of staff for plans, issued the warning in a paper analysing the implications of what he said was an arms buildup among members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</p>
<p>The paper, obtained by Reuters on Wednesday, was presented at a current conference in Manila among Philippine and Australian military and security experts. The three-day conference ends on Thursday.</p>
<p>Arugay said that at present no armed forces in the ASEAN region had the capability or intention to stage and sustain a major attack or invasion of another country.</p>
<p>&quot;However, several countries, as their arms acquisitions would show, are capable of conducting low level hostile actions against their neighbours, including the Philipines,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the present trend continues, several countries might have the capability in the future to project their military power beyond their immediate environs,&quot; he warned.</p>
<p>Arugay did not name any specific country.</p>
<p>ASEAN comprises Malaysia, Indonesia, Thailand, Singapore, the Philippines, Brunei and Vietnam.</p>
<p>Arugay stressed the need for ASEAN leaders to manage their countries' arms buildup and prevent an arms race that could exacerbate regional tension.</p>
<p>&quot;If in the future, the political situation and the strategic scenario deteriorate, the arms modernisations being undertaken by countries in the region will give them the capability to assert their territorial and maritime claims and to conduct hostile military actions against another country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Arugay cited several factors which had spurred ASEAN countries to build up their military firepower.</p>
<p>They included the economic growth these countries had achieved, &quot;a mosaic of territorial disputes&quot; and apprehensions over a rearmed Japan and China's security posture.</p>
<p>He said there was perception among security experts &quot;that China intends to make Southeast Asia as its sphere of influence with its declaration of sovereignty over the South China Sea&quot;.</p>
<p>China has laid claim to all of the Spratly Islands, a potentially oil-rich cluster of islands also claimed wholly or in part by Taiwan, Vietnam, Malaysia, the Philippines and Brunei.</p>
<p>Arugay said the &quot;uncertainty of U.S. commitment and capability to deal with regional contingencies&quot; was also a factor promoting the arms buildup in the region.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
