<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91067" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia cocoa exports to U.S. seen in slump.</title>
<headline>Indonesia cocoa exports to U.S. seen in slump.</headline>
<byline>K.T. Arasu</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian cocoa bean exports to the United States plunged last year due to stringent quality checks forcing local exporters to other markets, and are likely to be down this year, an industry official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Exports to the United States fell to 46,663 tonnes in 1995 from 79,434 tonnes the previous year, Siswoputranto, executive director of the Indonesia Cocoa Association, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Direct exports to the United States are likely to be weaker this year as well,&quot; he said. He did not have export projections for this year.</p>
<p>Siswoputranto said Indonesian exporters had increased sales to markets in Eastern Europe, the Middle East and China where quality checks were less stringent.</p>
<p>The United States is the single largest market for cocoa from Indonesia, the world's third largest cocoa producer after the Ivory Coast and Ghana.</p>
<p>&quot;During a trip to the United States I proposed that the U.S. authorities automatically refumigate all cocoa beans imported from Indonesia instead of keeping them in warehouses, checking them and then sending them for refumigation,&quot; Siswoputranto said.</p>
<p>&quot;But I was told that that was how it had to be done,&quot; he said, adding that the refumigation was due to insect infestations and that the storage added to costs.</p>
<p>&quot;The infestations occur despite the beans being fumigated before they are loaded into vessels,&quot; Siswoputrantro said.</p>
<p>He said studies were being done to determine if the infestations occurred at farms, warehouses, in the vessels or during the beans' month-long journey to the United States.</p>
<p>He said efforts had been made to improve the quality of overseas-bound cocoa by ensuring only professional and accredited companies carried out fumigation in Indonesia.</p>
<p>Siswoputranto also said next year the government would launch a major survey to determine the actual area under cocoa cultivation.</p>
<p>&quot;Presently there is a big disparity between our (Indonesia Cocoa Association) estimate and the government's,&quot; he said. &quot;Our estimate is 460,000 hectares (1.1 million acres) while the government's is nearly 600,000 hectares (1.5 million acres).&quot;</p>
<p>Siswoputranto said the survey would cover seven provinces considered key growing regions including Sulawesi, East Kalimantan, Sumatra and Java.</p>
<p>&quot;Once the survey is completed, it will be less difficult for us to make crop projections,&quot; he said, adding that the survey's duration would depend on how much money was allocated for the task.</p>
<p>&quot;General elections will be held next year, so how fast we can complete the survey will really depend on how much money the government allocates,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
