<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91076" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Aokam debt put on rating watch - RAM.</title>
<headline>Aokam debt put on rating watch - RAM.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The debt of logging concern Aokam Perdana Bhd was put on a ratings watch with the possibility of a downgrade following the company's report of a loss for its financial year, Rating Agency Malaysia Bhd (RAM) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>RAM said in a statement the rating concerned Aokam's 50.6 million ringgit redeemable unsecured loan stock, which are bonds convertible into stock.  </p>
<p>The company's loan stocks were downgraded on August 10 to A2 from a previous long-term rating of AA3.</p>
<p>Aokam on Monday reported a pre-tax loss of 145.07 million ringgit for the year ended June 30, 1996, versus a profit of 45.68 million ringgit a year ago.</p>
<p>RAM noted that Aokam's pre-tax loss for the half-year to December 1995 had been reported at 6.23 million ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;RAM notes that 57 percent of the loss is the result of provisioning and write-offs,&quot; RAM said in its statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The rating watch also reflects the worsening trend in the group's financial performance and RAM's expectations of a slow recovery in demand and prices for timber products in the international market over the immediate term,&quot; RAM said.</p>
<p>RAM said these factors would significantly change Aokam's cashflow position, &quot;which is expected to remain tight over the bond issue period&quot;.</p>
<p>It added that it is currently seeking details on the recently announced results from Aokam management.</p>
<p>Aokam's net loss of 144.73 million ringgit far exceeded market expectations of an eight to 10 million ringgit loss.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I46000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
