<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91070" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares close up on foreign buying, Telkom.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares close up on foreign buying, Telkom.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Jakarta composite index closed sharply higher on Wednesday following foreign buying of selected market heavyweights and local targeting of secondaries, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index rose 9.10 points, or 1.57 percent, to close at the day-high of 589.31 points. Gainers led losers 71 to 49, with 46 counters unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Dow makes gains tonight, foreigners are likely to continue buying on Thursday,&quot; a broker with a Japanese brokerage firm said. &quot;But today's gains was boosted by the rise of Telkom, which improved overall market sentiment,&quot; she added.  </p>
<p>Cross-trading amounting to 885.26 billion rupiah pushed total transactions to 1.151 trillion rupiah.</p>
<p>Lippo Bank, Lippo Life and Lippo Securities of the Lippo Group dominated the cross-trading along with Telkom and Astra International, brokers said.</p>
<p>Brokers said the surge in Telkom was due to speculation that Deutsche Telekom might be looking for a stake in the company. Company officials denied the rumours but said joint venture firm PT Satelindo, in which Deutsche Telekom has a 25 percent stake, is likely to join hands with Telkom to jointly acquire and operate the new generation Palapa D satellite.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
