<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91159" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mideast summit ends - agreement only on more talks.</title>
<headline>Mideast summit ends - agreement only on more talks.</headline>
<byline>David Nagy</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Middle East summit ended on Wednesday with no deal on any Israeli-Palestinian dispute, but the two sides did agree to resume talks and President Bill Clinton urged the tense region to &quot;please, please&quot; give peace a chance.</p>
<p>With the leaders of Israel, the Palestinians and Jordan seated in a grim, silent row behind him, Clinton announced that mid-level negotiations on the issues unsettled in Washington would resume on the Israeli-Gaza border on Sunday.</p>
<p>He insisted this represented success for his risky two-day summit -- making the case for the others who ignored questions and declined to speak. Clinton called the summit to save the peace process from collapse after a resumption of bloody and widespread Israeli-Palestinian violence last week.</p>
<p>Clinton had to walk a rhetorical tightrope in making his success claim, however.</p>
<p>&quot;They were not able to resolve their differences here, but to be fair, when we came together, there were no advance guarantees that there would be large-scale, substantive negotiations,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>He added: &quot;The message that I want to send out across the Middle East is: I'm convinced that this process and that these parties are in better shape in their relation to one another than they were two days ago, and please, please, give us a chance to make this thing work in the days ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>Israelis called the summit a success, but some Palestinians labelled it a failure since Israel had conceded nothing.</p>
<p>&quot;The results of the summit are a great success from the point of view of the government of Israel. All the demands ... we presented in the contacts and in the negotiations we've held night and day since coming here were accepted,&quot; Israeli Cabinet Secretary Danny Naveh said on Israel radio.</p>
<p>But Hasan Asfour, a senior Palestinian negotiator, told Reuters in Jerusalem: &quot;The summit has failed because of Israeli intransigence.&quot;</p>
<p>Arafat skipped a scheduled post-summit news conference and prepared to leave Washington without offering his own public assessment of the talks.</p>
<p>But Netanyahu was not at all reticent, holding a news conference to hail the outcome. &quot;There is a greater degree of mutual understanding than there was two days ago and this will increase in time, I hope,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also promised to press to a conclusion negotiations for a partial withdrawal of Israeli troops from Hebron in the West Bank, perhaps the biggest summit sticking point. But he repeated a determination to get return assurances of security.</p>
<p>&quot;This is perhaps the most important practical thing that we have decided: to begin as early as possible, on Sunday, simultaneous negotiations on Hebron and on security and to continue those negotiations until completion.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Palestinians considered that no triumph since Israel had already signed an accord for a Hebron pullback a year ago.</p>
<p>Part of Clinton's case for summit success was that it was a breakthrough merely that Arafat and Netanyahu were talking and cooperating diplomatically after last week's violence.</p>
<p>The summit finale offered an odd insight into that cooperation. By group agreement, those two and King Hussein took a vow of silence for the final ceremony, naming Clinton their spokesmen and refusing reporters' appeals for comment.</p>
<p>Clinton finally turned and invited his guests to speak if they wished, laughing and saying he had performed &quot;a miracle&quot; of silence when they smilingly declined.</p>
<p>The U.S. president said the main achievement was that the Israelis and Palestinians &quot;are ready to renew and intensify negotiations on implementing the interim (Israeli-Palestinian peace) agreement with Hebron as the first priority.&quot;</p>
<p>Hebron is the last major town patrolled by Israeli troops in the Palestinian-run West Bank.</p>
<p>Clinton said he was sending U.S. Middle East envoy Dennis Ross to assist the negotiations on this and other issues.</p>
<p>&quot;The very first meeting will take place on Sunday morning in Erez,&quot; on the Israeli-Gaza border, he added.&quot;</p>
<p>Another dispute concerned Arab demands that Israel close a new entrance it opened last week in a tunnel near shrines sacred to both Moslems and Jews in Jerusalem -- the initial spark for rioting and gunfights that killed 57 Palestinians and 15 Israelis in Gaza and the West Bank last week.</p>
<p>Clinton said no agreement had been reached on that issue.</p>
<p>Overall, he said, &quot;I dont know that the crisis is over... I hope the level of violence has been brought lower and can remain lower while all the people in the Middle East watch these talks unfold.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
