<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91165" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ex-detective Fuhrman reaches perjury plea agreement.</title>
<headline>Ex-detective Fuhrman reaches perjury plea agreement.</headline>
<byline>Steve James</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former police detective Mark Fuhrman was charged with perjury on Wednesday for his testimony at the O.J. Simpson murder trial, but attorneys said they had reached a plea agreement to settle the case without going to trial.</p>
<p>Terms of the deal were kept under wraps, and a Los Angeles judge said he would decide later in the day whether to grant his approval. Fuhrman could face three years in jail if convicted.</p>
<p>Fuhrman, a key investigator in the 1994 murders of Simpson's ex-wife, Nicole Brown Simpson, and her friend, Ronald Goldman, pleaded not guilty to a charge that he perjured himself last year when he testified he had not used the racial slur &quot;nigger&quot; anytime in the past decade.</p>
<p>The criminal case against Fuhrman, who retired in late 1995 and now lives in Idaho, stemmed from an 11-month investigation by the California attorney general's office.</p>
<p>The perjury charge was filed one year to the day after a mostly black jury reached a verdict in the sensational murder case after deliberating for less than three hours.</p>
<p>Fuhrman is accused of lying on the witness stand on March 15, 1995, when he testified that &quot;he had not addressed any black person as a 'nigger' or spoken about black people as 'niggers' in the past 10 years.&quot;</p>
<p>Following his testimony, an aspiring screenwriter came forth with taped interviews with Fuhrman in which he uttered the racial slur dozens of times and bragged about beating and torturing suspects.</p>
<p>When Fuhrman was called back to the witness stand, he invoked his constitutional right against self-incrimination and refused to answer questions. The defence built its case around claims that Fuhrman was a racist who planted a bloody glove found at the black celebrity's estate after the murders.</p>
<p>Dressed in a gray suit and wearing a stoic expression, Fuhrman was arraigned on Wednesday in two different courtrooms, entering not-guilty pleas both times. At a third hearing, his attorney, Darryl Mounger, and prosecutor John Gordnier told Judge John Ouderkirk they had agreed to settle the case.</p>
<p>A Los Angeles police investigation has so far failed to turn up any proof that Fuhrman and other officers brutalized suspects as he claimed in the tape-recorded interviews, police sources said.</p>
<p>At one point on Wednesday, a man approached Fuhrman in the courthouse hallway, shoved court papers into his hands and declared: &quot;Mark Fuhrman, you are served, buddy.&quot;</p>
<p>It was a subpoena from Simpson's attorneys ordering him to testify in the civil wrongful-death case brought by the victims' families. The defence in the civil trial, which got under way last month in Santa Monica, wants Fuhrman to take the stand again in hopes of bolstering their claims of a police conspiracy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
