<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91163" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Service Corp. launches hostile bid for Loewen.</title>
<headline>Service Corp. launches hostile bid for Loewen.</headline>
<byline>Robin Sidel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Service Corp. International, North America's largest operator of funeral homes and cemeteries, said Wednesday it was launching a $2.9 billion hostile takeover bid for rival Loewen Group Inc.</p>
<p>Houston-based Service Corp. said it would make a tender offer of $45 a share for Loewen, up $2 a share from the unsolicited offer that Loewen's board flatly rejected last week. The $43-a-share offer, first disclosed on Sept. 17,  had been valued at a total of $2.8 billion.</p>
<p>Vancouver, British Columbia-based Loewen, which said it would review the offer, was widely expected to fight Service Corp. vigorously. Loewen has said it wants to remain independent and would not feel pressured even if Service Corp. bid $52 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;I find it interesting. Our board unanimously rejected a $43 proposal last week so I'm a little confused by their strategy. With the board unanimously rejecting a $43 a share offer, I'm not sure what they're up to,&quot; Chief Executive Officer Ray Loewen said in an interview, adding that his board of directors will meet in the next couple of weeks.</p>
<p>The hostile bid came on the same day that Loewen began trading on the New York Stock Exchange under the symbol LWN. Previously, U.S. shares of the company traded on Nasdaq. The company has said the move to NYSE was important for its growth.</p>
<p>Despite being the target of a hostile takeover, Loewen appeared lighthearted about the day's events.</p>
<p>&quot;To our knowledge, apparently our company is the only company that has had a hostile takeover bid on the hour that we were listed. So I guess that's just another chapter for my book,&quot; Loewen said with a laugh.</p>
<p>In launching the hostile action, Service Corp. left the door open for a higher bid, saying that it would consider raising its offer if Loewen would agree to negotiate a transaction. It did not specify a price.</p>
<p>The Service Corp. offer is conditioned on its ability to win at least 75 percent of outstanding shares of Loewen's common and preferred stock. That is expected to be a difficult task because Ray Loewen holds about 15 percent of the company's shares and insiders hold another 5 percent.</p>
<p>The offer also calls for Service Corp. to form a new company called New Service Corp. International, of which Service Corp. would be a subsidiary.</p>
<p>Some industry experts expressed disappointment, saying they thought the bid would be higher. But others said Service Corp.'s strategy was to pressure shareholders into convincing Loewen to secure a higher price at the bargaining table.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a chess game and this is only Service Corp.'s second move,&quot; said Fran Bernstein at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>Loewen shares fell 75 cents to $41.125 and Service Corp. lost 12.5 cents to $29.75, both on the NYSE.</p>
<p>&quot;People are expecting this to be long and drawn out. Some people think it's a good time to get out with a profit,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Both companies have aggressively been buying privately owned funeral homes, although Loewen claims to have a stronger track record than Service Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;Service Corp. has been interested in our company for many, many years. We've always known that they would be opportunistic given the chance, so in that context, it's not unexpected,&quot; Loewen said.</p>
<p>Although a combined Service Corp./Loewen would hold only about 10 percent market share in the highly fragmented North American industry, antitrust issues already have emerged.</p>
<p>Loewen said on Tuesday that the Federal Trade Commission was investigating the proposed transaction. And last week, Florida officials said they were investigating antitrust implications associated with the Service Corp. offer.</p>
<p>Service Corp. has acknowledged that it may have to divest some properties if a deal were consummated.</p>
<p>Since Service Corp. disclosed its interest, Loewen has announced two acquisitions as part of its expansion strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;I really think it's the tip of the iceberg,&quot; Loewen said of the industry's consolidation. &quot;I think it's huge. We're talking about a $15 (billion) to $20 billion revenue industry and only a couple of billion is consolidated today.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I98100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
