<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91182" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republicans challenge truthfulness on Bosnia.</title>
<headline>Republicans challenge truthfulness on Bosnia.</headline>
<byline>Jim Adams</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican senators challenged Clinton administration truthfulness on Wednesday, saying it was sending 5,000 U.S. troops to Bosnia until March after assuring Congress all of them would be out in December.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the issues that has been raised here is the issue of candor or truth,&quot; Sen. William Cohen, a Maine Republican said at a Senate Armed Services Committee hearing on Bosnia.</p>
<p>Cohen said he believed the administration was &quot;surreptitiously&quot; putting a new U.S. force in place in Bosnia without Congress's advance approval.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not mission creep. This is mission explosion,&quot; Sen. Bob Smith, a New Hampshire Republican, said at the Senate Armed Service Committee hearing. &quot;You're changing the whole operation over there.&quot;</p>
<p>Sen. John McCain, an Arizona Republican, said Congress should have to approve any longer use of U.S. troops in Bosnia. He quoted statements by U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry and General John Shalikashvili, chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, last December that they expected the U.S. troops to be out of Bosnia in a year.</p>
<p>The Defence Department announced on Tuesday the 5,000 U.S. troops would be sent to Bosnia from Germany to cover the withdrawal of the U.S. peacekeeping contingent there and would stay until March.</p>
<p>Clinton administration officials said as recently as this week that U.S. peacekeepers would leave Bosnia about the end of the year. A Pentagon spokesman said on Tuesday the goal was to keep no American soldier in Bosnia longer than 365 days.</p>
<p>Retired Adm. Leighton Smith, who was the first commander of the NATO peacekeeping force in Bosnia, told the senators that the interpretation of the peackeeping mission's length changed about last February.</p>
<p>The former commander said he also believed at first that the last peacekeeper was to leave by Dec. 20. But he said he was told by his superiors early last year to keep an effective force in Bosnia until Dec. 20 and then begin withdrawing it rapidly after that.</p>
<p>Smith testified that either the Dec. 20 policy was changed or he misunderstood it initially.</p>
<p>The former commander said he believed the decision to send the 5,000 U.S. troops to cover the withdrawal of U.S. peacekeepers was sound.</p>
<p>Smith also said he believed a new NATO peacekeeping force should replace the one leaving but said peacekeepers should stay in Bosnia no longer than two more years at most.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a better chance for peace if we stay than if we leave,&quot; he said. He said odds for a new war would increase if there was no new peacekeeping force but it was not inevitable.</p>
<p>NATO defence ministers meeting at Bergen, Norway, last week ordered a study on options for sending a new peacekeeping force into Bosnia and Perry said Washington would strongly consider contributing U.S. troops if NATO decided to send one.</p>
<p>Republican senators also criticised Perry for turning down an invitation to testify at Wednesday's hearing. Perry told reporters at the Pentagon he offered to testify to the committee on Thursday or Friday, partly in closed session.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm anxious to talk about it,&quot; Perry said, denying that he was dodging the committee.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
