<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91227" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>SOYBEAN SALE - USDA said private exporters reported sales of 108,000 tonnes of soybeans to Taiwan for delivery during the 1996/97 marketing year.</p>
<p>BARLEY TENDER - Cyprus will tender on Thursday for 25,000 tonnes optional origin feed barley, U.S. exporters said. Shipment was slated for October 15-30. &quot;It will not be U.S. barley,&quot; one U.S. exporter said of prospective suppliers.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER -  Armenia will seek 21,000 tonnes optional origin wheat for shipment up to November 20, its U.S. export agent said. The wheat would come from the European Community, Ukraine, or if U.S. origin only hard red winter no.2. The latest date for offers was Oct 14, Yerevan, Armenia.</p>
<p>Slovenia was expected to tender early next week for 35,000 to 40,000 tonnes U.S. hard red spring wheat, U.S. exporters said. Shipment was slated for October 12-November 15.</p>
<p>- The Taiwan Flour Mills Association is expected to place a tender within two weeks for two 34,000-tonne shipments of U.S. wheat, local traders said. No details were available.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - Moroccan millers group Comite Professionnel de la Minoterie is tendering for 18,500 tonnes optional soft wheat for delivery in the second half October.</p>
<p>- Sri Lanka on October 18 seeks 100,000 tonnes optional-origin wheat. It seeks 50,000 tonnes soft white wheat and 50,000 tonnes hard red winter wheat for November 11-20 shipment.</p>
<p>- Syria's General Establishment for Cereal Processing and Trade offered 100,000 tonnes of hard amber durum wheat for November. Oct 1 was the final date for offers. Confirmation is set on October 2.  </p>
<p>SOYBEAN AND CORN TENDER - Taiwan's Hui Shung Group will tender on Thursday for 38,000 tonnes of U.S. soybeans and 16,000 tonnes of U.S. No.2 corn, traders said on Wednesday. The corn and beans were slated for Nov 10-25 delivery out of U.S. Gulf and/or Nov 26-Dec 9, Pacific Northwest.</p>
<p>RICE TENDER - Sri Lanka will soon invite bids for 50,000 tonnes of rice for November/December delivery, officials of the state buying arm Cooperative Wholesale Establishment (CWE) said. The new purchase will be for delivery in November and December and there will be no restrictions on rice origin.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - Top USDA officials said they have no confirmation that the Chinese government is going to relax its current ban on corn exports, but said they are actively pursuing reports of such action.</p>
<p>... Politics, not economics, will be the major factor behind any decision that China's grain gurus make on whether or not to export corn, Far Eastern traders said. Word that central authorities could grant permission for corn-growing provinces to export between 1.5 and 2.5 million tonnes of new crop early in 1997 could not be immediately confirmed as China's National Day holiday continued.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK cont'd - Domestic grain prices in Southeast Asia generally remained soft this week with some Indonesian importers washing out contracts for up to 70,000 tonnes of corn,traders said. But regional soymeal prices were steady to firmer, particularly in Thailand where prices continued to rise as Thai feedmillers delayed imports on expectations the government will lift import quotas, or at least cut tariffs for imported animal feed, trade and industry sources in Bangkok said.</p>
<p>--Doris Frankel 312-983-7305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
