<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91298" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gingrich ad mentions promises but not 'Contract'.</title>
<headline>Gingrich ad mentions promises but not 'Contract'.</headline>
<byline>David Morgan</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Even though House Speaker Newt Gingrich owes his leadership on Capitol Hill to the &quot;Contract With America&quot;, he has not been in the mood to broadcast the fact lately.</p>
<p>The first television ad of Gingrich's re-election campaign hit the airwaves this week with a strong 30-second message about the promises he has kept since the 1994 election and the achievements of his 104th Congress.</p>
<p>But nowhere is there any mention of the 10-point tract of conservative legislative aims that Gingrich and House Majority Leader Dick Armey of Texas used two years ago to lead Republicans to their first complete election victory on Capitol Hill in 40 years.</p>
<p>&quot;He kept his promises,&quot; a TV narrator says of Gingrich in the new ad. &quot;He forced Congress to live by the same laws as all Americans, sponsored the first balanced budget in a generation.&quot;</p>
<p>Both measures were a part of the &quot;Contract With America&quot;, as were some major features of the subsequent Republican legislative agenda, including welfare reform, tax cuts, legal reform and term limits.</p>
<p>Officials with the Gingrich campaign said there was no conscious decision to omit the Contract from the ad, but they recognised that the much-assailed document was a potential liability.</p>
<p>&quot;Why waste time putting out a term that can be misrepresented, as it has been by our opponents?&quot; said Gingrich campaign spokesman Mike Shields.</p>
<p>&quot;They have managed over a period of time to divert people from the issues and the specific accomplishments contained within the Contract and redefine it as this overall extreme agenda, where they're cutting Medicaid, cutting Medicare, cutting the environment and cutting education,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Those things aren't true and we're not going to sit there and allow them to do that,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The ad, which began running on Atlanta television stations Monday, emphasises the Republican reforms of welfare and health-care insurance, and criticises President Clinton for his veto of a balanced budget in 1995.</p>
<p>Never does it mention Gingrich's opponent for Georgia's 6th Congressional District -- Democrat Michael Coles, a millionaire businessman who already has his second TV commercial on the air, after having spent $500,000 on TV ads during the primary season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
