<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91313" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. NRC proposes fine against Thermal Science.</title>
<headline>U.S. NRC proposes fine against Thermal Science.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Wednesday said it proposed a $900,000 fine against Thermal Science Inc, of St. Louis, Missouri, for misrepresenting its Thermo-Lag fire barrier products.</p>
<p>The NRC said it concluded that the company misrepresented the involvement level of a test laboratory, Industrial Testing Laboratories Inc (ITL), in fire barrier and other tests.</p>
<p>Thermal Science submitted information to the NRC during an agency investigation on Thermo-Lag products used for fire protection in nuclear power plants.  </p>
<p>The NRC also said it found that Thermal Science indirectly misrepresented involvement of the company and of test laboratories, including ITL, in testing of Thermo-Lag products in reports and other documents that it knew contained inaccurate and/or incomplete information.</p>
<p>The NRC cited nine separate violations.  </p>
<p>&quot;Violations involving multiple instances in which a vendor deliberately provides inaccurate and/or incomplete information related to the performance and quality of its important-to-safety products constitute a very significant regulatory concern, are wholly unacceptable, and will not be tolerated,&quot; James Lieberman, director of the NRC's Office of Enforcement, said in a letter to Thermal Science.  </p>
<p>&quot;These violations are further aggravated because they were committed in the context of an ongoing NRC investigation into concerns about the quality and performance of Thermo-Lag products with significant implications regarding the compliance of a substantial number of nuclear power plant licensees with the Commission's regulations,&quot; Lieberman said.</p>
<p>Lieberman said the NRC staff decided to set the maximum statutory limit of $100,000 for each of nine violations &quot;because of the egregious, deliberate and repeated nature of these violations.&quot;  </p>
<p>Lieberman said supplying insufficiently-tested Thermo Lag to NRC licensees placed them in jeopardy of violating of NRC regulations, and compromised the level of plant safety.</p>
<p>Thermal Science has 30 days to pay the proposed fine or to protest it, the NRC said. The company may request a hearing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
