<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91409" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hong Kong will remain a top financial centre - Tsang.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong will remain a top financial centre - Tsang.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Thatcher</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong will remain one of the world's top financial centres after it reverts to China next year though that could be undermined if there are any signs that democracy was being blocked, the territory's financial secretary Donald Tsang said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He also reiterated the Hong Kong dollar's 13-year old link to the U.S. currency would not change under Chinese rule.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no reason to change it (the dollar peg). I expect the link to remain well beyond 1997,&quot; he told reporters during the annual meeting of the IMF and World Bank.</p>
<p>If anything, Hong Kong would be more democratic under Chinese rule, as its chief executive would have to be a local picked by a body of 400, in turn selected by Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;It is certainly better than now, of course, in Hong Kong where the governor is sent from Britain. We have no way of deciding who he would be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;(The chief executive) would be a Hong Kong resident, not someone who was just parachuted in. That is the only difference between the two systems,&quot; Tsang said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's attraction as a financial centre lies not just in its infrastructure but the fact it had a rule of law, freedom of speech, a level playing field and an honest civil service.</p>
<p>&quot;These are the things which make people invest in Hong Kong. If any of these things are removed ... then people would start to think about leaving.&quot;</p>
<p>While a fairly large chunk of the population had the means to move elsewhere, Tsang said for the forseeable future it was hard to imagine why professionals would choose to.</p>
<p>The political transition will take place against a backdrop of a steady economy with Hong Kong still ranking with New York and London as a top financial centre.</p>
<p>Only they had the four crucial elements -- the rule of law, a level playing field for all, freedom of speech and an honest civil service. Tokyo and Singapore could not quite match that, and certainly not Shanghai.</p>
<p>&quot;Shanghai has none (of those qualities) and is unlikely to have for a long, long time,&quot; Tsang said of the city which has been tipped by some as a potential competitior to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Tsang said he understood that those who did business in China were worried that Hong Kong would eventually come under a similar shadow of corruption.</p>
<p>&quot;The important thing is Hong Kong people believe in safeguarding their own system. We must not let corruption appear in Hong Kong.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
