<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91441" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Jaguar XK8 faces uphill sales struggle.</title>
<headline>Jaguar XK8 faces uphill sales struggle.</headline>
<byline>Neil Winton</byline>
<dateline>PARIS</dateline>
<text>
<p>A flame red Ferrari driven by a stunning movie star. A silver Porsche storming down the autobahn at 155 mph.</p>
<p>Anyone with an interest in cars will probably have an immediate picture in their minds when these charismatic and successful cars are mentioned.</p>
<p>Try Maserati. &quot;That's a famous old Italian sports car. Are they still around?.&quot; Just barely, selling less than 2,000 cars a year. Or Lotus. &quot;Didn't it win a few Grand Prix once?&quot;</p>
<p>Jaguar. In Britain, that could conjure up visions of rusting, unreliable and poorly built cars from the '70s and '80s.</p>
<p>Jaguar is about to fill its showrooms with its new $65,000 plus XK8 coupes and convertibles, and it is hoping that word-of-mouth at the recent Paris car show, where it launched XK8 sales, centred on its glamorous old marques like the legendary &quot;E&quot; type, or the XK120.</p>
<p>If not, Jaguar will have a hard time making money with the new car, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Image is all in the luxury sports car market,&quot; said Peter Schmidt, with Automotive Industry Data in Britain.</p>
<p>Being owned by a mass carmaker like Ford Motor Co. can't help. Jaguar was taken over by the the second-biggest carmaker in America for $2.5 billion in 1989.</p>
<p>Schmidt says the sector is dying, and only ultra-desirable products can be successful.</p>
<p>&quot;Sports cars are a dying and shrinking market. If you plot the sales of, say, the Toyota Supra, sales are falling like a stone,&quot; Schmidt said. &quot;And people's tastes are changing in Europe and America. They don't want to flaunt their wealth; the wives of the rich are even wearing their fur coats inside out.&quot;</p>
<p>Jaguar Chairman Nick Scheele has said he hopes to sell 12,000 XK8s a year, mainly in the United States. The price has yet to be announced, but the 4.0 litre V8's predecessor, the XJ-S, sold for between $65,000 and $75,000.</p>
<p>Competition will be formidable. Apart from Ferraris and Porsches at the high-priced end of the market, there will be attacks from below from Mercedes with its little SLK, and the BMW MZ3, a souped up version of the U.S.-made two-seater.</p>
<p>Some analysts see positive signs for the XK8, particularly in the U.S. market.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. looks pretty positive for the launch of the XK8. The market there is buoyant, Porsche is selling reasonably strongly there at the moment,&quot; said Ian Robertson of London's Economist Intelligence Unit.</p>
<p>&quot;The current competition in the U.S., the Mercedes SL, Porsche 911, Honda NSX, BMW 8 are looking a bit tired, so some new blood should lead to incremental sales,&quot; said Robertson.</p>
<p>But he also sees a shadow over the future of the high-performance cars.</p>
<p>&quot;Environmental measures like a long-mooted carbon fuel tax in Europe could spell the end of these big, high performance vehicles. And there's another negative. The sector immediately below -- the Porsche Boxster (also introduced at the Paris show) and smaller Mercedes, some buyers might opt for these more environmentally friendly types,&quot; said Robertson.</p>
<p>Tougher rules on the environment might force Jaguar, and other sports car makers, to seek new buyers in booming new economies like the Far East.</p>
<p>&quot;Outside of Europe there are fewer concerns about fuel consumption, particularly in the U.S.,&quot; said John Lawson, European automotive analyst for Salomon Brothers.</p>
<p>&quot;Vehicles that parade wealth and status are more fashionable in emerging markets. The sports and luxury car makers should concentrate more on opening up and servicing them where environmental concerns are not so pressing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Automotive Industry Data's Schmidt believes Jaguar will have a hard time meeting its targets.</p>
<p>&quot;After an initial flurry of registrations, many I'm sure among senior Ford executives, I don't feel confident that Jaguar will succeed -- 12,000 is a tall order and in my view it will be exceedingly difficult for them to achieve these sales,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jaguar will have an initial boost to its sales in the U.S.</p>
<p>Luxury store chain Neiman Marcus has included a special edition of the XK8 in its Christmas catalogue. It is offering 50 Titanium painted XK8s with extras, including a Harman Kardon sound system, chrome wheels, wool footwell rugs and a convertible wind deflector. Each costs $74,975 before taxes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
