<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91444" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. calls charges in Iraqi paper &quot;total nonsense&quot;.</title>
<headline>U.N. calls charges in Iraqi paper &quot;total nonsense&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali's spokeswoman on Wednesday said Iraqi newspaper allegations that he was delaying an oil-for-food deal to please Washington were &quot;total nonsense.&quot;</p>
<p>The daily Babel newspaper, owned by President Saddam Hussein's son Uday, said Boutros-Ghali had postponed implementing the limited oil sales plan in order to persuade Washington to allow him another five-year term in office.</p>
<p>&quot;Nonsense, total nonsense, &quot; said chief U.N. spokeswoman Sylvana Foa in answer to questions.</p>
<p>&quot;We are moving along with the implementation. We hope to get things really rocking and rolling as soon as the dust is settled and as soon as we get our assessments and everybody knows that,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The United States has said it would block Boutros-Ghali's re-election and has vowed not to change its mind. His term expires this year.</p>
<p>The United Nations is currently assessing the safety of aid workers and others who are to distribute humanitarian supplies in the Kurdish north after Saddam Hussein's offensive there last month in support of one Kurdish faction. Consequently relief workers left the country along with some Kurds who were instrumental for implementing the plan.</p>
<p>The oil-for-food deal, signed in a memorandum of understanding between Iraq and the United Nations on May 20 allows Baghdad to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months to purchase food, medicine and other supplies for its people suffering under six years of U.N. sanctions.</p>
<p>In an unusual attack against Boutros-Ghali, Babel on Wednesday said: &quot;Even the U.N. Secretary-General who had urged Iraq to enter dialogue to sign the memorandum, sought the first opportunity, giving the security in northern Iraq as an excuse, to postpone its implementation, flattering the U.S. in order that it may accept to extend his term of office.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is trading with this memorandum in order to achieve his own ends. Everyone is shedding tears for the Iraqi people,&quot; the Iraqi newspaper added.</p>
<p>The plan was about to go into force but Boutros-Ghali delayed it when the fighting in the north broke out and the United States responded with cruise missiles.</p>
<p>On Monday, U.N. relief officials ended a visit to northern Iraq to see if conditions were suitable for implementing the pact and said it appeared the security situation had improved.</p>
<p>&quot;My impression is that there is a possibility of humanitarian action,&quot; said Gualtiero Fulcheri, the head of the U.N. relief efforts in Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
