<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91449" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portuguese bonds at highs, await rate decisions.</title>
<headline>Portuguese bonds at highs, await rate decisions.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portuguese cash bonds and futures closed at record highs and the escudo hit a two-year high against the mark as the market awaited tomorrow's key decisions on official rates by the central banks of Portugal and Spain.</p>
<p>&quot;The market closed at historic highs, futures rose above 101.50 points and 10-year bonds closed well-supported, yielding below 7.70 percent,&quot; said one operator.</p>
<p>&quot;Portuguese bonds are rising on optimism Portugal will qualify for the European single currency, and the rise today, identical to Spain, is due to a conviction that we will see rate cuts in Spain and Portugal this week,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>&quot;Now we have to wait to see the size of the Spanish rate cut and see how the Bank of Portugal reacts,&quot; the operator said.</p>
<p>Analysts were divided over whether Portugal would cut its key repo rate tomorrow even if Spain does so because of continuing uncertainty over the inflation rate.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a reasonable possibility that the Bank of Portugal could cut rates, but I think it should wait until there is greater certainty over the inflation trend,&quot; said Valetim Martins of Lisbon broker Siemca.</p>
<p>Isabel Cabral of broker Fincor said: &quot;Consumer price inflation should be showing a more favourable trend now, the escudo is strong and the 1997 budget is practically approved. If Spain lowers rates, the Bank of Portugal will do so too.&quot;</p>
<p>She said that if the Bank of Spain cuts its repo rate by 25 basis points, the Bank of Portugal would do the same and both rates would stand at 7.00 percent.  </p>
<p>Growing confidence that Portugal will qualify for the European Union's single currency in the first wave drove the escudo to a two-year high, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The latest news about the Portuguese economy is positive and points to Portugal being ready to form part of the first group (moving to monetary union),&quot; said one market analyst.</p>
<p>The escudo stood at 101.20/25 per mark at 1643 GMT.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon newsroom +351-1-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
