<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91459" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. chief shocked at massacres in Liberia.</title>
<headline>U.N. chief shocked at massacres in Liberia.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali on Wednesday expressed shock at reports of weekend massacres in Liberia's Grand Cape Mount County, where thousands have been cut off from relief aid.</p>
<p>U.N. reports said that a &quot;cold-blooded massacre&quot; took place at Sinje on Saturday, leaving at least 17 civilians dead, many more wounded, and forcing about 1,000 others to flee the area. Some reports put the number dead at 42.</p>
<p>A United Nations team reached the area in southwest Liberia on Sept. 30 and evacuated some civilians for medical treatment in Monrovia, the capital. They included five women and men with bullet wounds and an 8-month-old girl whose foot had been hacked off.</p>
<p>&quot;The secretary-general condemns this heinous crime, which is now being investigated by the U.N. Observer Mission in Liberia (UNOMIL),&quot; said his spokeswoman, Sylvana Foa.</p>
<p>&quot;He was shocked to learn of the attack. He wishes to stress once again that the continued support of the international community for the peace process in Liberia is contingent on the Liberian factions' demonstrating their commitment to resolve their differences peacefully,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>U.N. reports said the attackers remained in Sinje after the massacre, and then left with food supplies that had been distributed previously. They kidnapped some civilians to carry the looted goods for them.</p>
<p>Anthony Nyakyi, the special U.N. representative in Liberia, said in a statement that most of the victims were women, children and elderly men.</p>
<p>He said the identity of the assassins was not known and that the massacre was a major setback to relief workers seeking to deliver food to the interior of the country.</p>
<p>A U.N. convoy last week dropped off food for 5,000 people in towns and villages in Cape Mount County for the first time in months. Civilians and local aid workers said people had been dying each day in villages in the area.</p>
<p>Charles Taylor, who launched the war in 1989 and whose faction was at the centre of fighting in Monrovia in April and May, said militia rivals had robbed and beaten his supporters who had tried to take food to Tubmanburg town.</p>
<p>People in the area, which is plagued by malaria and other killer diseases, have little medicine and subsistence food. There were signs of malnutrition among children.</p>
<p>West African peacekeepers on Monday ventured into Cape Mount for the first time since January. Two factions vying for control of the area agreed last week to grant relief groups unconditional safe passage for the first time since March.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
