<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91468" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Scientology Church members on trial in Lyon.</title>
<headline>French Scientology Church members on trial in Lyon.</headline>
<dateline>LYON, France 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former followers of the French Church of Scientology accused it in court on Wednesday of applying intense mental pressure and extracting large sums of money from those who joined it.</p>
<p>&quot;I suffered a lot,&quot; said Marie-There Massard, 60, with tears in her eyes as she spoke of sessions of questioning by church officers at which she had to stand against a wall with arms apart.</p>
<p>&quot;They shouted at me and pulled me,&quot; said Massard who told the court that she gave the church a million francs ($200,000) over four years.</p>
<p>Roman Catholic priest Louis-Michel Brolles, 53, said the Church of Scientology with which he flirted received 500,000 francs ($100,000) from him for &quot;purification sessions.&quot; He said he had received the money from an elderly woman.</p>
<p>&quot;It is completely different from the Catholic church because there is no God in it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The ex-followers were testifying at the trial of 23 French Scientologists in the central city of Lyon in a case expected to provide a rare glimpse of the organisation's inner workings.</p>
<p>The trial, which began on Monday and is expected to last seven days, was triggered by the 1988 suicide of a church follower in Lyon.</p>
<p>Prosecutors accuse the church of &quot;exploiting the good faith and gullibility of its victims for commercial profit, through pseudo-scientific and paramedical means, to their financial detriment and at their medical and psychological risk&quot;.</p>
<p>If found guilty, the defendants face up to five years in jail and fines of up to five million francs ($1 million) on charges ranging from manslaughter to embezzlement to fraud and complicity.</p>
<p>Presiding judge Patrick Lifschutz rejected a bid by defence lawyers to have the trial called off on procedural grounds.</p>
<p>Church of Scientology spokesman Marc Bromberg denounced the proceeding as &quot;heresy&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the return of the Inquisition,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;This is purely a religious matter. All religions have been accused of fraud. There is no proof in this case. There is no fraud in the Church of Scientology.&quot;</p>
<p>The religion, founded in 1954 by the late American science-fiction novelist L. Ron Hubbard, claims more than eight million adherents worldwide, including 4,000 in France.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LYON, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
