<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91552" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish bonds firm in positive convergence trade.</title>
<headline>Irish bonds firm in positive convergence trade.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish government bonds continued to firm in busy afternoon trade on Wednesday on the back of positive convergence trade and good bid interest, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen continued strength in the Irish market on the back of positive convergence trade and good sentiment throughout Europe. Irish bonds have been well bid for the last three weeks now,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;We are aware that Ireland's National Treasury Management Agency (NTMA) will be limited in the amount of issuing it can do before the year end and this, added to the fact that there is room for a cut in interest rates, has helped,&quot; the dealer added.  </p>
<p>NCB Stockbrokers said in a research note on Wednesday that the Irish Central Bank could not hold down the exchange rate and maintain current interest rate levels because demand for Irish pounds exceeded supply at these levels.</p>
<p>NCB said if the currency was not allowed to rise, then interest rates must fall to bring demand and supply into balance.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected the Irish bond market to get a further boost with the release of the end-September Exchequer Borrowing Requirement (EBR) which is due for release from the Department of Finance at 1630 local time.  </p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters forecast a budget surplus of up to 175 million Irish pounds, as timing factors and the robust economy boost the Exchequer's coffers.</p>
<p>By 1450 GMT, the 8.00 percent bond due 2000 had risen 50p from Tuesday's close to 106.96 to yield 5.92 percent having been at 106.76 at 1045 GMT.</p>
<p>The 8.00 percent bond due 2006 had gained 52p from the close at 107.65 to yield 6.78 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market also awaited the release of key U.S. non-farm payrolls data on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Damien Lynch, Dublin Newsroom +353 1 6603377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
