<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91554" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU rejects Portuguese TV state aid allegations.</title>
<headline>EU rejects Portuguese TV state aid allegations.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission rejected allegations on Wednesday that Portuguese public television was receiving state subsidies, a thorny issue which also divides the sector in France and Spain.</p>
<p>&quot;Public financing of Portuguese public TV channel RTP (Radiotelevisao Portuguesa)...relating to its public service obligations do not constitute state aid,&quot; the Commission said in a statement after its regular weekly meeting.</p>
<p>But EU sources warned against jumping to the conclusion that the Commission would react likewise regarding complaints filed by France's private broadcaster TF1 against its public rivals France 2 and France 3.</p>
<p>The Commission said that RTP's analytical accounting had made it easy to assess clearly how its television programmes were financed, including those which resulted from the obligation imposed by the Portuguese government to provide general interest services.</p>
<p>This could not be said of the books of French public broadcasters or Spain's TVE, against which the Commission has also received a complaint.</p>
<p>The Commission's decision on RTP is a setback for private TV channel SIC of Portuguese media tycoon and former Prime Minister Francisco Pinto Balsemao, which had cried foul at its rival receiving state money while also competing for advertising revenue.</p>
<p>In its decision, the Commission took into consideration the fact that RTP must cover the whole of Portugal, including distant islands of Madere and the Azores, engage in co-operation programmes with former Portuguese colonies in Africa and care for religious, cultural and educational needs.</p>
<p>In contrast, private broadcasters' programming was solely dictated by commercial considerations. The result was a clear slide in RTP's audience share since the sector was open to free competition.</p>
<p>The Commission said the Portuguese state had compensated RTP for public service obligations to the extent of 15 percent to 18 percent of the company's annual budget.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
