<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91643" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FedEx workers, Kennedy step up union fight.</title>
<headline>FedEx workers, Kennedy step up union fight.</headline>
<byline>William Scally</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Employees of Federal Express Corp appeared with Sen. Edward Kennedy Wednesday to support his uphill fight against pending legislation they say would block their efforts to join a union.</p>
<p>The seven employees told personal stories of alleged harsh management practices and arbitrary work rules and of inability to get any wage increases.</p>
<p>Kennedy is leading a Senate fight to remove from an airports bill what he calls a &quot;union-busting&quot; provision that would affect only FedEx. Both FedEx and labour have been lobbying hard in the dispute.</p>
<p>The Senate is to vote Thursday on cutting off Kennedy's filibuster of the popular bill. Sixty votes are needed to cut off a filibuster.</p>
<p>&quot;At the present time it's still an uphill battle,&quot; the Massachusetts Democrat said. But he said senators were becoming more aware of the issue.</p>
<p>Kennedy's ally in the union fight, Sen. Paul Simon, D-Illinois, said the disputed provision would improperly intervene in pending labour litigation over FedEx drivers.</p>
<p>He said Federal express management &quot;may very well win the vote tomorrow but it will be a Pyrrhic victory&quot; cited for years as an illustration of &quot;special interests prevailing over the public interest.&quot;</p>
<p>But at a separate news conference Senate Democratic Leader Tom Daschle said that even if the provision were deleted from the bill it would be difffcult if not impossible for the House to accept the change. This would mean that the bill, which authorises money for airport improvements, would die.</p>
<p>The House, which approved the bill last week, has adjourned for the year and Kennedy's filibuster is partly the reason that the Senate remained in session.</p>
<p>&quot;The reality is we either accept this conference report (the airports bill) or we lose it,&quot; Daschle said. &quot;I don't think we ought to lose it.&quot;</p>
<p>Senate Republican Leader Trent Lott has predicted that the bill's supporters will win as many as 70 votes to cut off Kennedy's filibuster.</p>
<p>At issue is whether FedEx truck drivers are covered by the Railway Labour Act, requiring them to form a nationwide bargaining unit if they wish to have a union, or the National Labour Relations Act, which allows more easily attainable local bargaining units.</p>
<p>The railway law covers airline pilots and FedEx's pilots are unionized. The truck drivers are not.</p>
<p>A bill passed last year left the situation ambiguous. FedEx and its supporters say the provision in the bill is needed to correct a mistake in the earlier measure.</p>
<p>Kennedy charged that workers' rights were being threatened by &quot;this right-wing Congress&quot; and that FedEx had conspired with key Republicans to &quot;sneak through a change in the Railway Labour Act that will deprive these workers of their right to form a local union.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
