<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91660" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Big dividends planned for Deutsche Telekom share.</title>
<headline>Big dividends planned for Deutsche Telekom share.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Telekom's share issue next month, set to be Europe's largest-ever stock offering, could go on the block for 25 marks a share and will be sweetened with promises of big dividends, analysts' reports said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The huge 15 billion mark ($9.8 billion) initial public offering (IPO) will transform the company overnight into the most heavily-weighted stock on Frankfurt's DAX index of 30 blue-chip stocks.</p>
<p>Analysts' reports that have begun to trickle out to the press portrayed DT as an investment with some short-term risks but one that could be quite profitable over time.</p>
<p>&quot;The Telekom share represents an interesting investment opportunity for long-term and risk-conscious investors,&quot; concluded Helaba Trust in a report obtained by Reuters.</p>
<p>Hoping to smooth over apparent risks, DT has said it will pay 1.5 billion marks in dividends for 1996 and plans to announce on Friday the amount it will pay for 1997.</p>
<p>DG Bank, a coordinator of the listing, said in a report the new shares would be eligible for full dividends in 1996, despite the fact that investors will only own them for six weeks of the year. It predicted a 1996 dividend of 60 pfennigs per share.</p>
<p>According to a report in the Evening Standard newspaper in London, Deutsche Bank, the main coordinator of DT's listing, expects DT to pay dividends totalling three billion marks for 1997. This should rise to four billion marks by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, the investment division of Deutsche Bank AG, declined to comment on the report.</p>
<p>DT is expected to float around 500 million shares on stock exchanges in Germany, New York, Tokyo and Toronto with trade beginning on November 18.</p>
<p>The new shares will result from a capital increase of 2.5 billion marks in nominal terms that will put DT's equity at 12.65 billion marks after the listing and reduce the German government's stake to around 80 percent.</p>
<p>The share price is expected to be set on November 17 after the conclusion of bookbuilding, the process in which bids are taken from potential investors. Bookbuilding is set to begin after October 22 with the publication of the final prospectus.</p>
<p>Studies by Sachsen Landesbank and investment bank Hauck Bankiers predicted Telekom would offer shares to investors in a range of 22 to 29 marks, which banks suggested would lead to an appropriate subscription price of 25 marks.</p>
<p>Not accounting for planned discounts in the share price to encourage investment, DG Bank said DT shares would have a price of 31.60 marks when discounted on earnings or 36 marks when discounted for cash flow.</p>
<p>The main risks facing DT investors after the company's IPO are competition as it loses its monopoly, tougher regulation, its mountain of debt and investor disappointment over an expected decline in 1996 profits.</p>
<p>Deutsche Bank analysts, according to the Evening Standard report, expect DT to shave its 100 billion mark debt mountain by one third over the next four years. But growing competition and the effects of new taxes will hit profits this year.</p>
<p>In the first half of 1996, DT's net profit plunged 96 percent from the previous year to 129 million marks. The huge fall resulted from one-off charges and allocations to reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;There is the risk that over the short- and mid-term weak 1996 results could be met with disappointment when it is made known next year,&quot; Helaba said in its report.</p>
<p>&quot;The DT share price could also suffer intermittently because of the large number of European telecommunications share offerings expected.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
