<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="91727" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US E. Coast heating oil stocks up 500,000 bbl- EIA.</title>
<headline>US E. Coast heating oil stocks up 500,000 bbl- EIA.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. East Coast heating oil stocks grew by 500,000 barrels to 23.8 million barrels in the week ending September 27, the Energy Information Administration said Wednesday.</p>
<p>However the gain was too little to offset losses in other regions, which pushed total U.S. heating oil stocks down 400,000 barrels to 48.7 million barrels, 29 percent less than a year ago, according to data from EIA.</p>
<p>&quot;Low heating oil stocks continue as an issue of concern as September ends and the traditional heating season begins,&quot; EIA said in its weekly distillate watch.  </p>
<p>East Coast distillate stocks, which include heating oil and diesel, gained 400,000 barrels to reach 38.4 million barrels last week from the previous week.</p>
<p>Total U.S. distillate stocks fell 800,000 bbls to 111.0 million barrels, including a 400,000 barrel drop in diesel inventories.</p>
<p>&quot;Total distillate production was a strong 3.4 million barrels per day, but heating oil output declined, especially in PADD I (East Coast),&quot; EIA said.</p>
<p>Imports averaged 234,000 bpd last week, their highest level since the beginning of August.</p>
<p>Distillate demand rose to 3.6 million bpd last week from 3.4 million bpd the previous week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
