<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92076" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMF/World Bank annual meetings preach to converted.</title>
<headline>IMF/World Bank annual meetings preach to converted.</headline>
<byline>Alver Carlson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The annual meetings of the International Monetary Fund, which continue on Wednesday, are taking on the character of a religious revival gathering, with no one willing to question the path of the global economy.</p>
<p>From rich and poor, large and small, the litany has been the same -- the global economy is entering a period of growing opportunity and well-being that provides a stepping off place to deal with issues that had seemed almost insurmountable.</p>
<p>Problems that have only been whispered about in the past, such as entrenched corruption in many countries, are being discussed openly in the belief that it can be changed.</p>
<p>World Bank President James Wolfensohn on Tuesday lashed out at corruption in industrial and developing countries, calling it a cancer and vowing not to tolerate it in the projects his organisation finances.</p>
<p>&quot;Corruption is a problem that all countries have to confront,&quot; he told policymakers from the bank's 181 member nations. &quot;We need to deal with the cancer of corruption.&quot;</p>
<p>By throwing a spotlight on a once hidden problem, the plain-speaking Wolfensohn risked raising the hackles of developing nations that may view his broadside against bribery as just an attempt to meddle in their affairs.</p>
<p>In the past, the meetings have hardly been cosy affairs. Those left out of the global economic dream have complained bitterly that the industrial countries were not doing enough to improve their condition.</p>
<p>The joint IMF and World Bank Development Committee, a forum where rich and poor countries can chew over differences, has often been the scene of frustration on both sides.</p>
<p>The industrial countries as well as the IMF have taken the view that their poor counterparts have refused to take the painful medicine of reform -- opening their markets, cutting runaway budget deficits, reducing subsidies and the like.</p>
<p>The decision to go ahead with a multi-billion dollar plan to help the poorest countries unload a portion of their unsustainable debt might easily have ended in bitterness on both sides with the donors saying it was too expensive and the debtors saying it was not enough.</p>
<p>But the outcome in the Development Committee was almost unprecedented as both sides hailed the agreement in what Wolfensohn called a &quot;lovefest.&quot;</p>
<p>Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin is expected on Wednesday to repeat again the current economic orthodoxy when he speaks to the plenary session.</p>
<p>The United States, Rubin will likely say, has tightened its belt and has produced a big payoff in growth, low inflation and unemployment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
