<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92148" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FOCUS-Dutch hold to strategy with TNT bid.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Dutch hold to strategy with TNT bid.</headline>
<byline>Keiron Henderson</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch telecoms and mail group Koninklijke PTT Nederland NV (KPN) said on Wednesday its bid for Australia's TNT Ltd was part of a strategy to expand globally and did not mark a retreat from telecoms.</p>
<p>KPN earlier launched a 2.7 billion guilder ($1.58 billion) recommended offer for the worldwide transport group in one of the biggest bids in Dutch corporate history.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no change in our strategy. This is a concrete implementation of our strategy,&quot; the managing director of KPN's postal division, Ad Scheepbouwer, told a news conference in Amsterdam.</p>
<p>Asked whether the bid marked a softening in the attitude of KPN -- made up of PTT Telecom and PTT Post -- towards telecoms competition, he replied: &quot;Absolutely not.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;PTT Telecom and PTT Post both have the aim to improve their performance and to expand their business. Telecom has done that through a series of joint ventures...PTT Post because of the different dynamics of the market cannot go that way, he said.</p>
<p>TNT Ltd, with its strong European courier delivery and logistics businesses, gave PTT Post big opportunities, said Scheepbouwer.</p>
<p>&quot;If we want to grow, we can't do it in our real core business, letters, so we look at other businesses. If you look at the opportunities this one is a very unique chance,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>KPN finance director Cees Griffeon said the company wanted to position PTT Post strongly ahead of eventual postal liberalisation in Europe, anticipated by the end of the decade.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage we really want to be able to go as far into European networks to the extent that liberalisation would permit us to do so, to position ourselves for whenever Europe is going to move,&quot; he said in an interview after the news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition has nothing to do with telecoms. It's a KPN strategy that we want to develop both businesses, jointly and severally, in the best possible way.&quot;</p>
<p>The share market applauded the deal, driving Dutch PTT shares up 2.10 guilders to 61.00 guilders on much higher than usual daily turnover of 4.0 million shares by 1145 GMT.</p>
<p>Analysts said TNT, which in its 1996 financial year made an operating profit in Europe of A$172 million ($137 million) would give Dutch PTT a strong advantage in big economies such as Germany and Britain after any postal liberalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like a sensible deal for them, basically what they want to do is achieve a dominant position in the international postal market before it's liberalised,&quot; said London-based analyst James Ross of ABN AMRO Hoare Govett.</p>
<p>&quot;TNT has got a good strategic position in the U.K. and German markets and an excellent position in the Pacific Rim markets,&quot; Ross said.</p>
<p>He was unconcerned by the Dutch company's decision to develop the postal arm at a time when competition in the telecoms was growing ever more intense.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people have generally accepted that the postal story is not a bad one and that the postal market is at the stage of development (pre-liberalisation) that the telecoms market was 10 years ago,&quot; said Ross.</p>
<p>Analysts said investors would like the TNT acquisition as it would enhance earnings quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;People might see this as developing the other string to their bow,&quot; said an analyst, who declined to be named. &quot;If you can manoeuvre yourself away from the telecoms battlefield a little that could be positive because it's a market with a lot of new issues on the horizon,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Others expressed initial reservations about the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;From the risk profile we're not too enthusiastic about it. We don't really think this is the move that's going to put them far apart from everyone else,&quot; said ING analyst Eric de Graaf.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to change the risk profile of the company substantially in our view. It's a more cyclical business, it's much more dependent on world wide economic activity,&quot; he said. ($1=1.709 Guilder)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
