<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92287" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIAN OLOS SPREAD OVER BUNDS SEEN NARROWING MORE.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN OLOS SPREAD OVER BUNDS SEEN NARROWING MORE.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian OLOs started higher on Wednesday and dealers were unanimous in believing the market had the potential to outperform Bunds in the near term.</p>
<p>But some warned it would take just one big seller to spoil the post-1997 budget convergence play and that further down the road all the risk remained on the downside.</p>
<p>&quot;The market remains extremely well bid with strong domestic demand. In 10-years, we are at 13 basis points above Bunds. I can imagine we will go to 10,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;I really have the feeling we are going to 10 basis points. I'm not happy about it, but there you are,&quot; said another.  </p>
<p>Presenting his 1997 budget to parliament on Tuesday, Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene said the country had now done all it needed to qualify for European economic and monetary union (EMU) in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are convinced Belgium will be in EMU and you look at other core European markets, we are still the cheapest,&quot; one trader said, noting that Dutch DSLs were trading at a 15 basis point discount to Germany in the 10-year area, while French OATs were almost flat.</p>
<p>He also noted that Belgium had the steepest yield curve of any of the core markets.</p>
<p>But only at the long-end of the yield curve were yields strongly above German levels.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is fresh buying in the market it will be in the 10-year area, around the 2004 to 2006 maturities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But another dealer was sceptical that Belgium could continue to outperform. &quot;People think that after EMU the spread will be 10 to 15 basis points, but that's not right. Once EMU happens the only way to punish countries is through their credit rating. Therefore even after EMU the spread can go out to 30,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the 1997 budget was little more than a book keeping exercise that was storing up problems for the future.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
