<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92399" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: TV3 says new channel to focus on young NZ viewers.</title>
<headline>TV3 says new channel to focus on young NZ viewers.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's TV3 Network Ltd said on Wednesday its second channel, due to go to air in mid 1997, would focus on young, urban viewers with entertainment-based programming.</p>
<p>Managing Director Graeme Hunter told a news conference the new channel, TV4, would be available in the main centres of Auckland, Wellington, Christchurch, Hamilton and Dunedin, as well as Whangarei, Tauranga, Rotorua, Palmerston North, Timaru and Invercargill, by next June.  </p>
<p>TV3, controlled by Canada's CanWest Global Communications Corp  CWW.TO, was embarking on a multi-million dollar investment in existing transmitting sites to enhance the broadcasting reach and quality of the new channel, which would have an audience reach of over 2.0 million viewers.</p>
<p>Hunter said TV4 would, for the first time in TV3's six-year history, enable it to compete on a more equal basis with the two state-owned Television New Zealand channels.</p>
<p>Programming for TV4 would include a combination of new series and and programmes that had developed a popular following.  </p>
<p>&quot;While I won't be specific about the exact programming content for commercial reasons, I can confirm that our new channel will deliver what viewers have told us they want and, at the same time, give advertisers access to a more targeted audience group,&quot; Hunter said.</p>
<p>TV3's audience share growth of more than 25 percent over the past three years demonstrated its ability to deliver programming demanded by the critical 18-49 year old market.  </p>
<p>He said it was conceivable TV4 would produce some of its own programmes but news and current affairs were not intended for the network. Hunter said TV3 had successfully built up &quot;critical mass&quot; to handle the expansion.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
