<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92431" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Oct 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Oct 2.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Wednesday's Malaysian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NEW STRAITS TIMES</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad on Tuesday night declared open the 421-metre Kuala Lumpur Tower, Asia's tallest telecommunications tower, amid a display of fireworks.</p>
<p>-- Technical hitches led to the postponement of the signing of the Bakun dam contract, said Mahathir.</p>
<p>-- Shareholders removed Seal Inc Bhd's chairman Jaffar Abdul, his deputy and two directors, and replaced them with a new management team.</p>
<p>BUSINESS TIMES</p>
<p>-- Stockbroking houses may be subject to a tiered regulatory system similar to that for banks and finance companies in efforts to further liberalise the capital market, said Securities Commission chairman Munir Abdul Majid.</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad on Tuesday unveiled a prototype of the Malaysian natural gas vehicle, a collaboration between national car-maker Proton and state-owned oil firm Petronas.</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>-- The Securities Commission has submitted a proposal to the government to build a benchmark yield curve in its bid to develop the ringgit bond market, said commision chairman Munir Majid.</p>
<p>- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
