<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92455" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan PM faces outside chance of losing election.</title>
<headline>Japan PM faces outside chance of losing election.</headline>
<byline>Teruaki Ueno</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto faces an outside chance of losing his parliamentary seat in this month's general elections, which could tip his party and national politics into turmoil, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a closely fought contest under a new electoral system, Hashimoto could be the first incumbent prime minister in the country's political history to lose his seat in a general election.</p>
<p>Under a new system introduced in 1994, 300 seats in the 500-seat Lower House will be chosen from first-past-the-post districts and the other 200 by proportional representation on regional lists.</p>
<p>Along with several executives of his Liberal Democratic Party (LDP), Hashimoto decided to run only in a winner-take-all constituency in Okayama, southwestern Japan.</p>
<p>Normally, if Hashimoto lost in the single-seat district, he would have been able to return to parliament by being high enough on his party's proportional representation list, but he abandoned that safe-haven option to show &quot;his strong resolve&quot; to win the October 20 elections, an LDP official said.</p>
<p>A Hashimoto loss would certainly trigger a power struggle within his party and wreak havoc on Japan's entire political scene, political observers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't completely rule out the possibility of Prime Minister Hashimoto losing in the election,&quot; Rei Shiratori of Tokai University near Tokyo said.</p>
<p>If Hashimoto loses his Lower House seat, he would have to immediately resign as prime minister and possibly as party president. Under the constitution, a prime minister must come from the Lower House of parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;The most-devastating case scenario would be the LDP scoring a stunning victory and Hashimoto losing in his own district,&quot; political analyst Minoru Morita said.</p>
<p>&quot;In that case, naming a new prime minister would be delayed for weeks because of a power struggle within the LDP,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But not all analysts agreed with Shiratori and Morita on the prime minister's election chances.</p>
<p>&quot;That will never happen,&quot; said political analyst Masaya Ito, a secretary to then-prime minister Masayoshi Ohira in the late 1970s. &quot;If it did, Japan would be plunged into political upheaval.&quot;</p>
<p>Pitted against Hashimoto is veteran politician and former agriculture minister Mutsuki Kato, 70, from the main opposition Shinshinto (New Frontier Party).</p>
<p>Kato joined the Shinshinto in December 1994 after defecting from the LDP a year earlier and has strong backing from trade unions and Japan's biggest lay Buddhist group Soka Gakkai.</p>
<p>In the last 10 general elections when the riding was a multi-seat one, Hashimoto was the top vote-getter five times, and Kato five times.</p>
<p>But in Upper House elections in July 1995, Shinshinto finished 10,000 votes ahead of the LDP in proportional representation voting in the constituency.</p>
<p>&quot;The biggest point is which side the Soka Gakkai will take -- Hashimoto or Kato. The Soka Gakkai will hold the key,&quot; Morita said.</p>
<p>He said Hashimoto could win the election by striking a secret deal with the Buddhist organisation. Others say Hashimoto will prevail with heavy support from Okayama's many auto workers, grateful for his help in blunting U.S. car trade demands last year when he was trade minister.</p>
<p>&quot;The clash between Hashimoto and Kato will be one of the main parts of the general election,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
