<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92469" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia dam signing to pave way for share offer.</title>
<headline>Malaysia dam signing to pave way for share offer.</headline>
<byline>Reme Ahmad</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A pact to begin construction on the controversial $5.5 billion Bakun dam in the jungles of Borneo island was set for signing on Wednesday after two delays, laying the groundwork for the project's huge stock offering.</p>
<p>The dam's main contractor, Ekran Bhd, was to sign the engineering contracts with a consortium led by Zurich-based ABB Asea Brown Boveri AG and Brazil's Companhia Braseileira de Projectos e Obras (CBPO).</p>
<p>The planned 2,400-megawatt dam in Borneo's Sarawak state in Malaysia has been the target of protests and environmental scrutiny even before construction begins.</p>
<p>The latest delay in sealing the pact, which was to have been signed on Monday, followed rumours that the main force behind the project, Ekran executive chairman Ting Pek Khiing, had fallen ill. Ekran declined comment on the speculation.</p>
<p>Ting was hospitalised in Singapore for nine days last month and discharged on Saturday.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad, among the project's biggest supporters, said on Tuesday that technical hitches had delayed the signing.  </p>
<p>An Ekran official on Wednesday said the signing ceremony would take place later on Wednesday at 5:30 p.m. local (0930 GMT) at a hotel here.</p>
<p>&quot;The signing means the project is on track after the hitches. There'll be more hitches down the line, but that's normal for large projects,&quot; said UBS Research analyst Azman Mokhtar.</p>
<p>Dam operator Bakun Hydro-Electric Corp Bhd, had already signed a power purchase agreement with utility firm Tenaga Nasional Bhd, with Tenaga buying 70 percent of the electricity generated by the dam.</p>
<p>Environmentalists have criticised the scale of the project, which will clear 69,000 hectares (170,000 acres) of forest land, flood an area the size of Singapore and force more than 9,000 tribal residents to move.</p>
<p>The initial public offering of Bakun Hydro-Electric is expected early next year with at least two billion shares at 1.80 ringgit ($0.72) each. The offering is slated to be among the biggest ever on the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Bakun Hydro-Electric's major shareholders are Ekran and the Sarawak state government with a combined 51 percent stake and Tenaga with 25 percent.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the contract signing was likely to again perk the interest of stock market players in a favourite pastime -- guessing which companies would be the next in line to be awarded Bakun sub-contracts.</p>
<p>Ekran's Ting has so far handed out 4.5 billion ringgit worth of sub-contracts to four of his associate companies, which make up about 35 to 40 percent of the total energy, procurement and construction contract for the dam.</p>
<p>But lingering concerns remain over how the giant Bakun Hydro-Electric share offer, likely to be launched early in 1997, will fare. Analysts said that without a profit track record, and the start of power generation and profit stream only in 2003, investors may need some hard persuasion to buy the shares.</p>
<p>&quot;If you rely on income from power, your profit is fixed. In the stockmarket, if there is no growth, there is no excitement unless Bakun can say it's a dividend stock,&quot; said Phua Lee Kerk, an analyst at Vickers Ballas Research.</p>
<p>($1 = 2.5 ringgit)</p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020011">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
