<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92514" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan takes delivery of second French frigate.</title>
<headline>Taiwan takes delivery of second French frigate.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan has taken delivery of the second of six Lafayette-class missile frigates ordered from France and will commission the radar-evading ship on its October 10 national day, the Central News Agency said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The 3,600-tonne Hsi Ning frigate arrived in waters off southern Kaohsiung harbour early on Wednesday, according to the state-funded agency, which quoted unnamed military sources.</p>
<p>The advanced frigate would sail to the navy's Tsoying military base later this week to prepare for its commission on national day, it said.</p>
<p>Taiwan maintains it needs such advanced weapons to counter the rapid military modernisation of China, the island's arch rival since the Chinese civil war separated them in 1949.</p>
<p>The first frigate delivered, the Kang Ting, was commissioned in May to celebrate the inauguration of Taiwan's first directly elected president, Lee Teng-hui.</p>
<p>The ships have many surfaces clad in high-tech composite materials that make them far less visible to radar, earning them the nickname of &quot;stealth frigates.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan ordered the French ships in 1991 before Paris agreed to demands by China to stop arming the island, which Beijing views as a renegade province.</p>
<p>France's acquiescence ended a bitter row with China.</p>
<p>China held war games and unarmed missile tests in the Taiwan Strait in the weeks before Taiwan's March 23 presidential election in what Beijing acknowledged was a bid to intimidate voters against pursuing independence.</p>
<p>Beijing vows to retake Taiwan by force if the island opts for independence.</p>
<p>Taiwan has said the frigates would be armed in Taiwan with U.S.-built, surface-to-air missiles, Taiwan-developed surface-to-surface missiles, and other systems.</p>
<p>The remaining four French frigates along with 60 Mirage 2000-5 fighters ordered from France in early 1993 are due to arrive in coming months.</p>
<p>Media reports have put the price tag for the six frigates at close to US$3 billion, but the Defence Ministry has not confirmed the figure.</p>
<p>Taiwan also is taking delivery in 1996 of the first of 150 F-16 jet fighters purchased in 1992 from the United States over China's strenuous objections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
