<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92593" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan says will take Indonesian car policy to WTO.</title>
<headline>Japan says will take Indonesian car policy to WTO.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan plans to file a complaint to the World Trade Organisation (WTO) over Indonesia's national car policy within a week or so, an official at the Ministry of International Trade and Industry (MITI) told reporters on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Indonesia's national car plan, announced earlier this year, has come under fire from Japan, the United States and the European Union as a violation of world trade rules.</p>
<p>In February, Indonesia gave special tax and tariff breaks to PT Putra Timor Nasional to make a &quot;national car&quot; in partnership with Kia Motors Corp of South Korea.</p>
<p>The Indonesian firm is controlled by President Suharto's youngest son, Hutomo Mandala Putra.</p>
<p>Tokyo argues that Jakarta's scrapping of import duties on components and exemption of a luxury sales tax for local carmakers able to meet local content and other requirements breaches World Trade Organisation rules.  </p>
<p>The Trade Ministry confirmed on Tuesday that Indonesia had not imposed any tariff on its national cars produced in South Korea when they passed through Indonesian customs checks, the ministry official said.</p>
<p>&quot;As soon as we confirm the number and sales price of these cars, we will start the procedures for filing a complaint to the WTO within a week or so,&quot; the ministry official said.  </p>
<p>Japan's announcement came one day after the United States warned Indonesia that its policies of granting tax and tariff benefits to &quot;national car&quot; makers based on the percentage of domestic content in their vehicles would be subject to a U.S. complaint to the WTO.</p>
<p>Acting U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky told a news conference on Tuesday that the car issue would also be subject to investigations under the so-called Section 301 U.S. trade law that allows retaliation against unfair practices.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States, European Union and Japan are basically taking a united front on this issue,&quot; the MITI official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
