<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92626" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Oct 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Oct 2.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- Mubarak says he did not attend Washington summit because of Israeli practices and Netanyahu's challenge to public opinion; says violence will continue and a disaster will happen if the suffereing of Palestinians is not ended and if the peace process does not move.</p>
<p>- President says underground system is a huge project that lessens the public's burden.</p>
<p>- Mubarak tells Ma'ariv newspaper that he did not go to Washington summit so that he would not upset Egyptian public.</p>
<p>- Weizman regrets Mubarak's absence from Washington summit.</p>
<p>- Hopelessnes among Americans and Israelis because of Mubarak's absence from summit.</p>
<p>- C.N.N. says Mubarak has great influence over summit despite his absence.</p>
<p>- Moussa and Arafat hold talks in Washington on summit issues.</p>
<p>- Presidential decree reduces tariff rates.</p>
<p>- Erbekan in Cairo today.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- Egypt paying five billion pounds for second metro line.</p>
<p>- Chirac says Mubarak will soon reveal new ideas for boosting peace process.</p>
<p>- Palestinians pleased with Mubarak's stand on summit.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- Mubarak says absence from Washington is indication of displeasure with Israel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
