<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92701" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Yugoslav trade bans end but World Bank off limits.</title>
<headline>Yugoslav trade bans end but World Bank off limits.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. Security Council, acknowledging Serbia's contribution towards halting the war it fomented in Bosnia, has terminated crippling economic sanctions against the rump Yugoslav state.</p>
<p>Bans on trade, travel and transport had already been suspended in November against the Yugoslav republics of Serbia and Montenegro as the price for Belgrade's contribution to the Dayton, Ohio, peace accords that ended the Bosnian war.</p>
<p>But late on Tuesday, the Security Council formally ended the embargoes in a unanimous 15-0 vote.</p>
<p>The United States said it would still oppose Yugoslavia's re-joining the U.N. General Assembly and other U.N. bodies as well as institutions like the World Bank until further demands were met.</p>
<p>These included cooperation with a U.N. war crimes tribunal, reducing tensions in the restive Serbian province of Kosovo, which is dominated by ethnic Albanians, and settling claims and other issues with the former Yugoslav states.</p>
<p>The resolution also does not release Belgrade's frozen assets until all claims against them are settled by successor states to the former socialist Yugoslavia -- Croatia, Bosnia, Slovenia and Macedonia.</p>
<p>The sanctions were first imposed in May 1992 because of Belgrade's role in provoking Bosnia's ethnic strife as part of its design to create a &quot;Greater Serbia,&quot; melding the Serb lands in Bosnia and Croatia with Serbia proper.</p>
<p>But at the Dayton peace talks, Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic signed the pact for the Bosnian Serbs who objected to terms for ending the war. In return the United States and its allies agreed to suspend and then end the sanctions.</p>
<p>The council in November stipulated that the sanctions would be terminated after Bosnia's elections, held two weeks ago on Sept. 14.</p>
<p>Russia said this meant Sept. 24 but the United States held off until the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe certified the elections, which it did on Sunday.</p>
<p>The council's resolution on Tuesday, however, said that it would consider reimposing any of the sanctions if Yugoslavia or the Bosnian Serbs failed &quot;significantly&quot; to meet their obligations under the Dayton peace agreement.</p>
<p>But most diplomats considered this proviso a symbolic warning, doubting Russia would vote to restore any of the embargoes.</p>
<p>Sergei Lavrov, Russia's U.N. ambassador, indicated Belgrade's continued suspension from the U.N. General Assembly was illegal. &quot;Their only condition was that the war should stop, and the war has stopped long ago,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he welcomed the lifting of sanctions, saying: &quot;I think it is the right thing to do,&quot; adding that the action should help put Belgrade's trade &quot;on a firmer basis.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador Madeleine Albright said in a statement, &quot;We support the progress that has been made but more needs to be done by the parties to live up to their obligations under the Dayton peace accords.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Serbia-Montenegro will not be able to participate in international institutions, including the United Nations and the World Bank, until it makes susbstantial progress in Kosovo, cooperates fully with the International (war crimes) Tribunal in the Hague and Belgrade settles successor state issues with its neighbours,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Western Europeans have long agreed with the United States in linking Kosovo to Yugoslavia's re-admittance to international financial institutions. But except for Germany some were more reluctant about keeping Yugoslavia out of the United Nations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
