<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92723" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodian economy improves but analysts wary.</title>
<headline>Cambodian economy improves but analysts wary.</headline>
<byline>Katya Robinson</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Government indicators give cause to be bullish about the Cambodian economy, with single digit inflation, a stable local currency and per capita income rising if still low at under $300.</p>
<p>But analysts said the statistics, however rosy, were not necessarily grounds for optimism.</p>
<p>While this war-ravaged country had made modest gains in its transition to a free market economy, Cambodia's economic development has been built on a creaky foundation, they said.</p>
<p>It was ruled by a fragile coalition government, had low tax revenue, an incomplete commercial code and an unhealthy dependence on imports and foreign aid.</p>
<p>The image of instability lingers in the minds of foreign investors as well, causing the government to resort to fire-sale tax concessions and investment incentives that have brought in more speculative players than blue-chip industries.</p>
<p>&quot;Cambodia needs to get its house in order,&quot; said Kao Kim Hourn, executive director of the Cambodian Institute for Cooperation and Peace, a think-tank based in Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>&quot;We often have the wrong kind of foreign investment, and that's the dark side of an open economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Kao Kim Hourn cited political instability, loopholes in the tax collection system and smuggling woes as reasons why Cambodia had failed to bring in top investors.</p>
<p>But he added that two recent developments -- Washington's granting of Most Favored Nation trade status and Cambodia's July 1997 entry into the powerful Association of Southeast Asian Nations -- could help to change that.</p>
<p>Newly released statistics for August indicate Cambodia's inflation rate is steady at around 7.1 percent, down from 7.5 percent in July. The consumer price index was 112.72, an increase of 0.57 percent from July.</p>
<p>GDP growth for 1996 is forecast at seven percent, with per capita income expected to climb to $309, almost triple the $119 level five years ago.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of 1996, the riel has depreciated against the dollar, falling from 2,554 riels to 2,705 riels to the dollar, according to the National Institute of Statistics.</p>
<p>Other monthly figures vary slightly, as the National Institute of Statistics, the economic unit of the Ministry of Economy and Finance and the National Bank of Cambodia all compile their own statistics.</p>
<p>&quot;It would appear that the economy continues to register broad-based growth with low inflation and a broadly stable exchange rate,&quot; said Joshua Charap, resident representative for the International Monetary Fund (IMF).</p>
<p>Finance Minister Keat Chhon recently cited government statistics as evidence that &quot;the economy has turned away from the erratic patterns of the past and is now stable.&quot;</p>
<p>The country's coalition government, led by the royalist FUNCINPEC party's First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh and Second Prime Minister Hun Sen of the Cambodian People's Party, is a particular cause of concern.</p>
<p>&quot;As long has we have two heads of state from two different political factions, every  business deal has to be done twice,&quot; said Tep Rithivit. &quot;Cambodia needs one decision maker.&quot;</p>
<p>Tep, who represents major foreign investors, said the lack of legal framework was another big problem.</p>
<p>The Committee for the Development of Cambodia (CDC), which approves foreign investments, has offered many incentives.</p>
<p>Vichit Ith, secretary of the Cambodian Investment Board at the CDC, said he expected to approve $500 million in foreign investment in 1996, about 35 percent of which will be implemented before the end of the year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
