<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="92739" id="root" date="1996-10-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Win Win buys control of Mosel HK unit.</title>
<headline>Win Win buys control of Mosel HK unit.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Textile machinery distributor Win Win International Holdings Ltd said on Wednesday it had agreed to buy a 51 percent stake in Vitelic (Hong Kong) Ltd from third party Mosel Vitelic Inc for HK$51.60 million.</p>
<p>Win Win said the purchase would be funded by an issue of a HK$51.60 million loan note to Mosel Vitelic.</p>
<p>The loan note was convertible into Win Win shares on the second anniversary of the issue at HK$1.40 per share, compared with Win Win's closing price of HK$1.23 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Win Win said 36.86 million new shares, or 11 percent of the enlarged share capital, would be issued on exercise in full of the conversion rights attached to the note.</p>
<p>The loan will also carry a coupon of 4.5 percent. Principal was payable on the second anniversary of the loan note issue and the interest will be paid semi-annually, it said.</p>
<p>Vitelic (Hong Kong) is an integrated circuit semi-conductor manufacturer based in Hong Kong. It has entered into a six-year technology transfer and production agreement with Motorola Inc for the transfer of Motorola's TMOS power chip processing technology to the Hong Kong-based company.  </p>
<p>Win Win also said it intended to sell all its stake in knitting machinery supplier Win Win Investments (BVI) Ltd to its former controlling shareholders Savio Lam Holdings Corp and Daniel Lam for HK$65 million in cash.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
