<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93075" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: ATHLETICS-ENGLISH SAY COMMONWEALTH DATES COULD BE CHANGED.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-ENGLISH SAY COMMONWEALTH DATES COULD BE CHANGED.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>English Commonwealth Games officials said on Thursday they saw no reason why the 1998 Games in Malaysia could not be moved to fit in with the World Cup athletics due to take place in South Africa just days before.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see any problem with moving either event by a week or so one way or the other at this stage,&quot; Norman Sarsfield, chairman of the Commonwealth Games Council for England (CGCE), told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;I firmly believe the (International Amateur Athletic Federation) IAAF and Malaysia will find a solution to this. It's far too important a problem for them not to.&quot;</p>
<p>The problem came to light at the weekend when IAAF president Primo Nebiolo revealed the World Cup in Johannesburg would be staged from September 11-13, 1998.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Games have long since been pencilled in for a September 14 start, and the fear is that athletes would skip Malaysia in favour of the World Cup, especially as the IAAF has promised prize money at all its events from next year.</p>
<p>The IAAF did not consult the Commonwealth Games Federation (CGF) before announcing its dates, and Nebiolo said the World Cup team event must take priority.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commonwealth Games cannot occupy any window. This is the situation,&quot; Nebiolo said at the weekend. &quot;Who is leading athletics around the world?&quot;</p>
<p>The IAAF's stance raises the possibilty of athletes enduring a long-haul flight from South Africa across six time zones to compete in the days following for no extra financial gain.</p>
<p>But English Commonwealth officials were stressing their flexibility on Wednesday, denying there was a conflict of interests between the CGF and the IAAF.</p>
<p>&quot;When I first heard about the World Cup dates I was suprised,&quot; CGCE president Sir Christopher Chataway said. &quot;But it looks like a cock-up rather than a conspiracy.</p>
<p>&quot;I was suprised by the tone (of Nebiolo's comments) but I don't think there's anything to be gained by reacting.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he did not think English athletes would be lured away from Kuala Lumpur by the promise of lucrative World Cup prizes in Johannesburg.</p>
<p>Sir Christopher, a former Commonwealth medal winner, said South Africa, with half an eye on its bid for the 2004 Olympics, would be willing to compromise with the CGF over dates for the two events.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm quite sure Cape Town would not want to alienate the Commonwealth just at the time when it is bidding for the Olympics,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
