<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93125" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-ATLETICO FANS ANGRY OVER TICKET PRICES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ATLETICO FANS ANGRY OVER TICKET PRICES.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Atletico Madrid officials have moved to defend club policy after fans daubed the Vicente Calderon stadium with grafitti complaining about ticket prices.</p>
<p>&quot;It's worth it to see our football,&quot; said coach Radomir Antic, who had criticised fans for not turning out in greater numbers to watch the Spanish champions this season.</p>
<p>&quot;Faith is in the heart and not in the pocket,&quot; read one slogan surrounded by dollar signs &quot;M A Gil, less talk and cheaper season tickets,&quot;  said another.</p>
<p>Miguel Angel Gil, Atletico's director general and the son of owner Jesus Gil, said that his team was not amongst the most expensive to watch in Spain, and emphasised that season tickets included all 21 league and cup games and three Champions' League matches.</p>
<p>Passes start at 49,000 pesetas (around $380), but include a mobile phone and a free car check-up, while the cheapest match tickets are 3,000 pesetas ($23.40).</p>
<p>The 56,000 capacity Calderon stadium, which was 30-years old on Wednesday, was at only two-thirds full for Atletico's opening Champions League match against Steaua Bucharest on September 11, and has been only just over half full for several league matches.</p>
<p>Most Spanish clubs base their ticket income on selling large numbers of relatively inexpensive season tickets, but match tickets are generally expensive, and this is one of the reasons why there is no tradition of travelling support in the country.</p>
<p>At Valencia, for example, passes start at 20,000 pesetas ($156), while match tickets are 3,000 pesetas ($23.4)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
