<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93141" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: FEATURE-AMBER IS &quot;STONE OF POVERTY&quot; FOR ROMANIAN VILLAGE.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-AMBER IS &quot;STONE OF POVERTY&quot; FOR ROMANIAN VILLAGE.</headline>
<byline>Roxana Dascalu</byline>
<dateline>COLTI, Romania 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florin Carabus shoulders his pickaxe and sets off for the hills on the edge of Romania's eastern Carpathians. A dusty military cap on his head, he looks like the young Indiana Jones.</p>
<p>He scrambles up rugged slopes above the village of Colti, the Romanian word for crags, on a trail beaten by the care-worn and desperate before him, lured to prospect for amber.</p>
<p>&quot;The stone of poverty,&quot; is what local villagers call the yellow stone they fish from streams or dig from the hills.</p>
<p>&quot;Rumanit&quot; is the word used for Colti amber by scientists who extol its virtues, saying it is richer in hue and more valuable than amber washed up on the shores of the Baltic.</p>
<p>But for the farmers who live in this secluded village, with only one telephone in the mayor's office to link them to the outside world, there is more despair than romance in the stone.</p>
<p>&quot;Amber is the last hope for peasants striving to survive when their crops are lost. Then they go to the mountains to look for it,&quot; says Viorica Nica, curator of the Colti &quot;Amber Museum.&quot;</p>
<p>Nica, 48, leans against oak log walls of the one-storey museum, the largest building in the village.</p>
<p>She points to flocks of geese ambling unperturbed on an asphalt strip that meanders through Colti, across mountain streams and joins the main road that leads to the nearest town, Buzau, 60 km (37 miles) away.</p>
<p>&quot;We thought of opening the amber museum as a way to communicate with the outside world. That's how we got the money to build the road and the bridges over the streams,&quot; Nica said.</p>
<p>Save for its museum, which has drawn a steady trickle of visitors since it opened in 1980, Colti, population 1,654, is typical of villages burrowed in Romania's Carpathian mountains.</p>
<p>Beneath the picture-postcard beauty of the hills, the farmers live in a time warp, raising cattle or working as lumberjacks, much as previous generations did.</p>
<p>Political change has done little for them. Chaotic post-communist land redistribution gave villagers 900 hectares (2,224 acres) of farmland in rich plains 150 km (90 miles) to the south.</p>
<p>&quot;It takes them five days to get there, in carts pulled by oxen, to till the land for their cash crops,&quot; Nica said.</p>
<p>To beat such odds, many villagers turn back to the &quot;stone of poverty&quot;.</p>
<p>Especially after storms, they scour the streams for amber rocks, which fetch around 3,000 lei (less than $1.0) a gram on an informal local market.</p>
<p>Villagers say the amber used to be worth more than its weight in gold at the turn of the century, when it was mined in quarries and pits by Dumitru Grigorescu, an eccentric explorer.</p>
<p>Grigorescu bought land from the villagers but he was not a shrewd entrepreneur. He was broke when he died in 1938.</p>
<p>The mines at Colti were closed 10 years later, when the extraction of minerals became a monopoly under communism.</p>
<p>The ban is still officially in force, six years after the 1989 revolution, though the state has no interest in mining such an unproductive stone.</p>
<p>The crags around Colti still bear the ravages wrought by strip mining, during the &quot;rush for amber&quot; in Grigorescu's days.</p>
<p>The biggest piece on display in the village museum is an unhewn stone that weighs 1.78 kg (62 ounces).</p>
<p>The museum showcases Gheorghe Murgoci, a geologist known as &quot;the father of Romanian amber&quot;.</p>
<p>Murgoci took pains at the turn of the century to demonstrate that the stones found at Colti, which the peasants used to burn for incense, were actually amber.</p>
<p>Since then, scientists who have studied the Colti amber have identified 160 hues, ranging from honey to coal black.</p>
<p>They believe that small insects and bits of conifers trapped in the fossil resin date back 30 million years to when the region around Colti was a sub-tropical delta.</p>
<p>Local geologists say American scientists submitted pieces of &quot;Rumanit&quot; to nuclear magnetic resonance tests in 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;Those studies found an extinct species of conifer in the amber, which now only exists in Australia and New Zealand,&quot; said Antonela Popescu, a Bucharest University geology student.</p>
<p>&quot;There are Americans or Germans who go to the village and offer up to three million lei (around $945) to the peasants for their stones -- a small fortune for them,&quot; said Popescu.</p>
<p>&quot;At present, there is no official price for Romanian amber, while amber from the Baltics sells for $300 per kilo (2.2 lb).&quot;</p>
<p>The stone has spawned legends linking Colti to Colchis, the mythical land of the Golden Fleece on the Black Sea, which is hundreds of kilometres (miles) to the east.</p>
<p>&quot;In the old times the name of our village was pronounced &quot;Colchi&quot;, and we believe that it comes from Colchis. The legend says that Colchis, the country of the Golden Fleece, was here, in this bend of the Carpathians,&quot; Nica said. REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLTI, Romania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
