<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93152" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLAND'S KACZMAREK VOWS TO PURSUE PRIVATISATION.</title>
<headline>POLAND'S KACZMAREK VOWS TO PURSUE PRIVATISATION.</headline>
<byline>Marcin Grajewski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's new deputy Treasury Minister Wieslaw Kaczmarek vowed on Thursday he would try to speed up privatisation but warned he would quit if he got no powers to oversee sell-offs.</p>
<p>Under last week's deal between two ruling leftist parties, Kaczmarek is to continue supervising sales of state assets even though his privatisation ministry was taken over on Tuesday by the new treasury portfolio and he failed to keep the top job.</p>
<p>He told Reuters in an interview he would step down if the agreement remained only on paper and he had no official powers to sign privatisation deals.</p>
<p>&quot;My rule is to seek a different job when putting my word, my face behind some venture proves ineffective,&quot; said Kaczmarek, seen widely as the most reform-minded member of his ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD).</p>
<p>&quot;For me privatisation is a mission, a tool helping the economy to expand. If there is no agreement for that, it will be difficult to associate myself with the process,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In a compromise with the smaller Polish Peasant Party (PSL) -- which has often criticised sales of state assets -- the SLD conceded the new ministry to PSL's Miroslaw Pietrewicz to win the Peasants' cooperation in a major government reform.</p>
<p>Kaczmarek said that if Pietrewicz gave him powers to manage sell-offs he would not only continue his three-year-old privatisation policies but even try to improve them.</p>
<p>He said that as a deputy minister he would be able to focus more on privatisation.</p>
<p>Privatisation deals should come together faster also thanks to a new privatisation bill, due to come into force this year, Kaczmarek added.</p>
<p>The bill allows to incorporate state-owned companies quickly as the first step to their privatisation. It also guarantees employees of privatised firms 15 percent of shares in their companies.</p>
<p>Kaczmarek said he would pursue his 1997 privatisation outline, adopted earlier this week, which envisages selling 115 large and medium-sized companies directly to investors and floating at least five firms on the Warsaw bourse.</p>
<p>He said next year his ministry would offer to the public shares in the giant KGHM Polska Miedz copper concern, white goods maker Polar SA, paper maker Swiecie SA, non-ferrous metal trader Impexmetal SA and non-fearrousr metal maker Hutmen SA.</p>
<p>&quot;These are not the only proposals as we also consider a public offering of Orbis (travel agency and hotel chain) and perhaps a capital increase in the Domy Towarowe Centrum (DTC) (department stores' chain),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also said the privatisation of chemical and pharmaceutical sectors and a partial sell-off of the national airline LOT, originally planned for this year, should be completed in 1997.</p>
<p>He confirmed the privatisation of the state-owned telecommunication monopolist TPSA and the country's oil refineries and the energy sector should also start in 1997.</p>
<p>Kaczmarek said that by the end of the year he wanted to complete all pending deals, including the sale of the news-stand chain Ruch SA, wholsale food trader PHS and DTC.</p>
<p>Another major task for this year is to define about 400 companies, shares in which will be used to support various government compensation programmes, he said.</p>
<p>Under the pivotal social security reform, universal pension funds are to be set up and endowed with minority in privatised companies as start-up capital.</p>
<p>Kaczmarek said distillers were especially suitable for the scheme because of their good financial standing.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
