<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93312" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Burundi warns Hutu rebels as U.S. envoy leaves.</title>
<headline>Burundi warns Hutu rebels as U.S. envoy leaves.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's army-backed president told Hutu rebels on Thursday they cannot win the ethnic civil war and a U.S. envoy left saying a political settlement looked a long way off.</p>
<p>&quot;(The rebels) cannot win. Especially where the civil war is also a kind of ethnic war. Peace can only come through negotiations,&quot; Major Pierre Buyoya told Reuters.</p>
<p>Buyoya was made president last July 25 when the mainly Tutsi army seized power, saying Burundi was sliding into anarchy after three years of ethnic violence in which 150,000 people are feared to have died.</p>
<p>Howard Wolpe, U.S. President Bill Clinton's special envoy for Burundi, left after four days of talks. He praised Buyoya's decisions to lift a ban on political parties and restore the national assembly but added a sombre rider.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite these steps, we are a long ways from seeing a just and durable political solution for Burundi,&quot; Wolpe said before leaving to tour regional capitals whose leaders clamped a total economic embargo on landlocked Burundi six days after the coup.</p>
<p>Wolpe termed Buyoya &quot;interim president&quot;. He did not mention ousted President Sylvestre Ntibantunganya, a Hutu, who has lived in the U.S. ambassador's residence since two days before the coup.</p>
<p>He is the last prominent Hutu still in an embassy. The speaker of parliament, Leonce Ngendakumana, emerged from German diplomatic protection on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He told a news conference on Thursday the 81-member national assembly will meet on October 7. The mainstream Hutu party Frodebu won 65 seats in 1993 elections but more than half their deputies are in exile or have been murdered.</p>
<p>Buyoya suspended the constitution and said his government would stay up to three years while a new political system was devised. Diplomats say this is a tall order and many believe the Tutsi elite will not share power with Hutus.</p>
<p>Regional leaders will review sanctions on October 12 in Arusha, Tanzania. Buyoya said he had not received an invitation but hoped to explain plans for making peace with Hutu rebels who are waging a hit-and-run guerrilla war.</p>
<p>&quot;We think we have fulfilled all the conditions and we want the sanctions to be lifted,&quot; Buyoya said in the interview.</p>
<p>Buyoya says he has met conditions for easing sanctions by agreeing to direct negotiations with rebels. Buyoya has toned down pre-conditions but still says they must cease fighting during negotiations.</p>
<p>Buyoya's Tutsi ethnic group has always held power in Burundi but Hutus are 85 percent of the population and the rebels say their days as underdogs will soon be over.</p>
<p>The government is not alone thinking rebels may avoid talks because they reckon the blockade on all imports and exports can help them to victory against an under-supplied army.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they are not ready to talk because they think the embargo is helping them. But on our side we want dialogue and negotiations, we are ready,&quot; Buyoya said.</p>
<p>Reliable reports of fighting in the interior are few because aid workers, diplomats and journalists are at high risk if. But the rebellion is gaining strength and is even trying to set up parallel administrations, diplomatic sources say.</p>
<p>As Wolpe flew out Aldo Ajello, the European Union's envoy for Burundi, Rwanda and Zaire, arrived in Bujumbura.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
