<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93376" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin says in charge, tells Lebed to stay on.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin says in charge, tells Lebed to stay on.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin sent a resounding message on Thursday that he is still in charge in Russia, despite his heart problems, and rejected an apparent threat by security chief Alexander Lebed to resign.</p>
<p>Speaking slowly but clearly in a six-minute radio address, broadcast from the hospital where he is preparing for heart surgery, Yeltsin hit back at rivals who say the country is rudderless and want him to step down.</p>
<p>He also rallied behind Lebed, urging him to stay on, one day after the outspoken national security adviser was branded a traitor in parliament over the terms of a peace deal he signed to halt the conflict in Chechnya.</p>
<p>But in a later television appearance he also had sharp words for the retired general, telling him to drop a threat to resign over a minor matter and to stop squabbling with the government.</p>
<p>The 65-year-old president said on the radio it was not time to write him off and take his picture down from office walls.</p>
<p>&quot;I am in touch with what is going on in the country. I am helped by a strong team of professionals,&quot; said Yeltsin, who has been in Moscow's Central Clinical Hospital since September 13 and faces a bypass operation in six to 10 weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I said before the elections and repeat now -- don't rush to change the portraits. The country has a president and an active president at that!&quot; he said, referring to a slogan he used before he was re-elected on July 3.</p>
<p>The president later had his first meeting with Lebed in more than two months. Yeltsin suggested Lebed had threatened to resign over the appointment of a long-term Yeltsin ally to head a committee on senior military appointments.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me Lebed does not have sufficient grounds for using this as a basis for saying 'In that case I should quit',&quot; said Yeltsin, speaking slowly and directly to the camera.</p>
<p>The resignation offer would cap a stormy first 100 days in the Kremlin for Lebed in which his frustration appeared to reach a climax when he was jeered in parliament on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lebed has portrayed himself as isolated and friendless since Yeltsin won him over to his side after he came third in the first round of the presidential election on June 16.</p>
<p>Since then, Yeltsin has reacted coolly to repeated outspoken comments by Lebed on NATO's expansion plans and other policy issues. But he wants to keep him on his side to keep a delicate balance in the Kremlin and avoid making an awkward enemy.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Lebed) needs to get down to business now, carry out the tasks he already has and make more effort to work with the premier and with the other services,&quot; the president said.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't quarrel with everyone all the time. You can't settle issues that way. Our state apparatus must live in peace.&quot;</p>
<p>Critics regard Lebed as hungry for power and recklessly ambitious, and say he has been jostling for power with Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin and the head of the Kremlin administration, Anatoly Chubais.</p>
<p>Responding to the talk of a power struggle in his absence, Yeltsin signalled his approval of the work of all three potential rivals but saved particular praise for Lebed.</p>
<p>&quot;My aide Alexander Lebed fulfilled my instruction and stopped the military conflict (in Chechnya),&quot; Yeltsin said, adding that a lot still had to be done to implement the deal.</p>
<p>Late on Thursday, Lebed and Chernomyrdin signed a new deal with separatist leader Zelimkhan Yandarbiyev in Moscow, setting up a joint commission to implement details of the August 31 accord, including rebuilding Chechnya's economy.</p>
<p>In separate comments, Yeltsin commemorated the third anniversary of a hardline uprising in Moscow in which he used tanks to put down a rebellion by parliamentarians.</p>
<p>About 140 people were killed in clashes.</p>
<p>&quot;Let us do everything to...ensure that those tragic events never happen in our land again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Around 600 communists waving red flags and banners that read &quot;Long live Soviet power&quot; marched through a section of central Moscow on Thursday to commemorate the &quot;tragic events of October 1993&quot;, Interfax news agency reported.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
