<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93381" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Shy Polish poet happy, nervous over Nobel prize.</title>
<headline>Shy Polish poet happy, nervous over Nobel prize.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Barker</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish poet Wislawa Szymborska, shy winner of this year's Nobel Literature Prize, said on Thursday she was very pleased but also apprehensive at the prospect of intense worldwide attention.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a difficult situation. I am normally a very private person and now I forsee some difficult moments,&quot; Szymborska, 73, laughing with excitement, said by telephone from a hotel for writers in the mountain resort of Zakopane.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very pleased for Polish literature although there are other poets like me in Poland...Tadeusz Rozewicz and Zbigniew Herbert to mention only two,&quot; Szymborska told Reuters.</p>
<p>She said that although she had been named among the candidates, her selection by the Swedish academy -- which carries a $1.12 million award -- had come as a surprise.</p>
<p>Szymborska paid warm tribute to Anders Bodegard, Swedish translator of her poems, which the academy recognised were hard to put into other languages due to their stylistic variety.</p>
<p>&quot;If this had been a mediocre translator we would not be talking today,&quot; she said, herself a translator of French poetry.</p>
<p>Asked whether she would appear more in public and perhaps give lectures abroad, the slight, grey-haired poet said she did not yet know, but commented: &quot;No, I never give lectures.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier this week Szymborska won the Polish PEN Club's poetry award and Polish literary critics were overjoyed at the Nobel literature award, the fourth to go to a Pole.</p>
<p>&quot;We could not believe it at first. She was a candidate we put forward many times,&quot; Jacek Bochenski, the Club's deputy president, told Reuters, calling the news wonderful.</p>
<p>&quot;Her poetry is profound, beautiful, full of humour, simple. It easily finds its way to the reader, it is universal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;She is the best Polish post-war woman poet,&quot; literary critic Tadeusz Nyczek told Zycie newspaper, which had speculated earlier on Thursday that Szymborska might win.</p>
<p>Respected Polish novelist Stanislaw Lem, who like Szymborska lives in the southern city of Krakow, told PAP news agency: &quot;Wiska (Wieslawa) simply deserved this prize.&quot;</p>
<p>The high-brow science fiction author pointed out that poet Czeslaw Milosz had won the 1980 literature prize, adding that this showed Poland's poetry was greater than its prose.</p>
<p>Milosz, who lives in the United States, told RMF-FM radio he was glad, as he was a great admirer of Szymborska's work.</p>
<p>&quot;Above all, this is a great triumph of Polish 20th century poetry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier Polish winners are novelists Henryk Sienkiewicz in 1905 and Wladyslaw Reymont in 1924.</p>
<p>The award to Szymborska surprised international observers, who had expected a novelist to win this year after Irish poet Seamus Heaney, who was due to begin a visit to Krakow on Thursday, took last year's prize.</p>
<p>The Swedish academy said Szymborska won for &quot;poetry that with ironic precision allows the historical and biological context to come to light in fragments of human reality.&quot;</p>
<p>Szymborska, also a literary critic, has published several slim volumes of poetry since Stalinist censorship was lifted in 1957 -- she has disowned earlier poems which reflected Stalinist era literary style and content.</p>
<p>Her poetry includes &quot;Calling out to the Yeti&quot; (1957) and &quot;People on the Bridge&quot; (1986), and &quot;The End and the Beginning&quot; written in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
