<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93397" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Cleric says pope to visit Ukraine next year.</title>
<headline>Cleric says pope to visit Ukraine next year.</headline>
<byline>Rostislav Khotin</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top cleric in Ukraine's Greek Catholic church said on Thursday that preparations were under way for an unprecedented visit by Pope John Paul to the former Soviet republic's five-million strong Catholic community.</p>
<p>Bishop Lyubomyr Huzar, the Exarch of Kiev, was speaking before a visit to Ukraine next week by papal envoy Cardinal Achille Silvestrini, responsible for Catholicism's Eastern churches.</p>
<p>He said he hoped tensions between Greek Catholics and Ukraine's 35-million-member Orthodox community would ease sufficiently to allow the Pope to come.</p>
<p>&quot;Preparations have started for a papal visit. There are no doubts about that. But it cannot realistically take place before autumn next year,&quot; Huzar said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;The visit will have a very positive impact if there are no disputes or negative attitudes in advance. If someone views this as the enemy coming, we cannot force them to think otherwise. But I hope most Orthodox believers will accept it.&quot;</p>
<p>Based mostly in western Ukraine, the Greek Catholic Church was forced by Stalin to merge with the Orthodox church in 1946.</p>
<p>Its property was confiscated and thousands of priests and believers were sent to distant Siberia in Russia. Catholics held illegal services in private homes and forests until 1991 when Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev made their church legal again.</p>
<p>Disputes over property have since periodically spilled over into violence involving elderly worshippers. In 1993, irate Orthodox worshippers halted an attempt by the head of the Greek Catholic church to hold an ecumenical service in Kiev.</p>
<p>Unlike the leadership in neighbouring Russia, President Leonid Kuchma has resisted attempts by leaders within Ukraine's Orthodox faith, itself badly divided, to establish Orthodoxy as a state religion.</p>
<p>Kuchma told the Pope in the Vatican last year that the time was not yet ripe for a visit. But this week, the president's chief of staff suggested that disputes between the communities had improved enough five years after the fall of communism to allow a papal visit to go ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;In regions where there was rivalry, the situation looks stable for now,&quot; Dmytro Tabachnyk said. &quot;Matters were dramatic because of a lack of churches. But they are now being erected quickly. Soon the rivalry will become a part of the past.&quot;</p>
<p>The Pope's visits to former Soviet territory have so far been confined to the three Baltic states -- heavily Catholic Lithuania and mainly Protestant Latvia and Estonia. He has already planned at least four trips for next year.</p>
<p>Statistics show there are more than 2,000 churches of all faiths under construction in Ukraine. Greek Catholics, who view the Pope as their spiritual leader but use Eastern rites similar to the Orthodox faith, have 3,000 parishes.</p>
<p>Silvestrini is to stop in Kiev, headquarters of Ukraine's competing Orthodox churches. He then attends a conference of Catholic bishops in their stronghold, the western city of Lviv.</p>
<p>The conference is being held to celebrate the fourth cetenary of the Church's restoration of ties with Rome.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
