<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93390" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Oct 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Oct 3.</headline>
<text>
<p>PRAVO -  Parliament accepted a proposal that the newly-formed parliamentary investigative commission should look into the privatisation and economic functioning of steel-maker Poldi Kladno.</p>
<p>- Parliament approved using a portion of the 7.23 billion crown surplus from last year's state budget and putting the rest into reserves. 1.7 billion crowns is to be used for health insurance while 80 million is for the Culture Ministry.</p>
<p>- There will be five to 10 percent less Carp on the market this Christmas while prices for the fish, traditionally used for Christmas dinners, are expected to increase.</p>
<p>- The foreign trade deficit will be between 60-70 percent higher than last year's according to Evzen Kocenda from the Czech Economic Institute of the Academy of Sciences. This means the deficit could be as high as 170 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- Skoda Mlada Boleslav, long a money-loser, should be profitable this year according to the chairman of Volkswagen's board of directors, Ferdinand Piech.</p>
<p>- Nova Hut posted a net profit of 360 million crowns between January and August, 1996. The profit in August was 55 million crowns, which was lower than expected.</p>
<p>- Parliament expects to open discussion with Iraq for exchanging crude oil for Czech goods after sanctions against the country are dropped.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - The increase in heating prices by one third effective from July, 1997, is making energy suppliers nervous. They are worried that the price rises will cause people to search for cheaper energy alternativess, mainly electricity and gas.</p>
<p>- The National Property Fund received only two entrants in the public tender for 42 percent of the shares of Liberec's Textilana, a textile plant. The fund requested 387 million crowns for the shares. The winner of the tender is expected to be announced by the end of the week.</p>
<p>- 73.7 percent of Chemicky Zavod Sokolov is expected to be privatised at the beginning of next year. While this company was to have been privatised earlier, Parliament decided to postpone it until it had approved a method for privatising the chemical industry, which is expected by the end of this year.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
