<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93678" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's Bolger issues dire warnings on economy.</title>
<headline>NZ's Bolger issues dire warnings on economy.</headline>
<byline>Mark Trevelyan</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand Prime Minister Jim Bolger crossed swords with an international credit rating agency on Thursday as he warned of job cuts, capital flight and higher inflation if the left won power at next week's general election.</p>
<p>Bolger said the three main opposition parties were bent on turning back the clock and the risk of economic upheaval was worse than implied by rating agency Standard and Poor's.</p>
<p>He referred to comments by an S&amp;P official that drastic policy changes were unlikely and New Zealand's AA+ rating was not threatened by the October 12 election.</p>
<p>Bolger said it would be extraordinary if a change in policy direction did not affect the rating, a key measure of the country's creditworthiness.</p>
<p>&quot;We have three parties that are out there campaigning as a bloc, Labour, the Alliance and New Zealand First, and all are committed, passionately committed, to going back to the policies that we left behind in the early 1990s,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If Standard &amp; Poor's wants to come out and say 'that's fine by them', well let them do it, but I have to say I think that would be totally wrong,&quot; Bolger said.</p>
<p>New Zealand newspapers on Thursday widely reported S&amp;P Sovereign Risk Managing Director David Beers as telling an audience in New York on Wednesday that the New Zealand economy ws the strongest it had been in years.</p>
<p>He said there could be a slowdown after the election but a new government was unlikely to depart drastically from current policies.</p>
<p>&quot;We actually think that there's a cushion there in economic and financial terms which will allow the new government time to figure out how to operate under the new rules,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The conservative National Party government has presided over a vigorous economic recovery and is portraying itself as the sole guarantor of stability. It cut taxes this year, promises more to come in 1997, and is fast repaying public debt.</p>
<p>But opinion polls show New Zealand's first election under proportional representation is finely balanced, and the trio of left and centre-left parties has a good chance of ousting National.</p>
<p>Labour would increase spending on health and education, repeal union-busting legislation and adjust the central bank's inflation target, but would still run surpluses and repay debt. Economists generally see its policies as responsible.</p>
<p>But Bolger said even a Labour-led government would need support from the left-wing Alliance, and this would come at a price. Alliance policies include heavy increases in taxation and expenditure, 10 percent tariffs on imports and major changes to the central bank framework.</p>
<p>Bolger quoted a newspaper survey saying a quarter of New Zealand chief executives expect investors to pull money out of the country if a left-wing coalition takes power.</p>
<p>&quot;If a quarter of New Zealand CEOs say they're going to take money out of New Zealand if there's a left-wing government after October 12, we should be very nervous. The loss of jobs if we take a quarter of the investment capital away from the major corporates is huge.&quot;</p>
<p>Interest rates, taxes and inflation would all rise if a left-wing government took power, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
