<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93839" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. says Mideast summit helped all sides.</title>
<headline>U.S. says Mideast summit helped all sides.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States insisted on Thursday that &quot;everyone was a winner&quot; in this week's Middle East summit, but officials stressed the need for fast results from follow-up talks between Israel and the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Secretary of State Warren Christopher signalled an intention to go the region at some point to help push the talks along. There has been speculation he could visit the area at the beginning or end of an Africa tour due to start on Monday.</p>
<p>The Washington summit on Tuesday and Wednesday brought together Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat to ease tensions after Israeli-Palestinian clashes last week that killed 72 people.</p>
<p>The only concrete result was a commitment by the two sides to start talks on Sunday on an Israeli troop deployment in the West Bank town of Hebron. Both Israelis and Palestinians interpreted that limited result as a victory for Israel.</p>
<p>But Christopher, speaking before talks with Tunisian Foreign Minister Habib Ben Yahia, said: &quot;I don't think it ought to be evaluated in terms of winners and losers.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that while a week ago Israelis and Palestinians were fighting, now their leaders had met, had recommitted to non-violence and agreed to hold further talks.</p>
<p>&quot;In that sense, everyone comes out a winner,&quot; Christopher told reporters. &quot;But we've got a long ways to go. There are difficult times ahead, and I think we need to see some results flowing from those negotiations.&quot;</p>
<p>His remarks reflected clear U.S. concerns that while the summit may have staved off further bloodshed for now, the situation could again spin out of control if the talks to be held at the Erez crossing between Israel and Gaza bogged down.</p>
<p>The Washington Post termed the summit a disaster, and said the Middle East peace process was &quot;floating into a perilous realm of stagnation and uncertainty&quot;. The New York Times, however, called the summit outcome respectable.</p>
<p>The United States will be represented at Erez by special Middle East coordinator Dennis Ross, who said Thursday on NBC's &quot;Today Show&quot; that his role would be &quot;principally, I think, to shape the agenda for how they will proceed.&quot;</p>
<p>But, echoing Christopher's theme, he added: &quot;One thing is very clear: we are not out of the woods. The fact that we have them talking is very important but we have to begin to produce results.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I can't predict how long it will take to produce results because the problems, even though technical in nature, are also very difficult,&quot; Ross said.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said Ross would probably spend several days at the talks. Even after he left the United States would be continuously represented by other officials such as ambassador to Israel Martin Indyk or consul-general in Jerusalem Edward Abington, Burns said.</p>
<p>The spokesman said Netanyahu and Arafat had pledged in Washington that if the Erez talks failed to make satisfactory progress, they would intervene personally to complete them.</p>
<p>Hebron is the last major West Bank town from which Israel is to redeploy under accords with the Palestinians. But after Moslem guerrilla bombings early this year, former Israeli Prime Minister Shimon Peres delayed the withdrawal. Israel fears for some 400 Jewish settlers living in the town centre.</p>
<p>Burns denounced a call by the Islamic resistance movement Hamas for demonstrations Friday against the summit results as &quot;exactly the wrong advice for the Palestinian people&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the voice of extremism that will lead the Palestinian people towards more violence, more destruction, and more confrontation,&quot; he said at a news briefing.</p>
<p>In a move to bring some tangible gain to the Palestinians, the White House announced Thursday that President Bill Clinton had signed legislation granting duty-free status to goods from the West Bank and Gaza Strip sold in the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
