<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="93920" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bridal registry for FHA home down payment.</title>
<headline>Bridal registry for FHA home down payment.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration unveiled a new programme on Thursday that would allow brides and grooms to open federal &quot;bridal registry&quot; savings accounts for a down payment on a home.</p>
<p>The couple could request that family and friends deposit cash wedding gifts directly into the interest-bearing accounts at Federal Housing Administration-approved banks across the country. The money would accumulate until they had enough to make a down payment equal to 3 percent of the price of a house.</p>
<p>To qualify for an FHA-insured loan, the amount of the mortgage could not exceed $157,000 for a single-family home. FHA loans typically offer lower interest rates than those available for conventional loans.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a myth that young couples can't afford a home of their own, and many are resigned to renting,&quot; said Henry Cisneros, secretary of Housing and Urban Development. &quot;But in many cases it may be easier than they think.&quot;</p>
<p>The programme is part of a broader effort by the Clinton administration to boost the home ownership rate among young families, which fell sharply during the 1980s. The rate for homeowners under the age of 35 is 58.8 percent, while the rate for households nationwide is 65.4 percent.</p>
<p>More than 30 lenders have agreed to participate in the programme.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
