<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94026" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: DC officials pleased by GO bond sale.</title>
<headline>DC officials pleased by GO bond sale.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>District of Columbia officials said Thursday they were very pleased with the results of today's competitive offering of $168.8 million of general obligation bonds.</p>
<p>A 16-member underwriting syndicate led by Merrill Lynch was the winning bidder when it offered to purchase D.C.'s bonds at $165,537,898, at an interest cost of 6.534155 percent on the bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;We came in much more aggressively than expected,&quot; Thomas Huestis, deputy chief financial officer for the District, said at a press briefing.  </p>
<p>District CFO Anthony Williams said, &quot;We realize that this is just one of the first steps on the road to full financial recovery for the District.  However, I'd like to acknowledge this vote of confidence from the investor community.&quot;</p>
<p>Today's sale marks the first time D.C. has issued long-term bonds since the city was downgraded to &quot;non-investment grade&quot; ratings by all three major rating agencies last year.</p>
<p>D.C. officials said it follows the city's successfully repaying its $220 million note borrowing and a $379 million U.S. Treasury borrowing on October 1.  </p>
<p>Other bidders for today's bond offering were syndicates headed by Lehman Brothers, J.P. Morgan Securities, and Prudential Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The District is one of the first major cities to quickly re-enter the capital markets based upon their own credit after falling into financial emergency,&quot; the city said.</p>
<p>Both New York City and Philadelphia needed a state-sponsored authority backed by new sources of revenue to issue bonds on their behalf, the city said.</p>
<p>Some firms included in the winning syndicate headed by Merrill are Reinoso &amp; Co; Roosevelt &amp; Cross; William E. Simon &amp; Sons; Southwest Securities; Pryor, McClendon, Counts &amp; Co; Janney Montgomery Scott; J.C. Bradford &amp; Co; Interstate/Johnson Lane Corp; Greenwich Partners; Advest; and Axelrod Associates. --Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
