<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94071" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - GSCI at 3-month high helped by heating oil.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - GSCI at 3-month high helped by heating oil.</headline>
<byline>Clive McKeef</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Goldman Sachs Commodity Index (GSCI) and its related futures contract rose to three month highs Thursday, boosted by five-year highs in heating oil prices as well as gains in natural gas, live hogs and coffee.</p>
<p>&quot;World economic growth is currently being led by the U.S., which tends to make it energy intensive, with a positive impact on agricultural commodity prices also,&quot; Goldman Sachs commodities research director Steve Strongin said.  </p>
<p>The GSCI was up 2.87 points at 207.02 midday, after seeing a session high at 207.25, its highest level since July 17.</p>
<p>CME October GSCI futures were up 2.50 points at 206.80, after seeing a life-of-contract high at 207.10, and the highest level on the weekly continuation chart since July.</p>
<p>The Knight Ridder Commodity Research Bureau Index (CRB), which has a lower weighting in the energy sector, was up only 0.93 points at 245.57, while NYFE November CRB futures were up 0.50 points at 244.30.  </p>
<p>October GSCI futures have been in an uptrend since early August and technical indicators, such as a standard nine-day relative strength indicator (RSI), show the contract is not overbought yet, closing at 55 percent Wednesday.</p>
<p>On the weekly continuation charts, GSCI futures have been in a longer term uptrend since July last year.</p>
<p>With the GSCI's heavy 49 percent rating in the energy sector, the rise in NYMEX November heating oil and NYMEX November natural gas futures boosted the GSCI Thursday.</p>
<p>NYMEX November heating oil was up 1.52 cents at 73.50 cents a gallon, after seeing a life-of-contract high and new five year high on the continuation charts at 73.90 cents.</p>
<p>But the November heating oil/crude crack spread rose further to around $6.40 a barrel, the highest levels since last winter, which may eventually encourage a move to higher distillate yields by refineries, analysts said.</p>
<p>U.S. distillate inventories, which include heating oil, rose 1.80 million barrels to 112.3 million barrels in the latest week's data from the American Petroleum Institute (API).  </p>
<p>The American Gas Association (AGA) reported an 84 billion cubic feet (bcf) net injection to natgas storage in the latest week, bringing the total to 2,475 bcf, but storage remains behind year-ago levels going into the winter.</p>
<p>The large spread between natural gas prices and oil prices on an energy equivalent basis is also bullish for natural gas and should encourage fuel switching by utilities in the week's ahead, analysts said.</p>
<p>Heating oil is trading at the equivalent of around $5.00 per mmbtu currently, compared to Gulf Coast cash natgas prices of around $2.00, analysts noted.</p>
<p>CME December live hog futures also saw a fresh contract high Thursday at 58.80 cents a lb, extending the rally since September, though the nine-day RSI reached the overbought zone at 72 percent at Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>Asian demand for pork is up in the third quarter from the second quarter this year, while the seasonal demand for holiday hams is ahead in the U.S., analysts said.</p>
<p>But hog prices have yet to recover to the five year highs at 66.725 cents seen in May this year.</p>
<p>--New York Commodities Desk, +1-212-859-1641; email: clive.mckeef@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
