<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94106" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Record U.S. trailer, container rail traffic in week.</title>
<headline>Record U.S. trailer, container rail traffic in week.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of U.S. trailers and containers moved on U.S. railroads rose to 177,813 in the week ended September 28, its highest weekly level ever, a railroad trade group said Thursday.</p>
<p>The Association of American Railroads said volume was up 3.8 percent from 171,293 in the same period last year. So far this year, trailer and container traffic has increased 0.8 percent over the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>New carloadings in the latest week of 352,396 were down 4.3 percent from the year-ago period. So far this year, carloadings were off 1.0 percent from the same period of 1995.  </p>
<p>The AAR said the biggest declines in carloadings of various products from year-ago levels included grain, down 42.7 percent; primary forest products, down 17.7 percent; and food and kindred products, off 11.4 percent.</p>
<p>The AAR said ton-miles on major railroads fell to 26.2 billion, down 3.3 percent from 27.1 billion a year ago. A ton mile is equal to one ton of freight hauled one mile. Ton miles so far this year are up 1.8 percent from the 1995 period.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
