<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94162" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Publishers at fair upbeat - except U.S..</title>
<headline>Publishers at fair upbeat - except U.S..</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT, Germany</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most international publishers at the world's biggest book fair Thursday described business as buoyant, with one glaring exception: the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Business is as flat as a board,&quot; said Random House Inc. Chairman Alberto Vitale.</p>
<p>Frankfurt has attracted more than 9,200 publishers from 110 countries to its 1996 book fair. About 80 percent of all global rights are concluded here. It is the perfect sounding board for the industry.</p>
<p>Contrary to the optimism prevailing at the book fair, Vitale painted a grim picture of the U.S. domestic market.</p>
<p>&quot;(Book) returns are very high. There is inefficiency in the retail trade,&quot; he said. &quot;We need to see a more balanced trade. The margins are tighter.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;For the last three years, sales have been flat. We are going to see a couple of tight years ahead. Hopefully, next year will be better,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Executives from London to Australia, however, were in an upbeat mood, relieved that the soaring paper prices of the past two years had finally come down.</p>
<p>&quot;Paper prices have stabilised. The chaos of last year is a thing of the past,&quot; said Susan Blackwell, executive director of the Australian Publishers Association. &quot;Trade is healthy and solid. We are optimistic for a good Christmas, our main season.&quot;</p>
<p>In Asia, both international and local publishers painted a rosy picture of the outlook.</p>
<p>The British and American publishers who once dominated the international market are finding local competition stiffer.</p>
<p>&quot;There are far more active indigenous publishers. The world used to be carved up by the U.S. and the U.K. That is no longer the case,&quot; said John Stachiewicz, managing director of the international division of London-based HarperCollins.</p>
<p>&quot;The vibes are positive. It is buoyant. With the exception of South Africa, where we don't know what is going to happen, the outlook is fairly rosy,&quot; he said. &quot;But we are having to acquire and produce and get into books much quicker.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47530">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
