<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94225" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Brokers upgrade Gle Eaux on telecoms.</title>
<headline>Brokers upgrade Gle Eaux on telecoms.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A number of Paris brokerages upgraded or held their positive recommendations on French utilities company Cie Generale des Eaux following an analysts meeting on Wednesday in which the company gave details of its telecommunications ambitions.</p>
<p>Market operators said Exane upgraded the stock to &quot;reinforce&quot; from &quot;lighten&quot; and Dupont Denant put it on &quot;overweight&quot; from &quot;performance in line&quot;.</p>
<p>Dupont Denant, citing a conservative outlook, also revised upward its 1997 profit forecast to 7.2 billion from three billion francs based on the Cegetel profit contribution.</p>
<p>The entry of international partners into its Cegetel 50-percent subsidiary will generate a exceptional gain, or &quot;profit dilution&quot;, analysts said.</p>
<p>SGE Delahaye held its outperform rating, Oddo maintained its overweight and Massonaud at &quot;+&quot; although the latter remained cautious on the outlook for a second telecommunications operator in France.</p>
<p>Generale des Eaux wants to become the second telecoms operator after France Telecom. It announced on September 26 that British Telecommunications Plc is taking a 25 percent of Cegetel, with SBC taking 15 and Mannesmann taking 10.</p>
<p>Generale des Eaux chairman Jean-Marie Messier told analysts that the French telecommunications market would be worth 187 billion francs in 2003 compared to 117 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>Current telecommunications sales for its SFR mobile telephone unit and TDR radio-messaging activities total three billion francs, rising to 8.6 billion francs in 1997, 12.9 billion in 1998, 25.2 billion in 2000 and 38.6 billion in 2003.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
