<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94336" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Taleban force women into strict Islamist mould.</title>
<headline>Taleban force women into strict Islamist mould.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peering at the world through a blue cloth mesh is a new experience for educated Kabul women, but few venture out without wrapping themselves in a burqa -- a flowing head-to-toe robe that masks the face -- for fear of offending their new rulers' concept of Islamic dress.</p>
<p>The Sunni Moslem Taleban movement that captured the Afghan capital last week has yet to rule on whether women must veil their faces or simply cover their hair to be suitably attired.</p>
<p>&quot;There are different opinions,&quot; Acting Deputy Foreign Minister Sher Mohammed Stanakzai told reporters this week. &quot;This question has been handed over to the religious ulema (scholars) and will then go to the high court.&quot;</p>
<p>Women who once strolled Kabul streets in bright dresses or jeans, with a loose headscarf their only concession to Moslem modesty, now risk abuse or even a public beating from young, black-turbaned Taleban warriors moving around the city in pickup trucks if they fail to cover up completely.</p>
<p>&quot;We will try our best to execute all the rules and regulations of Islam,&quot; said Stanakzai. &quot;We love our country and our people, and we also love Islam.&quot;</p>
<p>The Taleban moved swiftly to stamp their puritan interpretation of Islam on Kabul as they have done in other areas under their control, ordering men to grow beards and pray five times daily, banning television, cinema and music, and decreeing that the sexes should be segregated outside the home.</p>
<p>As a result, schools and colleges in Kabul, where 70 percent of teachers are women, have yet to reopen a week after the Taleban takeover.</p>
<p>Women government employees have been told to stay at home, with a promise that they will be kept on full pay until Taleban leaders figure out how they can return to work without coming into contact with men.</p>
<p>The edict has hit hardest at Kabul's estimated 25,000 war widows, many of whom were employed in government jobs or involved in food-for-work programmes run by relief agencies. They are now left with virtually no means of support for themselves or their children short of begging on the streets.</p>
<p>The Taleban say female doctors and nurses may resume their posts, but only if they wear burqas and do not work alongside male colleagues. They say they will not deny education to girls and women, but have made clear that radical reforms must occur before they can go back to school or university.</p>
<p>&quot;The schools and universities were running in a manner common in Russia and Communist countries,&quot; Stanakzai complained. &quot;It will take time to establish rules and regulations for how women should come to schools.&quot;</p>
<p>International aid agencies have been trying to come to terms with the changes ordered by the Taleban, a few of which they have succeeded in moderating by quiet diplomacy. But some programmes have ground to a halt.</p>
<p>Mine awareness classes in schools run by a U.S.-based charity have stopped because most of the teachers are momen.</p>
<p>Women doctors and nurses are still working at city hospitals assisted by the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC), though not all have returned to their posts for fear of harassment. They may only care for female patients.</p>
<p>&quot;This causes serious disruption, but females have not been denied treatment,&quot; said an ICRC employee, adding that it would take time for hospitals to adjust to rules already applied in other Taleban-held areas where medical staff and patients are separated by sex.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an enormous hassle because hospitals in the capital were not gender-separated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lars Eliason, head of the Red Cross Federation here, said women working at clinics it supports had been given special work permits from the Afghan Red Crescent Society, which now has a Taleban president.</p>
<p>&quot;So far we have had no message that we should change our procedures,&quot; he said, adding that male and female staff work together in many clinics, although men, women and children come for treatment on different days.</p>
<p>Avice Warmington, health programme coordinator at the Federation, said her projects were continuing without too much disruption. &quot;So far so good,&quot; she said, but added that she personally felt troubled.</p>
<p>&quot;I cover myself from top to toe apart from my face, but at a professional level I am slighted every day,&quot; she said, citing previous experience elsewhere in Afghanistan meeting Taleban leaders.</p>
<p>Some of them had refused to shake hands, look at her or acknowledge her presence.</p>
<p>&quot;I have never not been able to do my work, but it has not come without a personal cost in anger and humiliation,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
