<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94375" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida court rejects tobacco plea.</title>
<headline>Florida court rejects tobacco plea.</headline>
<dateline>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florida's highest court has refused to throw out a class action suit against the tobacco industry, paving the way for the first trial on behalf of a large group of smokers, lawyers said Thursday.</p>
<p>The Florida Supreme Court Wednesday refused to overrule an appellate court decision in May allowing attorneys representing smokers to file a class action lawsuit against the industry. The case was filed in a state circuit court in Miami in 1994.</p>
<p>In a one-page opinion, the Florida court let stand a lower court ruling that tobacco defendants had hoped would be reviewed by Florida's highest court.</p>
<p>The lawsuit, Engle v. R.J. Reynolds et al, claims tobacco companies failed to protect consumers from the dangers of smoking and that thousands of those consumers became addicted to cigarettes and suffered tobacco-related illnesses.</p>
<p>An attorney representing smokers said the high court ruling closed the last appellate avenue for the tobacco industry, which had argued against class action status.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of where this puts the tobacco companies, they are at the end of their appellate rope,&quot; said Stanley Rosenblatt, a Miami attorney representing smokers in the case.</p>
<p>The case could be ready for trial by spring, Rosenblatt said. The Miami attorney is also suing the industry in another case filed by flight attendants over second hand smoke.</p>
<p>In response to the ruling, Philip Morris Cos. Inc. said the propriety of the class certification may still be reviewed at a later time by the Florida Supreme Court.</p>
<p>&quot;In the meantime, we will be considering whether to ask the U.S. Supreme Court to review the decision,&quot; the company said. &quot;Philip Morris believes the Engle case is without legal and factual merit, and the plaintiffs still face several substantial legal hurdles before they can get to trial.&quot;</p>
<p>Defendants include Philip Morris Cos. Inc., R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co. a unit of RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp., Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp., a unit of B.A.T Industries Plc, Lorillard Tobacco Co., a unit of Loews Corp. and Liggett Group Inc., a unit of Bennett LeBow's Brooke Group Ltd.</p>
<p>Tobacco stocks fell in response to the ruling, but losses were small because the decision was expected, analysts said.</p>
<p>Philip Morris fell $1.375 to $91 and RJR Nabisco was down 37.5 cents at $26.50 in consolidated New York Stock Exchange trading.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the stocks are going to get whacked because it was really anticipated that this would happen,&quot; said Ronald Morrow, tobacco stocks analyst at Rodman &amp; Renshaw.</p>
<p>Rosenblatt is also representing flight attendants in a class action suit alleging injuries related to second-hand smoke. Last week, the judge in that case, known as Broin v. Philip Morris, said he wants the trial to begin in the spring.</p>
<p>The largest class action against ever filed against the tobacco industry, known as Castano v. The American Tobacco Co., was thrown out by a New Orleans federal appeals court in May. The court found that the case, which was brought on behalf of all smokers alleging injury from cigarettes, would have been too cumbersome if brought to trial.</p>
<p>In a related development, the Richmond (Va.) Times-Dispatch reported Thursday that a retired Philip Morris research chief was ordered to give pre-trial testimony in three tobacco lawsuits pending in south Florida.</p>
<p>The researcher, Dr. Thomas Osdene, of Richmond, Va., was ordered to testify in a ruling Wednesday by U.S. District Judge Robert Payne, the newspaper reported.</p>
<p>Osdene's attorney had asked that Osdene be excused from testifying because of poor health.</p>
<p>Smith Barney tobacco analyst Martin Feldman said despite the ruling, the burden on the plaintiffs was to devise a way to make such a large class action -- which could include upwards of two million people -- manageable for trial.</p>
<p>Another class-action suit, in which 60,000 flight attendants are suing the tobacco industry for the effects of second-hand smoke, was upheld as a class but has so far languished because it is so unwieldy.</p>
<p>Another, the Castano case, which would have attempted to sue the industry on behalf of every U.S. smoker claiming addiction, had its class status overturned in Lousiana in May.</p>
<p>Chief among the reasons for its demise was the court's belief that it was too big. Feldman said Rosenblatt's failure to move forward on Broin does not bode well for Engle suit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLAHASSEE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
