<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94601" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: European bonds immune to mild U.S. jobs growth.</title>
<headline>European bonds immune to mild U.S. jobs growth.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Nisbet</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bonds are so high on optimism about monetary union (EMU) that they should shrug off any surprise growth in U.S. September job numbers unless it is very bearish indeeed, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is reason to believe that a decoupling (of U.S. and European bonds) is under way at the moment,&quot; said Ken Wattret, economist at Paribas Capital Markets.</p>
<p>Analysts said the September non-farm payrolls number due at 1230 GMT on Friday would attract the usual close attention but its transatlantic impact should be less than in past months.</p>
<p>Expectations of a low jobs growth been building up and analysts said there was scope for disappointment in bonds if the outcome exceeded the consensus forecast of 166,000 -- compared with a recent monthly average of 230,000 or more.</p>
<p>Robert Prior, economist at James Capel, said a stronger than expected figure should have limited impact on European bonds because of the domestic, EMU-linked factors propelling a wave of popularity in those markets.</p>
<p>&quot;There is so much European momentum behind these rallies that it (the jobs data) could serve only to slow the rallies unless it is an absolutely extraordinary number,&quot; Prior said.</p>
<p>Wattret agreed it would take an exceptionally strong U.S. jobs report to knock the European bond market off its stride.</p>
<p>&quot;If it is only relatively strong, say 250,000, I don't think it would have a pronounced impact,&quot; Wattret said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would probably be shrugged off because the view in Europe is that the German economy is picking up but not very strongly and that European interest rates are set to remain at very low levels for quite some time.&quot;</p>
<p>Even if Germany took &quot;a modest hit&quot; after a kneejerk fall in U.S. Treasuries, peripheral Europe's star performers like Italy and Spain, should not suffer from a strong report, Wattret said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is so much money going into the high yielders at the moment that it would not really ruffle them. Sentiment seems so positive it would take something very negative indeed to derail this (European) convergence.&quot;</p>
<p>David Hewitt, Tokyo Mitsubishi International, bond strategist, said the suspicion was that T-bonds might be a bit too complacent about Friday's payroll.</p>
<p>If the suspicions were proved right, he said this could cause Treasury prices to pull back at the end of this week.</p>
<p>&quot;The medium-term trend is still bullish, but on a one- or two-day view there might be some volatility ahead of the numbers given the upmove we've seen in the last couple of weeks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hewitt said that with German 10-year bond yields down to the bottom of their historical trading range at six percent, &quot;people may be looking for an excuse to sell Bunds which a fall in the Treasury market could provide&quot;.</p>
<p>Wattret said a strong figure could send the T-note/Bund 10-year yield spread ballooning out to 70 or perhaps even 75 basis points from 67 currently.</p>
<p>Despite European high flyers' unusual degree of immunity to bad knock-on effects from the U.S. payrolls data, Wattret said Treasuries might still be the place to invest.</p>
<p>&quot;The bad numbers we have had had in the last couple of employment reports mean anything remotely good this time around would probably push the market up quite strongly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are looking for value and for a market to rise, then given what has been priced in in the U.S. -- that interest rates are going up before the end of the year -- any sign that is not going to happen should be taken as a positive.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
