<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94675" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Jail terms for &quot;sons of evil&quot; in Rabin murder.</title>
<headline>Jail terms for &quot;sons of evil&quot; in Rabin murder.</headline>
<byline>Galina Vromen</byline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The assassin of Yitzhak Rabin, his brother and a third religious Jew were on Thursday described as &quot;sons of evil&quot; as they were sentenced to prison terms ranging from five to 12 years for plotting the prime minister's murder.</p>
<p>The prosecution had asked for much longer sentences.</p>
<p>Yigal Amir, 26, is already serving a life term for killing Rabin last November to try to halt Middle East peace moves. The three were convicted on all charges last month in a separate conspiracy trial.</p>
<p>&quot;These sons of evil sat and planned and meticulously explored how to murder a man because...because they didn't approve of his policies and goals,&quot; said presiding Judge Amnon Strashnov in delivering the verdict.</p>
<p>The Tel Aviv court sentenced Yigal Amir to an additional five years in prison, Hagai Amir to 12 years, and Dror Adani to seven years.</p>
<p>The three were convicted of plotting Rabin's murder, considering such plans as rigging his car with explosives and poisoning him before deciding to shoot him at a Tel Aviv peace rally. The convictions were based largely on their own confessions parts of which they later retracted.</p>
<p>They were also found guilty of planning attacks against Palestinians and Hagai Amir was convicted of various weapons charges. Prosecutors said Hagai crafted the bullets used in the murder.</p>
<p>Yigal Amir said in court he was proud of killing Rabin and was only sorry he had not done it years earlier, before Israel handed over parts of the West Bank and Gaza for Palestinian self-rule.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sorry I didn't do it three years ago. What we see today (in the West Bank and Gaza) wouldn't be happening. There is no justice here...blame it all on me,&quot; Amir told the court before judges read out the the sentence.</p>
<p>He smiled to family members in court throughout the hearing. The other defendants appeared glum.</p>
<p>Strashnov blasted the three for using religious arguments to justify the murder, peppering his remarks with quotes from Jewish scriptures.</p>
<p>&quot;Who are you to quote (the Jewish prophet) Isaiah,&quot; Hagai Amir interjected and was thrown out of the courtroom.</p>
<p>The prosecuting attorney said the defendants had exploited democratic rule to murder Rabin and bring down his government and asked the court to sentence the three to at least 30 years in prison.</p>
<p>Defence attorneys said the court decision was fair.</p>
<p>&quot;The public wanted blood but the court disconnected itself from the atmosphere surrounding the case,&quot; said lawyer Zion Amir who respresented Dror Adani.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
