<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94774" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Muni mart gets pep talk in wake of Grigsby matter.</title>
<headline>Muni mart gets pep talk in wake of Grigsby matter.</headline>
<dateline>BALTIMORE 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top MSRB staff Wednesday night urged municipal bond market players not to get depressed by press reports about alleged activities of former Grigsby Brandford &amp; Co president Calvin Grigsby.</p>
<p>&quot;It's kind of sad that the travails of a particular firm (in) the last week have landed in the press,&quot; Christopher Taylor, executive director of the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board, told bond analysts meeting here this week.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is that the municipal bond industry has a lot of good people in it (and it has done) a remarkable job. I hope as you read the headlines, you never forget this is a damn good industry,&quot; Taylor said.</p>
<p>The Miami Herald reported Sept 26 that Calvin Grigsby, who resigned in late September from the firm, was shown on videotape allegedly offering a $300,000 bribe to a Dade County, Fla., official in exchange for county bond business.</p>
<p>Grigsby resigned Sept 17 and has not been available for comment. The firm's two remaining partners, Napoleon Brandford and Suzanne Shank, announced this week they will join New York securities firm Muriel Siebert &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Taylor said the Grigsby headlines top off three years of continuous press reports about federal probes of the municipal bond market.</p>
<p>&quot;After three years of seeing cases laid out in the press it is very difficult for all of us, whether you are a regulator, analyst or dealer, to go out into the industry,&quot; Taylor said</p>
<p>&quot;Now if I go to a cocktail party and say I'm from the municipal bond industry, they say, 'Oh, those guys, they've got all those scandels,' &quot; Taylor said.</p>
<p>But actually, Taylor said, &quot;This is a good industry. We all should take great pride.&quot;</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALTIMORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
