<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="94850" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Swiss lax on protecting U.S. POWs - document.</title>
<headline>Swiss lax on protecting U.S. POWs - document.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States worried as the Second World War neared its end that the Swiss government was not doing enough to protect American prisoners of war in Germany.</p>
<p>A newly uncovered document in the U.S. National Archives written by Secretary of War Henry Stimson said that he had received reports that &quot;the Swiss Government is not acting vigorously as protecting power in protecting the rights of American prisoners of war in Germany.</p>
<p>In a Jan. 19, 1945, letter to the Secretary of State, Stimson said his information came from an American officer &quot;who had first-hand experience in German prisoner of war camps&quot; and was in a position to receive other reports.</p>
<p>He said the reports indicated that &quot;the Swiss government is neither prompt nor thorough in investigating complaints of violations of the Geneva Convention&quot; and lacked aggressiveness and persistence in attempts to improve conditions.</p>
<p>He added that the reports also said the Swiss were &quot;more interested in retaining German goodwill than in properly protecting American prisoners under the Geneva convention.&quot;</p>
<p>Stimson asked the Secretary of State to complain to the Swiss who were responsible for seeking compliance with the Geneva Convention.</p>
<p>The letter was discovered by researchers for the World Jewish Congress who are combing the archives for information relating to the assets of Holocaust vicitms that might still be in Swiss banks.</p>
<p>It was turned over to New York Republican Sen. Alfonse D'Amato whose Senate Banking Committee is conducting an investigation.</p>
<p>D'Amato recently called for the United States to reopen negotiations with the Swiss on a treaty in which Switzerland agreed to give the Allies $60 million in compensation for accepting gold looted by the Nazis during the war.</p>
<p>D'Amato said the compensation was not enough because archive documents showed that the Swiss had up to $600 million in Nazi gold.</p>
<p>A statement from the U.S. embassy in Bern said the U.S. government had not yet taken a position on whether to reopen the negotiations despite press reports to the contrary.</p>
<p>On Monday, the Swiss parliament voted to set up a commission for a five-year investigation into the role of Swiss banks during the Holocaust.</p>
<p>But D'Amato said in a statement, &quot;It's not acceptable. This is certainly a step in the right direction, but five years is far too long. There's no reason it can't be done in a year or less. In five years' time, even the sons and daughters of survivors may be gone. The Swiss need to act more quickly.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
