<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95021" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: World book sales post record growth-survey.</title>
<headline>World book sales post record growth-survey.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The global book market posted record growth of eight percent last year and China looks set to expand fastest of all by the year 2000, a survey showed on Thursday.</p>
<p>Market analysts Euromonitor, releasing the survey results at the world's biggest book fair in Frankfurt, said that in 1991-1995 world book sales rose by 24.3 percent from $64.3 billion to $80 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Interestingly the main reason for the strong value growth lies in the reported difficulties. Dramatically higher paper prices forced up the unit price of books, resulting in value sales increases,&quot; Euromonitor said.</p>
<p>The United States topped the retail sales market with $25.5 billion worth of sales in 1995 followed by Japan, Germany, Britain and France.</p>
<p>Euromonitor forecast: &quot;By the year 2000 the Americas will continue to lead the world's book market with a projected value of $37 billion.&quot;</p>
<p>It said supermarkets now offered the greatest threat to traditional booksellers. &quot;Their share of book retail sales remains low but it is rising across all markets worlwide,&quot; the survey said.</p>
<p>Jason Armitage, Euromonitor reports editor, said that the Chinese publishing market is set to enjoy staggering growth.</p>
<p>&quot;China is forecast to post double the growth rate of any developed market by the turn of the next century at over 28 percent between 1996 and 2000.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the Asia-Pacific region had the fastest growth rate of any area in the past four years.</p>
<p>Electronic publishing could be equally spectacular.</p>
<p>&quot;Provided government restrictions do not inhibit organic growth of Internet publishing, China presents a potentially massive market for electronic business publishing in particular which will benefit from rapidly rising PC ownership,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47530">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
