<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95038" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Silk Cut promotes its brand at UK discos.</title>
<headline>Silk Cut promotes its brand at UK discos.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The makers of Silk Cut cigarettes said on Thursday they had been promoting their brand by draping purple silk around several discotheques in Britain.</p>
<p>Gallaher, the tobacco company that makes Silk Cut and is a part of American Brands Inc, told Reuters it had sponsored a series of parties at discos in Britain since March and the campaign would end next week.</p>
<p>Gallaher is running the parties, called the Renaissance Silk Grand Tour, in conjunction with the Renaissance Group, one of Britain's leading night club promoters.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Gallaher said: &quot;There is no overt Silk Cut branding but venues around the country will be draped with purple silk.&quot;</p>
<p>Silk and the colour purple are a strong element in  the company's long running advertising campaign created by M &amp; C Saatchi. It features images of purple silk slashed by scissors, cacti and a rhinoceros horn.</p>
<p>Gallaher said it did offer people attending the parties sample packs of cigarettes.</p>
<p>Advertising tobacco products in Britain is restricted.</p>
<p>Cigarette product sampling campaigns are legal, but companies are only allowed to target existing smokers aged over 18 who have to sign a document confirming they already smoke and are over 18.</p>
<p>Gallaher declined to say how much it was spending on the disco parties. The spokesman said, &quot;We felt it was the right sort of event with which we want Silk Cut associated.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
