<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95086" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: SUZUKI PLANS TO EXPORT TO S. AMERICA FROM HUNGARY.</title>
<headline>SUZUKI PLANS TO EXPORT TO S. AMERICA FROM HUNGARY.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Suzuki Motor Corp said on Thursday its Hungarian car plant plans to expand its exports into South America with production of upgraded Suzuki Swifts.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to start selling in South America, possibly beginning with Brazil and Chile,&quot; Shinzo Nakanishi, sales director for the Hungarian plant ~Magyar Suzuki RT~(MS), said.</p>
<p>&quot;The time is not yet known, but we hope to start next year,&quot; he told Reuters after a news conference to introduce the upgraded Swift.</p>
<p>MS, the only Japanese automaker in former Communist Europe, has exported cars to more than 30 countries, Nakanishi said. The main foreign markets are in Europe, but MS also has shipped cars to China, Hong Kong, and Singapore, he added.</p>
<p>Suzuki invested three billion yen to upgrade the Swift, which the automaker now builds only in Hungary, Nakanishi said.</p>
<p>&quot;This project brings Suzuki's total investment in Hungary to 27 billion yen,&quot; he said. &quot;We don't foresee any additional investment in Hungary now, but we would have to consider adding production capacity if demand increases. We have the land.&quot;</p>
<p>Serial production of the face-lifted Swift, roughly 4,000 units a month, will start in mid-October, but Suzuki dealers in Hungary will start taking orders for the new model immediately, Nakanishi said.</p>
<p>The main changes in the Swift include a redesigned front grill and new headlights and taillights. The interior, as well as equipment and safety features, also are improved, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The face-lift was designed by Suzuki in Japan with contributions from engineers and workers in Hungary,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The new Swift will be built in 13 versions, including 3-door and 5-door hatchbacks, sedans and vans, Nakanishi said.</p>
<p>MS plans to build at least 50,000 cars in 1996 -- 36,500 units for export and 13,500 units for domestic sales, he said.</p>
<p>Other MS officials at the news conference said production could approach 52,000 units, including 39,000 units for export.</p>
<p>Output will include roughly 7,500 units badged as Subaru Justys, a model of Japanese conglomerate Fuji Heavy Industries Ltd , he said.</p>
<p>Fuji, which has contracted MS to build Justys since September 1995, sells its Hungarian-built cars in western Europe, he said.</p>
<p>In the first nine months of 1996, MS said it sold 26,289 units abroad (including Justys) and 9,354 units domestically.</p>
<p>MS is owned 79.51 percent by Suzuki, 13.61 percent by</p>
<p>MS is owned 79.51 percent by Suzuki, 13.61 percent by Japanese trading company Itochu Corp , 3.50 percent by the International Finance Corp and 3.37 percent by others.</p>
<p>-- Ryan Tutak, Budapest newsroom +361 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
