<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95096" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU mulls charging fees for merger reviews.</title>
<headline>EU mulls charging fees for merger reviews.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission is mulling the possibility of charging fees for probing mergers and takeovers, but the extra staff needed would cost much more than the fees' revenue.</p>
<p>In a proposal to revise European Union merger rules, aimed at catching a higher number of corporate deals, it said it &quot;will consider the possible charging of registration fees&quot;.</p>
<p>The fee could be 6,000 European currency units ($7,500) per deal notified, the proposal to EU industry ministers said.</p>
<p>The Commission estimated it would need an extra 28 people to deal with the increased workload resulting from the revised merger rules on top of its current staff of about 60.</p>
<p>But it said this would cost 2.5 million Ecus ($3 million), double the 1.2 million Ecus ($1.5 million) the fees would raise -- assuming the force would receive 200 notifications a year.</p>
<p>Governments are reluctant to allow a rise in the central Union budget as they try to meet strict Maastricht treaty criteria to qualify for the European single currency in 1999.</p>
<p>If they agreed to the proposal, they would have to increase the budget for merger reviews as the fee would cover only a fraction of the costs involved in vetting such deals.</p>
<p>When the Commission said in July it had agreed to revise the turnover thresholds set in the regulation that determine whether a merger or takeover is large enough to qualify for EU review, it did not breathe a word about possible fees.</p>
<p>Anti-trust lawyers said the proposal, made available this week, came as a surprise. But it was no bold step.</p>
<p>The Commission said competition authorities in Germany and Britain charged higher fees -- between 12,000 to 15,000 marks ($7,800 to $9,800) for the German Federal Cartel Office and 5,000 to 15,000 pounds ($7,800 to $23,500) in Britain.</p>
<p>Alec Burnside, a partner with law firm Linklaters &amp; Paines in Brussels, said the fee was small compared to the legal costs of clearing a merger under EU fast-track rules -- $25,000 to $500,000 depending on the deal and its geographical markets.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not going to be significant when seen against the overall cost of doing the deal,&quot; Burnside told Reuters. ($1=1.5317 Mark) ($1=.6388 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
