<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95094" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: OPEC quota should not be raised -- Qatar minister.</title>
<headline>OPEC quota should not be raised -- Qatar minister.</headline>
<byline>Kiyoshi Takenaka</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>OPEC's quotas should not be raised because of Iraq's expected return to the international oil market, Qatar's Energy and Industry Minister Abdullah bin Hamad al-Attiyah said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe they (quotas) should not be raised. Iraq is coming to the market and to achieve a balance between demand and supply, quotas should be rolled over,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The minister said talks between three Japanese trading houses and Qatar regarding their taking a partial stake in a second liquefied natural gas (LNG) project in the country will be concluded by the end of October.</p>
<p>He said a portion of the project will be sold to the Japanese trading houses, Sumitomo Corp, Itochu Corp and Nissho Iwai.</p>
<p>Qatar General Petroleum Corp has a 70 percent stake in the project and Mobil Corp the remaining stake.</p>
<p>At the last Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries meeting in June, there were suggestions the quotas could be raised at the next meeting in November.</p>
<p>Quotas for the 13-member oil cartel were kept steady at the June meeting except for an additional 800,000 barrels-per-day for Iraq's expected return to the market.</p>
<p>Iraq's military foray in the north, where Kurdish rebels enjoyed a measure of self-rule since the end of the 1991 Gulf War, prompted punitive U.S. missile strikes and warnings that its long-awaited oil-for-food deal could be further delayed.</p>
<p>The accord was finally signed in May and would allow Iraq, crippled by six years of trade sanctions following its 1990 invasion of Kuwait, to export $2 billion worth of oil over six months to buy food and medicine and make limited war reparations.</p>
<p>Energy and Industry Minister Abdullah bin Hamad al-Attiyah is in Japan for a ceremony marking the first liquefied natural gas LNG vessel to carry Qatari term gas cargoes to Japan. He will be here until Saturday.</p>
<p>Sumitomo Corp, Nissho Iwai Corp and Itochu Corp have been seeking to acquire a combined 10 percent stake in the Ras Laffan LNG Co project, traders said.</p>
<p>The minister declined to say how large the stake would be. The project is expected to start production in 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OPEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
