<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95099" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Inflation soars in Sri Lanka as subsidies go.</title>
<headline>Inflation soars in Sri Lanka as subsidies go.</headline>
<byline>Rohan Gunasekera</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Inflation is soaring in Sri Lanka, fuelled by cuts in state subsidies, rising defence spending to fight Tamil separatist rebels and the impact from drought earlier this year, analysts and officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Census and Statistics Department said this week that Colombo's consumer price index on a 12-month moving average rose 14.8 percent in September year-on-year, the highest in five years. This compares with 5.3 percent a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;Inflation continues its upward trend partly because of strong growth in broad money as a result of burgeoning credit to the government,&quot; said Anush Amarasinghe, associate director of Socgen-Crosby.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, supply-side constraints due to power outages and drought-fuelled price hikes,&quot; he said. &quot;The gradual removal of subsidies on wheat flour and food added to the cost-push pressure.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists said the government was borrowing heavily to fund the purchase of arms and meet the cost of intensified operations against Tamil rebels, who are fighting for an independent homeland for minority Tamils in the country's north and east.</p>
<p>Defence spending is expected to exceed 50 billion rupees ($880 million) this year against the allocated 38 billion rupees ($669 million).</p>
<p>A drought earlier this year disrupted agricultural production and caused severe hydropower shortages that hit industrial output, sending prices soaring, economists said.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Census and Statistics Department said year-end inflation based on a 12-month moving average was likely to be 16 percent, compared with 7.7 percent last year.</p>
<p>The September increase was mainly because of higher prices for bread and wheat flour after the government reduced subsidies in late August, as well as price rises for coconuts and eggs, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;What happened was that the effect of the increase in the price of bread at the end of August was felt in September,&quot; said Azra Jafferjee, an economist at Jardine Fleming Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a huge increase in the food index which was a major contributor,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>President Chandrika Bandaranaike Kumaratunga, who is also finance minister, has said some subsidies would have to go to contain the budget overrun.</p>
<p>Some of the subsidies likely to be cut include 7.0 billion rupees ($123 million) on wheat flour, 1.5 billion rupees ($26 million) on fertilisers, and 8.0 billion rupees ($141 million) in help for the poorest, government economists said.</p>
<p>The government has said it was forced to raise prices as it could no longer afford to bear the massive cost of subsidising bread after international flour prices almost doubled.</p>
<p>The government is also under pressure from international lending agencies to cut subsidies.</p>
<p>Economists said last week's fuel price hike could further boost inflation and that the government was also likely to raise electicity charges.</p>
<p>Crosby's Amarasinghe said the gradual depreciation of the rupee added to inflationary pressure.</p>
<p>The rupee was quoted at 56.80 to the dollar on Thursday, and Jafferjee of Jardine Fleming said she expected it to weaken to around 59.50 to the dollar by year-end.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
