<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95393" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: PRESS DIGEST - Vietnam - Oct 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Vietnam - Oct 3.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the official Vietnamese press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>VIETNAM NEWS</p>
<p>-- Communist Party Chief Do Muoi has said greater efforts are needed to improve the national education system, which has deteriorated since the Vietnam war ended in 1975.</p>
<p>-- Foreign Minister Nguyen Manh Cam has met with U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher and National Security Adviser Anthony Lake to exchange views on improving economic and commercial ties.</p>
<p>-- Vietnam will levy an infrastructure tax on urban construction projects from next year, the Ministry of Finance has announced. - - - -</p>
<p>NHAN DAN</p>
<p>-- Vietnam's garment exports to the European Union reached $285 million in the first nine months of 1996. Total garment exports this year are expected to reach about $1 billion.</p>
<p>-- Visiting foreign military ships will be required to respect Vietnam's sovereignty and independence and comply with Vietnamese law, under new government regulations.</p>
<p>-- Communist Party Secretary Do Muoi has concluded a tour of central and southern provinces to prepare for the Party Central Committee's second plenum on education, training, science and technology. - - - -</p>
<p>QUAN DOI NHAN DAN</p>
<p>-- Vietnam sold 70 billion ($6.35 million) worth of one-year Treasury notes with an annual coupon of 8.0 percent at an auction on Wednesday. - - - -</p>
<p>HA NOI MOI</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Vo Van Kiet has issued a decision tightening controls on non-state enterprises and service companies.</p>
<p>-- Hanoi has launched an anti-drugs campaign in its schools. - - - -</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
