<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95399" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Police seek guns in raid on Japan islands group.</title>
<headline>Police seek guns in raid on Japan islands group.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese police on Thursday carried out raids on a right-wing group which built a lighthouse on a disputed East China Sea island, looking for illegal weapons.</p>
<p>Police said they searched the Tokyo headquarters of Nihon Seinen Sha (Japan Youth Federation) and three other locations following the arrest on September 19 of an adviser to the group on a charge of illegal possession of firearms.</p>
<p>The Japan Youth Federation's construction of a makeshift lighthouse on one among a cluster of uninhabited East China Sea islets has raised tensions between Japan and its Chinese neighbours.</p>
<p>Tokyo has claimed the islands, which it calls the Senkakus, since 1895. China, which calls the islands the Diaoyu group, has claimed them for centuries -- a position shared by Taiwan.</p>
<p>The advisor to the Federation, 54-year-old Masao Hasegawa, was arrested on suspicion of hiding a Chinese-made gun and 10 bullets in the home of his daughter in Osaka, western Japan.</p>
<p>The lighthouse row has escalated into a bitter anti-Japan campaign by Chinese nationalists in Hong Kong, Taiwan and China, which last week claimed the life of a Hong Kong activist who drowned after jumping off a protest ship near the islands.</p>
<p>The protesters have charged that Tokyo, which does not officially recognise that a territorial dispute exists, has abetted or failed to curb the rightists' activities. Japan claims to have no control over a private group's movements.</p>
<p>The Japan Youth Federation, one of hundreds of ultra-nationalist groups in the country, was founded by a former underworld figure in 1969 and has about 1,500 members.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
