<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95476" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Prodi urged to scrap tax hike in budget.</title>
<headline>Italy's Prodi urged to scrap tax hike in budget.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Political parties backing the Italian government urged Prime Minister Romano Prodi on Thursday to remove an unpopular property tax hike from his 1997 budget.</p>
<p>The call came hours before Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi was due to unveil in parliament an austerity budget designed to cut a massive 62.5 trillion lire ($41 billion) off next year's projected deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no doubt that one of the points that needs to be changed is the (house) tax,&quot; Massimo D'Alema, leader of the largest coalition party, the Democratic Party of the Left (PDS), told reporters.</p>
<p>The package was approved at a marathon cabinet meeting last Friday and included measures that would effectively increase taxes on land and houses by up to 10 percent.</p>
<p>Centre-right opposition parties threatened a &quot;revolution&quot; unless the proposal was reversed and even key government supporters said they wanted to see the hike supressed.</p>
<p>Italian markets, traditionally hyper-sensitive to worries about political turmoil, shrugged off the opposition threats, with Italian debt futures soaring to new highs early on Thursday and the lira holding firm.</p>
<p>D'Alema blamed the hard-left Communist Refoundation, which guarantees government majority in the lower house of parliament, for forcing Prodi to drop plans to tax some pensions in favour of the house tax.</p>
<p>But Refoundation leader Fausto Bertinotti rejected this.</p>
<p>He said he too wanted amendments to the property tax, which the finance ministry says will raise 194 trillion lire next year. Unions estimate it will cost Italians 900 billion lire.</p>
<p>The most hostile reaction was from the opposition Freedom Alliance, headed by former prime minister Silvio Berlusconi.</p>
<p>&quot;The government must remove the house tax...unless they want a revolution,&quot; Pierferdinando Casini, leader of the small centrist CCD group and Berlusconi ally, told reporters.</p>
<p>Berlusconi has also protested against Treasury plans to introduce a once-off &quot;Euro-tax&quot; which is expected to pour 13 trillion lire into state coffers next year and boost Italy's chances of becoming a founder member of the planned European economic and monetary union (EMU) in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;We will fight this budget which is recessionary and will not be enough for Italy to meet the criteria needed for European union,&quot; Berlusconi said.</p>
<p>Political sources said the Freedom Alliance will hold a demonstration in Rome on November 9 against the budget.</p>
<p>The federalist Northern League is also spoiling for a fight over the budget, the latest in a succession of belt-tightening budgets in the 1990s drawn up to tame Italy's debt mountain.</p>
<p>League parliamentary leader, Domenico Comino, on Wednesday said his party would use filibustering tactics to slow passage of financial bill. Parliament has until the end of the year to ratify the package.</p>
<p>Prodi was forced to use confidence motions to side-step dogged League filibustering when a government mini-budget passed before parliament earlier this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
