<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95496" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Oct 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Oct 3.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in Norwegian papers this morning:</p>
<p>AFTENPOSTEN</p>
<p>- A large-scaled survey by the Statistics Office concludes that the government's financial policy is more effective than before. As a result of deregulation of the credit market in the 1980s, variations in interest rates on savings and loans are having a greater impact on investment and consumption, the survey says.</p>
<p>- On Wednesday King Harald opened a new session of the Norwegian parliament, the Storting. In the king's speech the Labour government said that growth the national budget's expenses must decrease to avoid growth in inflation and higher interest rates.</p>
<p>- The consumer association is to investigate suppliers of the Internet after a barrage of consumer complaints. The Internet boom in Norway has been so large that suppliers are having problems delivering services that customers are paying for.</p>
<p>DAGENS NAERINGSLIV</p>
<p>- According to a survey by ScanFact, Norsk Hydro ASA and Orkla ASA have the best profile among stockbrokers, analysts and large investors. Shipping company Bonheur, Gange Rolf and Kvaerner ASA have the largest potential for increasing share price, the survey says.</p>
<p>- Two German drug companies have denied speculation they are looking to takeover Norwegian pharmaceutical group Nycomed ASA. Nycomed shares rose on Monday and Tuesday on rumours of a potential buyer of the group. Analyst Henrik Schultz at FIBA Nordic Securities says the rumours have more basis today than three months ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
