<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95508" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Oct 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Oct 3.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-10-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>--- Major international hotel group Sheraton, with 450 hotels worldwide, is to quit Copenhagen in mid-October due to poor results, renting its downtown hotel to the Swedish hotel group Scandic. Both hotel groups and tourism officials blame the present business climate in Denmark for making it difficult to profitably run and maintain hotels.</p>
<p>--- If the economic upswing of the last four months continues, Denmark's 1996 state budget deficit will fall by 10 to 12 billion crowns, according to a survey by France's Banque Indosuez. A Danish government August forecast predicted a deficit of 31.6 billion crowns for 1996.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>--- The Danish information technology sector is developing so fast that companies are now forced to look abroad to find qualified employees. Next autumn Denmark is to initiate new three-year high level information technology education courses, but the sector criticises this as being too late.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS POSTEN</p>
<p>--- This year's sugar beet harvest has started in Denmark, with sugar producers expecting production to exceed the EU quota of 425,000 tonnes as this year's Danish beet has the highest sugar content in five years.</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--- A new Swedish survey shows that Danish industry has to pay much more for electricity than industrial companies in the rest of Scandinavia, due to monopoly conditions and high production costs in Denmark.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
