<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95552" id="root" date="1996-10-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: SAS sees mln crown loss on Asia, US cargo.</title>
<headline>SAS sees mln crown loss on Asia, US cargo.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-10-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scandinavian Airlines System (SAS) said on Wednesday it expected to lose at least 10 million crowns this year on its new cargo route to Japan, Macau, India and the United States due to sharp competition, disappointingly low tonnage and high costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We are losing money on this route due to a combination of flying insufficient freight at prices that are too low and above all huge costs,&quot; SAS Cargo director Peter Groenlund told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are currently looking into every possible way of bringing our costs down,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said SAS Cargo was considering closing its route to New Delhi, India and switching to more lucrative Middle East destinations, using lower paid pilots as its competitors did.</p>
<p>SAS put in cargo planes on its Gothenburg-Osaka-Macau-New Delhi-New York- Gothenburg cargo route, with 105 tonnes capacity, last April.</p>
<p>Groenlund said he was also looking into closer co-operation on air cargo with German airline Lufthansa, the world's biggest air cargo carrier, with which SAS entered a strategic alliance on January 1, 1996.</p>
<p>He added that SAS Cargo was investing around one billion crowns in the coming years in building modern cargo terminals with advanced computer systems in Copenhagen, Oslo and New York.</p>
<p>-- Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom +45-33969652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
