<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="95765" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida firm disappointed with comp decision.</title>
<headline>Florida firm disappointed with comp decision.</headline>
<dateline>TALLAHASSEE 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>National Council on Compensation Insurance Inc, a non-profit industry rating group that sets rates for Florida's workers' compensation insurance, said it was disappointed on Friday with the state's decision to cut rates by 11.2 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We're disappointed that we apparently didn't persuade (Florida Insurance Commissioner Bill Nelson) with the basic case we presented supporting our findings that the rates filed were correct,&quot; said Chapin Clark, senior vice president for regulatory and external affairs at Boca-Raton-based NCCI.</p>
<p>He added the organization's actuaries were looking at Nelson's order to see if the group would challenge the rate reduction or not.</p>
<p>In announcing the rate reduction, Nelson also said he was concerned NCCI was considering becoming a for-profit corporation because it might run into conflict of interest issues in determining Florida workers' comp rates.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the view of management that the for-profit structure in all likelihood represents the best (plan) for us to go forward...,&quot; Clark said. A final decision had not been made by NCCI's board of directors. He added that the company would be able to calm Nelson's fears of conflict of interest if it did change its status.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLAHASSEE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
