<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96074" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada's Goodale plans revamping CWB legislation.</title>
<headline>Canada's Goodale plans revamping CWB legislation.</headline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Agriculture Minister Ralph Goodale said on Friday he is considering submitting legislative changes to the Canadian Wheat Board Act that would create a board of directors who would then have the authority to alter the agency's marketing mandate.</p>
<p>&quot;Consideration is being given to place the governance of the Canadian Wheat Board in the hands of a board of directors, the majority of whom would be farmers,&quot; Goodale told reporters at a press briefing in Regina, Saskatchewan.</p>
<p>The CWB is currently run by three government appointed commissioners.  </p>
<p>&quot;The proposal that we are considering would provide for future mandate changes contingent upon the formal, considered advice of the Canadian Wheat Board board of directors,&quot; Goodale said.</p>
<p>An interim CWB board of directors could be in place by 1997, he added.</p>
<p>The 61-year-old state commodity trading agency is one of the world's oldest and largest such monopolies.</p>
<p>The CWB had a 21 percent share of world milling wheat markets and a 71 share of world durum wheat exports in marketing year 1994/95 (Aug/July).  </p>
<p>&quot;We are considering enabling legislation that would make it possible for the Canadian Wheat Board to make cash purchases of wheat and barley,&quot; Goodale said.</p>
<p>The CWB currently pools all wheat, durum, feed and malt barley deliveries into common accounts and pays one price for each commodity to all farmers. That has been a founding principle of the CWB since its inception July 5, 1935.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear from the press briefing whether this would allow for a CWB spot market in grains.</p>
<p>Goodale will answer reporters' questions in a phone conference in about 90 minutes.  </p>
<p>The proposed legislation would also allow the CWB to manage adjustment payments within a crop year, terminate pool accounts at any time and pay out farmers' returns rapidly, to issue negotiable producer certificates and use &quot;modern risk management tools,&quot; Goodale said.</p>
<p>Future mandate or quality control changes implemented by the CWB could be determined by its directors and may go to a vote to the Prairies' 110,000 farmers.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Canadian Wheat Board directors consider any proposed change significant, or fundamental, a producer vote would be a prerequisite before implementation,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Barley marketing has been the focal point of an intensifying debate around western Canada's farms, agribusiness board rooms and provincial and federal cabinet tables in the past year.</p>
<p>A panel appointed by Goodale last December unanimously recommended removing feed barley from the CWB monopoly.</p>
<p>&quot;On barley marketing, the Government of Canada is considering proceeding this winter with a formal poll among farmers to determine their precise marketing preferences with respect to barley,&quot; Goodale said.</p>
<p>Canada exports 30 percent of its feed barley.</p>
<p>-- Gilbert Le Gras 204 947 3548</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
