<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96099" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: EU envoy says framework needed for Burundi talks.</title>
<headline>EU envoy says framework needed for Burundi talks.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior European envoy met Burundi's military leader, Major Pierre Buyoya, on Friday and said the framework of negotiations with Hutu rebels needed to be agreed in detail.</p>
<p>&quot;The context in which these negotiations can be held needs to be decided,&quot; Aldo Ajello, the European Union (EU) special envoy to the troubled Great Lakes nations of central Africa -- Burundi, Rwanda and Zaire -- told reporters after his talks with Buyoya.</p>
<p>The retired major was installed in the mainly Tutsi army's July 25 coup, which was condemned by regional states who clamped a total trade and transport embargo on Burundi on July 31.</p>
<p>Buyoya, viewed by most foreign embassies as a relative dove among Burundi's military hawks, is waging a diplomatic campaign to have the crippling embargo lifted.</p>
<p>Ajello, who referred to Buyoya as &quot;president&quot;, said the EU was not involved in the sanctions but welcomed Buyoya's decisions to unban political parties and restore parliament.</p>
<p>The third condition for an easing or lifting of sanctions is direct and unconditional talks between the regime and its opponents, including armed Hutu rebels.</p>
<p>The rebels are waging a hit-and-run guerrilla war against the army but have yet to take firm control of any town in the small country of six million people.</p>
<p>Buyoya says he is willing to enter such negotiations and wants to explain his plans to pro-sanctions African leaders at their next summit on Burundi, expected to be held in Tanzania on October 12.</p>
<p>Asked whether he thought the summit would herald the start of talks with the rebels, Ajello replied: &quot;I think we can expect the creation of a framework in which these negotiations can take place&quot;.</p>
<p>The ethnic war in Burundi since 1993 has killed an estimated 150,000 majority Hutus and minority Tutsis. The country's perilous condition evokes fears of the genocide in neighbouring Rwanda in 1994 and has led to the appointment of an array of special envoys.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
