<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96110" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAB announces $360 mln share offer.</title>
<headline>SAB announces $360 mln share offer.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Breweries Ltd announced on Friday that it had authorised an offering of around $360 million to fund its international expansion.  </p>
<p>It said the issue would take the form of 20 South African cents each and American Depositary Shares (each representing the right to receive an ordinary share) at a price of $25.43 (115 rand) per share, aggregating to 14.25 million new South African Breweries (SAB) shares of 20 South African cents each.</p>
<p>The offer could be raised to $410 million if there was sufficient demand via an over-allocation option.</p>
<p>The company said international demand for its share offering had exceeded $600 million.</p>
<p>The issue price represented a discount of about four percent to the share's closing price of 120 rand on October 3.</p>
<p>The offering is one of the largest emerging market equity issues to international investors undertaken by a private sector company, it said.</p>
<p>The proceeds would be used, subject to the approval of South African exchange control authorities, to fund the company's continuing expansion of its interests outside South Africa.  </p>
<p>&quot;In connection with the offering, Robert Fleming &amp; Co Ltd, on behalf of the managers to the issue, may over-allot or effect transactions which stabilise or maintain the market price of the securities at levels which might not otherwise prevail,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>Such stabilising, if commenced, could be discontinued at any time.</p>
<p>Subject to final approval from the Johannesburg and London Stock Exchanges, the new South African Breweries shares would be listed on both exchanges from October 10.</p>
<p>If the proceeds of the offering had been available to the company at the financial year ended March 31, assuming the exercise in full of the over-allocation option, there would have been no material impact on earnings per share.</p>
<p>&quot;However, net asset value per share would have increased from 1,881 South African cents to approximately 2,400 South African cents,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
