<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96153" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: FEATURE - Bosnians fight to reopen pre-war industrial jewel.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Bosnians fight to reopen pre-war industrial jewel.</headline>
<byline>David Stamp</byline>
<dateline>BIHAC, Bosnia 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>When the Slovene company Gorenje decided to build a new refrigerator factory, it made probably one of the worst investment decisions in business history.</p>
<p>The site Gorenje chose a decade ago for the $45 million plant was the Bosnian town of Bihac.</p>
<p>Within five years of its opening, Serb artillery was pounding the factory. It took 96 hits and 70 of its workers died during a three-year siege of the Moslem-held Bihac enclave, either under the barrage or fighting at the front.</p>
<p>Today workers have patched up the factory. But production lines lie idle and some of the fridges and freezers, abandoned in the plant when war broke out in 1992, are peppered with shrapnel damage.</p>
<p>However, the factory's managers will not accept that the plant, once the jewel in the crown of Yugoslav industry, is lost for ever. Technical manager Edin Muslic hopes to restart production within a month, albeit at a fraction of pre-war levels. &quot;Step-by-step,&quot; is how he describes his philosophy.</p>
<p>Gorenje, which also makes cookers and other home appliances, can hardly be blamed for the Bihac disaster.</p>
<p>Back in the mid-1980s, nobody foresaw the tragedy which was about to befall the country. Today Gorenje is a successful Slovene company in the process of privatisation. But in those days it was an enterprise controlled by the Yugoslav state.</p>
<p>The decision to build in Bihac was probably not made by managers of Gorenje, based in the prosperous north of the former Yugoslavia, but by communist bureaucrats.</p>
<p>For the party, developing poor areas of the country such as Bosnia came before any business criteria. So Bira Gorenje, as the Bihac factory is called, started production in 1987.</p>
<p>Bira Gorenje nicely illustrates the economic catastrophe that befell the former Yugoslavia and particularly Bosnia.</p>
<p>&quot;Without any doubt this was one of the most modern factories in former Yugoslavia,&quot; said Muslic, a 33-year-old engineer who fought with Moslem forces during the war.</p>
<p>Before the war it employed 1,280 people in Bihac and another 4,000 worked for suppliers around ex-Yugoslavia, said Muslic, who shares the factory's offices with international aid workers helping Bihac to recover from war.</p>
<p>Bira Gorenje once turned out 400,000 fridges and freezers a year worth $40 million. All but 10 percent were for export, some supplied to Western manufacturers such as Zanussi, who then sold them under their brand name.</p>
<p>Muslic's plans are much more modest. Only 102 people now work at the factory and his aim is to start production at just 15,000 units a year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have already set several dates when the factory should restart production and failed, but now I hope it might resume soon,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The plant faces a host of problems. Power supplies are erratic, some component suppliers elsewhere in former Yugoslavia have closed and the plant's technology is dated in a business which changes as fast as the car industry.</p>
<p>Another problem it that nobody really knows who owns the factory. Gorenje is now majority-owned by the Slovene state, which declared its independence in 1991. But does it own the Bihac factory or does the Bosnian government?</p>
<p>At Gorenje headquarters in the town of Velenje, technical director Miha Dolinar said the Slovenian Chamber of Economy was negotiating with the Bosnian government over the Bihac factory.</p>
<p>Gorenje, which has reorientated its business towards western Europe since the war, was interested in maintaining links with the factory, he said.</p>
<p>But sources close to the firm said it was unlikely that Gorenje would ever regain control of it and the prospects of receiving any compensation were uncertain.</p>
<p>In Bihac, Muslic has more immediate worries. &quot;At the moment we are interested only in restarting production,&quot; he said. He hoped that Bosnian elections held in September might help.</p>
<p>&quot;It will cost too much for domestic investors to rebuild our economy,&quot; he said. &quot;I hope for some influx of foreign capital after the elections. It would be our only hope for faster development.&quot;</p>
<p>He realised that foreign investment will be hard to lure and that a step-by-step strategy is the best for the moment.</p>
<p>&quot;We had lots of promises so far, but the fact is that people here are fighting for survival,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we have learned anything in the past four years of war, it is the art of survival.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BIHAC, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
