<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96164" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Bosnian Serb leader cries foul on Paris accord.</title>
<headline>Bosnian Serb leader cries foul on Paris accord.</headline>
<byline>Peter Greste</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Serb member of Bosnia's three-man presidency accused Moslem chairman Alija Izetbegovic on Friday of undermining the Dayton peace agreement by acting on his own.</p>
<p>&quot;Should this practice continue, I see no future either for our working together or for Bosnia as a whole,&quot; Momcilo Krajisnik told the Bosnian Serb news agency SRNA.</p>
<p>Krajisnik was protesting about Izetbegovic's meeting in Paris on Thursday with Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic and their signature of an accord on bilateral ties.</p>
<p>According to Krajisnik, Izetbegovic acted without consulting his presidential colleagues.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot agree with this action by Izetbegovic, because he has assumed the right to make decisions without the consent of the other two members of the presidency,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Izetbegovic, Krajisnik and Croat leader Kresimir Zubak were elected to the presidency last month in a historic poll aimed at reuniting Bosnia under joint democratic institutions.</p>
<p>The Dayton Accord makes the presidential candidate with the most votes chairman, but says decisions must be taken by consensus.</p>
<p>Krajisnik said Izetbegovic was also wrong to speak to the United Nations in New York after he was elected, without consulting his colleagues on the content of his speech.</p>
<p>Bosnia's joint parliament is due to convene in Sarajevo on Saturday but Krajisnik said two issues remained to be settled -- where the meeting will be and &quot;the text of the statement which is being described as an oath.&quot;</p>
<p>The Serbs have proposed a number of places, including Sarajevo airport or a foreign embassy, chosen for the safety of Serb members entering a city they besieged for four years.</p>
<p>Krajisnik said Serb parliamentarians would assemble in their stronghold of Pale on Saturday and prepare to go to Sarajevo if a satisfactory solution is found. &quot;Failing that, the session will not take place at all,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Izetbegovic, by contrast, told reporters he was optimistic about the parliamentary session.</p>
<p>&quot;It is better to believe that everything will be in order though until this moment, problems have not been resolved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I can say that tomorrow's meeting will be held and it is very important step in establishing the joint institutions of Bosnia Herzegovina and in ensuring its continuity in spite of everything.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
