<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96277" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mixed on OTC market.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mixed on OTC market.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is the closing report for Croatia's over-the counter securities market in Varazdin, including its outpost Osijek, for Thursday, October 3.</p>
<p>* Of thirteen active issues six rose, two fell, five remained flat</p>
<p>* 10-stock VIN index up 1.55 percent to 7,886 points.</p>
<p>* Most active hotelier Suncani Hvar was down 0.79 percent to 12.60 marks a share on volume of 1,096.</p>
<p>* Confectioner Kras was the biggest loser, down 5.88 pct to 160 marks on volume of 225 shares.</p>
<p>* Biggest gainer hotelier Jadranturist Rovinj, up 63.93 percent to 100 marks with 51 shares sold, followed by:</p>
<p>* Hotelier Arenaturist Pula, up 25.0 pct to 50 marks a share on volume of 439 units.</p>
<p>* Hotelier Rivijera Porec, up 11.11 pct to 50 marks a share on volume on 728.</p>
<p>* Adriatic pipeline operator Jadranski Naftovod Zagreb was up 3.45 pct a share to 600 kuna with 10 shares sold.</p>
<p>* Hotelier Plava Laguna Porec, up 1.89 pct to 270 marks on volume of 62 shares.</p>
<p>* Hotelier Istraturist Umag, up 1.79 pct to 57 marks on volume of 631. In Osijek it was flat at 56 marks with 409 shares sold.</p>
<p>* Unchanged:</p>
<p>- Croatia Banka at 38 marks with 108 shares sold.</p>
<p>- Cable maker Elka Zagreb at 55 marks with 146 shares sold.</p>
<p>- Textile firm Varteks at 19.50 marks with 280 shares sold.</p>
<p>- Food processor Podravka at 75 marks with 1,069 units sold in Varazdin and 15 in Osijek.</p>
<p>- Hotelier Haludovo traded at 35 marks on volume of 177 shares.</p>
<p>* Volume 5,446 shares, turnover 299,025 German marks.</p>
<p>--Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
