<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96336" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Tribasa to announce new partners to bid on railway.</title>
<headline>Tribasa to announce new partners to bid on railway.</headline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grupo Tribasa said Friday it will announce in coming weeks new partners in its consortium to bid in the privatization of Mexico's national railways.</p>
<p>&quot;We are on the verge, perhaps in a couple of weeks, of announcing new partners to try to strengthen our position. We have been in negotiations with prominent groups, both Mexican and U.S.,&quot; Fernando Gutierrez, vice president of operations told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Tribasa and its partners, RailTex and Impulsora Tlaxcalteca de Industrias (Itisa), announced Friday they will bid on the Pacific-North route, after recently withdrawing from the Chihuahua-Pacific bidding. The Pacific-North line starts in Colima state and runs toward the U.S. border and is due to be awarded next April or May.</p>
<p>In the consortium as it stands, Tribasa has a 50 percent stake, and the other two partners have 25 percent apiece.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly those stakes will be diluted with the incorporation of new partners,&quot; Gutierrez said.  </p>
<p>He added that if Tribasa and its parners decide to bid on the Northeast line, they would join one of the other groups already bidding.</p>
<p>The Northeast line is considered the most attractive in Mexico's railway privatization package. It connects Nuevo Laredo, Monterrey and Mexico City, and carried 30-40 percent of Mexico's rail cargo in 1995.</p>
<p>At present, there are seven groups registered to bid of which two have prequalified. Some analysts believe the section may draw bids of over $600 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly more groups will be approved (to bid on the Northeast line). We would join the one that offers the most advantages to all involved,&quot; said Gutierrez.</p>
<p>-- Daniel Perez-Whitaker, Monterrey newsroom +528.345-7617</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
