<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96378" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil September exports drop 1.25 pct vs year ago.</title>
<headline>Brazil September exports drop 1.25 pct vs year ago.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil exported $4.115 billion of goods in September, down 1.25 percent from September 1995, the Ministry of Industry and Commerce said Friday.</p>
<p>The ministry said in a statement that average daily exports reached $196 million, down 5.9 percent from the daily average of $208.4 million in the same month a year ago.  </p>
<p>Exports in the January-September period of 1996 rose to $35.858 billion from $34.178 billion in the same period a year ago, the ministry said.</p>
<p>It said that exports of primary goods increased 13.57 percent in September compared with the same month of 1995, &quot;pushed by the high external price of soymeal.&quot;</p>
<p>Semi-manufactured exports fell 3.49 percent year-on-year, and manufactured goods dropped 6.46 percent.  </p>
<p>An exemption on the so-called ICMS sales and circulation tax on exports, which went into effect September 16, produced &quot;a relatively better&quot; performance of daily averages in the second half of the month, the ministry said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is to be expected in the medium and long term that there will be a significant increase in competitiveness,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The biggest gains from the ICMS exemption were likely in exports of soybeans, coffee, aluminium, tobacco, beef, sugar, metals, minerals, cocoa and orange juice.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 5561 2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
