<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96414" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Runoff mayoral vote seen in Brazil's two top cities.</title>
<headline>Runoff mayoral vote seen in Brazil's two top cities.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Voters in Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro will face a runoff election for mayor in November after no candidate won more than 50 percent of votes in Thursday's municipal election.</p>
<p>In Sao Paulo, Brazil's largest city, right-wing candidate Celso Pitta just missed winning outright in the first round after receiving 49 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>Pitta, a political neophyte who had never before run for political office, could become Sao Paulo's first black mayor if he beats runner-up Luiza Erundina of the Worker's Party (PT) in the Nov. 15 runoff.</p>
<p>In Rio de Janeiro, Pedro Conde of the Liberal Front Party (PFL) will face Sergio Cabral of President Fernando Henrique Cardoso's Social Democrat Party (PSDB).</p>
<p>Voting nationwide came off smoothy as more than 100 million Brazilians went to the polls on Thursday to pick mayors and councilmen in 5,500 municipalities across the country.</p>
<p>Local issues such as public transport, crime and housing dominated voter concerns, disappointing some opposition candidates who hoped to turn the nationwide poll into a referendum on Cardoso's free market reforms.</p>
<p>Analysts said Cardoso, who is halfway through a four-year term in office, would appear to have emerged strengthened by Thursday's election results.</p>
<p>They said the president would benefit from signs that voters were choosing candidates with moderate platforms and rewarding predictable politicians that offered them continuity.</p>
<p>&quot;This election was all about continuity and that is good news for the president,&quot; said political analyst Walder de Goes.</p>
<p>With the elections now over, Cardoso is expected to concentrate his efforts on persuading congressmen to approve a constitutional amendment that will allow him to run for re-election.</p>
<p>Billed as Latin America's first computerised election, some 30 percent of voters punched candidates' numbers into shoe-box sized electronic ballot boxes.</p>
<p>However electoral officials confessed being embarassed by delays in vote counting process which continued long after it was scheduled to end.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
