<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96421" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ govt denies deal with Maori politically-driven.</title>
<headline>NZ govt denies deal with Maori politically-driven.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Brockett</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand on Friday announced a US$120 million settlement with a South Island Maori tribe for claims dating back 150 years but denied that the deal, eight days before a general election, was politically motivated.</p>
<p>Treaty Negotiations Minister Doug Graham said the government had agreed in principle with Ngai Tahu (pronounced Ni Taahu) Maori to settle the tribe's claim to large tracts of the South Island after negotiating for more than five years.</p>
<p>The tribe's grievances date back to 1844 when the Crown bought the first of 10 parcels of land covering most of the South Island for what it now acknowledges was an artificially low price.</p>
<p>Colonial powers went on to acquire 34 million hectares (84 million acres), most of the South island, for just 14,750 pounds. In one transaction 20 million hectares, or 30 percent of New Zealand's land area, was acquired for 2,000 pounds.</p>
<p>Promises to create reserve lands for Maori were never honoured.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Ngai Tahu) were devastated -- they've had 150 years really of poverty,&quot; Graham said in a television interview.</p>
<p>&quot;So this will give them the ability to take full part in society and provide health and education and upskilling for their people in their own way.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the settlement, the Crown will give Ngai Tahu a formal apology and NZ$170 million (US$119 million) in land and cash.</p>
<p>Among other things, the tribe gains first right of refusal over surplus Crown land, second right of refusal to the Crown's shares in Christchurch International Airport, title to the Crown Titi Islands and exclusive rights to 32 customary fishing areas.</p>
<p>The agreement-in-principle contains a commitment by both parties to negotiate and agree to a legally binding deal, but final settlement will depend on ratification by Ngai Tahu beneficiaries and the incoming government.</p>
<p>New Zealanders go to the polls for a general election on October 12, and the conservative National government has been keen to make progress on Maori claims to win the support of Maori and liberal voters.</p>
<p>But Graham denied that the settlement had anything to do with winning votes.</p>
<p>&quot;It was five years of hard work and it would have been grossly unfair to say to Ngai Tahu 'well after all that we've now reached agreement but I'm sorry we're not going to sign because we've got an election',&quot; Graham said.</p>
<p>&quot;That would not have been right and our task is to try and solve these matters fairly as quickly as we can.&quot;</p>
<p>The government has set aside NZ$1 billion to settle all Maori claims.</p>
<p>Last year it paid NZ$170 million and returned 15,790 hectares (39,000 acres) of land to the North Island Tainui tribe and earlier this week it settled the Whakatohea claim in the North Island for NZ$40 million.</p>
<p>There are hundreds of claims outstanding for ancestral land that was seized by colonial settlers and many Maori argue that the NZ$1 billion cap is an arbitrary, insufficient sum fixed without consultation.</p>
<p>But Graham defended the Ngai Tahu settlement as &quot;a weight off everybody's minds&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very good deal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>US$1 = NZ$1.43</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
