<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96478" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Australia pledges aid for Cambodia flood victims.</title>
<headline>Australia pledges aid for Cambodia flood victims.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia pledged Australian $575,000 (US$448,500) in aid for the victims of widespread floods in Cambodia on Friday as waters ebbed after killing at least 14 people.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is better now everywhere. Everywhere the waters have decreased,&quot; Cambodian Red Cross director Uy Samath told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>Liberal Party MP Andrew Thomson, parliamentary secretary for foreign affairs, made Australia's aid announcement shortly after arriving in Phnom Penh as the first senior member of Prime Minister John Howard's coalition government to visit Cambodia.</p>
<p>The aid package includes A$500,000 to the U.N. World Food Programme to buy rice for emergency relief distribution to hundreds of thousands of flood victims living along the Mekong River, an Australian Embassy statement said.</p>
<p>A further $75,000 would be given to Save the Children Australia for essential relief supplies, for drugs to combat dysentery, cholera, malaria and acute respiratory infection and for repair of water wells.</p>
<p>The government says half a million people are seriously affected by the floods and has called on international donors for $2.6 million in emergency aid to cover purchase of rice, food, clothes, sheeting and operational costs.</p>
<p>The United States and Japan earlier this week announced flood relief donations totalling more than $100,000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
