<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96558" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYS has no plans to limit workfare for food stamps.</title>
<headline>NYS has no plans to limit workfare for food stamps.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York State, which still is studying the effects of the new federal welfare bill, has no plans to ask Washington to waive a workfare requirement for the two million residents who collect fod stamps.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have any plans to ask for a waiver at this time,&quot; said Terrance McGrath, a spokesman for the state Department of Social Services, on Thursday.</p>
<p>Starting on November 22, the federal welfare reform bill will only allow able-bodied individuals who do not have children to collect food stamps for three months in any three-year period, unless they work part-time.</p>
<p>The federal government, which picks up the entire cost of the program, on that day also will begin requiring everyone who receives the non-cash benefits to register, in an effort to determine how many of them are eligible to work.</p>
<p>One of the key issues facing the state's task force on welfare is how best to adjust the mix of federal, state, and local dollars that now pay for its welfare programs, according to the state Budget Division.</p>
<p>That has prompted speculation that New York might wish to seek a waiver from the workfare requirement for the food stamp program.</p>
<p>A waiver would help ensure that these individuals continue to receive the non-cash benefits even though they might belong to the same group whose cash benefits will be restricted under the state's new program.</p>
<p>However, seeking a waiver -- which could be broad or targeted to areas where it is hard to find jobs -- might pose political problems for the administration of Gov. George Pataki, which has trumpeted its ability to boost the state's economy.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to pursue any waiver strategy...That seems to say we don't have the jobs under both The Assistance and Needy Family Block Grants and the federal food stamps program,&quot; said Rus Sykes, deputy director of the State Community Aid Program, an Albany, N.Y.-based association.</p>
<p>In August, the state's unemployment rate fell to 6 percent from 6.9 percent in January 1995. And the number of people employed rose above eight million in January 1996, the first time since November 1991, when measured on a seasonally adjusted basis, according to the state Labor Department.</p>
<p>During the election season, Pataki has been highlighting his administration's success in creating jobs. On Friday he said: &quot;In the future, when we look back, we will remember these years as a time when New York again was regarded with confidence and when New York again became the envy of the rest of the country, of the world, when New York again became the Empire State.&quot;</p>
<p>His comments, which were released by a spokesman, Patrick McCarthy, were made to the Syracuse Chamber of Commerce.</p>
<p>Saying the state was trying to create &quot;one unified cash assistance program&quot; for itself, Sykes painted a more fluid picture of how it was dealing with workfare issues, adding he did not believe that any final determinations had been made.</p>
<p>As with a number of issues raised by the federal welfare reforms, definitive answers about deadlines and other issues are scarce. The spokesman for the state Department of Social Services denied that the state was facing a November 22 deadline for seeking a waiver, saying it could apply for one at any time if it decided to do so.</p>
<p>Sykes, however, said he was not completely sure that was correct.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
