<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96617" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pool man, company, cleared in Gerulaitis death.</title>
<headline>Pool man, company, cleared in Gerulaitis death.</headline>
<dateline>RIVERHEAD, N.Y. 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A swimming pool mechanic and his employer were cleared on Friday of criminal charges in the gas poisoning death two years ago of former tennis star Vitas Gerulaitis.</p>
<p>Bartholomew Torpey and East End Pools and Courts Inc. were found not guilty of criminally negligent homicide and manslaughter, respectively, by a jury in Suffolk County, New York, criminal court after nearly three days of deliberations.</p>
<p>Torpey and the pool maintenance company were accused of improperly installing a pipe in a pool cottage where Gerulaitis died in September 1994 at age 40.</p>
<p>But Torpey, the pool maintenance company, a pool-heating system manufacturer and others connected to the case still face a $63 million civil lawsuit filed by Gerulaitis' mother.</p>
<p>&quot;It's great, a great feeling,&quot; Torpey told reporters after being cleared of the charges. &quot;It's been pretty tough. It's really tough that they even accused me of taking someone's life. That was very hard.&quot;</p>
<p>Prosecutors argued that Torpey rigged an incorrect length of pipe from a pool heating system, trapping carbon monoxide gas near the room in the Southampton, Long Island cottage where Gerulaitis was resting.</p>
<p>The defence argued that the wrong man was being prosecuted because the pool heating system maker Teledyne Laars and its expert James Cosmano had tinkered with it three days before the tennis star's death.</p>
<p>The only juror to speak with reporters on Friday after the verdict said she had been persuaded by that argument.</p>
<p>&quot;In my estimation, once someone else touched Bart's installation it was no longer Bart's installation. It was modified by someone else,&quot; said juror Charlene Azzara.</p>
<p>Gerulaitis, who retired from the tennis circuit in 1984 but later returned as a broadcaster and played in exhibition matches, won 27 singles and nine doubles championships, including the 1977 Australian Open.</p>
<p>His mother, Aldona Gerulaitis, has filed the civil lawsuit in New York City, citing nine defendants, including Torpey, the pool company and Martin Raynes, the friend who owned the estate where Gerulaitis died.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Edward Heilig said, &quot;In this case, the point that the jury was out for two days proves this case should have been here (in criminal court) and that it was properly brought. They could have easily come back the other way.&quot;</p>
<p>During deliberations the jury asked to be re-read the four elements required for a manslaughter conviction and the five elements that had to be proven to reach a guilty verdict on criminally negligent homicide. They also asked to hear for a second time testimony by the estate manager and a pipe vent expert.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIVERHEAD, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
