<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96709" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. Council ducks question of Afghan women.</title>
<headline>U.N. Council ducks question of Afghan women.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Security Council members expressed concern on Friday about events in Afghanistan but could not agree on criticism of the Taleban for discriminating against women when the radical Islamic group captured the Afghan capital last week.</p>
<p>Diplomats said Italy, backed by Russia, wanted the council to mention the Taleban's treatment of women in further destabilising the country.</p>
<p>But they said China, Indonesia and Egypt objected, saying the Security Council should not deal with human rights issues.</p>
<p>Instead, current council president, Gerardo Martinez Blanco of Honduras, told reporters members were concerned about the events of Afghanistan and hoped all parties would renounce the use of force and &quot;engage in constructive political dialogue to achieve national conciliation.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he was not authorised to comment on the debate over women, who have been ordered out of schools, universities and jobs.</p>
<p>The edict has hit hardest at Kabul's estimated 25,000 war widows, many of whom were employed in government jobs or involved in food-for-work programmes run by the relief agencies, including those affiliated with the United Nations.</p>
<p>They are now left with virtually no means of support for themselves or their children, short of begging on the streets.</p>
<p>The Taleban say female doctors and nurses may resume their posts, but only if they wear burqas -- a flowing head-to-toe robe that masks the face -- and do not work alongside male colleagues.</p>
<p>They say they will not deny education to girls and women, but have made clear radical reforms must occur before they can go back to school or university.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
