<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96780" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Denmark opens new offensive against warring bikers.</title>
<headline>Denmark opens new offensive against warring bikers.</headline>
<byline>Steve Weizman</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Denmark's government launched an offensive against warring motorcycle gangs on Friday, presenting parliament with rush legislation barring gang members from setting up attack-prone bases in residential areas.</p>
<p>Bikers from rival Bandidos and Hell's Angels gangs, counterparts of U.S. bands, have used guns, bombs, grenades and even anti-tank missiles in a bloody turf war spreading through the nordic region. Fears have grown that bystanders, especially children, could be hurt in increasingly reckless attacks.</p>
<p>Justice Minister Bjoern Westh has pledged that the Danish bill, announced on Tuesday by Prime Minister Poul Nyrup Rasmussen, will be in force by the end of next week, in time to eject Hell's Angels from a site in Copenhagen's Amager district before local children begin school holidays.</p>
<p>In his speech to the opening of parliament on Tuesday Rasmussen declared war on Hell's Angels and Bandidos.</p>
<p>&quot;Motorcycle gangs...are putting the lives of ordinary people at risk with their internecine rivalry. People are terrified of violence and drugs, of open narcotics trading on the streets.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot accept this. Everyone must be able to live and go about their business safely in Denmark,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A bomb attack on a Hell's Angels clubhouse in the Swedish port of Malmo on Thursday, in which four residents including a baby were injured, prompted police to order the gang to vacate properties in Malmo and nearby Helsingborg by Sunday night.</p>
<p>The order was made under existing legislation allowing police to remove residents whose presence in a neighbourhood could lead to violence or property damage.</p>
<p>The new Danish bill gives police powers to forbid members or associates of a particular group to occupy or visit a property where there is a risk of an attack endangering local people.</p>
<p>Rasmussen has promised police investigating major crimes powers to tap phones and search property without a court order.</p>
<p>Amager residents have staged street protests demanding the eviction of the Hell's Angels.</p>
<p>In the last attack, in the sleepy coastal town of Roskilde on September 22, a gunman poured more than 200 rounds from a belt-fed machine gun into the front of a Hell's Angels clubhouse from a vantage point in a playing field across the road.</p>
<p>One of the occupants was wounded, but local police said it was only by chance that no innocent motorist came down the street into the hail of fire.</p>
<p>A car bomb outside the same building 10 days earlier sent blazing debris 150 metres through the air, some of it cutting into the walls of nearby apartment buildings</p>
<p>Since the Bandidos started challenging Hell's Angels regional supremacy in 1993 there has been sporadic killing.</p>
<p>The war took on a new intensity in March 1996 when a Finnish Bandido leader was gunned down on a Helsinki street and leather-jacketed attackers at Copenhagen Airport raked arriving Bandidos with gunfire, killing one and wounding two.</p>
<p>In an audacious break-in at a prison north of the Danish capital in April, raiders tossed a hand grenade into the cell of a sleeping Bandido inmate before escaping unseen. The intended victim survived.</p>
<p>There was an apparent tit-for-tat strike at another prison in July when attackers using pistols and a grenade wounded Denmark's best-known biker, Joern 'Joenke' Nielsen.</p>
<p>Nielsen, serving a 16-year sentence for the 1984 murder of a rival gang-member, has written books, lectured in schools and acts as the Hell's Angels' spokesman. He was shot in the stomach and arm but recovered.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
