<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96822" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India court orders Rao to appear in forgery case.</title>
<headline>India court orders Rao to appear in forgery case.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Indian judge issued a warrant on Friday ordering former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao to appear in court later this month to face forgery charges.</p>
<p>Court officials said Rao and three others charged in the seven-year-old case could be arrested if they failed to appear in court on October 14.  </p>
<p>The Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI), India's federal police, charged Rao and three others on September 26 in the forgery case involving an alleged attempt in 1989 to tarnish the reputation of V.P. Singh, an opposition leader who later became prime minister.</p>
<p>The case involves the alleged falsification of bank documents to show that Singh's son, Ajeya Singh, had a secret bank account with large amounts of money on the Caribbean island of St Kitts.</p>
<p>Rao stepped down as leader of the Congress party on September 21 after a Delhi judge upheld a summons ordering him to appear in court to face criminal conspiracy charges in a separate cheating case.</p>
<p>His court appearance in that case, scheduled for last Monday, was postponed until October 9 after the Supreme Court said it would take up a police request for the venue of the hearing to be shifted from a local court to a more secure spot.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
