<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96876" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: FOCUS - Hungary sacks state privatisation board.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Hungary sacks state privatisation board.</headline>
<byline>Duncan Shiels</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hungarian government sacked the board of privatisation agency APV on Friday, saying it had made irregular payments of millions of dollars to lawyer Marta Tocsik, who negotiated with municipalities on APV's behalf.</p>
<p>But the government spared Tamas Suchman, the minister in charge of APV, although opposition parties said he was responsible and should go.</p>
<p>The supervisory committee of APV, unveiling the results of their inquiry into the Tocsik affair, said Prime Minister Gyula Horn did not react to their early warnings concerning the operations of APV.</p>
<p>&quot;We signalled our concern at a lack of forthcoming information to the Prime Minister on July 1 but did not receive an answer,&quot; said supervisory committee member Istvan Vasarhelyi.</p>
<p>Opposition party FIDESZ continued to demand the resignation of Suchman and one of its high-ranking officials, Tamas Deutsch, said that ultimately the prime minister was responsible for what his government dids.</p>
<p>The head of the APV's supervisory board, Sandor Puskas, said the board had only limited power and insight into APV's activity.</p>
<p>&quot;APV did not seem to make use of its supervisory board and often did not take kindly to our suggestions,&quot; Puskas said. &quot;We could only examine contracts post facto and if requested.&quot;</p>
<p>Puskas said there were many contracts involved. The first framework contract with Tocsik was signed in January by the then managing director Attila Lascsik, who was dismissed on May 30.</p>
<p>A later framework contract was signed by the present managing director, Istvan Kocsis. However, there were dozens of contracts as each local government had a separate one.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Elemer Kiss said Tocsik had two contracts with APV, one of which was awarded without competitive bidding.</p>
<p>They gave her eight to 10 percent of the amounts she saved for APV and Kiss said the money Tocsik received amounted to 804 million forints ($5.2 million).</p>
<p>&quot;Many of these contracts had unclear dates and did not specify what exactly Tocsik was supposed to do,&quot; Puskas said.</p>
<p>He added that despite knowing in advance the order of the expected savings, APV's board had approved Tocsik's fee.</p>
<p>He added that municipalities with which Tocsik had negotiated received 20 billion forints in cash and a further 3.4 billion forints worth of shares in privatised gas companies for their earlier investments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
