<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96887" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Rhonda Mining says makes base metal find.</title>
<headline>Rhonda Mining says makes base metal find.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY, Alberta 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rhonda Mining said on Friday drill results from its 1996 program confirm that the company has found a massive lead, zinc and silver deposit in the Northwest Territories.</p>
<p>At hole F-4-96 on its Epworth project in the Northwest Territories, assay results indicate 10.8 percent lead, 0.04 percent zinc and 0.613 ounces of silver per ton. Four other holes reveal lead grades of between 1.36 percent and 3.68 percent, zinc grades of between 0.23 percent and 6.98 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Company geologists estimate that Esker could harbour as much as 100 million tons of ore,&quot; Rhonda said.  </p>
<p>&quot;When we began the drilling program this year, we were anticipating that results would show that we were sitting on a high-tonnage, economic-grade deposit. So far we haven't been disappointed,&quot; corporate secretary Glen Alston said in a statement. In 1996, Rhonda completed 31 exploration core holes in eight targets at Epworth. Nine holes drilled on seven copper targets intersected significant mineralization.</p>
<p>&quot;More significant, however, were the results from 21 holes drilled to test widespread lead-zinc mineralization at Esker. All 21 holes intersected lead-zinc-silver mineralization averaging 10 feet in thickness,' the company said.  </p>
<p>Rhonda jointly owns 600,000 acres of the Epworth property with Noranda Inc and has 100 percent ownership of another 420,000 acres.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY, Alberta"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
