<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="96968" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Labor Dept revises seasonal impact in jobs data.</title>
<headline>US Labor Dept revises seasonal impact in jobs data.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Labor Department said the employment establishment survey data released earlier on Friday reflect a slight interim correction to the factors used to remove the impact of normal season variations.</p>
<p>Corrections to the seasonal factors were made after a minor coding error in the program used to create seasonal factors was uncovered and corrected, the department said.</p>
<p>Seasonal adjustment factors have not yet been recomputed for hours and earnings data, but the department said its preliminary tabulations indicate that the impact of the programming correction on the series will be negligible.</p>
<p>The department said the error had a negligible effect on its historical estimates of employment, hours and earnings.</p>
<p>For the period from February through July of 1996, for example, correcting the programming error will result in a net change in estimated employment growth of less than 20,000, the department said. The current estimate for job growth during that period is about 1.1 million, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
