<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97026" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Gulf War Syndrome - maybe a pesticide link - Britain.</title>
<headline>Gulf War Syndrome - maybe a pesticide link - Britain.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain said on Friday that certain pesticides used in the 1991 Gulf War could be linked to veterans' complaints popularly known as Gulf War Syndrome.</p>
<p>&quot;The use of some OPs (organophosphate pesticides) may possibly be a clue to the conditions that some Gulf War veterans have suffered from,&quot; said Nicholas Soames, defence minister for the armed forces, in a statement. &quot;It will be investigated fully and with the utmost care.&quot;  </p>
<p>Soames said that, during a review of operational and environmental conditions during the Gulf War, it became clear that organophosphate pesticides had been used more widely than had previously been believed.</p>
<p>Authority was given to purchase some OPs in the Gulf area, he said in a letter to the chairman of a parliamentary defence committee. While the government knew that one OP, malathion, was used, there was now evidence that three others were used.</p>
<p>&quot;We are conducting urgent investigations into the extent of use of such pesticides and I will write to you once we have a clearer picture on this,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Britain's defence ministry previously said it believed the sometimes crippling ailments described by veterans had been caused by stress.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
