<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97216" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE-Moja festival displays preserved black art.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Moja festival displays preserved black art.</headline>
<byline>Harriet McLeod</byline>
<dateline>CHARLESTON, South Carolina 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Many cities stage African-American arts festivals, but few can lay as much claim to preservation of the crafts, arts, architecture, music, and language of Africa and the Caribbean as this former U.S. colonial slave port.</p>
<p>&quot;Moja, A Celebration of African-American and Caribben Art,&quot; a weeklong festival running here through Sunday, is a colourful panoply of theatre, dance, music and visual arts.</p>
<p>It includes, for example, a tribute to Josephine Baker of 1920s Paris' &quot;La Revue Negre,&quot; a juried arts show, jazz, and reggae block parties reminiscent of Caribbean festivals.</p>
<p>But the Moja festival, which takes its name from the Swahili word meaning &quot;one,&quot; also pays homage to home grown arts and artists who carry on centuries-old traditions.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole idea of Moja is to foster appreciation for African-American artists' contribution to world culture,&quot; said Ellen Dressler Moryl, city cultural affairs office director.</p>
<p>There's a competition in South Carolina's country art of sweetgrass basketmaking -- which are woven row upon row and taught by mother to daughter only on the sea islands of South Carolina and Georgia, and the west coast countries of Africa.</p>
<p>Master blacksmith Philip Simmons, 83, has been signing minatures of the wrought-iron gates he has forged since the 1940s. Named a national treasure, he has built on the tradition of colonial slave ironwork preserved here.</p>
<p>In the galleries of the Dock Street Theatre, the oldest public theatre in the country, hang the family and heritage storytelling quilts of local quilter Marlene Seabrook.</p>
<p>This week, the Charleston Symphony Orchestra will perform the U.S. premiere of &quot;Charlestonia&quot; by Edmund Jenkins, an African-American expatriate who was a fellow at the Royal Academy of Music in London.</p>
<p>He lived in Paris most of his life and was a prolific composer of what was called American &quot;symphonic jazz&quot; in the early part of this century.</p>
<p>He was the son of the Reverend Daniel Joseph Jenkins, founder of the Jenkins Orphanage and its world-famous travelling jazz bands who played &quot;The Charleston&quot; on street corners here.</p>
<p>But shunned as a black classical composer in this country, Jenkins wrote &quot;Charlestonia&quot; in 1917 in Europe and based its melodies on tunes sung by African-American fishermen and dockworkers on the wharves of Charleston.</p>
<p>It was first performed in Belgium in 1925, but was lost with Jenkins' other work after his death, only to be found within the last few years in a steamer trunk in a relative's home.</p>
<p>Composer Vincent Plush has reconstructed the piece.</p>
<p>An original play, &quot;Hush Dat Gullah,&quot; nods to the unique &quot;geechie&quot; people of the isolated sea islands who have preserved their cultural attitudes, customs, relgious practices and Gullah language, which contains much West African syntax and vocabulary, through 300 years.</p>
<p>For years, said Art Gilliard, executive director of the festival who is directing the play, it was not a language that people were proud of or aspired to speak.</p>
<p>&quot;Hush Dat Gullah lets people know that there's no need to be ashamed of your language. It's the only language that depicts who you are and where you came from,&quot; Gilliard said.</p>
<p>&quot;We really are trying to highlight or showcase the things that have a direct link to Africa ... that comes from the Motherland.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARLESTON, South Carolina"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
