<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97302" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian shares end up, seen consolidating.</title>
<headline>Austrian shares end up, seen consolidating.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian shares closed 0.2 percent higher on Friday after spending most of the session bogged down in negative territory.</p>
<p>The ATX index of 21 blue-chip shares ended at 1,076.72 points -- 2.39 up on the day and 7.15 off the session low. October ATX futures stood 5.00 points higher at 1,073.5.</p>
<p>Traders said the market had entered a period of consolidation after clearing 1,075 points and forecast a period of consolidation before an assault on 1,080 to 1,090 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The mood in the market remains positive,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;Today was not particularly active but there was still selective demand.&quot;</p>
<p>Support at 1,060 points should limit the extent of any downward correction, market watchers said.</p>
<p>Seven ATX shares closed lower, 11 higher and three unchanged.</p>
<p>Semi-conductor maker Austria Mikro Systeme was the day's biggest gainer, rising 3.45 percent to 809 schillings. Traders said there were still unfilled buy orders for AMS and forecast the stock would continue to advance next week.</p>
<p>Creditanstalt ordinary and preferred shares also moved ahead as investors sense the bank's privatisation may be moving into its closing stage.</p>
<p>Brewer BBAG was the biggest decliner, dropping 1.38 percent to 715 schillings on low volume of 100 lots.</p>
<p>The listing of one-for-one bonus shares in hosiery and lingery maker Wolford AG will go ahead on October 7. -- Vienna Newsroom, 43-1-53112-258</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
