<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97365" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Gucci chief sees strong growth still to come.</title>
<headline>Gucci chief sees strong growth still to come.</headline>
<byline>Ed Brunetti</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian luxury goods and designer wear company Gucci Group NV expects strong growth to continue for the next couple of years and plans carefully-controlled expansion in Germany and Asia, chief executive Domenico De Sole said.</p>
<p>De Sole, in an interview with Reuters Financial Television, said the leather goods group realised recent rapid growth rates could not continue indefinitely.</p>
<p>&quot;We already have six quarters of doubling our sales and we don't expect it to continue forever but we will continue to enjoy a steady growth by the end of the year and to continue for several years,&quot; De Sole said shortly before the group unveiled its women's 1997 spring/summer collection here late on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot give projections but analysts believe we will enjoy very strong growth for the remainder of the year with our growth to be above 20 percent for the next couple of years.&quot;</p>
<p>Gucci's sales went up by 90 percent year on year in the first half of 1996 and net profits increased to $69.9 million from $26.4 million in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>The group floated 28.2 million shares at $22 per share in October last year on the New York and Amsterdam stock markets and a second tranche was placed in March at $48 per share.</p>
<p>De Sole noted in 1995 Gucci had sales of $500 million &quot;and everybody expects our sales this year to reach $850 million.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;For earnings per share the expectation is they will reach $2.40 or maybe $2.50. The expectation of the market is for dramatic growth from last year and we feel quite comfortable with the projections of the analysts,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked why gross operating margins had not grown as strongly as other results, he said the mix between wholesale and directly operated stores had changed, with a stronger increase in the first six months on the wholesale side.</p>
<p>&quot;If you unscramble the picture and look at the two segments, you see there was an increase in the margin both in the directly operated stores, our own retail stores, and the wholesale operation. However the change of mix has produced a decrease.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1995 directly operated stores represented 75 percent of total revenues, while in the first half of 1996 this slipped to slightly below 70 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Ideally we would like between 67 and 70 percent of sales to come through our own directly operated stores. That's the right mix that will give us the control over the brands which we believe is so important to continue the success of Gucci.&quot;</p>
<p>He expected strengthening of ready-to-wear to continue, but he also saw great growth potential for reinforcing the core products of leather goods and shoes.</p>
<p>&quot;Geographically we are now looking at some key markets in Europe where for historic reasons Gucci was not present. An important one now is Germany,&quot; he said, adding Gucci had just opened stores in Hamburg and Munich and expected to open in Berlin, Duesseldorf and Frankfurt.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time, we are repositioning ourselves in Japan. We'll be opening our first freestanding shop in Japan next year, in Osaka, and we are looking for further expansion in Tokyo with freestanding shops,&quot; he said and noted the first shop in China would open in Shanghai in spring 1997.</p>
<p>To prevent the brand losing its cachet, however, he said the company aimed to keep tight control over distribution, which is why it wanted to build up its directly operated stores.</p>
<p>&quot;We are way underdistributed and we are going to keep it very tight with tremendous control on our image and our stores.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked about the danger that institutional investors would steer clear of a fashion company for fear that it might itself fall out of fashion, he said in the past 10 years companies with well-managed luxury brands had performed steadily.</p>
<p>He doubted there was such a thing as a luxury goods cycle, &quot;but in any event for Gucci our repositioning, our strength, our story is just starting to unfold now.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I44000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
