<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97519" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia bonds firmer ahead of U.S. payrolls.</title>
<headline>Australia bonds firmer ahead of U.S. payrolls.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>--------------(Snapshot at 4.35 P.M./0635 GMT)------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES					  CASH YIELD</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS  (DEC) 93.45  (+ 0.02)     6.77   (- 0.03)</p>
<p>3-YR T-BONDS  (DEC) 93.06  (+ 0.02)     6.86   (- 0.04)</p>
<p>10-YR T-BONDS (DEC) 92.390 (+0.035)     7.59   (- 0.04)</p>
<p>AUD/USD  0.7893 (PREV 0.7919) US 30-YR  6.84   (6.84 NY)</p>
<p>---------------------------(Oct 4)------------------------------</p>
<p>*Australian bonds open strongly, soften, and recover to finish at fresh 30 months highs ahead of key U.S. payrolls data.</p>
<p>*Comments from Treasurer Costello suggesting room for more than one more rate cut buoys the short end of the market.  </p>
<p>Australian bonds continued their recent strength, closing at fresh 30 months highs in subdued trade ahead of the release of key U.S. payrolls data.</p>
<p>December 10-year futures closed at a contract high 92.390, while the three year ended one point off its high of 93.07 on the day. The close saw the 10-year bond yield end under 7.60 percent for the first time since March 23, 1994.</p>
<p>Despite the stronger close, traders said the market was failry subdued ahead of the September payrolls data to be issued later on Friday, with bonds held to four and five point ranges on the day.  </p>
<p>&quot;Today was akin to the proverbial 'calm before the storm', with bond market particpants not willing to second guess tonight's September non-farm payrolls number,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Overnight comments by Treasurer Peter Costello on the rates outlook supported the short end at the open and saw the March bill futures hit a contract high of 93.56, an implied yield  56 points below the 7.00 percent official cash rate.</p>
<p>Costello, asked by media in New York about rates, said that inflation, growth, the budget and the fall in bond yields were &quot;not bad&quot;, adding: &quot;I think that's reason enough for Santa Claus both this year and next year.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;With a pre-Christmas rate cut almost fully factored into the market, the 'new' news in these comments is that they lend weight to the possibility of another rate cut early next year,&quot; Bankers Trust Australia senior economist David Bassanese said.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank also announced a A$600 million bond tender for Tuesday, comprising A$200 million of the January 2001 stock and A$400 million of November 2006 bonds. The tender was announced today because the New South Wales market is closed on Monday, when futures trade will be restricted the SYCOM system.</p>
<p>The payrolls data are the key focus for the market, with U.S economists forecasting a September rise of 166,000.  </p>
<p>------------------------(SPREADS)------------------------  AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	 71 (- 03)   100 (- 04) * FUTURES   67   (-1.5)</p>
<p> CAD	164 (+ 01)    66 (unch) * CASH	73   (- 02)</p>
<p> NZD	-85 (- 12)   -28 (unch) *</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>After widening to the midsession, spreads narrow again into the close, with the key spread to U.S 10 years hitting 100 basis point at the close -- a 2-1/2 year low. The curves continued to flatten as the long end closed at its highs. The NZ short end corrected after Thursday's short squeeze.  </p>
<p>----------------------(TECHNICALS)--------------------------- FUTURES	*DAY'S RANGE *SUP/RES     *RSI    *MA-10 *MA-20</p>
<p>10-YEAR (DEC)*92.34-92.39 *92.35-92.39 *74 PCT *92.21 *92.08 3-YEAR  (DEC)*93.03-93.07 *93.00-93.07 *73 PCT *92.92 *92.79 90-DAY  (DEC)*93.44-93.46 *93.43-93.49 *67 PCT *93.38 *93.31 -------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Bonds remain near overbought territory, represented by RSI of 75 or more, and remain well ahead of moving averages.</p>
<p>-- John Mair 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
