<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97517" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Oct 4.</title>
<headline>RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Oct 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>** BIRTHDAYS **</p>
<p>English pioneer journalist in New South Wales, RICHARD JONES, was born in 1816. He founded the 'Maitland Mercury' in 1843.</p>
<p>American statesman and Republican president from 1877-1881, RUTHERFORD.B.HAYES, was born in 1822. He supported the welfare of minority groups and reformed the nation's civil service.</p>
<p>Australian poet and part-time actor HUGH McCRAE was born in 1876.</p>
<p>American comedian, actor and film director BUSTER KEATON (JOSEPH FRANK) was born in 1896. He began his career at the age of just three, as a 'human mop' in a family comedy act. He was known for his deadpan expression (&quot;the great stone face&quot;), and starred in several movies including &quot;One Week&quot; (1920), &quot;The Navigator&quot; (1924) and &quot;The Cameraman&quot; (1928).</p>
<p>American actor CHARLTON HESTON was born in 1924. He often starred in biblical and historical epics, including &quot;The Ten Commandments&quot; (1956) and &quot;Ben Hur&quot; (1959).</p>
<p>The New Zealand/Australian racehorse PHAR LAP was born in 1926.</p>
<p>American singer and songwriter LEROY VAN DYKE, who had a hit with &quot;Walk On By&quot; (1961), was born in 1929.</p>
<p>American bass player JIM FIELDER, who played with many groups including 'Buffalo Springfield' and 'Blood, Sweat And Tears', was born in 1947.</p>
<p>			 ** EVENTS **</p>
<p>    1535 :    The first complete English translation (by MILES</p>
<p>COVERDALE) of The Bible was printed in Zurich.</p>
<p>    1669 :    Dutch painter REMBRANDT VAN RIJN died in Amsterdam</p>
<p>at the age of 63. Following the death of his wealthy wife in 1642, REMBRANDT gradually went broke. He left a vast legacy of about 600 paintings, 1,500 drawings and 350 etchings.</p>
<p>    1824 :    Mexico became a republic.</p>
<p>    1859 :    German publisher KARL BAEDEKER, whose series of</p>
<p>travel guides became internationally famous, died.</p>
<p>    1904 :    The man who created the Statue of Liberty, French</p>
<p>sculptor FREDERIC AUGUSTE BARTHOLDI, died.</p>
<p>    1905 :    ORVILLE WRIGHT became the first person to fly an</p>
<p>aircraft for more than 33 minutes.</p>
<p>    1906 :    Five men drowned while trying to rescue stock from</p>
<p>floods around Orange in New South Wales. The flooding, which also struck Victoria and Tasmania following heavy  rains, was described as the worst in some areas in 20 years.</p>
<p>    1910 :    Portugal was proclaimed a republic, as KING MANUEL</p>
<p>II fled to Britain.</p>
<p>    1929 :    Hospital authorities in Melbourne called for the</p>
<p>formation of a 'blood bank', following difficulties in finding blood donors.</p>
<p>    1952 :    An external device called a pacemaker, developed</p>
<p>by Harvard Medical School Doctor PAUL ZOLL, was fitted to patient DAVID SCHWARTZ to control his heartbeat.</p>
<p>    1952 :    Chairman of Directors of The Herald and Weekly</p>
<p>Times Ltd and controlling shareholder of Queensland Newspapers and News Ltd - Adelaide, SIR KEITH MURDOCH, died at the age of 67. His part in reporting the end of the Gallipoli campaign in World War I made him famous, and one of his other great achievements was the part he played in establishing Tasmania's newsprint industry. He left his son RUPERT a large holding of shares in News Ltd.</p>
<p>    1957 :    Russia took a step closer to discovering the</p>
<p>possible uses of satellites, by launching the 'SPUTNIK I', the world's first artificial satellite.</p>
<p>    1961 :    Russian-born American painter MAX WEBER died.</p>
<p>    1967 :    Australian and American troops, some of whom</p>
<p>had been fighting the Viet Cong just three days earlier, became the first Vietnam servicemen to be given rest and recreation (R&amp;R) leave in Australia. The group of 187 servicemen and women was flown in to Sydney.</p>
<p>    1970 :    American blues and rock singer JANIS JOPLIN died</p>
<p>of a heroin overdose in her motel room in Hollywood. JOPLIN was know for her uninhibited singing style, and later in her career, for drinking a bottle of 'Southern Comfort' during performances on stage. She was born on the 19th of January, 1943.</p>
<p>    1976 :    The world's fastest diesel train service began in</p>
<p>London, as British Rail launched the HS-125 train, capable of speeds of 125 miles per hour (200kph).</p>
<p>    1981 :    The IRA called off a 10 month hunger strike that</p>
<p>had cost the lives of ten republicans, held in H-block of the Maze Prison in Belfast. The Maze became the focus of world media attention after the first deaths of hunger strikers, including the MP for Fermanagh and South Tyrone, BOBBY SANDS.</p>
<p>    1983 :    London businessman RICHARD NOBLE's &quot;Thrust II&quot;</p>
<p>became the fastest car in the world, setting a new mark of 633.47 miles per hour (1,013 kph) over the Black Rock desert in the American state of Nevada.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS.)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
