<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97548" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: New Zealand dollar ends steady, range-bound.</title>
<headline>New Zealand dollar ends steady, range-bound.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand dollar closed virtually unchanged on Friday, having traded within a tight US$0.6986-96 range.</p>
<p>&quot;The demise of the Aussie overnight really put a cap on the Kiwi and it never really looked as though we were going to go back above the (0.7000) figure on the day,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Saying that however, we've seen further Japanese buying, nothing of size, that's the reason we haven't moved, but it certainly helped underpin the Kiwi.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Kiwi closed at 0.6989/96, the same level at which it opened the session. On its Trade-Weighted Index, the Kiwi closed at 66.77, slightly above its 66.74 open.</p>
<p>Dealers said there was local buying interest in the Kiwi in the mid-0.6980 area.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook is pretty mixed,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;If anything, the topside is going to be relatively well capped up towards the 0.7010 level, particularly with the way the Aussie came off.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the Australian unit had reached 0.7965 mid-week, but was closing at around 0.7905/10 on Friday.  </p>
<p>The risks for the Kiwi now lay more on the downside, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think if anything the risks are that we could see the 0.6980 level break and maybe head down towards 0.6960,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;But to be honest it's in a tight range and it really doesn't look as though it's ging to break out of it right now.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers saw the Kiwi trading a 0.6980-0.7000 range overnight. -- Matthew Brockett 64 4 4714 272</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
