<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97565" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Big change in NZ fiscal policy would concern S&amp;P.</title>
<headline>Big change in NZ fiscal policy would concern S&amp;P.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard and Poor's Sovereign Risk Managing Director David Beers said on Friday a major change in New Zealand's fiscal policy would cause concern for the ratings agency.</p>
<p>But Beers told Reuters from New York the next government was not likely to deviate drastically from the type of policies that have been pursued first by Labour Party, then National Party governments over the last decade or more.</p>
<p>New Zealand faces its first election under the German style Mixed Member Proportional (MMP) system of representation on October 12, which is expected to deliver a coalition government.  </p>
<p>The governing conservative National Party currently leads in the opinion polls but not by enough to regain power outright.</p>
<p>Beers said other proportional representation countries tended to form centrist economic policies and it was not clear why New Zealand should prove an exception.</p>
<p>&quot;On the other hand, if we thought that the government of the day was going to drastically change the sense of fiscal policy -- and by drastically I mean to contemplate and then implement a position whereby New Zealanders started running large budget deficits again -- and ones that seemed likely to cause substantial increase in inflation and in the government's debt  </p>
<p>burden, then yes, that would certainly concern us.&quot;</p>
<p>S&amp;P would consider a substantial deviation to be abandonment of the commitment to budget surpluses, something closer to budget balance, or the adoption of outright budget deficits.</p>
<p>&quot;We might also be talking about radical changes to the Reserve Bank Act or even an abandonment of the commitment to inflation targetting altogether,&quot; Beers said.</p>
<p>But it was too soon to assume that substantial deviations were likely to occur, especially given the polls were showing a a large undecided vote.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are quite content to wait until the after the votes are counted to see wehther there is any significant change in the composition of the new parliament and then start focussing on what the new administration's economic poliices will be.</p>
<p>&quot;That makes sense to us in terms of judging whether this rating continues to be appropriate.&quot;</p>
<p>S&amp;P current rates New Zealand's New Zealand's foreign currency debt at AA plus with a stable outlook.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
