<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97574" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ parties haunted by comments from ex-ministers.</title>
<headline>NZ parties haunted by comments from ex-ministers.</headline>
<byline>Vernon Small</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eight days before a general election the governing conservative National Party and the main opposition Labour Party are both in damage-control mode over statements by former party luminaries.</p>
<p>Labour leader Helen Clark has denied there is a possibility of defections from her party to prop up a conservative National following statements by retiring former Labour Prime Minister David Lange that Prime Minister Jim Bolger would try to &quot;wheedle&quot; members away to support him.  </p>
<p>During an interview on Australian television Lange said there were MPs &quot;nearing the end of their lives, who could do with three years of privilege and preference&quot;.</p>
<p>Referring to other previous defections from Labour and National, Lange said: &quot;All I'm saying is political loyalty seems to have a rather low premium placed on it lately.&quot;</p>
<p>Lange later denied he was predicting defections or confining his comments to Labour MPs, but Clark took the matter seriously enough to point out that Lange &quot;is more like an independent commentator and he is not running for parliament again. I think he has called it wrong because I don't see anyone who is likely to leave my party&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Sometimes in my dreams I think, well, maybe after the election if the numbers are tight I could ring (National backbencher) Max Bradford and offer him something, but the truth is it's not going to happen.</p>
<p>&quot;And it's not going to happen with Mr Bolger trying to fish people out of Labour.&quot;</p>
<p>She said Labour would promote legislation to require any MP who left a party to resign from parliament.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile National, already reeling from a poor television performance by Bolger and foundering attempts to claim the economy would in danger from a Labour-led coalition, has been wounded by criticisms of its campaign strategy by former Finance Minister Ruth Richardson.</p>
<p>Richardson, who resigned from parliament after being dumped by Bolger after the 1993 election victory, described the National campaign as &quot;lamentable&quot; and advised supporters to give their party vote to the free-market ACT New Zealand to ensure a coalition partner for National.  </p>
<p>&quot;You can't govern in a coalition era if you are naked,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Her message was a direct contradiction of National's &quot;First tick National&quot; campaign slogan aimed at securing the party vote which determines the overall shape of parliament.</p>
<p>Under the proportional representation system adopted for this election National is firmly in the lead on 38 percent in the polls but is struggling to find coalition partners to lift it over the 50 percent level.  </p>
<p>The three main opposition parties, Labour, the left wing Alliance and economic nationalist New Zealand First together have just over 50 percent support and should be able to oust National if they can overcome their differences.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
