<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97581" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ consumer confidence rebounds in Q3 - Westpac.</title>
<headline>NZ consumer confidence rebounds in Q3 - Westpac.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand consumer confidence recovered sharply in the September quarter, according to the Westpac McDermott Miller survey published on Friday.</p>
<p>The index rebounded 8.1 points to 121.2, after plunging 15.7 points in the June quarter in the sharpest quarterly fall recorded by the survey.</p>
<p>The index still remains below levels seen last year when it reached 126.0.  </p>
<p>&quot;The latest result indicates that the large fall in optimism in the June quarter was perhaps overdone despite some confirmation from poor retail sales over that period,&quot; Westpac chief economist Bevan Graham said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the overall trend in confidence is down and we expect this to continue over the remainder of this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some volatility in consumer confidence numbers over the next few quarters is expected as the economy approaches a turning point in terms of growth in demand and the labour market,&quot; Graham said.  </p>
<p>Since June, anecdotal evidence pointed to steady economic activity with a bias on the upside, he said.</p>
<p>Much of the volatility in confidence over the last few quarters had been driven by consumers' outlook for the economy over the next 12 months.</p>
<p>McDermott Miller principal Richard Miller said the proportion of consumers who were undecided about the economy's prospects was growing.</p>
<p>&quot;Uncertainty about the outcome of the forthcoming election under MMP is the most frequently stated reason for this indecision,&quot; Miller said.  </p>
<p>Graham said a poor assessment of the short-term future in the June quarter appeared to be an overreaction to negative signs at the time. These included the apparent peak in residential property, lower retail demand and an expectation of labour market weakness.</p>
<p>As it turned out, the labour market remained strong, retail sales were given a modest boost by tax cuts and property sales plateaued, Graham said.</p>
<p>Eight of 11 regions reported an increase in consumer confidence but on an annual basis confidence was lower in eight regions.  </p>
<p>Confidence rose most strongly in metropolitan areas with Auckland up 11.0 points to 127.4, Wellington up 13.6 to 125.1 and Otago up 12.8 to 125.3 in the quarter.</p>
<p>An increased proportion of consumers (up four points to 32 percent) believed they were better off financially and expected to be even better off in a year's time (up four points to 42 percent). This was more marked in metropolitan areas.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
