<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97647" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Calls mount for pardons for exiled Cambodia princes.</title>
<headline>Calls mount for pardons for exiled Cambodia princes.</headline>
<byline>Leo Dobbs</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The recent royal pardon of a top leader of Cambodia's brutal 1970s Khmer Rouge regime has led to mounting calls for amnesties for government enemies convicted of far lesser crimes.</p>
<p>Prince Norodom Sirivudh, exiled last year for his alleged involvement in a plot to kill Second Prime Minister Hun Sen, is expected to write to his half brother King Norodom Sihanouk to seek forgiveness and approval to return home.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that he is writing to the king. I think this letter will be faxed soon,&quot; his wife Christine said in Phnom Penh.</p>
<p>The prince, contacted by Reuters in Paris on Thursday, would only say he would speak to the press soon.</p>
<p>Politicians advocating reconciliation and family members say the convicted ringleaders of a failed 1994 coup attempt -- the king's son Prince Norodom Chakrapong, former interior minister Sin Song and his deputy Sin Sen -- should also be pardoned.</p>
<p>They denied the charges but were sentenced to long terms at trials dismissed as farcical by human rights workers.</p>
<p>Sin Sen, the only one to serve time, was moved to house arrest under a partial amnesty this year. A bodyguard said earlier this week he was ailing and could not talk to Reuters.</p>
<p>King Norodom Sihanouk set a precedent last month by agreeing to pardon Ieng Sary from a 1979 death sentence handed down in absentia for his role in the genocide of more than one million people as foreign minister in the 1975-79 Khmer Rouge rule.</p>
<p>The king agreed to the amnesty request of co-premiers Prince Norodom Ranariddh and Hun Sen in the interests of peace. Ieng Sary had broken with Khmer Rouge hardliners in August and said peace talks could only progress once his legal status was clarified.</p>
<p>Royalist sources said the king wanted an amnesty for these political enemies of the government to further his goal of national reconciliation.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's really reasonable. If they're giving amnesty (to Ieng Sary) why shouldn't they give it to Prince Sirivudh and Prince Chakrapong when they haven't got blood on their hands,&quot; Princess Norodom Bophary, Chakrapong's daughter, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Many believe these people should return to Cambodia if the government is serious about national reconciliation,&quot; said Son Chhay, one of only a handful of government ministers opposed to Ieng Sary's amnesty.</p>
<p>Ranariddh said last week that Sirivudh should write and ask the king for an amnesty, adding that his royalist FUNCINPEC party would support one in light of the mercy shown Ieng Sary.</p>
<p>Sihanouk in August responded to pleas from the family of Sin Song, believed to still be in Asia after his release from Thai detention in April, by asking the premiers and parliament chief Chea Sim to let the fugitive return home to house arrest.</p>
<p>Chea Sim, believed to be the main sponsor of amnesty for the convicted coup leaders and former members of his faction in the Cambodian People's Party, and Ranariddh gave their support.</p>
<p>The position of the powerful Hun Sen is unknown, but some analysts believe his decision would depend on the progress of peace talks with the breakaway Khmer Rouge faction.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a vicious circle. The more concessions that they make in order to reach a real agreement...the more pressure there would be on them to give amnesty to the others,&quot; said one Asian analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;The instrument of amnesty has been used entirely in a political manner, not a juridical manner,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A senior diplomat said he believed that Hun Sen would reject a pardon for his political enemies without a dividend.</p>
<p>&quot;Hun Sen says amnesty for Ieng Sary is fine because he brought peace and delivered two divisions (of former Khmer Rouge guerrillas) at least, but amnesty for Sirivudh would not do anyone any good,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>Kem Sokha, a minister of parialment, echoed that sentiment, saying neither premier wanted Sirivudh, Chakrapong and Sin Song to return. &quot;They're interested in the Khmer Rouge...in (the rebel base at) Pailin.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
