<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97671" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dec JGB rallies to end Tokyo at new contract high.</title>
<headline>Dec JGB rallies to end Tokyo at new contract high.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key December Japanese government bond (JGB) contract rallied to end at the contract high of 122.83 on Friday, in line with the strong cash market, traders said.</p>
<p>The December, after opening at 122.70 and dipping as low as 122.56, ended at 122.83, the highest ever for any benchmark 10-year JGB futures contract. It closed at 122.53 on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The sentiment among traders is ...if you sell, you will lose,&quot; said a city bank trader.</p>
<p>He added that cash flows from public funds were the major reason behind the recent rally.  </p>
<p>The Housing Loan Administration Corp, the body set up to collect problem loans incurred by failed mortgage firms, said on Thursday it has started investing the funds it inherited from the firms.</p>
<p>Funds were believed to have been invested in certificates of deposits and short-end cash JGBs.</p>
<p>Cash JGBs with a remaining life of one to two years to maturity were stronger than any other sectors of the yield curve, traders said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the two-year interest rate swap rate fell to 0.97-1.01 percent from Thursday's 1.00/1.04 percent.  </p>
<p>Falls in the swap rate reflected active purchases of fixed interest rates by city banks in view of further rate declines, traders said.</p>
<p>The yield of the benchmark 182nd JGB was at 2.770 percent at 0655 GMT, down from 2.785 percent on Thursday.</p>
<p>In the money market, the outstanding volume of the call market has recently fallen to around 45 trillion yen from the peak of over 50 trillion, money traders said.</p>
<p>This indicated that the funds temporarily parked in the money market have begun to shift into long-term instruments, including cash JGBs, they said.  </p>
<p>The long-term end of the JGBs will remain the main beneficiary of funds moving away from the money market due to its relative yield advantage, and sluggish Tokyo stocks.</p>
<p>However, some worry about the recent bond rallies which have pushed the benchmark yield below three percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the current economic fandamentals and the state of the budget balance, the long-term yield should be a bit higher,&quot; said a senior analyst at Nomura Investment Trust Co.</p>
<p>He forecast a rebound in the benchmark yield to three to 3.2 percent by the end of the year.</p>
<p>----Yoshiko Mori, Tokyo Treasury Desk 813-3432-8676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
