<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97685" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai copper ends down on LME loss.</title>
<headline>Shanghai copper ends down on LME loss.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai copper futures ended down in dull trading on Friday due to overnight losses on the London Metal Exchange with most investors withdrawing their funds, traders said.</p>
<p>The most active January 1997 contract ended at 20,040 yuan ($2,414) per tonne, losing 10 yuan. It opened unchanged at 20,050 yuan, hitting an intra-day high of 20,060 and a low of 19,960.</p>
<p>October fell 100 to 20,330 yuan, November 40 to 20,160, December 40 to 20,110, February 10 to 20,040 and March 70 to 20,070.  </p>
<p>Combined volume fell to 9,160 tonnes form 22,240.</p>
<p>Copper opened mostly down and moved around 20,000 yuan for most of the session.</p>
<p>Traders said LME losses triggered some selling but short-covering on the unclear short-term market trend prevented prices from dropping further.</p>
<p>&quot;LME losses was the major factor and most investors were not willing to build new positions ahead of the weekend,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;The unclear short-term trend made later-maturing contracts find strong support at 20,000 yuan,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Traders said poor domestic fundamentals made many investors move their money to other more active markets such as the stock market.</p>
<p>Recent further restriction of futures trading by China's top securities authorities also made some money flow out of the metals market, they said.</p>
<p>Aluminium ended down. October did not trade. November fell 80 to 13,820 yuan per tonne and December 120 to 13,730.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 870 tonnes from 220.</p>
<p>($1=8.3006 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
