<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97865" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway says its strong economy is envy of Europe.</title>
<headline>Norway says its strong economy is envy of Europe.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian Finance Minister Sigbjoern Johnsen said on Friday in presenting the 1997 budget proposal that its oil-rich, strong economy was the envy of Europe.</p>
<p>But he cautioned against abandoning the current tight fiscal policy for fear of fuelling inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;The Norwegian economy is in a period of strong growth in terms of employment, production and revenue,&quot; he said in a statement. &quot;If we look at the situation in other European countries, we are to be envied.&quot;</p>
<p>But &quot;we must avoid getting into a situation...where the economic upswing makes prices and wages grow too strong, resulting in Norwegian companies pricing themselves out of the market,&quot; Johnsen said.</p>
<p>A ministry statement said the government was continuing to pursue a tight fiscal policy to avoid entering a period of excess demand and higher price and wage growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The budget entails a fiscal tightening, which is equivalent to about one percent of mainland GDP as measured by the non-oil cyclically adjusted budget indicator,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Strong government finances will enable the goverment to more fully accommodate the twin challenges in the first decades of the next century, as Norway will experience a decline in the petroleum revenues and a sharp rise in public expenditures on pensions and care of the elderly.</p>
<p>&quot;The strong cyclical upswing in the Norwegian economy over the last three years is expected to continue in 1997, albeit at a somewhat slower pace,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The expansion, which gathered momentum in the second half of 1993, was initially driven by increased growth in private consumption, housing investment and merchandise exports. In 1995, the upswing became more broadly based as investment in mainland industries picked up.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite strong growth, price inflation has remained subdued, at rates well below that of Norway's main trading partner countries,&quot; the ministry said.</p>
<p>--Oslo newsroom +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
