<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="97906" id="root" date="1996-10-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Oct 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Oct 4.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-10-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Friday morning's Austrian newspapers.</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Social Democrat (SPOe) whip Peter Kostelka has proposed a &quot;pact of openess and tolerance&quot; with junior coalition partners the conservative People's Party (OeVP). Kostelka accused OeVP whip Andreas Khol of taking the OeVP further to the right.</p>
<p>- Loewa retail group, a unit of Germany's Tengelmann, does not plan to pull out of Austria but will undertake major restructuring.</p>
<p>- State-owned Post und Telekom Austria AG wants state payments of 3.3 billion schillings a year. Post chief Josef Sindelka said he expects the firm to debut on the stock market by the end of the century, as planned.</p>
<p>- Austrian tourism should have access to around one billion schillings in investment capital within the next few months, under a GiroCredit scheme.</p>
<p>- Austrian soft drinks producer Coca-Cola-Amatil plans to close five depots and lay off 350 of its 1,600 workers.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- Savings cuts will bite deeper next year when Austrians will have to pay more for prescriptions. Pensioners may see their income decline in real terms. High earners will also make bigger social contributions.</p>
<p>- German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel spent the anniversary of German unification in Austria, where he met with Chancellor Franz Vranitzky and Foreign Minister Wolfgang Schuessel.</p>
<p>- GiroCredit announced plans for a tourism fund of one billion schillings in 1997.</p>
<p>- Economy Minister Johann Franleitner ruled out increasing road tolls on environmentally sensitive Alpine routes.</p>
<p>- Philips Speaker Systems said it plans to invest 100 million schillings in its Vienna plant.</p>
<p>- Fireproof materials manufacturer Radex-Heraklith is aiming for a five percent turnover yield by 1998 at the latest, chief executive Walter Ressler said. That would mean doubling last year's 577 million schillings group pre-tax profit.</p>
<p>- Talks about more flexible working hours in the metal industry start on Monday.</p>
<p>- Creditanstalt chief executive Guido Schmidt-Chiari reiterated he would favour a European partner for the bank</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Efforts to crack a code contained in an extremist bomb threat could cost Austria millions of schillings. In addition, Austria is willing to pay a reward of 14.5 million schillings for information leading to an arrest. Suspected right-wing extremists are behind a series of bomb attacks spanning three years.</p>
<p>- Austrians are learning the unpleasant lessons of &quot;shareholder value&quot; through job cuts at paper maker Leykam and tyre maker Semperit.</p>
<p>- Talks on more flexible working hours in the metal industry could eventually put pressure on top social partners -- employers and unions -- to adapt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
