<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98013" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SOCCER-START OF THE MLS CONFERENCE FINALS DELAYED.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-START OF THE MLS CONFERENCE FINALS DELAYED.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The start of the conference finals of the Major League Soccer playoffs has been delayed for a week to avoid missing key players due to World Cup qualifying.</p>
<p>Three of the teams -- the Tampa Bay Mutiny, D.C. United and Los Angeles Galaxy -- have players who will participate in qualifying from the South American and CONCACAF regions. The playoffs were supposed to have begun last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We attempted to schedule the conference finals to maximize player availability,&quot; MLS commissioner Doug Logan said. &quot;While working with factors such as stadium dates, World Cup qualifying matches and the league's national television games, we believe we have designed a schedule that will allow the fans the opportunity to see all of the league's top players.&quot;</p>
<p>Seven players have commitments with their respective national teams, including Los Angeles midfielder Mauricio Cienfuegos and United forward Raul Diaz Arce, who will play for El Salvador at Panama Sunday, Tampa Bay midfielder Carlos Valderrama, who will perform for Colombia at Ecuador Wednesday, Eduardo Hurtado, who will play for Ecuador, and United forward Jaime Moreno, a member of the Bolivian side that will visit Uruguay on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Tampa Bay defender Frank Yallop, the captain of the Canadian National Team, will miss games due to qualifiers against Cuba in Edmonton on Thursday and next Sunday (October 13). Los Angeles goalkeeper Jorge Campos, who will play for Mexico against Jamaica on October 16, isn't expected to miss any games.</p>
<p>The conference finals kickoff on Thursday, when Tampa Bay visits United and Kansas City plays at Los Angeles. The Mutiny will host United on Saturday, October 12, and for Game 3, if necessary on October  16. The Galaxy will host the Wiz on Sunday, Oct. 13 and, if necessary, on Thursday, October 17.</p>
<p>The winners will meet in a single-game matchup to determine the league's first champion -- MLS Cup '96 -- in Foxboro, Massachussets, on October 20.</p>
<p>Each of the four conference semifinal series went the full three games on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Roy Lassiter, the regular-season scoring champion, raised his playoff total to three with a goal in each half in the Mutiny's 4-1 triumph over the Columbus Crew in Tampa. Martin Vasquez and Steve Pittman also scored, while Brian McBride had Columbus' lone goal.</p>
<p>United edged the New York/New Jersey MetroStars on Raul Diaz Arce's penalty kick in the 89th minute in Washington, D.C., 2-1. Steve Rammel had give the home team the lead in the 65th minute, but Colombian Antony De Avila equalised with four minutes remaining.</p>
<p>Hurtado and Cienfuegos scored five minutes apart in the opening half to lift the Galaxy to a 2-0 win over the San Jose Clash in Pasadena, California, as Campos recorded the shutout.</p>
<p>The Wiz survived a shootout, outlasting the Burn in Dallas, 3-2. Frank Klopas, Paul Wright and Preki converted their attempts in the tie-breaker, as did Mexican Hugo Sanchez and Ricard Farrer theirs for Dallas. Mark Chung and Zimbabwean international Digital Takawira scored in regulation for the winners, Sanchez and Gerell Elliot for the Burn.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
