<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98071" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Turkey visit set to promote business with Nigeria.</title>
<headline>Turkey visit set to promote business with Nigeria.</headline>
<byline>James Jukwey</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commercial ties between Nigeria and Turkey should be significantly boosted by the controversial visit of Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan to the pariah African nation, officials and diplomats said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Addressing a technical session of their joint commission in the capital Abuja, the director-general of the foreign ministry Jibrin Chinade said Nigeria had proposed 14 areas of cooperation to raise the level of its economic relations with Turkey.</p>
<p>They included commerce and tourism, construction, agriculture, banking, health, free trade zones, transportation, telecommunications, gas and petrochemicals.</p>
<p>&quot;We need investment in each other's country, especially at the level of private sector operators,&quot; Chinade said.</p>
<p>Oil-rich Nigeria is shunned for alleged human rights abuses and its slow pace of democratisation by the West which has criticised the African tour that has taken the Turkish Islamist prime minister to Egypt and another pariah nation, Libya.</p>
<p>Turkish diplomats in Lagos said Erbakan was due to arrive in Nigeria on Sunday with a 250-strong team including the chief executives of several Turkish firms.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a historic visit and will be mutually beneficial commercially and culturally,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Trade between the two nations, currently insignificant at about 100 million naira ($1.25 million), is set to rise hugely in 1999 when Turkey will take annually $100 million worth of Nigerian liquefied natural gas (LNG) now under construction.</p>
<p>Nigerian officials said Erbakan would meet several senior ministers and also have an audience with military ruler General Sani Abacha on bilateral and international issues.</p>
<p>The West imposed token sanctions on Nigeria in 1993 when the then army rulers annulled a presidential election that would have restored democracy in Africa's most populous nation.</p>
<p>Relations worsened last November when Abacha's government defied international pleas for clemency and hanged nine minority rights activists including author Ken Saro-Wiwa found guilty of murder by a tribunal.</p>
<p>Contact with Nigeria and its officials were restricted but its main export crude oil remains unbanned with about half of it being imported by the United States.</p>
<p>Turkish diplomats said relations between Nigeria and Ankara have always been cordial and the prime minister's visit would further cement ties.</p>
<p>Erbakan would be the most senior official from the Western NATO alliance to visit Nigeria, which is not on the itinerary of U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher when he makes his first trip to black Africa next week.</p>
<p>While contact with the West has waned, Nigeria has forged alliances with Asian nations, principally China, which is backing multi-million dollar projects including the modernisation of Nigeria's railways.</p>
<p>Diplomats said during talks in the capital Abuja, Nigeria and Turkey try to revive a 1982 trade agreement and work out how to implement it for their mutual benefit.</p>
<p>They said a Nigerian-Turkish Business Council would also be established.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
