<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98163" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israelis, Palestinians prepare for fresh talks.</title>
<headline>Israelis, Palestinians prepare for fresh talks.</headline>
<byline>Danny Gur-arieh</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israelis and Palestinians prepared on Saturday for a resumption in talks interrupted by a wave of violence in the West Bank and Gaza Strip that threatened their delicate peace deal.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat arrived back in Gaza on Saturday, three days after an emergency Washington summit with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu which Palestinians described as a failure.</p>
<p>Asked about the chance for progress in the talks with Israel on Sunday, which PLO officials said would begin at 6 p.m. (1600 GMT), Arafat said: &quot;We have to wait and see.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not asking for the moon and we gave a new chance for peace,&quot; he told reporters outside his Gaza office as hundreds of supporters cheered his return.</p>
<p>Arafat arrived from Egypt after stops in Morocco, Tunisia, France and Italy. He was scheduled to brief members of his Palestinian Authority later on results of the summit U.S. President Bill Clinton convened to save Middle East peace talks.</p>
<p>In Cairo, Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa warned that the Middle East would be thrown into a crisis if Israel does not change its hardline stance in talks with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;Pessimism is the prevailing feeling in the area. The Washington talks, the decision to resume negotiations, the presence of the American side...all that behoves the Israelis to move and change their negative posture,&quot; Moussa told reporters after Arafat met Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak.</p>
<p>&quot;If not then it will be indeed be a very, very serious situation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The U.S.-sponsored peace process faced its biggest threat yet as violence erupted in the West Bank and Gaza last week when Israel opened a second entrance to an archaeological tunnel near a Moslem shrine. Clashes between Israeli soldiers and Palestinian police and civilians killed 73 people.</p>
<p>Israeli hardliners hailed Netanyahu for refusing to give Arafat concessions at the summit on the tunnel issue or set a date for Israel's promised redeployment of troops in Hebron.</p>
<p>The fate of Hebron, the last large West Bank town under Israeli occupation and the only Arab city with a Jewish settler population, was expected to head the agenda at Sunday's meeting.</p>
<p>The talks will be conducted at the Erez crossing between Israel and Gaza by members of an Israeli-Palestinian steering committe and mediated by U.S. Middle East envoy Dennis Ross. PLO officials said Arafat and Netanyahu would not take part.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christoper was expected to arrive in the region early on Sunday and meet separately with Netanyahu and Arafat before the talks begin.</p>
<p>On the ground, top Israeli and Palestinian officers toured the Gaza Strip together on Friday trying to forge a new working relationship after pointing their guns at one another in the clashes but the two sides quickly locked horns in a dispute over turf.</p>
<p>Israel announed after the joint tour that Palestinians had agreed to establish 300 metre (yard)-deep buffer zones around Israeli outposts in the Gaza Strip which demonstrators would be barred from entering.</p>
<p>A PLO security chief said Israel was lying.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no buffer zone. These are Israeli lies and Israeli illusions. This matter is totally rejected,&quot; said Major Abdel Razek al-Majaydeh, general-director of Palestinian security forces in Gaza.</p>
<p>Joint Israeli-Palestinian patrols have ground to a halt in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, in areas where Jewish settlements and Israeli soldiers remain pending a final accord. But a PLO security official in Jenin said on Friday joint patrols would resume in the West Bank town on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
