<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98169" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iran seizes 1,500 kg of drugs, arrests smugglers.</title>
<headline>Iran seizes 1,500 kg of drugs, arrests smugglers.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran said on Saturday it had seized over 840 kg (1,850 lb) of opium and 690 kg (1,520 lb) of other narcotics from drug traffickers.</p>
<p>&quot;Some 841 kgs of opium and a large amount of ammunition were seized from smugglers in the eastern deserts of the country over the past couple of days,&quot; Iran's official news agency IRNA said.</p>
<p>&quot;In another operation which involved armed clashes with the smugglers in the Salehabad and Torbat-e Jam area of Khorasan (north-eastern Iran), 690 kg of narcotics were confiscated and leading gang members arrested over the past few days,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>According to Iranian law, possession of five kg (11 lb) of opium or 30 grammes (just over one ounce) of heroin is punishable by death. More than 1,000 people have been executed in drug-related cases since the law took effect in 1989.</p>
<p>Iran is a key transit route for drugs, mostly opium from which heroin is made, being smuggled to Europe via Turkey from Afghanistan and Pakistan -- the so-called &quot;Golden Crescent&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
