<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98185" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Mubarak says regional peace in Israel's hands.</title>
<headline>Mubarak says regional peace in Israel's hands.</headline>
<byline>Miral Fahmy</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Hosni Mubarak said on Saturday Egypt's armed forces were necessary to maintain security in the region and there could only be real peace when Israel abided by treaties it signed with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>In a nationwide address on the anniversary of Egypt's October 1973 war against Israel, which led to a 1979 peace deal with the Jewish state, Mubarak also lauded his armed forces for recent manoeuvres that irked Israel but said he hoped there would not be any more Arab-Israeli conflicts.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that the October War is the last because wars spell destruction... but peace is not made nor does its roots flourish in the absence of the principles of equality that have been drafted by the international community,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no peace without abiding by treaties that were signed and witnessed by the whole world in the (1991) Madrid peace conference and a real will to implement them without exceptions,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Since he was elected in May on a plaform rejecting the &quot;land for peace&quot; principle of the Madrid accord, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has procrastinated on peace pledges made by previous governments, delaying a troop withdrawal from Hebron in the Palestinian self-rule West Bank due to security concerns.</p>
<p>Egypt, host of many rounds of negotiations, has repeatedly called on the Jewish state to implement its peace pledges.</p>
<p>But Mubarak did not attend this week's emergency summit in Washington because of what he called Israeli intransigence.</p>
<p>&quot;We are living in a region that is still liable to a lot of dangers that subject it to a lot of threats...It is a kind of self-delusion to rely on good intentions,&quot; Mubarak said.</p>
<p>&quot;History has taught Egypt to maintain a strong and able army -- not for making war or for aggression but to ensure peace and stability.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Egypt is the cornerstone of regional stability and its security is ransom to Egypt's ability to protect itself... we need a strong defence force that enables us to fulfill this vital role,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Egyptian Defence Minister Mohammed Tantawi said his forces could deal with an Israeli attack using nuclear or other weapons of mass destruction and the military manoeuvres -- codenamed Badr 96 -- included crossing the Suez Canal from west to east, similar to the operation which launched the 1973 war.</p>
<p>Israeli media said last month Netanyahu's defence team had been debating the significance of these exercises, the largest since 1993.</p>
<p>Mubarak also said he hoped there would be significant progress in peace negotiations between the Palestinians and Israel before an economic summit scheduled for November in Cairo which aims at including Israel in the regional economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Real movement in the peace track... revives hope of the people in the region and sets the stage for real regional cooperation,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
