<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98196" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Qatar says ties with Israel on hold.</title>
<headline>Qatar says ties with Israel on hold.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar, which has moved faster than any other Gulf state to forge economic ties with Israel, has put further normalisation with the Jewish state on hold, its foreign affairs minister said in remarks published on Saturday.</p>
<p>Sheikh Hamad bin Jassim bin Jabr al-Thani told the al-Hayat newspaper that relations with Israel were &quot;on hold.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There is a postponement in opening a (Qatari) trade office in Israel and there is a postponement in any meetings or direct contacts between us and Israel,&quot; he said in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we have stopped any activities with Israel,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Oman and Qatar have forged ahead of other Gulf states in establishing economic ties with Israel but have stopped short of diplomatic relations pending the resolution of all Arab-Israeli conflicts.</p>
<p>They are the only two states in the region that have allowed Israel to set up trade missions.</p>
<p>An 18-member group of Qatari private merchants was due to tour Israel in the third week of October to explore joint ventures in agriculture, power, mineral water and petrochemicals.</p>
<p>Israel's hardline Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu angered Qatar and other Arab states by challenging the key priciple of land-for-peace and not carrying out some measures agreed under the Palestinians and the previous Israeli government.</p>
<p>Sheikh Hamad said Netanyahu &quot;had no long-term strategy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
