<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98212" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole says he's ready for Clinton debate.</title>
<headline>Dole says he's ready for Clinton debate.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>BAL HARBOUR, Florida 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>After turning for advice to ex-President George Bush, the only Republican to debate Bill Clinton, Bob Dole said on Saturday he was ready for the opening presidential debate.</p>
<p>Dole joked to reporters in a brief photo-call that all he had to do to win Sunday's debate in Hartford, Connecticut -- an encounter aides hope will turn the tide in a lopsided presidential race -- was &quot;show up&quot;.</p>
<p>When asked if he was nervous, he said, &quot;Me?&quot; and then shook his hand in a mock tremor.</p>
<p>Dole spokesman Nelson Warfield said Bush flew in on a private plane from Houston to offer Dole tips on how to debate Clinton, a man the Republican campaign has painted as a brilliant, masterful, wily debater.</p>
<p>Bush sat with Dole and his wife Elizabeth at a poolside table at the Doles' condominium. They discussed Bush's experiences debating Clinton three times in the 1992 campaign, debates that the public deemed Clinton won.</p>
<p>In one debate Bush looked at his watch as if he wanted to get out as quickly as he could.</p>
<p>The ex-president diplomatically said he had no tips to offer Dole, adding, &quot;He knows the issues inside out. He'll do well.&quot; Bush said of his own debate experience with Clinton, &quot;I thought I did well, but maybe I didn't.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole said he had pretty much finished his preparations. &quot;You reach a point where you just stop. It's just like filling up your tank with gas. It only holds so much.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole has spent more than a week preparing for the debate that could be watched by up to 100 million Americans and possibly change his standings in the polls where he trails Clinton by between 11 and 25 points.</p>
<p>His long hours of preparation are in marked contrast to 1976, when as Republican vice presidential candidate he debated Democrat Walter Mondale and made the gaffe of his public speaking career, a comment some blamed on his having assumed he could just waltz in and talk to the TV cameras.</p>
<p>In that debate, Dole, then a senator from Kansas, talked of &quot;Democrat wars this century that cost 1.6 million lives.&quot; It was a comment that Mondale jumped on, calling Dole a &quot;hatchet man,&quot; and many thought it gave the Democrats a major edge in a close race.</p>
<p>Warfield said a very different Dole would be on display on Sunday. &quot;There has been a constant effort to demonise Bob Dole, and the man who is going to appear before 100 million viewers tomorrow is going to appear as he is: very warm, very affable, very funny and I think that will have a major impact on the race.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the debate would place Dole and Clinton on a level playing field. &quot;Just by appearing on the same stage with the President ... in the public's mind, it casts the race as even.&quot;</p>
<p>Warfield said the campaign hoped the polls would tighten after the debate and Clinton lose his double-digit lead.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAL HARBOUR, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
