<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98252" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal rightist leader tightens grip on party.</title>
<headline>Portugal rightist leader tightens grip on party.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portugal's main opposition Social Democratic Party (PSD) on Saturday sanctioned internal reforms put forward by leader Marcelo Rebelo de Sousa, who had staked his leadership on their approval.</p>
<p>At an extraordinary congress in Lisbon, Rebelo de Sousa won an overwhelming 77.5 percent of votes in favour of reforming party statutes, PSD officials said.</p>
<p>He also won a public endorsement from rival Pedro Santana Lopes, a former culture minister, after appealing for party unity in order to win next year's local elections on the path to general elections due in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;This country needs a strong opposition,&quot; Rebelo de Sousa said.</p>
<p>Socialist Prime Minister Antonio Guterres, attending a summit of European Union (EU) leaders in Dublin, praised his opponent's breakthrough.</p>
<p>&quot;We need stable politics in Portugal,&quot; he told a radio reporter.</p>
<p>&quot;Both the Socialist Party (PS) and the PSD must move forward to promote Portugal's participation in an integrated Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>TSF radio's political commentator Carlos Magno said: &quot;Marcelo deserves high marks. He has strengthened his leadership.&quot;</p>
<p>The Socialist victory in general elections a year ago after the 10-year premiership of the PSD's Anibal Cavaco Silva led to a crisis in the right wing.</p>
<p>The centre-right PSD has struggled to overcome internecine rivalries and to define its policies as it adapted to opposition, political analysts said.</p>
<p>Manuel Monteiro, leader of the smaller Popular Party (PP), which is unenthusiastic about closer integration with Europe, announced his resignation last month after criticism of his leadership from a hardline &quot;Eurosceptical&quot; rival, Paulo Portas.</p>
<p>Unlike the PP, the PS and PSD both seek Portugal's entry to a planned European single currency in 1999.</p>
<p>Rebelo de Sousa, a fast-talking former political commentator who has led the PSD for six months following the resignation of Fernando Nogueira, had said his continuing leadership of the party would depend on the approval of the party reforms.</p>
<p>Nogueira, a close ally of Cavaco Silva, stepped down as leader of the PSD after losing the general election to Guterres.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
