<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98293" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: World ignoring Peruvian rights abuses-Vargas Llosa.</title>
<headline>World ignoring Peruvian rights abuses-Vargas Llosa.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novelist Mario Vargas Llosa, famed for his abortive bid for the Peruvian presidency, on Saturday accused the international community of indifference to continuing human rights abuses in his native country.</p>
<p>Speaking at the Frankfurt Book Fair, where he is to be awarded the German book industry's prestigious Peace Prize, Vargas Llosa described the Peruvian regime under President Alberto Fujimori as authoritarian and deeply corrupt.</p>
<p>Deflected by Peru's attempts to attract investment and bring its economy under control, &quot;the international community ... is not paying attention to the dark, sinister aspects of the dictatorship&quot;, Vargas Llosa told reporters.</p>
<p>Peru is among several South American countries being monitored for human rights abuses by Amnesty International, which says 4,200 people who &quot;disappeared&quot; in the country in recent years remain unaccounted for.</p>
<p>Vargas Llosa, now 60 and dividing his time between London and Spain, said he had no more personal political ambitions after losing Peru's 1990 presidential elections to the unknown Fujimori.</p>
<p>&quot;I learned (from that) that I am an inept politician. I will stay doing what I do now, which is writing. Of course I believe that to be a writer is inseparable from a certain participation in political debate.&quot;</p>
<p>Vargas Llosa, who recently made a trip to Sarajevo, also denounced the rise of &quot;nationalism driven by hate and fear&quot; in the world, particularly in Europe, and criticised the European Union for failing to act to resolve the Bosnian crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;The European Union was supposed to be a remedy for misunderstandings and war, yet when it had to face its first crisis, it was totally inept,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only are there 200,000 dead and innumerable casualties, but this is the eternalisation of a problem...that can reproduce itself in other countries for exactly the same reasons.&quot;</p>
<p>Vargas Llosa, a long-established champion of democracy, has written 25 books and received many major international prizes.</p>
<p>Explaining its decision to award him Germany's top literature prize, the German Book Traders' Association said it wished to recognise Vargas Llosa's efforts to foster a &quot;culture of freedom&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
