<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98316" id="root" date="1996-10-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan Taleban scoff at CIS concerns.</title>
<headline>Afghan Taleban scoff at CIS concerns.</headline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kabul's new purist Islamic rulers scoffed on Saturday at concerns voiced by the Confederation of Independent States (CIS) over their sweep to power over much of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very happy that God has given this much pomp and credit to the Taleban that a big power is afraid of the Taleban,&quot; acting information minister Amir Jan Mutaqi told a news conference.</p>
<p>Five leaders of former Soviet republics, alarmed by the rise of the Taleban, ended a summit in Almaty on Friday with an appeal to the rival groups to hold talks and for the United Nations to discuss the situation.</p>
<p>&quot;We call upon all warring parties to stop hostilities and resume peace negotiations,&quot; Kazakh President Nursultan Nazarbayev had said in a joint news conference.</p>
<p>The Almaty summit was attended by the presidents of Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan, Tajikistan and Kyrgyzstan, and by Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin.</p>
<p>It was called to discuss possible steps if the Taleban were to advance north to the southern borders of the CIS, a loose 12-member grouping formed as the Soviet Union collapsed in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia has no more the talent or the capacity in this kind of action. (Russian President Boris) Yeltsin is himself sick and is not able to do anything,&quot; Mutaqi said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Russian people have not forgotten their past experience in Afghanistan and I think they won't dare to repeat that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The CIS had criticised the &quot;executions and human rights violations&quot; being committed in the war-ravaged nation.</p>
<p>Among those killed when the Taleban seized Kabul last month was former Moscow-backed Afghan president Najibullah, a communist installed as leader in 1987 during the 10-year Soviet occupation of the country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
