<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98357" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-PERUGIA MUZZLE TEAM AFTER RUMBLINGS OF MUTINY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PERUGIA MUZZLE TEAM AFTER RUMBLINGS OF MUTINY.</headline>
<dateline>PERUGIA, Italy 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serie A newcomers Perugia muzzled their players on Sunday after rumblings of mutiny following their Italian Cup defeat by a part-time side.</p>
<p>A statement from the struggling club said the news blackout had been decided following &quot;continual controversial statements which have appeared in certain newspapers&quot;.</p>
<p>It said only owner Luciano Gaucci was authorised to talk to the media and that it hoped the blackout would restore peace.</p>
<p>Perugia, promoted to the first division last season but lying fourth from bottom with just three points from four matches, crashed out of the second round of the cup last Wednesday 2-1 at home to serie C Nocerina.</p>
<p>The defeat denied Perugia a lucrative tie against European Cup holders Juventus and earned manager Giovanni Galeone a warning from Gaucci that he would be sacked if his record did not improve.</p>
<p>The players were also sent on a punitive training retreat ahead of next weekend's league match against Atalanta. One of them, Massimiliano Allegri, was expelled from the retreat on Friday after criticising the club's approach.</p>
<p>The team issued a statement on Saturday defending Allegri and saying they shared his views.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERUGIA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
