<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98415" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: HORSE RACING-HELISSIO STORMS TO FIVE LENGTH ARC GLORY.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-HELISSIO STORMS TO FIVE LENGTH ARC GLORY.</headline>
<byline>Dave Thompson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Helissio, ridden by rising star Olivier Peslier, stormed to a five-length victory in Sunday's Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe in one of the most impressive performances in the history of the race.</p>
<p>Helissio made virtually all the running in the 12-furlong (2.4 kms) test and when Peslier pressed the accelerator with 300 metres to go the colt responded in the fashion of a true champion.</p>
<p>He quickly sprinted clear of the 15-strong field and could have won by more had Peslier not eased down in the closing metres to salute the crowd and his excellent partner.</p>
<p>It was still the biggest winning distance in the race since 1965, when Sea-Bird won by six lengths.</p>
<p>Second at a respectable distance came Pilsudski, the mount of Walter Swinburn, just clear of the fast finishing Irish raider Oscar Schindler, ridden by American Cash Asmussen.</p>
<p>Peslier, 22, and currently leading the French jockeys' title race said: &quot;I never had a moment's doubt. It was like a morning workout. I just gave him one flick (of the whip) and that was it.&quot;</p>
<p>Helissio, a three-year-old colt, started favourite on the strength of some excellent form this season, marred only by a disappointing run in the French Derby under Dominique Boeuf.</p>
<p>But since Peslier has taken over, the horse has done nothing wrong and on Sunday's performance a glittering future looks assured.</p>
<p>Plans for his next race are currently on hold while the possible purchase by Japanese interests is discussed.</p>
<p>No other horse got in a blow at the winner. Pilsudski, a group one winner in Germany last time out, raced with Helissio for most of the trip but at the business end of the race he could only plug on for second place.</p>
<p>Oscar Schindler, the Irish St Leger winner, came with an exceedingly late run in the final 200 metres to grab third place, a length clear of Swain, the mount of French champion Thierry Jarnet.</p>
<p>English raider Pentire, winner of the King George VI and Queen Elizabeth Diamond Stakes at Ascot in July, found, as expected, the ground a little too soft for his liking and could only finish 10th.</p>
<p>His jockey, Michael Hills, said: &quot;The winner had the race under control from seven furlongs (1.4 kms) out.&quot;</p>
<p>Classic Cliche, last year's English St Leger winner and the mount of all conquering Frankie Dettori, raced prominently in the early stages but faded turning into the straight and, as anticipated, found the trip too short.</p>
<p>Epsom Derby winner Shaamit, ridden by Pat Eddery, looked to be involved in a barging match early on but recovered to finish a respectable seventh without ever threatening the winner.</p>
<p>Zagreb, who won the Irish Derby in impressive fashion at the end of June, was fourth for much of the race but his challenge faded in the final two furlongs (400 metres) and was done no favours by Oscar Schindler, who burst through for his late challenge and who appeared to hamper Zagreb.</p>
<p>Outsider Polaris Flight fell soon after turning into the straight but jockey John Reid escaped with a shaking.</p>
<p>However the horse broke a leg and had to be destroyed, much to the distress of trainer Peter Chapple-Hyam.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
