<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98439" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WALL ST WEEK AHEAD - The economy - Too slow too soon?.</title>
<headline>WALL ST WEEK AHEAD - The economy - Too slow too soon?.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>With the Dow Industrials within a hair's breadth of 6000, the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index finally surpassing a psychologically critical milestone and long-term interest rates apparently headed lower, the outlook for stocks has suddenly turned...cautious.</p>
<p>Last Friday's surprisingly weak employment report, which saw U.S. payrolls decline by 40,000, convinced many economists the Fed would refrain from raising interest rates at its November meeting. The bond market soared.</p>
<p>Stocks followed suit, with the S&amp;P 500 topping 700 points for the first time in its history and the Dow 30 rallying more than 50 points to finish a whisker below 6000.  </p>
<p>However, market analysts were nearly unanimous in warning that on this occasion, what was good news for the bond market represented a mixed blessing at best for stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is does the payrolls number really equate to a slowing down in the third quarter and does that mean that corporate earnings will be lower,&quot; said Robert Froehlich, chief investment strategist at Van Kampen American Capital.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether we go through 6000 or back to 5500 is going to depend on earnings,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The renewed focus on profits is partly a function of the reporting cycle. Quarterly reporting is slated to begin in earnest next week, with banks traditionally first to file.  </p>
<p>While Wall Street favors a low interest rate environment, the manner in which one is being achieved -- an  economy that seems suddenly to be slowing more quickly than expected -- is less than ideal for stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't get away from the possibility that in a slowing economy, earnings will also slow,&quot; said Peggy Farley, chief executive at Amas Securities. &quot;I'm a little worried that the market may be forecasting stronger third quarter earnings than are possible.&quot;</p>
<p>That stocks were able to participate in Friday's rally failed to convince analysts that the apparently tamer inflation outlook would fuel a sustained stocks rally.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are two kinds of markets -- one that anticipates and one that reacts,&quot; said Richard Cripps, chief market strategist at Legg Mason Wood Walker. &quot;Friday's move was reactive and usually gains that are reactive are not as powerful.&quot;</p>
<p>One indication companies may be bracing for a downturn may be the shrinking rate of dividend increases.</p>
<p>According to Standard &amp; Poor's Outlook, an investment advisory news letter, September marked the second straight month of year-to-year declines in the number of dividend increases reported to Standard &amp; Poor's.</p>
<p>&quot;The slowdown in dividend increases may mean that companies are conserving cash out of fear that profits will level off in 1997,&quot; Outlook editor Arnold Kaufman said.  </p>
<p>Among the Dow 30, AT&amp;T Corp and Aluminum Co of America have already warned about or reported disappointing earnings.</p>
<p>While caution flags have been raised on the market, analysts stopped short of calling for a selloff like July's.</p>
<p>&quot;This market has had a huge run since the July lows so I would not disagree that it would level off here,&quot; Cripps said, &quot;but I don't think we'll go much lower unless people get disillusioned with stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>Bonds remain an uninspiring alternative, analysts said, because yields have worked their way so low.</p>
<p>Another sign of mounting earnings concern is that the worries have all but eclipsed the presidential election as a topic of interest on Wall Street, perhaps in part because many view the outcome of the election as a foregone conclusion.</p>
<p>As such, less attention is being paid to such topics as which sectors might thrive under which candidate. But analysts cited one sector that could serve as a barometer for prospects for Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole.</p>
<p>&quot;If you want to know how well Bob Dole did in the debate on Sunday, look at the tobacco stocks on Monday,&quot; said Froehlich.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
