<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98636" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian entrepreneur plans huge media business.</title>
<headline>Indonesian entrepreneur plans huge media business.</headline>
<byline>Raju Gopalakrishnan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peter Gontha is often called Indonesia's Rupert Murdoch.</p>
<p>With plans for a 40-channel satellite television network and newly-purchased control of an English-language newspaper plus existing links to four radio stations, an Indonesian-language daily and a local television channel, comparisons between Gontha and the Australian-born tycoon are perhaps inevitable.</p>
<p>Gontha, a trim, balding 48-year-old, laughs away the suggestion and will only say his involvement with the media business springs from a love for music.</p>
<p>&quot;I love music very much, I love entertainment very much. It really came from the love of music and entertaining people,&quot; he said of his extensive media holdings during an interview on Friday in his office.</p>
<p>Photographs of Gontha with U.S. President Bill Clinton and former president Ronald Reagan are on display, and a copy of &quot;The Fourth Estate,&quot; a Jeffrey Archer novel drawing much from Murdoch and late media baron Robert Maxwell, lies on his desk.</p>
<p>&quot;I just believe in one thing: 195 million people need entertainment when their primary needs are fulfilled,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gontha's Indovision satellite TV network will air 40 channels, including American soaps, sports, news and Indonesian launguage movies, all across the archipelago when its own Indostar satellite is launched in June next year.</p>
<p>Until then, it will use the Palapa-C satellite to broadcast at least 18 channels starting from December. These will include Murdoch's Star TV channels, BBC news, Turner Broadcasting's Cable News Network and TNT, the Home Box Office movie channel and others.</p>
<p>A soft launch of six or seven channels, to be digitally delivered, is scheduled for later this month. These will exist side-by-side with Indovision's current network, which works on an analogue platform offering CNN, HBO, the Discovery channel and sports channel ESPN.</p>
<p>Gontha entered the newspaper world last month when he bought the Indonesian Observer, the country's oldest English-language newspaper that has a circulation of only about 5,000.</p>
<p>A re-launch is planned for January with fresh funds, and Gontha projects a quick rise to a circulation of about 15,000-20,000, challenging the market leader, the Jakarta Post.</p>
<p>&quot;I want a very constructive English newspaper,&quot; he said. &quot;Newspapers are not very balanced right now. I just believe in responsible journalism.&quot;</p>
<p>He dismissed suggestions that his close links with President Suharto's family could affect credibility.</p>
<p>&quot;Look at how Seputera Indonesia has developed. It is the front-runner of democracy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Seputera Indonesia, or Across Indonesia, is a relatively frank current affairs programme broadcast by Rajawali Citra Televisi Indonesia (RCTI), a television station owned by the Bimantara Group, in which Gontha is a partner.</p>
<p>Suharto's son Bambang Trihatmodjo controls Bimantara, and he invited Gontha, then a senior officer with a U.S. bank, to join the group in 1983.</p>
<p>They knew each other well, Gontha says, because the two families were neighbours in the 1960s. The relationship has progressed well, he says.</p>
<p>&quot;Bambang would have been successful without me. I was already a vice-president in charge of the whole of Asia. So we pooled our resources together,&quot; he said of charges that his success has been overshadowed by links with the first family.</p>
<p>Despite also owning parts of four radio stations with plans to add a fifth, Gontha says he spends only about a quarter of his time on the media business.</p>
<p>He prefers to concentrate on the privately-owned Chandra Asri petrochemical firm, of which he is the chief executive officer, and relax at the jazz club he owns, Jamz.</p>
<p>&quot;Jazz, that's it, that's my relaxation,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
