<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98639" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China says foreigners to sell oil at world prices.</title>
<headline>China says foreigners to sell oil at world prices.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>China is to allow some foreign-invested onshore oilfields due to go into production next year to sell their oil at world market prices from early 1997, the China Daily Business Weekly said on Sunday.  </p>
<p>&quot;China's intention to keep its oil market tightly regulated until the year 1999 may be facing a stiff challenge as incentive systems begin to take effect,&quot; the newspaper said.</p>
<p>The relaxation on prices as part of a preferential policy system to onshore investors, means the creation of a three-tier oil pricing system for onshore fields, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Oil from China's onshore fields currently sells for prices averaging 300 yuan ($36) below the world market price per tonne, it said.</p>
<p>The first project expected to benefit will be a project near the Bohai Bay involving ACL China Ltd of the U.S., it said.  </p>
<p>China's onshore oil industry last year pumped 140 million tonnes, or 93 percent of total output, and a small increase was expected for 1996.</p>
<p>In the first half of this year, China imported 10.9 million tonnes of crude, up by 56 percent compared with the year ago period, the newspaper said. Imports of oil products were 6.9 million tonnes in the first half, up 31 percent.</p>
<p>Exports of crude oil in the first half were 8.5 million tonnes, down by 3.3 percent while exports of oil products fell 16 percent to 1.7 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The reform of the oil pricing system will become urgent as more major refineries and petrochemical projects come on line, many using only imported crude, the newspaper said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
