<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98677" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>OMAN: Oman says gas export project to India is off.</title>
<headline>Oman says gas export project to India is off.</headline>
<dateline>MUSCAT 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oman on Sunday said it was not willing to go ahead with a $5 billion gas export deal with India, citing financial and technological problems with the proposed deep sea gas pipeline project.</p>
<p>&quot;Oman is not willing to spend more money on this project and we feel it is economically unfeasible,&quot; Oman's Commerce and Industry Minister Makboul bin Ali bin Sultan told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The obstacles facing the gas pipeline between the sultanate and India...in addition to the money that has been spent on the feasibility study, has prevented the implementation of this project,&quot; bin Sultan said at a news conference in Muscat.</p>
<p>Bin Sultan's comments appeared to scotch the pipeline plan which would have initially exported one billion cubic feet a day of Omani gas to India from 1999. &quot;There are no investors willing to invest in this project and all of the contracting companies have asked Oman to guarantee the entire project whose cost in the first phase is $5 billion which will reach $10 billion at the end of the second phase,&quot; the commerce minister said.</p>
<p>The countries signed a memorandum of understanding in 1993 to study the project which would stretch a twin pipeline 1,300 km (800 miles) from Ra's al Jifan in Oman through the Arabian Sea to Rapar Gadhwali in the western India state of Gujarat.</p>
<p>Parts of the pipeline would be submerged in water depths of more than 3,000 metres (10,000 feet) which would have made it the deepest pipeline in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;From the technical side there were many issues that were not completed,&quot; bin Sultan said.</p>
<p>He said Oman has informed the Indian government of its decision.</p>
<p>Oman has already spent $70 million on feasibilty studies, he said, adding: &quot;Oman is not ready to spend any more money on this project.&quot;</p>
<p>A working group of experts from Oman and India were to form last month to study the pipeline.</p>
<p>The sultanate is already involved in a $6 billion liquefied natural gas (LNG) project which is expected to begin exports of LNG to Asia in the first quarter of the year 2000.</p>
<p>-- Bombay Newsroom +91-22-265-9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUSCAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="OMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
