<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98717" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Russia nuclear disarmament not assured - Gorbachev.</title>
<headline>Russia nuclear disarmament not assured - Gorbachev.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Croft</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev said on Sunday that if countries played &quot;new geopolitical games,&quot; efforts to reduce nuclear arms in Russia could suffer.</p>
<p>Stressing that he wanted to see post-Cold War arms reduction continue, Gorbachev said during a debate in San Francisco that the international community was failing to take advantage of tremendous opportunities.</p>
<p>&quot;The disappearance of the Soviet Union from the geopolitical arena has created a new situation, and I am afraid that some are trying to play new geopolitical games,&quot; Gorbachev said, in an apparent allusion to the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;If that happens, then the process of nuclear disarmament in Russia will be very difficult, including ratification of START II,&quot; he said, referring to the pending strategic arms reduction treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;If we hear from the United States that military budgets here could grow, if ballistic missile defences will be created here in this country, if NATO expands to the east, then in Russia people are beginning to think: 'What's happening? Is it a return to the past?'&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gorbachev spoke during a debate on nuclear disarmament and other issues that closed the &quot;State of the World Forum,&quot; a five-day conference on international issues organised by the Gorbachev Foundation USA.</p>
<p>The debate, in which Haitian former President Jean Bertrand Aristide, Israeli former Foreign Minister Abba Eban and several other current and former officials took part, was broadcast live outside the United States by BBC World Television.</p>
<p>Gloria Duffy, a former deputy assistant defence secretary in Washington, said there was no question that terrorists and rogue states were trying to obtain nuclear weapons and other weapons of mass destruction, such as chemical and biological arms.</p>
<p>She said the United States removed enough nuclear material from Kazakhstan for 20 nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>&quot;But Iran had been there before us, looking around, as they are in many areas, to obtain the material for nuclear weapons. This is a true danger. There is enough nuclear material in the former Soviet Union for the equivalent of 100,000 Hiroshima and Nagasaki-sized bombs,&quot; Duffy said.</p>
<p>&quot;We can abolish nuclear weapons, but we can't abolish their components and the material in them that can be used to make new nuclear weapons,&quot; she said. The United States and Russia, as well as the rest of the international community, should cooperate in combating the problem, she added.</p>
<p>Richard Butler, Australia's permanent representative to the United Nations, said the United States and Russia had made quite good progress in recent years in reducing nuclear weapons and must continue. &quot;If they do not continue, we will face a terrible price in the major developing countries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Eban said the recently signed international treaty against nuclear testing should be implemented and its scope broadened to include other countries, &quot;including India, for example, who have not yet found it possible to adhere.&quot;</p>
<p>Aristide said leaders negotiating disarmament agreements should think about the &quot;millions and millions of people asking for peace, dying for peace,&quot; and &quot;move ahead building a new world of peace.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
