<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98741" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OCC to consider pending US bank proposals - Ludwig.</title>
<headline>OCC to consider pending US bank proposals - Ludwig.</headline>
<dateline>HONOLULU 1996-10-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Comptroller of the Currency Eugene Ludwig said Saturday he expects decisions will be made in coming weeks on pending proposals aimed at increasing the competitiveness of the U.S. banking industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We have taken those plans off the shelf, dusted them off, and reexamined them,&quot; he said in a speech to the American Bankers Association convention. &quot;And I'm confident that decisions will be made on those plans within the next few weeks,&quot; the bank regulator added.</p>
<p>William Grant, director of banking relations at the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC), later told reporters Ludwig was referring to proposed bank insurance sales guidelines and interpretation of the &quot;town of 5,000&quot; rule related to insurance activities that a bank can conduct if it has an office in a small town.</p>
<p>Ludwig was also referring to a proposal first aired nearly two years ago about what activities are permissible for banks through their operating subsidiaries, Grant said.</p>
<p>The OCC has not specified any activities, and the intention of that proposal was to consider applications on a &quot;bank-by- bank basis&quot; rather than issue a blanket rule related to operating subsidiaries, Grant said.  </p>
<p>&quot;What people are afraid of is the OCC would just make a blanket statement saying banks can do all these kinds of things in their operating subsidiaries, and that's not true,&quot; Grant said. &quot;Any application that would be made, if we decided to do something like that, would be looked at on a bank-by-bank basis,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONOLULU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
