<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98773" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France says Europe must have say on Mideast.</title>
<headline>France says Europe must have say on Mideast.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>France said on Sunday that the European Union must have a bigger role in promoting diplomatic efforts to achieve Middle East peace.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Herve de Charette, speaking after an EU summit in Dublin, told France-3 television: &quot;Europe showed in Dublin that it had things to say. President Jacques Chirac and I had to insist because for the first time there was a demand.&quot;</p>
<p>In the past weeks, he added, &quot;not only has nothing happened (on the peace process), but people have taken a step backwards.&quot;</p>
<p>France had earlier expressed irritation that the Europeans were left out of last week's Washington talks involving Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasse Arafat.</p>
<p>EU leaders decided in Dublic to send Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring, whose country now holds the EU presidency, to Israel. He was expected to meet Netanyahu later on Sunday and would probably have talks with Arafat, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Spring must express the European stance,&quot; de Charette said. &quot;The peace process must be relaunched and the only way to do that is to act on what has been agreed and to be very attentive to Israel's security concerns.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
