<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98775" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: China dissident's sister seeks UN action on rights.</title>
<headline>China dissident's sister seeks UN action on rights.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sister of jailed Chinese dissident Wei Jingsheng urged the United Nations on Sunday to persist in attempts to pass a resolution censuring China for its human rights record.</p>
<p>Last April, China succeeded for the sixth year running in averting a U.S.-sponsored draft resolution in the U.N.'s 53-nation Human Rights Commission over its rights record.</p>
<p>&quot;I find it incredible that this has been going on for six years without result,&quot; Wei Shanshan told Reuters at the Frankfurt Book Fair, where she is promoting a book by her brother entitled My Life for Democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;Soft diplomacy does not have any effect on a hard, dictatorial government like the Chinese. There is a need for a joint action, on a European level or from the United Nations.&quot;</p>
<p>Wei Jingsheng, viewed as one of the fathers of China's struggling democracy movement, last December began a 14-year jail term, his second lengthy prison term, for allegedly plotting against the Chinese government.</p>
<p>His fragile health has given his family's campaign for his freedom added urgency. Wei Shanshan said her brother had suffered several heart attacks since being imprisoned as well as continual verbal harassment from the six prisoners with whom he has shared a cell since June.</p>
<p>While expressing gratitude for the support offered by European governments for human rights in China, especially by Germany, Wei Shanshan, who has lived in Hamburg for the past six years, said tougher action was needed.</p>
<p>Buoyant business with the international community had left Chinese authorities confident they did not need to change their human rights policies to secure investments, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was some increased openness in China from 1992 to 1994 (during which Wei Jingsheng enjoyed a six-month period of freedom) but I think that has ended now,&quot; Wei Shanshan said.</p>
<p>Germany, China's biggest European trading partner with annual bilateral trade of some 27 billion marks ($17.6 billion), has just ended a diplomatic spat with Beijing over its Tibet policy.</p>
<p>&quot;I know many German businessmen and what I hear again and again is that the human rights issue does not harm their business. But if they want a long-term business arrangement, they need a stable political environment.&quot;</p>
<p>Wei Shanshan, who says she hopes eventually to return to live in China, is currently working on a book about her family to be published in English next year.</p>
<p>She welcomed China's release last week of Tong Yi, Wei Jingsheng's former secretary, who had served a 2 1/2 year term of &quot;re-education through labour&quot; because of her links with her mentor, but said Tong had been treated very harshly.</p>
<p>&quot;She was beaten badly but she still says she will continue to work for my brother,&quot; Wei Shanshan said.</p>
<p>Wei Jingsheng was first imprisoned in 1979 for &quot;counter-revolutionary incitement&quot; during the Democracy Wall movement, an eruption of public criticism of the ruling Communists.</p>
<p>China paroled Wei in September 1993, in what was a seen as an attempt to win overseas support for Beijing's bid to stage the 2000 Olympics, but vanished into legal limbo in April 1994 and was convicted in December 1995 of financing the Chinese democracy movement.</p>
<p>The latest conviction provoked international outrage, but Beijing responded by rebuking foreign countries for meddling in its domestic affairs.</p>
<p>Wei Shanshan said her brother would almost certainly remain in China to continue his fight for democracy, should he be released. &quot;That is simply his way. He has a feeling for everyone else that he has proved through his support for other dissidents, a very strong sympathy,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
