<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98839" id="root" date="1996-10-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka opposition urges prisoner swap.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka opposition urges prisoner swap.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-10-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lankan opposition leader Ranil Wickremasinghe has urged the government to consider exchanging three captured Tamil rebels for 22 members of the security forces in guerrilla custody, his spokesman said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Wickremasinghe, a former prime minister heading the main opposition United National Party (UNP), wrote to Deputy Defence Minister Anuruddha Ratwatte after he received a letter signed by the 22 prisoner, the spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>The prisoners said in their letter, which was made public, that Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam rebels offered them freedom in exchange for three guerrillas held by the military, including two women.</p>
<p>Among the 22 was a naval officer captured by the Tigers when they sank his patrol vessel in a suicide attack in late 1994, on the eve of abortive peace talks with the government.</p>
<p>&quot;In the event the letter is found to be genuine I would suggest that you decide on this case after factoring in its intrinsic humanitarian merits,&quot; the spokesman quoted Wickremasinghe as telling Ratwatte.</p>
<p>The prisoners' letter said the LTTE wanted the release of a rebel identified as &quot;Kennedy&quot; who was captured in an attack on an airbase and two female rebels known as &quot;Mala&quot; and &quot;Uma&quot; who were seized after a guerrilla attack on a navy base in the north. The rebels were captured last year.</p>
<p>The rebels are fighting for an independent homeland for minority Tamils in the predominantly Sinhalese Indian Ocean island's north and east.</p>
<p>The government says more than 50,000 people have died in the ethnic war, now in its 14th year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
