<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98900" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MOTOR RACING-STEWART SIGNS MAGNUSSEN.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-STEWART SIGNS MAGNUSSEN.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former world champion Jackie Stewart signed Danish driver Jan Magnussen for his new Formula One motor racing team on Monday.</p>
<p>Magnussen, 23, has agreed to a four-year contract with the Ford-powered Stewart Grand Prix team which will make its debut in the 1997 season opener in Australia next March.</p>
<p>&quot;Jan is the best Formula Three driver I have ever seen, including Ayrton Senna. He displayed an outstanding talent in the formative classes of the sport,&quot; Stewart said.</p>
<p>Magnussen, who made his debut for McLaren Mercedes at last year's Pacific Grand Prix in which he finished 10th, has already had a successful association with the Stewart name.</p>
<p>He made his debut for Paul Stewart Racing, the team run by Jackie's son, in 1993 winning the Formula Three title with them the following year.</p>
<p>&quot;I am absolutely thrilled to have a seat in Formula One for next season. My dream come true,&quot; Magnussen said. &quot;It is a real pleasure to be going back to the Stewart family whose experience and professionalism I trust and respect.&quot;</p>
<p>Paul Stewart said: &quot;When Jan Magnussen drove for us in Formula Three he displayed both raw talent and an enormous potential to become a successful Grand Prix driver.&quot;</p>
<p>Magnussen began his driving career in traditional fashion in karting, winning the world title in 1990. He has been the McLaren test driver for the past two seasons.</p>
<p>He competed in the last four IndyCar races of this season for Penske.</p>
<p>Stewart-Ford will announce their second driver at a later date.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
