<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="98920" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RUGBY UNION-ENGLAND TEST RULED OUT, SAYS ARU.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-ENGLAND TEST RULED OUT, SAYS ARU.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian Rugby Union (ARU)</p>
<p>said on Monday the Wallabies would definitely not play a test</p>
<p>against England during their forthcoming tour of Europe but</p>
<p>would still go ahead with a match against Wales.</p>
<p>ARU spokesman Greg Thomas said attempts to resolve a dispute</p>
<p>over the possibility of adding a test against England to the</p>
<p>Wallabies' eight-week, 13-match tour had failed.</p>
<p>&quot;The (British) Home Unions reiterated it was impossible to</p>
<p>include an England test this time around,&quot; Thomas said.</p>
<p>ARU delegate Dick McGruther attended an International Rugby</p>
<p>Board (IRB) meeting in Rome at the weekend but was unable to win</p>
<p>over his counterparts in the Home Union Tour Committee (HUTC).</p>
<p>&quot;The ARU are very disappointed at the outcome,&quot; Thomas said.</p>
<p>&quot;We tried every avenue we could and we are still baffled by the</p>
<p>attitude of the Home Unions.&quot;</p>
<p>Australia had earlier threatened to scrap their test against</p>
<p>Wales at Cardiff Arms Park on December 1 if their request for a</p>
<p>match against England was rejected.</p>
<p>The Wales test was added to the Wallabies' itinerary at the</p>
<p>request of the Welsh union. Australia's request for an England</p>
<p>test set off a dispute over dates, with the HUTC refusing to</p>
<p>reschedule a match against the Barbarians at Twickenham on</p>
<p>December 7 and Australia rejecting two midweek dates.</p>
<p>Thomas said the ARU had decided to go ahead with the Wales</p>
<p>test despite the disappointment of being denied their first</p>
<p>&quot;Grand Slam&quot; against the four Home Unions of England, Ireland,</p>
<p>Scotland and Wales since 1984.</p>
<p>&quot;We are committed to the Wales test, we agreed to it,&quot;</p>
<p>Thomas said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our board decided we didn't want to be seen to be</p>
<p>dishonouring a test. It would have been a retrograde step for us</p>
<p>to turn Wales down after England had turned us down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thomas said the ARU would now ask for an unspecified</p>
<p>percentage of the gate-takings from the Barbarians match to</p>
<p>compensate for the loss of between A$600,000-700,000</p>
<p>($480,000-560,000) they said they would have received from an</p>
<p>England test.</p>
<p>Australia and England agreed last August to play each other</p>
<p>twice a year from 1997 until at least 2003. Thomas said the next</p>
<p>possible year for a &quot;Grand Slam&quot; would be 2000.</p>
<p>Australian tour itinerary:</p>
<p>Oct 15  Arrive Catania</p>
<p>19  Italy A Catania, Sicily</p>
<p>23  Italy, Padova</p>
<p>30  Scotland A, Galashiels</p>
<p>Nov  2  Combined Scottish Districts, Old Anniesland, Glasgow</p>
<p>5  Scottish Districts Select, McDiarmid Pk, Perth</p>
<p>9  Scotland, Murrayfield</p>
<p>13  Connaught, The Sports Ground, Galway</p>
<p>16  Ulster, Ravenhill, Belfast</p>
<p>19  Leinster, Lansdowne Road, Dublin</p>
<p>23  Ireland, Lansdowne Road, Dublin</p>
<p>26  Munster, Thomond Park, Limerick</p>
<p>Dec  1  Wales, Cardiff Arms Park</p>
<p>7  Barbarians, Twickenham, London</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
