<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99069" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries end lower after profit-taking spree.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries end lower after profit-taking spree.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries closed lower on Monday, hit by a profit-taking wave after Friday's sharp rally and by anxiety ahead of fresh upcoming supply, analysts said.</p>
<p>The 6-3/4 percent benchmark 30-year Treasury bond ended down 15/32 at 99-16/32. Its yield was at 6.79 percent.</p>
<p>The selling was triggered by some early foreign central bank selling, which was followed by domestic speculators and day-traders. But the lack of broad-based participation provided a languid tone to the session.  </p>
<p>&quot;There was a lack of broad-based participation. The price action was in the hands of dealers and they're mostly eyeing the 10-year note auction (on Tuesday),&quot; said Josh Stiles, senior bond strategist at consulting firm I.D.E.A.</p>
<p>The Treasury will auction $10 billion in 10-year notes on Tuesday. The bidding deadline for the auction has been set at 1300 EDT/1700 GMT.</p>
<p>Analysts said demand for the securities is still uncertain, but they added some overseas investors and portfolio managers might show interest in the issues.  </p>
<p>&quot;One potential source of buying could come from those who own mortgage holdings and are seeking to increase their durations after this latest wave down in rates,&quot; Stiles said.</p>
<p>The bond strategist was referring to a sharp rally seen late last week after the Labor Department reported a much weaker than expected September employment report, which showed a 40,000 drop against an expected 166,000 rise.</p>
<p>The buying spree pushed prices up, dragged yields down and steepened the yield curve substantially. In when-issued trade on Monday, the 10-year note yield was at 6.51 percent.  </p>
<p>Analysts said that once the auction is out of the way, the market is likely to focus on upcoming fresh data, which will include the producer price index (PPI) and retail sales. Both are for the month of September.</p>
<p>The data, due out on Friday, is likely to provide further hints on the performance of the economy and on what may be the Fed's next move.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a split opinion ... Some in the Fed apparently think we are beginning to see hopes of moving into the direction of a soft landing,&quot; said David Jones, chief economist at Aubrey G. Lanston and Co. Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;But others apparently are worried that we are close to full employment and that inevitably it could produce an acceleration of wage and price pressures and it may eventually force the Fed to do some tightening,&quot; Jones added.</p>
<p>On the technical front, analysts said a close at 111-4/32 on the benchmark December futures contract on Monday showed the day's selling bout could be short-lived.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking at 111-4/32 as a technical resistance level. And we didn't break it on Monday. But if prices break below that level we could see some selling,&quot; said a trader at a U.S. investment bank.  </p>
<p>The three-month Treasury bill rate closed up five basis points at 4.93 percent. The six-month bill rate rose five points to 5.10 percent. The year bill rate was up five points at 5.23 percent.</p>
<p>The two-year note closed down 3/32 at 100-6/32, yielding 5.90 percent. The five-year note traded off 5/32 at 100-16/32 to yield 6.26 percent. The ten-year note closed down 8/32 at 103-12/32, yielding 6.53 percent.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
