<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99143" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: M.A. Hanna CEO-to-be sees no major change.</title>
<headline>M.A. Hanna CEO-to-be sees no major change.</headline>
<byline>Susan Zimmerman</byline>
<dateline>CLEVELAND 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>M.A. Hanna Co president Douglas McGregor said Monday he plans no major change in direction for the specialty chemical and rubber company when he takes the helm as chief executive officer in January.</p>
<p>He also said the company expects rubber compounding volumes to return to near-year-ago levels by the beginning of 1997, although some volume softness remains in that business.</p>
<p>&quot;Is there going to be any major change in direction?  I think the answer is no,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Hanna will emphasize more international growth, he said.  </p>
<p>It will also pursue a modestly slower acquisition pace but essentially, it will refine existing strategy, he said.</p>
<p>McGregor, 55, with Hanna nine years, worked with outgoing chief executive Martin Walker and others on a strategy begun in 1990 to reduce dependency on auto and building industries.</p>
<p>Today the Cleveland-based company focuses on plastics and rubber compounding, plastic colorants and additives and distribution of plastic resins and engineered shapes. Cyclical auto and construction industries, 40 percent of revenues in 1990, today account for less than 30 percent, he said.  </p>
<p>Hanna, which sold its last mining assets in 1995, earned $1.07 a share on revenues of $1.9 billion last year.</p>
<p>Hanna's rubber business accounts for about 20 percent of overall revenues.  McGregor said that unit's volumes declined this year due to &quot;a big tire inventory out there&quot; and a key customer that moved compounding in-house.  He said he believes new customers, more business from existing customers and a growing non-tire business will replace much of the volume.</p>
<p>McGregor said he hopes margins return to year-ago levels by the first quarter.  </p>
<p>The rubber unit and acquisitions hurt &quot;a bit,&quot; he said, but &quot;I'd rather make $0.50 a pound on something with a 10 percent margin than $0.10 a pound with a 100 percent margin,&quot; he said, referring to value-added products.</p>
<p>Hanna has said its five-year revenue goal is $4 billion, or 13-15 percent revenue growth a year.  Most will come from existing businesses, while acquisitions, which contributed about a third of revenue growth since 1990-91, will likely account for 25-30 percent of growth through 2001, he said.  </p>
<p>Selling more to existing customers via technical service and customer solutions, as well as Hanna's &quot;one-stop shop&quot; approach for plastic resins, compounds and colorants, will help internal growth, he said.</p>
<p>The company plans to increase international revenues, now about 20 percent of total revenues, to 25 percent, focusing on continued growth in existing European markets and expansion in Asia, he said.  In 1990, Hanna did not have a significant amount of international sales.</p>
<p>Higher international sales and less dependency on autos and construction help prepare Hanna to weather an economic recession, but it is not immune if a downturn occurs, he said.</p>
<p>Hanna has moved from retaining names on acquired companies to emphasizing the M.A. Hanna name, a move well received by suppliers, McGregor said.  Some changes in sales staff assignments led to some &quot;temporary disconnects&quot; with customers, but it has not been a big issue with customers, he said.</p>
<p>-- Cleveland Newsdesk 216-579-0077</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25140">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CLEVELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
