<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99191" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gap shares fall ahead of Sept sales report.</title>
<headline>Gap shares fall ahead of Sept sales report.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gap Inc shares fell in anticipation of softer September sales figures, which are expected to be reported on Thursday, analysts said.</p>
<p>Shares of Gap fell 1-1/8 to 28. A Gap spokesperson was not available but analysts said the stock fell on views that  sales comparisons are becoming increasingly challenging, particularly after August's flat same store sales.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Gap will have a relatively soft number on Thursday,&quot; said Donald Trott of Dean Witter Reynolds. &quot;August numbers spooked a lot of people and the stock got hit hard, but we think that was just the first tremor.&quot;  </p>
<p>Trott said there were still many &quot;momentum players&quot; holding onto the stock but these investors' tolerance levels for further disappointments from the Gap were relatively low.</p>
<p>Another analyst said, &quot;I don't think there are high expectations for the month.  Everybody's digested the fact that sales of the first part of September were difficult.&quot;</p>
<p>Late last month, Morgan Stanley &amp; Co analyst Sharon Pearson downgraded Gap on views that its sales gains would be weaker during the rest of the year than in the spring and summer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
