<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99276" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British Conservatives open key pre-poll conference.</title>
<headline>British Conservatives open key pre-poll conference.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>BOURNEMOUTH, England 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Conservatives open a crucial party conference on Tuesday with their grip on power less sure than at any time since Margaret Thatcher piloted them to a 1979 general election victory.</p>
<p>Rows over Europe are expected to dominate a conference which Prime Minister John Major has said should be the launchpad for a another triumph in the election he must call by next May.</p>
<p>With the party over 20 points adrift of Labour in the polls, and the Conservatives seen by voters as the party of sleaze, Major needs a successful conference to begin the fight back.</p>
<p>But harmony was notably lacking with John Redwood, the right-winger who last year challenged Major for the party leadership, prominent among those rocking the boat.</p>
<p>Redwood, appearing on a BBC television current affairs programme, hesitated when asked whether he would urge voters to back the Conservatives or the tiny Referendum Party which wants a plebiscite on Britain's relations with Brussels.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you have to ask me that nearer the time,&quot; he said before adding when pressed: &quot;Of course I will answer. Vote for the Conservative Party.&quot;</p>
<p>A further sign of tension was the revelation that legislator James Cran, a strong Eurosceptic, had resigned as an aide to Northern Ireland Secretary Sir Patrick Mayhew.</p>
<p>Party aides said Cran wanted to spent more time in his constituency which he feared may now be a marginal seat.</p>
<p>There is widespread dissatisfaction among the Conservative rank-and-file over Major's attempts to bridge the gap between the Eurosceptic wing of the party and members of parliament more favourable to Brussels.</p>
<p>They are particularly opposed to Major's refusal to rule out British membership of the single currency ahead of the election, saying that a commitment to retain the pound is the one thing that could revive the party's political prospects.</p>
<p>Anti-European sentiment could show itself in the first debate of the conference in which Agriculture Minister Douglas Hogg will defend his handling of the &quot;mad cow&quot; issue.</p>
<p>Traditionally pro-Conservative farmers are angry at plans to slaughter thousands of their cattle to stamp out Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy (BSE) following scientific evidence that it may be transmissable to humans.</p>
<p>But some believe Hogg's negotiating tactics in Brussels to try to lift a ban on British beef exports and the government's handling of the technical aspects of the cull have made a bad situation even worse.</p>
<p>But it will be the reception given to finance minister Kenneth Clarke when he speaks on Thursday that will reveal most clearly how deep the Euro-divide is in the party.</p>
<p>Clarke is widely seen as the most pro-European member of the cabinet, and recently said it would be &quot;pathetic&quot; for Britain to dither over whether to join a single currency once plans for it have been finalised.</p>
<p>A frosty response to his speech from conference delegates would be seen as a sign they are less interested in winning the next election than in triumphing in the internal party debate on Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOURNEMOUTH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
