<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99287" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: One blast, then another, then cries of the injured.</title>
<headline>One blast, then another, then cries of the injured.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>LISBURN, Northern Ireland 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>First there was a big explosion at Britain's Northern Ireland army nerve centre. Then a smaller one.</p>
<p>&quot;Then there were an awful lot of squeals,&quot; said one man living nearby.</p>
<p>&quot;There was squealing as if a lot of people had been hurt. By this time ambulances were flying up and down, ferrying people away,&quot; said the man, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>Dazed and bewildered, he was one of several residents of the dormitory town of Lisburn, 10 miles (16 km) south of Belfast, to recount their shock at a guerrilla attack on Britain's army headquarters in the province.</p>
<p>Smoke billowed from inside the tightly-guarded barracks where the elite of a force commanded by Britain's Gulf War commander and Bosnia hero Lieutenant-General Rupert Smith is said to live.</p>
<p>Hundreds of police cordoned off the area to prevent local people getting inside.</p>
<p>The exact number of troops housed in the barbed-wire and brick fortifications is not known but visitors say it is a vast complex which accommodates a small village.</p>
<p>Some 2,000 civilians work at the base and several thousand families are thought to live inside what until Monday was the highest security outside of the province's main Maze jail where one thousand pro-British and Republican guerrillas are imprisoned.</p>
<p>Spokesmen for police and the army said they suspected that a car, a favoured weapon of Irish Republican Army (IRA) guerrillas fighting British rule, had been used.</p>
<p>Security sources speculated that the guerrillas had somehow penetrated the maximum security perimeter of the Thiepval army base, using intimate knowledge of the layout to park and detonate the bomb.</p>
<p>The blast shook the town and could be heard in Belfast.</p>
<p>&quot;The smoke billowed sky-high. My garage has been wrecked and my shed at the back too. Slates have been blown off the roof as well,&quot; said another Lisburn resident.</p>
<p>Reverend Brian Gibson, who lives next door to the barracks, described how debris from the blast landed in a playing field near the base.</p>
<p>&quot;I was sitting in my study when it went off,&quot; he said. &quot;I could see shrapnel all over the playing field. It seemed to be in the middle of a field where some girls were playing hockey.</p>
<p>&quot;There were bits of some sort of vehicle, I would say it was a lorry.  When the second bomb went off, two windows in my house broke with the force of the explosion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The barracks lies at the end of a leafy lane. Callers have to stop their cars to be searched by troops, even regular suppliers of food for the hundreds of British families inside.</p>
<p>A huge steel gate stands at the main entrance to guard against car bomb attacks.</p>
<p>Anyone failing to stop their vehicle at the designated check point triggers an immediate siren of warning and troops scramble into combat positions, recent visitors said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBURN, Northern Ireland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
