<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99376" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Empty seats in parliament show Burundi violence.</title>
<headline>Empty seats in parliament show Burundi violence.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's decimated parliament met on Monday for the first time since last July's military coup and the rows of empty seats bore witness to the ethnic violence that is destroying the country.</p>
<p>The majority of the 81 members elected in 1993 are in exile or have been assassinated during three years of butchery that have cost 150,000 lives in a population of six million.</p>
<p>All the dead and exiled members were from the mainly Hutu Frodebu party that took 65 seats. The remaining 16 went to Uprona, the Tutsi-dominated party.</p>
<p>Major Pierre Buyoya, installed in the army coup on July 25, agreed to restore the national assembly -- parliament -- last month, meeting one of the conditions for the lifting of sanctions imposed by regional states after the putsch.</p>
<p>The speaker, Leonce Ngendakumana, declared the assembly's session open but said it would not start work formally until Buyoya restored the suspended constitution.</p>
<p>With parliament technically powerless and refusing to accept Buyoya's legitimacy -- official portraits of his ousted predecessor, Sylvestre Ntibantunganya, still hang in the assembly's offices -- the significance of Monday's opening was more symbolic than real.</p>
<p>But Ngendakumana, a Frodebu member, said parliament was ready to join the search for peace between Hutus and Tutsis.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very encouraged that they were able to meet. Now they have to decide how to continue the process through negotiations,&quot; U.S. ambassador Rusty Hughes told Reuters after hearing Ngendakumana's speech.</p>
<p>Eugene Nindorera, Buyoya's minister in charge of relations with parliament, said it was premature to discuss the restoration of the constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;We first need to hear exactly what members of the assembly, not just the speaker, are proposing,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Only 38 members were present, 28 from Frodebu and 10 from Uprona.</p>
<p>One was Fanuel Ntabiriho who took over a Frodebu seat in Cibitoke province last May after the unsolved murder of the sitting member, Bibiane Ntamutumba, and her family.</p>
<p>&quot;I live in Bujumbura becaus it's too dangerous to travel to Cibitoke,&quot; he said. The northwest province is in the heart of the war zone between Hutu rebels and the mainly Tutsi army.</p>
<p>Ngendakumana is the fourth speaker since the election. One was murdered in the army's attempted coup in October 1993, one is in exile and one, Ntibantunganya, is still living inside ambassador Hughes's residence where he took refuge two days before the military putsch.</p>
<p>Ngendakumana said the assembly had lost more than 20 members since 1993. One western embassy says the precise count is 22, all from Frodebu.</p>
<p>Buyoya met the U.S. special envoy on Burundi, Lakhdar Brahimi on Sunday, after discussions last week with special emissaries from the United States and the European Union.</p>
<p>He is pressing all of them to help get the sanctions lifted, saying they are harming ordinary people and &quot;radicalising&quot; the situtation.</p>
<p>Diplomats interpret this as a warning that if the economic embargo is maintained as a lever to force Buyoya into quick talks with Hutu rebels, he may lose out to hardline Tutsi military and civilians demanding total war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
