<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99372" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GHANA: Ghana bourse slips as two blue-chips slide.</title>
<headline>Ghana bourse slips as two blue-chips slide.</headline>
<dateline>ACCRA 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Ghana Stock Exchange index lost ground again on Monday as market heavyweight Ashanti Goldfields Company and Standard Chartered Bank slipped in value, its trading report showed.</p>
<p>The GSE All-Share Index fell 2.89 points in lacklustre trade to close at 378.48, down from Friday's 381.37 points -- itself slightly down on Wednesday's closing tally.</p>
<p>Ashanti (down 500 cedis to 28,000 cedis) and Standard Chartered (down 200 cedis to 5,300 cedis) were the only losers. Dealers blamed the Ashanti slip on uncertainty over the world price of gold.</p>
<p>After a brief surge in demand on Friday with block sales in Accra Brewery Limited and Kumasi Brewery Limited, the market returned to a more familiar pattern.</p>
<p>Offers of 1.02 million shares far outstripped demand of 203,330 shares. A total of 26,730 shares changed hands, compared to more than 4.2 million on Friday and 48,670 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Unilever (up 4 cedis to 794 cedis), Social Security Bank (up 2 to 1,035 cedis) and Pioneer Tobacco Company (up 1 to 126 cedis) were the only risers.</p>
<p>($1=1,720 cedis)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ACCRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GHANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
