<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99393" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Turkish premier visits pariah Nigeria.</title>
<headline>Turkish premier visits pariah Nigeria.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's Islamist prime minister, Necmettin Erbakan, arrived in outcast state Nigeria on Monday, the last step of a controversial African tour that should increase commercial ties.</p>
<p>&quot;He arrived at around 1410 (1310 GMT),&quot; a protocol official at the airport in the capital Abuja said.</p>
<p>Erbakan was originally scheduled to arrive in Nigeria on Sunday for a two-day visit, but Turkish embassy officials said his flight from North Africa was delayed because of bad weather in the Sahara desert.</p>
<p>Nigeria is shunned for alleged human rights abuses and lack of democracy by the same western countries that have criticised the tour that has taken Erbakan to Egypt and another pariah nation, Libya.</p>
<p>Erbakan is expected to hold talks with Nigerian military ruler General Sani Abacha on Monday.</p>
<p>Diplomats and officials say the visit will probably give a significant boost to commercial ties between Turkey and Africa's most populous nation.</p>
<p>A foreign ministry statement said agreements on both trade and shipping were likely to be ready for signing.</p>
<p>&quot;We need investment in each other's country, especially at the level of private sector operators,&quot; the director-general of the foreign ministry Jibrin Chinade told a technical session of the joint commission of the two countries in Abuja at the weekend.</p>
<p>In his entourage of about 200 people, Erbakan is bringing the chief executives of several of Turkey's biggest companies.</p>
<p>Areas earmarked for special attention during the visit include commerce and tourism, construction, agriculture, banking, health, free trade zones, transportation, telecommunications, gas and petrochemicals.</p>
<p>Trade between the two nations, currently insignificant at about 100 million naira ($1.25 million), is set to jump in 1999 when Turkey will take an annual $100 million worth of liquefied natural gas (LNG) from a plant now under construction.</p>
<p>&quot;This session will afford both parties the opportunity to examine this matter in greater detail,&quot; a foreign ministry statement said.</p>
<p>Relations between Nigeria and the West reached a low point in November last year with the hanging of nine minority rights activists including author Ken Saro-Wiwa for murder despite international pleas for clemency.</p>
<p>The wave of condemnation and limited sanctions imposed by western countries have forced Nigeria to turn away from its traditional allies to look to Asian countries, principally China for ties.</p>
<p>Erbakan would be the most senior official from the Western NATO alliance to visit Nigeria. A visit to the state is not on the itinerary of U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher, who on Monday begins in Mali his first trip to black Africa.</p>
<p>On Saturday Erbakan met Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi, and dismissed U.S. claims that Tripoli sponsors terrorism as &quot;propaganda&quot;.</p>
<p>However, Turkish papers said Gaddafi had slighted Erbakan by calling for the foundation of a Kurdish state -- in direct contradiction to long-standing Turkish policy. ($1=80 naira)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
