<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99410" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAB shares rise, prospects seen good.</title>
<headline>SAB shares rise, prospects seen good.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in drinks giant South African Breweries Ltd rose on Monday as the market digested the prospects for its international expansion.</p>
<p>SAB rose 225 cents, or 1.88 percent, to 121.75 rand attracting 141 separate moves, the highest level in morning trade on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>More than 175,000 shares had changed hands by 1030 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;The company's cash flows are strong, prospects are good. There is nothing negative to say about the company really,&quot; said Wynand van Zyl, analyst at SMK Securities.</p>
<p>On Friday SAB said it had authorised an offering of around $360 million to fund its international expansion. The offering is one of the largest emerging market equity issues to international investors undertaken by a private sector company.</p>
<p>The offer could be raised to $410 million if there was sufficient demand via an over-allocation option. International demand for the share offering exceeded $600 million.</p>
<p>The firm has sown up its domestic market and is expanding abroad, in areas like China and central Europe, in order to maintain its strong recent growth levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The (share) issue is going to be a success. It will give them the cash they need to keep going overseas,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>Van Zyl said the shares had looked undervalued just after the announcement of the placing and predicted an upward trend over the next six months.</p>
<p>He said the stock could go as high 140 rand by next March.</p>
<p>-- Paul Harris, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
