<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99425" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Oct 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Oct 7.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Friday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- A number of high profile people in the former Bophuthatswana -- including a string of politicians and their families and associates -- obtained farms from the former homeland government under questionable circumstances, the De Meyer commission of inquiry has found.</p>
<p>- Several financial institutions and other parties have shown an interest in buying Community Bank's 110 million rand loan book, the price of which could be heavily discounted because the bank's loans were made out at the prime interest rate.</p>
<p>- The foreign capital drain has continued to take its toll on the Reserve Bank's forex and gold reserves, which fell to 10.04 billion rand in September from August's 10.07 billion rand, figures released by the Reserve Bank show.</p>
<p>- The National Union of Mineworkers and the migrant labour and hostel system will come under fire when a comission of inquiry into mine violence presents its report to President Nelson Mandela today.</p>
<p>- An analysis prepared by the justice department on bribery allegations against hotel magnate Sol Kerzner demonstrated that the case against Kerzner might not be closed after all, parliamentary justice committee chairman and ANC MP Johnny de Lange said yesterday.</p>
<p>- The South African navy will ask Parliament's defence committee on Wednesday for an urgent go-ahead to buy four British submarines, defence sources confirmed at the weekend.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- Pharmacies around the country have banded together to demand fair play from the medical-aid industry, which is withholding sums running into billions of rands and rejecting claims for up to a year after medicines are dispensed.</p>
<p>- If the rand exchange rate and the oil price remain at present levels, the price of petrol could be increased by up to 10 cents a litre, equivalent to five percent, over the next two months, in the process adding 0.2 percent to the inflation rate, Econometrix, the economic research unit, said.</p>
<p>- Spoornet, the state-owned railway company, announced a complete overhaul of its management structures on Friday to make it more market-driven and position it to compete with road freight.</p>
<p>- South African Breweries (SAB) received a rush of demand for shares in its 1.8 billion rand international equity issue last week, with demand far outstripping the amount of scrip on offer.</p>
<p>- The Absa bank group is considering an alliance with a financial boutique or investment banking operation as the way forward for its business in the Asia-Pacific region, a top bank official said on Friday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Today, a story as grim and harrowing as ever told in a court will begin to unfold at the trial of the man accused of being the worst serial killer in the country's history.</p>
<p>- Seventy-eight people, including five primary school children, lost their lives and more than 40 were injured in three horrific bus accidents during a black weekend on South African roads.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
