<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99466" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Gains to Slovak VUB shares push SAX index higher.</title>
<headline>Gains to Slovak VUB shares push SAX index higher.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak blue chips opened the week mixed in heavier trading on the Bratislava Stock Exchange (BSE) on Monday, with gains to shares of bank VUB pushing the SAX index slightly higher.</p>
<p>Slovakia's largest commercial bank VUB gained 40 crowns to close at 1,660, with its average price -- used for calculating the index -- rising 2.41 percent, driving the SAX up 0.58 points to 200.90.</p>
<p>However brokers said investors remained cautious over VUB and that they were sceptical its could post sustained gains.</p>
<p>Major paint producer Chemolak led the day's trading with 9,695 shares changing hands, closing up 150 crowns at 2,050, while oil and gas storage company Nafta closed down 20 at 1,950.</p>
<p>&quot;Nafta is in a downward trend, as it still isn't clear whether the new majority owner and its managment will pay dividends, or will impose a strategy of reducing the company's profit,&quot; said Dusan Sykora of ING Barings.</p>
<p>Oil refiner Slovnaft closed up 10 at 930 crowns, with brokers saying investor interest in the issue has been reviving and that a further rise in its share price was expected.</p>
<p>Steel producer VSZ closed unchanged at 630, with traders considering the issue undervalued, saying that after some time at present levels, the share will again become interesting for investors.</p>
<p>Overall volume increased to 783,720 shares, from 381,788 shares traded on Friday, while the turnover rose to 744.77 million crowns from 152.17 million on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
