<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99477" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonia Tallinna Pank 9 month profit 38 mln kroons.</title>
<headline>Estonia Tallinna Pank 9 month profit 38 mln kroons.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Estonia's fourth largest bank, Tallinna Pank, on Monday reported a nine-month retained profit of 37.5 million kroons, versus retained earnings of 20.9 million kroons at the end of the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>It did not give comparisons for the 1996 and 1995 nine-month figures.</p>
<p>The bank said in a balance sheet statement that its assets grew 18.7 percent over the third quarter to 1.8 billion kroons at the end of September.</p>
<p>Income from securities rose to 175.8 million kroons by the end of September from 138.6 million at the end of June.</p>
<p>The net loan portfolio was 981.3 million kroons, compared with 762.1 million kroons at the end of the first half.</p>
<p>The bank said its share capital was stable at 96 million kroons.</p>
<p>Most of the top Estonian commercial banks, which are quoted on the Tallinn stock exchange, are expected to release nine-month reports this week.</p>
<p>Eesti Uhispank, also quoted in Helsinki, earlier reported profits for the first eight months of the year of 36.8 million kroons and forecast full-year earnings of 56 million kroons.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
