<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99493" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania launches polio immunisation campaign.</title>
<headline>Albania launches polio immunisation campaign.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian health officials on Monday launched a two-week campaign to immunise everyone under 50 against polio, in an effort to halt an epidemic which has claimed 12 lives.</p>
<p>&quot;The immunisation campaign has started all around Albania and everything is going like clockwork,&quot; said Tatjana Harito, head of the health ministry's epidemiology department.</p>
<p>&quot;We have distributed the vaccines and set up a chain of cold boxes in every corner of the country.&quot;</p>
<p>The campaign to vaccinate Albania's 3.5 million population is being coordinated by the World Health Organisation and the United Nation's Children's Fund and will be done in two stages, second scheduled to begin in mid-November.</p>
<p>Health Minister Maksim Cikuli on Sunday urged Albanians in a television broadcast to get themselves vaccinated. He said polio was traditionally known as a disease affecting children but that Albania's epidemic was unusual, as it had mainly afflicted people aged 19 to 35.</p>
<p>&quot;We decided to vaccinate people up to 50 years of age because polio has mostly affected people from 19 to 35, which may be due to defects in vaccinations given before 1992 (in the years under communism),&quot; Cikuli said.</p>
<p>He said it was believed people over 50 might be immune to the virus as virtually no polio cases had been registered in that age group.</p>
<p>&quot;I can confirm the vaccine is of a high quality, the same type used in the whole of Europe and does not create any side-effects,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>To show the vaccination was not dangerous, Cikuli made his own son and daughter take a dose before swallowing one himself.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
