<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99520" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine to sell 26 pct shares in paper maker.</title>
<headline>Ukraine to sell 26 pct shares in paper maker.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's State Property Fund plans to offer for sale 26 percent of shares in the country's largest newsprint maker to a strategic investor, the company director said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Fifty-one percent of shares in the Zhydachivsky TsBK paper manufacturer will remain in state hands and 11 percent will be controlled by the workers' collective,&quot; Mikhailo Tytykalo said.</p>
<p>Strategic investor shares were increased to 26 percent from 20 percent allocated in a previous plan, after workers purchased only 11 percent shares instead of their allotted 19 percent, he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The remaining shares will be privatised through certificates held by citizens, he added.</p>
<p>The Zhydachivsky company is one of 208 government-designated companies to be privatised through strategic investment.</p>
<p>Zhydachivsky's authorised capital is valued at 22.8 million hryvnias ($13 million). During the first eight months of this year the company manufactured 11,800 tonnes of newsprint and 13,000 tonnes of office stationery.</p>
<p>Paper was exported to Bulgaria, Hungary, Moldova and Turkmenistan. --Yuri Kulikov, Kiev Bureau +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
