<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99600" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Nicaragua's Sandinistas unveil economic plan.</title>
<headline>Nicaragua's Sandinistas unveil economic plan.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA, Nicaragua 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nicaragua's formerly Marxist Sandinista Front on Monday made official the party's apparent conversion to free-market principles when it unveiled its economic plan for the October 20 presidential election.</p>
<p>In the plan, the Sandinistas promised to respect the free market, maintain the country's monetary stability, control inflation and continue the structural adjustment program started by the government of President Violeta Chamorro.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our economic policy will start from those elements of economic stability that have been achieved so far by the current government,&quot; said Daniel Ortega, the Sandinista leader and former president of Nicaragua, at a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We will rescue what is positive of the current government, adjust it to the new situation and promote a policy of employment-generation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ortega said his government's priorities would be creating employment and alleviating poverty through private investment.  </p>
<p>&quot;The motor of the Nicaraguan economy should be private and foreign investment, and with this in mind, legal policies and regulations must be created to make our country attractive to private foreign investment,&quot; the economic plan said.</p>
<p>This new business-friendly attitude is a major ideological shift for the Sandinistas, who governed Nicaragua from 1979 to 1990 with the support of the Soviet Union and Cuba.</p>
<p>Many Nicaraguan business leaders have doubts about the Sandinistas' sudden turnaround and remember how the Sandinista government confiscated private property and implemented centralized economic planning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA, Nicaragua"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
