<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99640" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Latam stocks seen rising but profit-taking looms.</title>
<headline>Latam stocks seen rising but profit-taking looms.</headline>
<byline>Margaret Orgill</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latin American stocks, which enjoyed a lively rally last week, are expected to resume their winning streak this week, although a wave of profit-taking could snap the string of gains, said traders.</p>
<p>&quot;Friday's U.S. jobs data was a huge surprise and stretched the local rally, but stocks will soon have to pause and consolidate,&quot; said Dario Lizzano, at Buenos Aires brokerage Rio Valores in remarks which apply to most Latin American markets.  </p>
<p>Although the bullish mood is region-wide, investors are focusing on domestic issues ranging from protests against labor reforms in Argentina to prospects of higher electricity prices in Venezuela, which are seen setting the Caracas bourse alight.</p>
<p>In Brazil, stocks are seen staging a moderate rally, with the bolsa watching for further developments in municipal elections and awaiting the release of September trade figures, said dealers. &quot;The market will be eyeing political alliances for the second round of municipal elections,&quot; said Evandro dos Rios Jr, a trader at the Indusval brokerage house.  </p>
<p>The bourse will also be dominated by a fight over options settlements to be made on October 21, they said.</p>
<p>Brazilian stocks ended last week up 2.6 percent at 66,269 points with volume thin at an average $350 million.</p>
<p>Argentine blue chips are expected to keep a firm underlying tone this week, although profit-taking could rob the market of momentum, said traders.</p>
<p>Players are seen continuing to focus on the government's labor reform initiatives in the face of mounting trade union protests.  </p>
<p>So far new strike threats coming only days after a 36-hour walkout were not seen marring the government's drive to make employment conditions more flexible.</p>
<p>The selective MerVal index jumped four percent last week to a three month high of 580.03 points, drawing momentum from Wall Street and the successful launch of Argentina's $1 billion global bond issue.</p>
<p>In Caracas, stocks are seen bullish at the prospect of higher electricity tariffs, although investors could soon move to cash in gains, said dealers.  </p>
<p>&quot;Theoretically there should be a correction as all signs are of an overbought market,&quot; said a trader at brokerage Bancaracas.</p>
<p>But the week ended &quot;on the up; there's still residual demand and we could see further rises,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The 19-share  index vaulted nearly 17 percent last week to close at 6,391.01 points.</p>
<p>The Mexican bolsa, which rallied over four percent last week, is seen looking to Wall Street and to company quarterly results for direction this week, said dealers.  </p>
<p>As in other markets, the rally could falter on a wave of profit-taking, they said.</p>
<p>The Mexican bolsa closed Friday up 0.08 percent at 3,376.05 points with a rise in the week of 4.3 percent.</p>
<p>Chilean stocks, which rallied last week amid optimism local interest rates could soon fall, are seen resuming their upward slant this week, said traders.</p>
<p>&quot;The market wasn't particularly overbought last week, so we expect it to be mixed to positive this week,&quot; said Lance Eckel, an analyst at brokerage Sud Americano.</p>
<p>The 40-share IPSa index ended the week up 2.09 percent at 101.01 points.</p>
<p>--Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595x212</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
