<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99683" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - Oct 8.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - Oct 8.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>The September ANZ job advertisements series painted a depressing picture of the labour market yesterday, with the number of job advertisements falling for a third consecutive month to its lowest level since January 1994, providing further pressure for a Reserve Bank interest rate cut. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard's Parliamentary Secretary, Nick Minchin, has prepared a confidential paper for Federal Cabinet, understood to examine a number of options for the Government on the republic, which raises arguments against fulfilling the Government's election commitment to hold a People's Convention on the issue. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to a survey by companies Internet Profiles and DoubleClick Network, Web surfers don't like Mondays. The survey showed Web site advertising fails to hit its targets on Mondays because Internet subscribers don't click on as much that day. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to tax advisers contacted yesterday by The Australian Financial Review, a large part of the toll rebate for motorway users announced on Sunday by the New South Wales Government is likely to be taxable because, although the money is to be given back to motorists as a refund, it runs the risk of being classified as revenue. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Australian researcher Dr Peter Doherty, 55, along with fellow researcher Rolf Zinkernagel, 52, of Switzerland, were awarded the Nobel prize for medicine last night for their pioneering work at the John Curtin School for Medical Research in Canberra in the 1970s, when they discovered how the immune system recognises virus-infected cells. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In what is being hailed as an historic announcement for opera audiences in Sydney and Melbourne, the Sydney-based Australian Opera yesterday took control of Victoria's long-established performing arts company, the Victoria State Opera, to form the Australian National Opera from 1998. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Amendments to the Native Title Act, scheduled to be submitted to Coalition MPs at their regular party room meeting today, give Federal Aboriginal Affairs Minister John Herron the power to override Mabo-style land claims in the case of resource projects considered to be of fundamental importance to Australia. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Rod Dent, the son of the first person to die under the Northern Territory's euthanasia legislation, and other members of the Coalition of Organisations for Voluntary Euthanasia launched a campaign for a national referendum on voluntary euthanasia yesterday. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>A Herald AGB-McNair poll conducted at the weekend has revealed there is strong public pressure on Prime Minister John Howard to make a clear stand on the Government's position on racism amid growing controversy sparked by comments from Queensland Independnt MP Pauline Hanson. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A sudden shift downstream by the huge reservoir of the Hume Dam on the Murray River near Albury has sparked a massive safety operation involving the release of nearly a million mega-litres of water and the insertion of steel cables in the dam wall. Page 1</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>As academics step up their bid to secure pay rises of 15 per cent, which would cost the Federal Government more than A$200 million if met in full, twelve of Australia's universities will experience industrial action within weeks, with academics banning students from receiving their exam results. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian-born Professor Peter Doherty, who is now at the St Jude's Research Hospital in Memphis, Tennessee, and Rolf Zinkernagel of Switzerland have been awarded the Nobel Prize for physiology or medicine for their discoveries while working at the John Curtin School of Medical Research in Canberra about the immune defences of cells. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Creating a powerful local contender to buy Melbourne Airport, the City of Melbourne and Victorian-based companies the Pratt Group and National Mutual will contribute more than A$300 million to the Victorian Airports Ltd consortium, which also includes Macquarie Bank and UK-based groups Serco and Manchester Airport. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to Australian Bureau of Statistics figures, occupancy in Victorian hotels and motels has grown almost twice as much as in other States. Victoria's hotels and motels recorded a 15 percent jump in occupancy compared with two years ago and revealed a 32 percent growth in takings from accommodation in the past two years.  Although Queensland and New South Wales still dominate the Australian tourist market, Victoria turned around its gradual decline since 1989, recording the highest growth of any State. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In the lead up to the annual parliament of the Melbourne diocese of the Anglican Church, the Bishops of Wangaratta and Ballarat have threatened to refuse to recognise a male or female priest ordained by a woman bishop. The Melbourne synod will debate a report on whether women should be bishops, by the Commission on Women in the Episcopate, when the synod's 1000 members meet on Friday. Page A3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australia's Professor Peter Doherty and Switzerland's Rolf Zinkernagel are joint winners of the Nobel Prize for physiology or medicine for their studies of infectious diseases at the John Curtin School of Medical Research. The winners used mice to study how the immune system could protect animals against infection from a virus able to cause meningitis. Page A3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
