<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99773" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan bond market seen getting way ahead of itself.</title>
<headline>Japan bond market seen getting way ahead of itself.</headline>
<byline>Hideyuki Sano</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Japanese government bond market is setting records daily, but some analysts say investors are in for a rude awakening as the rises are based on speculation and not supported by strong economic fundamentals.</p>
<p>The benchmark December contract explored the 123 range for the first time in its history on Monday, reaching as high as 123.45. Its previous high of 122.83 was hit last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The bond market's rally since August has been purely based on speculation and not on changes in fundamental variables,&quot; said Shoji Kitta, managing director of Tokyo Tanshi Co Ltd, the largest money broker in Japan.</p>
<p>Many dealers said what is supporting the current strong mood of the market is speculation that some investors will have to buy JGBs because there are no other investment vehicles that are as attractive.</p>
<p>With prospects for Japanese stocks far from promising, and with the outlook for the dollar/yen exchange rate unclear, Japanese bonds are the only reliable source of capital gains, they say.</p>
<p>It is widely expected that agricultural institutions, which are set to receive a large amount of funds (of about 2.76 trillion yen ($24.8 billion) in total) from failed mortgage firms, their major borrowers, will buy bonds in the future.</p>
<p>Many other investors also limited or reduced the amount of bonds in their portfolios during the first half of the financial year ended September in preparation for rising interest rates.</p>
<p>Kitta said the recent rally had been led by foreign speculators and local major financial institutions which bought purely to get ahead of the game and that investors have not actually bought much yet.</p>
<p>Smaller investors, such as regional credit unions, have yet to get on the bandwagon, Kitta added.</p>
<p>&quot;The current situation is a bit like short-squeezing. People know there are investors who have lots of money and don't know what to do with it, and so they are taking advantage of these investors,&quot; one trader at a Japanese bank also said.</p>
<p>Fuji Securities' Research Group recently estimated an adequate level of long-term interest rates by calculating the average spread between long-term interest rates and short-term interest rates for the past several years.</p>
<p>The result was about 3.18 percent, based on the current short-term rate (three-month certificates of deposit rate) of 0.52 percent.</p>
<p>The cash benchmark 182nd JGBs were yielding 2.75 percent at the close of Monday trade.</p>
<p>An economist, who declined to be identified, said, &quot;Worries that the fall of Japanese interest rates was overdone is rife in the central bank.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the yield of JGBs should theoretically be the sum of the growth rate and inflation rate.</p>
<p>If the GDP is growing at 2.5 percent, as forecast by the government, and the inflation rate is at 1.0 percent, the yield should be around 3.5 percent, he said.</p>
<p>The current level of the JGBs means the market is more pessimistic about the recovery of the Japanese economy and more optimistic about inflation, he added.</p>
<p>Dealers often say that selling is difficult as the market has rallied for nearly two months despite worries about the current high levels.</p>
<p>However, Tokyo Tanshi's Kitta warned the upward momentum will turn and bonds will nosedive as soon as speculators reverse their positions later this year or early next year. ($1=111 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
