<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99781" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan heads to polls as parties bash bureaucracy.</title>
<headline>Japan heads to polls as parties bash bureaucracy.</headline>
<byline>Paul Eckert</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's political parties kick off general elections on Tuesday in a race expected to see well-organised incumbents rake in rural votes while fractious opposition parties' fight for fickle city voters.</p>
<p>Politicians' messages -- many similar-sounding slogans deriding an unpopular bureaucracy -- are set to blare out from loudspeakers on trucks as candidates press the flesh for the first day before October 20 elections.</p>
<p>Giving the nation a test of what their groups offered in a televised debate on Monday, party leaders struggled to present their plans for cutting bureaucratic red tape as the most radical -- or the most feasible.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto, president of the Liberal Democratic Party, said if the LDP party won a majority to give him a second term, he would work quickly to reorganise powerful bureaucracies, placing them under close control of elected cabinet ministers.</p>
<p>Opposition Shinshinto (New Frontier Party) President Ichiro Ozawa said in the debate that the record of Hashimoto's coalition of the LDP, the Social Democratic Party and tiny Sakigake did not bode well for administrative reform.</p>
<p>&quot;They had a clear majority in both houses of parliament for two years during which they called for deregulation and reform, but achieved nothing,&quot; said Ozawa, who would be prime minister in a Shinshinto government.</p>
<p>Ozawa, an old LDP ally turned rival of Hashimoto, mentioned Ronald Reagan by name as he touted his supply side tax cut schemes, funded by temporary borrowing, as the best cure for Japan's economic ills.</p>
<p>Last week Ozawa unveiled plans to dish out 18 trillion yen ($162 billion) in tax cuts by halving income and residential taxes and by trimming corporate taxes to 40 percent from the current 50 percent, predicting more than 20 trillion yen ($180 billion) in stimulus effects.</p>
<p>&quot;I have my doubts about those numbers,&quot; said Hashimoto.</p>
<p>The LDP and Shinshinto, made up mainly of lawmakers who left the LDP in 1993-94, are the only two parties running enough candidates to have a theoretical chance of capturing a clear majority in the 500-seat Lower House of parliament.</p>
<p>In a survey last week by the Yomiuri Shimbun daily newspaper, 33 percent of voters surveyed said they will vote for the LDP, while eight percent opted for Shinshinto.</p>
<p>The newly formed Democratic Party, the Social Democratic Party and the Japanese Communist Party each polled five percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said the LDP was set to win big in rural districts, its traditional power base, while the Democratic Party was set to fare well in urban areas and in the 200 seats contested from party lists by proportional representation.</p>
<p>Most pundits predict that the two largest parties will both fall short of a clear majority, triggering a scramble for a coalition partner or defectors from the enemy camp to tally 251 seats and select a prime minister. ($1-111 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
