<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99798" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysian city rejects outdoor Jackson concert.</title>
<headline>Malaysian city rejects outdoor Jackson concert.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Malaysian municipal council on Monday rejected an application to stage a show featuring pop king Michael Jackson, saying it could not be sure the U.S. entertainer would abide by its rules of propriety.</p>
<p>The national Bernama news agency said the Shah Alam Municipal Council rejected the application by organisers to hold the outdoor concert at the Shah Alam stadium on October 27.</p>
<p>Bernama quoted council president Aini Taib as saying the proposed concert was rejected after taking into account several factors, including its affect on young people in the predominantly Moslem nation.</p>
<p>Aini said applications for such shows must satisfy many conditions, including the attire of the artists, and the council could not be certain Jackson would abide by the conditions.</p>
<p>He said the concert promoter could appeal.</p>
<p>Jackson staged a concert in Moslem Brunei in July for Sultan Hassanal Bolkiah's 50th birthday, at which his trademark crotch-grabbing gestures were noticeably absent.</p>
<p>The Malaysian stop was to be part of Jackson's &quot;HISstory&quot; world tour. Tickets were priced between 160 and 350 ringgit ($64 and $140).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
