<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99934" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton, Dole hit campaign trail after debate.</title>
<headline>Clinton, Dole hit campaign trail after debate.</headline>
<byline>Michael Posner</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton and Bob Dole rushed back to the campaign trail on Monday, one day after a debate that analysts called a congenial clash in which Dole had scored without landing a badly needed knockout blow.</p>
<p>&quot;Take your pick of sports metaphors: No runs, a few hits, no errors. And no knockouts&quot; was how The Hotline, a widely read daily report on American politics, summed up the encounter.</p>
<p>&quot;The Clinton-Dole debate was more a civil discourse than a campaign milestone,&quot; it said. &quot;Dole gave his best debate performance ever, but did it matter?&quot;</p>
<p>It pointed to instant polls by ABC, CBS, CNN/USA Today/Gallup and Newsweek showing the Democratic president the winner among debate watchers by a margin of roughly 5 to 3.</p>
<p>His Republican challenger, badly trailing in the polls, clearly led the debate in laughs, delivering one-liners and humorous gibes as he sought to put Clinton on the defensive.</p>
<p>But he failed to score the telling knockout many analysts said he needed to catch Clinton less than a month away from the Nov. 5 election.</p>
<p>The former Kansas senator and Senate Republican leader, who quit Congress in June for active campaigning, said the Sunday night debate gave him the boost he needed.</p>
<p>&quot;When the story is written about this campaign, the record will show that we turned it around in Hartford, Connecticut,&quot; Dole told a post-debate rally.</p>
<p>The latest Reuters daily tracking poll, completed before the debate in Hartford, showed on Monday that Dole had closed the gap with Clinton to about 9 percentage points.</p>
<p>It put Clinton's backing at 44.4 percent, Dole's at 35.1 percent and Reform Party candidate Ross Perot's at 5.8 percent. The rolling three-day tracking poll, taken by John Zogby Group International for Reuters, had Clinton ahead by 15 points on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm calling this the October adjustment we've all been expecting,&quot; pollster John Zogby said, noting there had been no single event that caused the race to tighten.</p>
<p>Dole is solidifying his Republican base and &quot;is now getting three out of four Republican voters,&quot; Zogby said.</p>
<p>Both candidates resumed active campaigning on Monday with a full schedule in the Northeast, where polls show that Clinton is running strong.</p>
<p>In Stamford, Conn., Clinton picked up endorsements from 2,500 business people, executives at some top corporations.</p>
<p>In an effort to counter this, Dole's national campaign chairman, Donald Rumsfeld, announced at a news conference the formation of a National Business Coalition. The group of business executives will start a nationwide grassroots drive among business people to muster backing for the Dole-Kemp ticket.</p>
<p>Dirk Van Dongen, president of the National Association of Wholesale Distributors, made up of some 40,000 companies, said that despite Clinton's wooing of business, a majority of businesses were behind Dole and his economic growth programme.</p>
<p>Dole was in New Jersey campaigning by bus before big and enthusiastic crowds, urging people not to believe the polls, predicting he would win the election and promoting his economic plan, centred on a 15 percent across-the-board cut in personal income tax rates.</p>
<p>Dole's running mate, Jack Kemp, and Vice President Al Gore will debate on Wednesday in St. Petersburg, Florida, and Dole and Clinton will go at it again in a final debate in San Diego on Oct. 16.</p>
<p>Perot, the man who wasn't invited to debate, said in a speech in San Francisco that both Clinton and Dole had avoided major issues in their clash.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
