<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99944" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jardine chief says sees positive outlook.</title>
<headline>Jardine chief says sees positive outlook.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jardine Matheson Holdings Ltd said on Monday that its long-term overall outlook remains positive, despite a poor first half performance due to its Dairy Farm International Holdings Ltd unit and charges resulting from trading scandals at Jardine Fleming.</p>
<p>Alasdair Morrison, managing director of Jardine Matheson told an investment conference in New York that Dairy Farm's fortunes will take time to turn around. Profits at the unit were down 55 percent in the first half of 1996, mainly due to repositioning costs at Franklins Supermarket, he said.  </p>
<p>Earnings will continue to be affected over the next two years as repositioning continues.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be a couple of years before we see the fruits of work at Franklin,&quot; said Morrison.</p>
<p>Morrison said costs arising from regulatory problems at Jardine Flemings had been factored into the first half and should not affect Jardine Matheson's second half results. Jardine Matheson paid a fine of $10 million related to a trading scandal at Fleming.  </p>
<p>Looking ahead, Morrison said Jardine Fleming would be facing &quot;some vulnerability to tighter margins in the industry,&quot; and added that Jardine Fleming's main objective would be &quot;to re-establish the confidence of (its) clients.&quot;</p>
<p>Morrison said the positive rental cycle for Hong Kong Land was ending and that could temporarily affect earnings from negative rental reversions. However, new investments in Hong Kong and elsewhere in Asia would offset any impact on results. Morrison was very positive about Hong Kong Land's prospects.  </p>
<p>Going on to other businesses, Morrison said Jardine Pacific's new franchises at the new Hong Kong airport should be positive for that unit's results. However, he said the restaurant business in Australia continued to be a drag on earnings and the company was looking to exit this business.</p>
<p>Morrsion said the company's luxury hotel group, Mandarin Oriental, was poised to perform well as the strong Hong Kong market continued and the company sought to expand to other destinations in Asia Pacific and other locations internationally.  </p>
<p>He said that Jardine Matheson's motor distributor and retailer, Jardine International Motors, had suffered from difficult markets in Hong Kong and China in the first half, but the unit should see better sales in 1997 in the company's main market, Hong Kong.</p>
<p>In response to a question, Morrison said Jardine Strategic, which has a cross share holding with Jardine Matheson, will be going ahead with its previously announced five percent share buyback plan and added that the repurchase should be &quot;earnings and net asset value (NAV) enhancing.&quot;</p>
<p>Jardine Matheson owns 59 percent of Jardine Strategic and Jardine Strategic owns 36 percent of Jardine Matheson.</p>
<p>Morrison declined to comment on earnings projections, but said: &quot;We believe in the Asian growth story,&quot; and added that the company was positive about its position going forward in the Asia Pacific region and Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Jardine Matheson derives 80 to 85 percent of its profits from the Asia Pacific region, he added.</p>
<p>-- Kamalakshi Mehta/New York Equities 859-1700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BERM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
