<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99985" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BARLEY -- New MGE contract meets limp interest.</title>
<headline>BARLEY -- New MGE contract meets limp interest.</headline>
<byline>Greg Frost</byline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Minneapolis Grain Exchange's new barley futures contract has so far been met with limited interest because West Coast feed buyers have not been using it as a hedge vehicle, traders said Monday.</p>
<p>Barley futures were launched July 30, and MGE traders and other grain trade sources agreed that it was too early to judge whether the contract would be a success or a failure.</p>
<p>But they noted that the contract was not yet being used actively by the group it was designed for -- the end-user feedlots in California.  </p>
<p>&quot;They kind of tailored a few elements of the contract to the end-user and the buyer -- someone who's always short feed and needs to cover their shorts by buying barley,&quot; said an MGE trader who asked that his name not be used.</p>
<p>&quot;The ironic thing is that those are the people who have been least responsive to the barley market,&quot; the trader said. &quot;We've actually had fairly good participation by the commercials, the people selling the barley, but the problem is the trade's been so light that there hasn't been anyone for them to trade with on the other side except for locals.&quot;  </p>
<p>In August, 280 barley futures contracts exchanged hands on the MGE. But volume dropped off sharply in September, when only 137 contracts were traded.</p>
<p>The MGE said it was satisfied with the contract despite the mostly lackluster volumes. &quot;We're pleased with where the contract is at this point.</p>
<p>It's regularly being traded. The volume is by no means going through the roof, but that's not something we expected,&quot; said Catherine Newton, a spokeswoman for the MGE.</p>
<p>&quot;As time goes on here and as more and more people get involved, we'll have a really strong contract,&quot; Newton said.</p>
<p>The September contract expired with no one taking or making delivery against it, traders said.</p>
<p>Approximately 48 percent of all feed barley consumed within the United States is done so in California and Oregon, according to a study done by economists at North Dakota State University. For this reason, the MGE's contract specified delivery within a 35-mile radius of Tulare, Calif. -- the most often-used price discovery point within the barley trade.</p>
<p>Traders said part of the contract's problem was that the West Coast market was more oriented toward flat prices and was accustomed to hedging against CBOT corn futures.  </p>
<p>&quot;The barley business is a flat-price business... so we do not need to play the futures market,&quot; said a West Coast grain buyer who asked that his name not be used.</p>
<p>Other MGE traders pointed out that the U.S. cash barley market has been fairly liquid since barley futures were launched.</p>
<p>&quot;If the cash market dries up, which it typically does going into winter, then they (end-users) may have some cause...to trade it,&quot; a MGE trader said.</p>
<p>Newton said the MGE was also anticipating Canadian producers being given the go-ahead to market their own barley. But she declined to speculate when this might happen.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that was something we were counting on happening right away. That's something we were looking for in the future,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>--Kansas City bureau, 816 561-8671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
