<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="99992" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live and feeder cattle close higher.</title>
<headline>CME live and feeder cattle close higher.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle futures closed higher on expectations of strong cash cattle markets, amid underlying support from an oversold condition. Feeder cattle followed in light dealings, traders said.</p>
<p>Expectations that fed cattle markets will remain firm supported October live cattle after early carryover pressure and rolling of long positions into December. Market ready fed cattle supplies were expected to remain tight through October before starting to increase later in the year and early next year. Commercial and professional support lifted October for a net gain, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders also cited expectations of little or no delivery certificates posted against October.</p>
<p>December and other deferreds were supported from the start on the rolling of longs. December and February showed Relative Strength Index's in the 20's after the steep break in prices last week and futures were already at a large discount to cash, they said.</p>
<p>But prices eased from best levels on concern that fed supplies will rise and fed prices will tumble before the year is out, they added.  </p>
<p>Rand Financials and LFG bought October while Cargill Investor Services sold. Lind-Waldock and E.D.&amp; F. Man sold December late after early buying by Refco and RBH, much of which came on spreading against October, pit sources said.</p>
<p>In live cattle options, volatility was weak. Commercials sold December 68 calls early with commission houses buying February 60 and 62 puts and December 66 puts later, pit sources added.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle futures continued to follow the lead of live cattle futures and held gains in slow trade. Higher corn futures provided only light resistance, traders said.</p>
<p>E.D.&amp; F. Man bought November while locals sold October late. Cargill Investor Services notably spread long May feeders/short October 1997 live cattle early. ING sold October while R.J. O'Brien bought October early, pit sources said.</p>
<p>The latest CME feeder cattle index was up $0.09 at $63.88 per cwt.</p>
<p>Live cattle closed 0.275 to 0.550 higher with December up 0.375 at 66.400 cents. Feeder cattle ended 0.250 to 0.350 cent higher with October up 0.250 at 63.650 cents.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
